{"summary":"Former FTX director of engineering Nishad Singh made more than $13 million in donations to Democratic Party initiatives, CNBC said.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/192654\/ftx-prolific-democrat-party-donor-cnbc","publishDate":"2022-12-06T14:16:17","id":10005,"type":null,"title":"Former FTX executive Nishad Singh was a prolific Democratic Party donor: CNBC","category":["LOBBYING"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Former FTX Director of Engineering Nishad Singh donated millions to candidates and causes aligned with the Democratic Party beginning in 2020, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.cnbc.com\/2022\/12\/06\/former-ftx-engineer-quietly-became-millionaire-democratic-donor.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CNBC<\/a> reported.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Prior to taking a senior role in Sam Bankman-Fried’s now-crumbling crypto empire, Singh's only political contribution was $2,700 to Rep. Sean Casten, D-Ill., in 2018. However, when Singh joined FTX in 2019 after a brief role at Alameda Research, he would go on to donate more than $13 million to Democrats after the 2020 elections, CNBC said, citing state and federal campaign records.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">At least $8 million from Singh flowed to Democratic causes in the 2022 election cycle, including $1 million to support a political action committee (PAC) behind Joe Biden’s presidential bid, $2 million to support the Senate Majority PAC, a combined $4 million to Reproductive Freedom for All, and another $1 million to Mind the Gap, a super PAC founded by Bankman-Fried's mother, CNBC said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Nonpartisan campaign tracker <a href=\"https:\/\/www.opensecrets.org\/outside-spending\/top_donors\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">OpenSecrets<\/a> ranks Singh 31st in its list of top donors to outside spending groups.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A donation marked as coming from infrastructure company&nbsp;Prime Trust to the Democratic Part of Oregon PAC actually originated from Singh, <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Oregonian <a href=\"https:\/\/www.oregonlive.com\/politics\/2022\/11\/oregon-democrats-said-they-accepted-500000-from-a-las-vegas-cryptocurrency-startup-now-they-say-the-real-donor-was-someone-else.html?outputType=amp\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a>.&nbsp;<\/span>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Updated for clarity.<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Senate Majority PAC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$13 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Democratic Party","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Joe Biden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$2,700","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX Director of Engineering Nishad Singh","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sean Casten","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$4 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$2 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Democratic Part of Oregon PAC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CNBC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$8 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Ill.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Singh","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Singh","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["PACS"],"authors":["Jeremy Nation","The Block"]}