{"summary":"CEX trading volumes rose by 23.7% in November, while DEX volumes jumped 93.2%.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/191352\/decentralized-crypto-exchange-volumes-nearly-double-in-november-amid-ftx-debacle","publishDate":"2022-12-01T10:18:36","id":10029,"type":null,"title":"Decentralized crypto exchange volumes nearly double in November amid FTX debacle","category":["CRYPTO INFRASTRUCTURE"],"content":["Cryptocurrency exchange volumes <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockresearch.com\/november-by-the-numbers-3-191219\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">jumped<\/a> in November from the previous month as the collapse of FTX roiled markets, with decentralized platforms seeing an increase of 93%.","Centralized (CEX) exchange volumes, which include platforms like Binance and Coinbase, rose by 24% to $673 billion, up from $543 billion in October, according to The Block's data. Decentralized (DEX) exchanges, excluding layer 2's, saw a substantially bigger increase, with volume doubling to $65 billion from $34 billion.","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/crypto-markets\/spot\/cryptocurrency-exchange-volume-monthly\/embed\" title=\"Cryptocurrency Exchange Volume (The Block Legitimate Index)\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","&nbsp;","The Block Research's Lars Hoffman <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockresearch.com\/november-by-the-numbers-3-191219\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">attributed<\/a> the increases to the \"collapse of FTX and subsequent de-risking from CEX's to on-chain.\" Crypto holders are likely losing faith in centralized exchanges and moving to decentralized exchanges where they self-custody their keys.","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/decentralized-finance\/dex-non-custodial\/dex-volume-monthly\/embed\" title=\"DEX Volume\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Curve, an exchange liquidity pool on Ethereum, saw an increase of 371% in volume during the month.","November marked a recovery for crypto exchange volumes, which <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/181394\/crypto-exchange-volumes-23-month-low\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reached<\/a> an almost two-year low in October.&nbsp;","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Lars Hoffman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$34 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$65 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$543 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"93%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$673 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Block Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"DEX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CEX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"24%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"371%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"October","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE","BITCOIN","BLOCKFI","ETHEREUM","FTX"],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}