{"summary":"Sinclair, an NFT artist involved in the $1 million Whitney Houston NFT sale, joins UTA&#x27;s growing roster of web3 creators. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/173219\/uta-signs-on-nft-artist-diana-sinclair-the-hollywood-reporter","publishDate":"2022-09-27T15:18:43","id":10065,"type":null,"title":"UTA signs on NFT artist Diana Sinclair","category":["NFTS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Diana Sinclair, an 18-year-old NFT artist, has signed on with the talent representative United Talent Agency and will sell some of the inaugural NFTs for Christie's 3.0.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Christie’s 3.0. is a platform for on-chain NFT sales out the art auction house <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/113817\/christies-to-hold-first-ever-sale-of-meebits-and-bored-ape-yacht-club-nfts\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Christie’s<\/a>. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sinclair is set to auction nine of her NFTs<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> between Sept. 28-Oct. 11, 2022, according to a Christie's release. Three companies are helping to build Christie's 3.0: the metaverse developer Spatial, the blockchain forensics firm Chainalysis and&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sinclair has created work covering Black identity, racial inequities and social injustice. Late last year, Sinclair provided the video for a previously unreleased Whitney Houston track that sold as an NFT for $1 million on the Tezos-powered marketplace OneOf.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sinclair joins other individual web3 artists such as Emonee LaRussa, Vinnie Hager and Andrew Wang represented by UTA, The Hollywood Reporter writes, along with the NFT brand&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/142561\/talent-agency-uta-to-represent-nft-project-deadfellaz\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Deadfellaz<\/a>.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The popular NFT project CryptoPunks was included in this list, but as UTA’s head of web3 Lesley Silverman told The Block, UTA no longer represents this project after Yuga Labs <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/137631\/bored-apes-creator-yuga-labs-acquires-ip-for-cryptopunks-and-meebits\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">acquired<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> the CryptoPunk intellectual property.<\/span>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Update: This story was updated to better represent Sinclair's involvement with Christie's.<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Diana Sinclair","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"UTA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Vinnie Hager","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sept. 28","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Andrew Wang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Oct. 11, 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Emonee LaRussa","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Whitney Houston","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sinclair","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Christie's","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lesley Silverman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Christie","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"United Talent Agency","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}