{"summary":"Limit Break promoted DigiDaigaku NFTs during the Super Bowl while a phishing scammer stole several valuable digital assets belonging to the same ecosystem.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/211179\/scammers-nab-nfts-from-ecosystem-of-super-bowl-advertiser-on-game-day-peckshield","publishDate":"2023-02-13T16:04:09","id":10114,"type":null,"title":"Scammers nab NFT&#x27;s from ecosystem of Super Bowl advertiser on game day: PeckShield","category":["METAVERSE & NFT"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Limit Break took to one of the biggest stages in television on Sunday to promote a new NFT collection belonging to its anime-styled <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">DigiDaigaku <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">brand during the Super Bowl. F<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ar from the spotlight a scam artist was busy stealing several DigiDaigaku NFTs from their rightful owners<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, according to <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">crypto security firm PeckShield.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The phisher 0xA69F8 has grabbed 153<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> NFTs<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in the past 12 hours, including four<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Digidaigaku<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> and six <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">DigiDaigakuHeroes<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,” PeckShield posted on Twitter. The crypto security firm also said that DigiDaigaku #756 and DigiDaigaku #1407 had, in the past, sold for more than $12,000 each on the X2Y2 platform.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">NFT studios are trying to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/208152\/january-nft-data-wrap-eth-volumes-rise-nearly-50-as-bayc-leads-blue-chip-brand-expansion\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">expand the reach<\/a> of their brands in order to attract mainstream consumers, even as the broader industry has suffered a months-long crisis of confidence triggered by hacks, scams and allegations of fraud.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Super Bowl promotion advertised Limit Break's 10,000-piece NFT collection called DigiDaigaku Dragon Eggs. The NFTs, which were free to mint, have already generated more than $1.7 million in trading volume on the secondary market, according to OpenSea data.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Limit Break's DigiDaigaku Genesis collection has racked more than $28 million in volume since launching last year, also according to OpenSea.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Sunday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"DigiDaigaku #","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DigiDaigaku Genesis","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"DigiDaigaku","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1407","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$1.7 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$28 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"DigiDaigaku Dragon Eggs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"PeckShield","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"OpenSea","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$12,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Digidaigaku","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}