{"summary":"Crypto markets were generally in the green Friday morning.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/204193\/crypto-prices-stocks-up-with-bitcoin-above-21000","publishDate":"2023-01-20T10:10:03","id":1013,"type":null,"title":"Crypto prices, stocks up with bitcoin above $21,000","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["Cryptocurrencies were mostly higher after the U.S. open, with bitcoin trading back above $21,000.","Ether was up 1.3% to around $1,553, as of 9:40 a.m. ET.","Traditional markets were also in the green, with S&amp;P 500 up by 0.2% and the Nasdaq 100 higher by 0.7%.","","","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/chart\/h7wYKiIo\/?symbol=COINBASE%3ABTCUSD\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BTC\/USD chart by TradingView<\/a>","FTT held on to gains from yesterday when it <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/203860\/ftt-token-price-soars-after-ftx-ceo-floats-exchange-restart\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">jumped about 30%<\/a> on the news that FTX's new CEO was considering restarting the exchange. It was trading at around $2.30.","","","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/chart\/h7wYKiIo\/?symbol=CRYPTO%3AFTTUSD\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">FTT\/USD Chart by TradinfView<\/a>","Crypto stocks also traded up, with Silvergate shares gaining 3.3%. MicroStrategy was up by a more modest 0.3%, Block by 1.7% and Coinbase by 2.5%.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"9:40 a.m. ET","content":"TIME"},{"type":"TradingView","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1.7%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"0.7%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"3.3%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"1.3%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"S&amp;P","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$2.30","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"USD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"0.3%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$1,553","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"0.2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"30%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"TradinfView","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$21,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"MicroStrategy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nasdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Catarina Moura","The Block"]}