{"summary":"KBank said in a stock exchange filing that it has acquired the local exchange through a subsidiary.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/259955\/thai-banking-giant-kbank-acquires-satang-exchange-to-grow-crypto-business","publishDate":"2023-10-30T03:21:16","id":10139,"type":null,"title":"Thai banking giant KBank acquires Satang exchange to grow crypto business","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kasikornbank, Thailand's <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.kasikornbank.com\/en\/ir\/generalinformation\/pages\/corporate.aspx\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">second-largest<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> bank by assets, today announced the acquisition of a local crypto exchange through a subsidiary.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.kasikornbank.com\/en\/IR\/FinanInfoReports\/LetterToSET\/20231030_UnitaCapital_EN.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">letter<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> filed today to the Stock Exchange of Thailand, Kasikornbank, also known as KBank, said it acquired 97% of the shares of Satang Corporation Co. Ltd, which operates a digital asset exchange, on Oct. 27. KBank plans to rename Satang as Orbix Trade Co. Ltd., the filing said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The acquisition was made through Unita Capital, a wholly-owned subsidiary of KBank with registered capital of 3.7 billion Baht ($102.8 million), according to the filing.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Unita Capital has also set up three subsidiaries — Orbix Custodian, Orbix Invest and Orbix Technology &amp; Innovation Co. Ltd. — for its digital asset custodian, fund management and blockchain infrastructure development businesses, the filing showed.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Last month, KBank announced a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/250981\/kbank-web3-ai-vc-fund\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$100 million fund to invest in web3 and artificial intelligence startups<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. The fund, dubbed KXVC, was set up by KBank's tech arm, Kasikorn Business Technology Group.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The fund<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> will target AI, web3 and deep tech fintech startups globally with a potential focus on Asia Pacific, according to KBank.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Orbix Trade Co. Ltd.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Orbix Technology &amp; Innovation Co. Ltd.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$100 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Kasikornbank","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"97%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Unita Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$102.8 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Satang Corporation Co. Ltd","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Orbix Invest","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Stock Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thailand","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Kasikorn Business Technology Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"3.7 billion Baht","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Oct. 27","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Asia Pacific","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["CRYPTO","PUBLIC COMPANY M&AMP;A","TRADFI BANKS"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}