{"summary":"AR company Kaleidoco completed its first funding round with investment from the likes of Animoca Brands, Gemini and Merit Circle.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/152185\/ar-company-kaleidoco-announces-7-million-seed-funding-round","publishDate":"2022-06-15T08:00:21","id":10144,"type":null,"title":"AR company Kaleidoco announces $7 million seed funding round","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Augmented Reality (AR) company Kaleidoco announced the completion of $7 million seed round on Wednesday.","Investors include Animoca Brands, GameFi Ventures, Gemini, Jane Street, Adit Ventures, Merit Circle, Nexo, HexTrust, SuperChain Capital, and The Seelig Group.","In a statement, the company said it would use the seed funding&nbsp;to accelerate growth and make new hires.","<span class=\"xn-person\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Founded in 2018 by Cassandra Rosenthal and Jennifer Tuft, who are co-CEOs of the company, Kaleidoco debuted its Particle Ink metaverse at TED2022 in April. <\/span>","<span class=\"xn-person\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">It described its metaverse as being in the \"2.5th dimension\" as it mixes augmented reality with other web3 technologies.<\/span>","“Using AR as the foundation for a metaverse allows us to stay grounded in our physical world and with those around us while also benefiting from the boundless potential of the digital world,” said Tuft.","The raise is the latest example of funds flowing into the web3 and gaming space in search of better development of online worlds. Earlier this week Wildcard Alliance, a new gaming project created by the developer behind popular app-based game Words with Friends, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/151816\/team-behind-words-with-friends-raises-46-million-for-new-gaming-venture-on-polygon?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">raised $46 million<\/a> in a Series A round.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Jennifer Tuft","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Cassandra Rosenthal","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gemini","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$7 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"The Seelig Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jane Street","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Adit Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Animoca Brands","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kaleidoco","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$46 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Nexo","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Wildcard Alliance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Merit Circle","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["FUNDRAISING"],"authors":["Callan Quinn","The Block"]}