{"summary":"Grayscale filed a new registration statement with the SEC in its ongoing attempt to convert GBTC into a spot bitcoin ETF.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/258299\/grayscale-submits-new-filing-to-sec-in-attempt-for-spot-bitcoin-etf-approval-following-pivotal-court-ruling","publishDate":"2023-10-19T08:30:03","id":1016,"type":null,"title":"Grayscale submits new filing to SEC in attempt for spot bitcoin ETF approval following pivotal court ruling","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Grayscale Investments filed a new registration statement with the Securities and Exchange Commission in its ongoing attempt to convert its Grayscale <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitcoin <\/span><span class=\"articleTooltip\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"\/price\/248348\/bitcoin-btc-usd\" class=\"articleTooltip__link\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"><img src=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2023\/10\/bitcoin.png\" alt=\"\" title=\"\" class=\"articleTooltip__tokenImage\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">BTC<\/span> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText articleTooltip__tokenText_price articleTooltip__tokenText_positive\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">\n      +1.08%\n    <\/span><\/a> <!----><\/span><\/span> Trust into a spot bitcoin ETF after a D.C. circuit court's ruling directing the regulator to re-review the firm's application.&nbsp;<\/span><\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The asset manager on Thursday morning submitted an S-3 filing, a shortened version of the typical S-1 filing used to offer new shares. Grayscale's latest move comes as other big name asset managers including BlackRock and Fidelity are seeking approval for spot bitcoin ETFs from the SEC.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Grayscale said it was eligible to use Form S-3 for its filing because its shares have been registered under the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 since January 2020 and meet the other requirements for the form.<\/span>","GBTC intends to list the shares on NYSE Arca under the symbol GBTC, and issue the shares on an ongoing basis upon approval of NYSE Arca's application on Form 19b-4 to list the shares and effectiveness of the form S-3 to register the shares, Grayscale said in a statement.&nbsp;","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The filing comes a day before the U.S. Court of Appeals for the D.C. Circuit is expected to issue a court mandate that will essentially reiterate its initial ruling from August, but is seen as a final proceeding in the matter.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The SEC did not file an appeal for a rehearing of the court's ruling last week, which led to optimism in the industry that a spot bitcoin ETF could be around the corner. However, a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/255560\/gold-etfs-could-shed-light-on-the-secs-thinking-about-proposals-for-spot-bitcoin-funds\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">number of things<\/span><\/a> would still need to happen before one hits the market.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Grayscale first brought the case against the SEC last year for the rejection of its proposal to convert its flagship fund, GBTC, into a spot bitcoin ETF. <\/span><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The asset manager sent a letter to the SEC last month, asking to meet with regulators to discuss converting its Grayscale Bitcoin Trust into a spot bitcoin ETF.<\/span>","SEC Chair Gary Gensler <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/258226\/sec-chair-gensler-says-agency-staff-doing-work-on-multiple-bitcoin-etf-filings\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said Wednesday<\/a> that agency \"staff is doing work on those multiple filings,\" referring to existing proposals that it's received. He declined to comment specifically on Grayscale when asked about it by a reporter.&nbsp;","\"What we have in front of us, just so that the viewing public understands, we have not one, but multiple, I think it's eight or ten filings that the staff, and ultimately the Commission, is considering,\" he said. \"When an asset manager is seeking to take something public, these exchange traded products need to register with the SEC, and they go through a filing, somewhat similar to going public, like an IPO.\"","\"And so it's really the work of our Division of Corporation Finance that gives feedback, our Division of Trading and Markets of course looks at the filings,\" he continued. \"This is a time tested process that goes back decades. The staff of the SEC, it's called the Disclosure Review Team, but in that group, they respond and give feedback to potential issuers.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"+1.08%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"January 2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Grayscale","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Grayscale Bitcoin Trust","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Disclosure Review Team","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gary Gensler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Grayscale <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitcoin <\/span><span class=\"articleTooltip\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"\/price\/248348\/bitcoin-btc-usd\" class=\"articleTooltip__link\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"><img src=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2023\/10\/bitcoin.png\" alt=\"\" title=\"\" class=\"articleTooltip__tokenImage\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"3","content":"DATE"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"},{"type":"D.C. Circuit","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BlackRock","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. Court of Appeals","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Division of Corporation Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1934","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Fidelity","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Securities Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"morning","content":"TIME"},{"type":"last week","content":"DATE"},{"type":"D.C.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"NYSE Arca","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["SEC"],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}