{"summary":"The world’s largest bitcoin mining rig manufacturer, however, did not disclose the timeline of the launch.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/258881\/bitmain-plans-to-unveil-mining-rigs-for-aleo-blockchain","publishDate":"2023-10-23T03:59:25","id":10189,"type":null,"title":"Bitmain plans to unveil mining rigs for Aleo blockchain","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The largest bitcoin mining rigs manufacturer Bitmain plans to launch mining machines for Aleo, a proof-of-work blockchain that aims to achieve privacy using zero-knowledge proofs.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The China-based firm announced in a<\/span>&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/mp.weixin.qq.com\/s\/UVLKlHGryXvlaqMh6MfFFA\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">post<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on the social media platform WeChat that it planned to roll out an 'Antminer' model for Aleo, which is<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/160545\/aleo-to-test-virtual-machine-ahead-of-mainnet-launch\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">in the testnet phase<\/a>.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The developers of Aleo last year <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/133218\/aleo-raises-200-million-softbank-tiger-others-blockchain\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">raised $200 million<\/a> in its series B funding round co-led by <\/span>SoftBank Vision Fund 2 and Kora Management. Tiger Global, Andreessen Horowitz (a16z), Samsung Next, Slow Ventures and Sea Capital also participated in the funding round.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitmain did not disclose the timeline of the launch in the statement.&nbsp;<\/span>","The planned launch of new Aleo-based miners comes after Bitmain earlier this month drew public attention for its internal announcement to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/255393\/bitmain-wages-cash-flow-issues-paid\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">delay staff payments<\/a> for September amid reported cash flow issues. The company has repaid the wages, <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/WuBlockchain\/status\/1710946118467813521?s=20\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">according to<\/a> crypto reporter Colin Wu.","Still the firm has made progress in other areas. In September, Bitmain launched its latest Antminer S21 model, and some miners have already expressed interest in purchasing the new machine. <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">For example, CleanSpark, a Nasdaq-listed American bitcoin miner,<\/span> <a href=\"https:\/\/www.prnewswire.com\/apac\/news-releases\/cleanspark-acquires-4-4-ehs-of-new-antminer-s21-bitcoin-miners-expects-to-achieve-hashrate-of-over-20-ehs-301953186.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that it has purchased 4.4 exahashes per second of the S21 mining rigs. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitmain<\/span> has also <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/252452\/bitcoin-mining-rig-maker-bitmain-plans-to-invest-54-million-in-bankrupt-core-scientific\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced plans to invest $54 million<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in bankrupt bitcoin mining firm Core Scientific.<\/span> Bitmain designs and manufactures application-specific integrated circuit (ASIC) chips for bitcoin mining and operates the largest mining pool known as Antpool.","\"We’re excited to see Bitmain and others contribute to the space with their specialized proving hardware,\" Alex Pruden, chief executive officer of Aleo, told The Block. \"As our breakthrough cryptography gets implemented in advanced hardware, we believe it will greatly accelerate the adoption of ZKPs for use cases —large and small — across not just Web3, but the internet more broadly.\"","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Colin Wu","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SoftBank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sea Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kora Management","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$54 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Alex Pruden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Andreessen Horowitz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$200 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Aleo","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Samsung Next","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Antminer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"China","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Nasdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["MINING","MINING COMPANIES"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}