{"summary":"FTX owes money to Apple, Meta, Binance, Twitter, Netflix and many others.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/205859\/ftx-creditor-list-includes-star-athletes-crypto-firms-state-governments","publishDate":"2023-01-26T10:08:05","id":10201,"type":null,"title":"FTX creditor list includes star athletes, crypto firms, state governments","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">An extensive list of creditors hoping to get back a piece of crippled crypto exchange FTX and its family of companies was published late on Wednesday.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The 116-page document <a href=\"https:\/\/www.docdroid.net\/9hVtHdm\/746caf04-a236-4598-a1bc-825f889bf35d-1-pdf#page=43\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filed<\/a> to the U.S. Bankruptcy Court District of Delaware shows an extensive overview of who FTX owes money to, including industry players, banks, law firms and companies the failed crypto empire had a commercial partnership with.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Companies that offered their services to bankrupt crypto exchange FTX are included on the creditor list, which lists vendors as well as business partners. Digital service providers are joining the line to get back a piece of their funds, including giants like Amazon Web Services, Apple, Meta Platforms, LinkedIn, Twitter, Netflix and Adobe.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">From the crypto industry, names like Coinbase, Binance Capital Management, Chainalysis, Yuga Labs, Doodles, BlockFi and Silvergate Bank made the list. News publications include<\/span><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> The Wall Street Journal<\/span><\/i><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, <\/span><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CoinDesk<\/span><\/i><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> and <\/span><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Benzinga<\/span><\/i><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.&nbsp;<\/span>","Creditors also included star athletes, like Tampa Bay Buccaneers Quarterback Tom Brady and David Ortiz, the former designated hitter for the Boston Red Sox. Brady and Ortiz have also been targeted in a separate class action lawsuit over their paid endorsement of the failed crypto company. Other businesses on the creditor list included the Coachella music festival, Carbone’s Miami Beach restaurant and the posh Nobu Hotel.","The prime minister of the Bahamas, other governmental offices for the island nation, as well as U.S. state tax, consumer affairs, and attorney general offices were also listed.&nbsp;","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Individual retail FTX users were not included in the list. While the document does not break down the amounts owed to creditors, it was previously <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/188642\/ftx-owes-almost-3-1-billion-to-its-top-50-creditors-filing-says\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">revealed<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that FTX owes more than $3 billion to its top 50 creditors, many of whom are institutional investors.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The U.S. Trustee overseeing the FTX bankruptcy was interested in appointing an examiner to add transparency to the case.<\/span> <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Investigate the collapse of FTX could cost nearly $100 million, FTX debtors argued in a document <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/205712\/court-docs-ftx-debtors-bahamian-liquidators-object-to-u-s-trustees-examiner-request\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filed<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on Wednesday, arguing it would “provide no benefit” to creditors.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n\n<\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Tampa Bay Buccaneers Quarterback Tom Brady","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Silvergate Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nobu Hotel","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$3 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$100 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Meta Platforms","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Yuga Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Netflix","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Boston Red Sox","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. Bankruptcy Court District of Delaware","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Adobe","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance Capital Management","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ortiz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Amazon Web Services","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chainalysis","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Carbone’s Miami Beach","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"David Ortiz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bahamas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","Stephanie Murray","The Block"]}