{"summary":"The Federal Reserve&#x27;s Michael Barr called for a strong framework for stablecoins amid concerns about their reliance on the central bank. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/261984\/federal-reserves-michael-barr-calls-for-a-strong-federal-framework-for-stablecoins","publishDate":"2023-11-07T10:45:47","id":10227,"type":null,"title":"Federal Reserve&#x27;s Michael Barr calls for a strong federal framework for stablecoins","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Michael Barr, v<\/span>ice chair of the Federal Reserve for supervision,&nbsp;<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">called for a strong federal framework for stablecoins amid concerns that p<\/span><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">rivate entities are essentially creating private money.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Private money needs to be well regulated,\" Barr said Tuesday at DC Fintech Week, adding that stablecoins that are linked to fiat currency, such as the dollar, borrow \"the trust of the Fed.\"<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The central bank has increased its focus on <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/243813\/federal-reserve-increases-oversight-of-banking-crypto-ties\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">stablecoins<\/span><\/a> and in August announced new guardrails to strengthen its supervision of banks involved in stablecoin activity. Barr said last month that he was \"deeply <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/249935\/top-fed-official-says-he-is-deeply-concerned-about-stablecoins-without-federal-oversight\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">concerned<\/span><\/a>\" about issuing stablecoins without strong federal oversight.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Lawmakers within the House Financial Services Committee advanced a stablecoin bill over the summer to regulate those assets. That came with a few sticking points, however, such as disagreement from Rep. Maxine Waters, D-Calif, over a provision that would allow state regulators to approve stablecoin issuance without Federal Reserve input.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Waters told <a href=\"https:\/\/www.politico.com\/newsletters\/morning-money\/2023\/10\/27\/mchenrys-next-move-00123910\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Politico<\/span><\/a> last week that she expects talks on that stablecoin bill to start back up. <\/span><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Barr said on Tuesday that it would be better if Congress takes a role.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The central bank published a report last year to examine the pros and cons of a potential CBDC. Barr said no decision has been made on whether the central bank would issue one.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Fed would only create a retail CBDC if Congress and the executive branch \"clearly authorized us to do that,\" Barr said. Retail CBDCs are meant for consumer use, and some have said they could be a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/216340\/u-s-treasury-convening-regular-biden-administration-discussions-on-cbdc\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">complement<\/span><\/a> to cash, though not replace it.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Barr emphasized that the central bank was still deep in the research phase.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"We're very focused on research questions,\" Barr said.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Nellie Liang, under secretary for domestic finance at U.S. Treasury, said a future CBDC would be more of a decision for the Federal Reserve, and less for Treasury.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Distributed ledger technology has potential, Liang added on Tuesday at DC Fintech Week.&nbsp;<\/span>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Updated at 3:30 p.m. with comments from Nellie Liang&nbsp;<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Federal Reserve","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nellie Liang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"DC Fintech Week","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Maxine Waters","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Michael Barr","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Fed","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Congress","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"3:30 p.m.","content":"TIME"},{"type":"Calif","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Barr","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"last month","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Politico","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"House Financial Services Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"summer","content":"DATE"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["FEDERAL RESERVE"],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}