{"summary":"Four months after acquiring a Japanese licensed crypto exchange, FTX has launched FTX Japan to service customers in the country.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/150055\/ftx-launches-licensed-crypto-exchange-service-in-japan","publishDate":"2022-06-03T09:27:34","id":10267,"type":null,"title":"FTX launches licensed crypto exchange service in Japan","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["Crypto exchange giant FTX has launched its Japanese cryptocurrency trading service called FTX Japan, the company announced on Thursday.","FTX Japan is the result of FTX’s prior <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/132746\/ftx-liquid-acquisition-japan-crypto-exchange\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">acquisition of Liquid Group<\/a> in February. Liquid was the parent company of Quoine Corp., one of the first crypto exchange platforms licensed in Japan in 2017.","The launch of the platform will see FTX able to migrate its existing customer base in Japan under the FTX Japan umbrella for crypto spot and perpetual contracts trading.","These supported cryptocurrencies include bitcoin (BTC), ether (ETH), and solana (SOL) among others.","Customers will also be able to make deposits and withdrawals using the Japanese yen.","The announcement marks Japan as the latest entry in FTX’s global expansion push. Japan remains one of the most tightly-regulated jurisdictions for crypto trading and was one of the first to create a formal licensing framework for exchanges.","FTX was the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/149654\/ftx-surpassed-coinbase-as-second-biggest-centralized-crypto-exchange-in-may\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">second-largest centralized crypto exchange<\/a> in May, as previously reported by The Block. Sam Bankman-Fried, the company’s CEO, has stated plans to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/149276\/bankman-fried-says-ftx-prepared-to-spend-billions-on-acquisitions-bloomberg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">spend billions of US dollars<\/a> on further acquisitions.","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"February","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Japan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"US dollars","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX Japan","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Quoine Corp.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Liquid Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Osato Avan-Nomayo","The Block"]}