{"summary":"OpenSea CFO Brian Roberts has left the NFT marketplace company less than a year after he joined, according to his LinkedIn update post. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/175758\/opensea-cfo-leaves-less-than-one-year-after-joining","publishDate":"2022-10-08T12:30:05","id":10309,"type":null,"title":"OpenSea CFO leaves less than one year after joining","category":["NFTS"],"content":["<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">OpenSea CFO Brian Roberts has left the NFT marketplace company less than a year after he joined, according to his LinkedIn update <a href=\"https:\/\/www.linkedin.com\/feed\/update\/urn:li:activity:6984258573081989120\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">posted<\/a> on Friday.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Roberts, the former CFO at the ride-sharing giant Lyft,&nbsp;<\/span><a class=\"editor-rtfLink\" href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/126426\/former-lyft-executive-joins-nft-marketplace-opensea-as-cfo\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">joined<\/span><\/a><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> OpenSea last December as the company's first finance employee and built the finance team from the ground up, his LinkedIn update said. He will be staying on as an adviser to the company.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Roberts' departure comes amid something of a crypto industry exodus. Several executives have left crypto firms in recent weeks. Earlier this week, The Block <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/174513\/ftxs-head-of-otc-and-institutional-sales-has-quietly-left-the-firm\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a> that FTX's head of OTC and institutional sales Jonathan Cheesman had quietly left the firm. Last month, FTX.US president Brett Harrison stepped back to an advisory role. In the same month, Kraken CEO Jesse Powell stepped down to make way for incoming CEO David Ripley. Bitcoin investment services firm NYDIG’s CEO Robert Gutmann and president Yan Zhao also left the company last week.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Reasons behind the moves may vary, but they all come amid difficult market conditions. Bitcoin's price has declined more than 70% from last November's all-time highs of around $69,000 to about $19,500 today.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">NFT trading volumes have also declined sharply in recent months. Last month, there was a drop of about 18% in trading volume on Ethereum-based NFT marketplaces to $504 million, according to data from <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockresearch.com\/september-by-the-numbers-2-174035\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block Research<\/a>.<\/span>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/nft-non-fungible-tokens\/marketplaces\/nft-marketplace-monthly-volume\/embed\" title=\"NFT Marketplace Monthly Volume\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">OpenSea, the largest NFT marketplace, saw its volumes drop more than 30% last month. Roberts said in his LinkedIn update that he remained \"incredibly bullish on web3 and especially OpenSea.\"<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"The company is heads down building and I assure you, the best is yet to come,\" he added.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">OpenSea is backed by high-profile investors, including Paradigm and Coatue. Earlier this year, the company <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/129250\/opensea-eyeing-raise-that-would-value-it-at-13-billion-with-backing-from-coatue-and-paradigm-sources\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">raised<\/a> $300 million in a Series C funding round at a $13.3 billion valuation. Shortly after the fundraise, OpenSea <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/130606\/opensea-confirms-acquisition-of-dharma-sets-sights-on-fiat-onramps\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">acquired<\/a> crypto wallet firm Dharma Labs, and in April this year, it acquired NFT aggregator <a href=\"https:\/\/www.google.com\/search?q=opensea+gem+site%3Atheblock.co&amp;ei=8aBBY5G5OPiZseMPpq-q0AY&amp;ved=0ahUKEwjR9c3QgtH6AhX4TGwGHaaXCmoQ4dUDCA4&amp;uact=5&amp;oq=opensea+gem+site%3Atheblock.co&amp;gs_lp=Egdnd3Mtd2l6uAED-AEBSK8JUPUBWLQHcAF4AMgBAJABAJgBYKABqAOqAQE14gMEIEEYAeIDBCBGGACIBgE&amp;sclient=gws-wiz\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Gem<\/a>.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Roberts said in his LinkedIn profile that helped OpenSea close the fundraise and the two acquisitions.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">OpenSea did not immediately respond to The Block's request for comment on Roberts' departure.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"70%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Roberts","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"April this year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Coatue","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Brian Roberts","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kraken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"30%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jonathan Cheesman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"David Ripley","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Yan Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$504 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$13.3 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"The Block Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Robert Gutmann","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$69,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Jesse Powell","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$19,500","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"18%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Brett Harrison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$300 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"last December","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Dharma Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["OPENSEA"],"authors":["Yogita Khatri","The Block"]}