{"summary":"The proposal aims to increase public trust in real-time payments and make sanctions screening more efficient.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/180579\/european-commission-instant-euro-payments-draft-law","publishDate":"2022-10-28T03:12:35","id":10329,"type":null,"title":"European Commission proposes real-time euro payments in draft law","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The European Commission proposed a draft law on Wednesday obliging banks within the European Union's member states to offer instant euro payments for the same (or lower) fee as existing credit transfers.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We would estimate that if we left it to the market, it might take a decade for instant payments to become the norm,” European Commissioner for finance Mairead McGuinness <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/ec.europa.eu\/commission\/presscorner\/detail\/en\/statement_22_6410\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in a press conference on Wednesday. “Therefore we are nudging this sector in this direction.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Instant payments would release up to €200 billion that is locked in the financial system in a day, McGuiness explained.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The proposal aims to standardize and increase public trust in these types of transfers, as well as make sanctions screening more efficient.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In the United States, the Federal Reserve <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/166327\/federal-reserves-fednow-payments-system-will-be-live-within-a-year-says-brainard\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that a similar instant payment system, FedNow, will be live before the end of next summer.&nbsp;<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"My expectation is that FedNow addresses the issues that some have raised about the need for a CBDC,” Federal Reserve Governor Michelle Bowman <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/164085\/federal-reserve-governor-pumps-the-brakes-on-us-cbdc-in-favor-of-fednow\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in a speech in August.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A digital euro <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/170734\/amazon-among-five-companies-to-develop-digital-euro-prototype-for-the-ecb\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">prototype<\/a> is <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">in the works<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> under the supervision of the European Central Bank. The evaluation and results of the project are expected in March 2023. <\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Federal Reserve","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"European Union","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"” Federal Reserve","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"McGuiness","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"European Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"March 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Mairead McGuinness","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Michelle Bowman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"European Central Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"summer","content":"DATE"},{"type":"United States","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["ECB","FEDERAL RESERVE"],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}