{"summary":"Proceeds of the auction on popular marketplace Rarible will go to MET Orchestra musicians affected by the coronavirus pandemic.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/112951\/the-dallas-symphony-orchestra-is-selling-a-collection-of-nfts","publishDate":"2021-07-29T16:11:50","id":10334,"type":null,"title":"The Dallas Symphony Orchestra is selling a collection of NFTs","category":["THE BLOCK"],"content":["The Dallas Symphony Orchestra (DSO) has launched a three-tiered collection of non-fungible tokens, on digital marketplace Rarible, in an effort to support MET Orchestra musicians impacted by the pandemic.&nbsp;","The collectibles commemorate a concert that took place at the Morton H. Symphony Center in Texas in May 2021. The orchestra was led by DSO music director Favio Luisi, and featured a combination of musicians from both the DSO and the MET Orchestra. It was the first time many non-DSO musicians had performed for a live audience since the pandemic shut down live music performances in early 2020.&nbsp;","\"It is devastating that these incredible musicians have not had an opportunity to perform together in over a year,\" said Luisi in a statement. \"Sadly, this is the case for many musicians around the country, and many have been affected so greatly by this reduction of income. I urged the DSO to find a way to gather musicians together to make music in a way we have not heard in more than a year as a symbol of solidarity.”&nbsp;","The main NFT features a video of the full concert, with behind-the-scenes footage as well as a VIP experience at the reunion concert, which includes dinner with the musicians, airfare and a hotel stay. Bids start at $50,000.&nbsp;","The three-tier collection also includes 25 NFTs priced at $100 each featuring audio of the final movement of Mahler's First Symphony, which the orchestra performed at the concert, as well as photos of the musicians and the performances. Fifteen additional NFTs, priced at $1,000 each, feature video of the first movement of the symphony, footage of an interview with Favio Luisi, and a ticket to the 2022 reunion concert in New York City.&nbsp;","“The collaboration with the Dallas Symphony Orchestra marks a significant milestone in our journey to take NFTs mainstream and to reach new audiences,” said Rarible co-founder and head of product Alex Salnikov. “This NFT is a true testament to the value NFTs can generate for artists and creators by creating new streams of revenue.”","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"New York City","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Dallas Symphony Orchestra (DSO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"May 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Luisi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$50,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Dallas Symphony Orchestra","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Texas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Morton H. Symphony Center","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Favio Luisi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mahler's First Symphony","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MET Orchestra","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alex Salnikov","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Rarible","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"DSO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$100","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2020","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Saniya More","The Block"]}