{"summary":"The Trump administration is set to release a new set of requirements for crypto assets, said Treasury Secretary Steven Mnuchin.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/55734\/trump-administration-to-release-new-fincen-requirements-for-cryptos-mnuchin-tells-congress","publishDate":"2020-02-12T15:15:36","id":10419,"type":null,"title":"Trump administration to release new FinCEN requirements for cryptos, Mnuchin tells Congress","category":["REGULATION"],"content":["U.S. Treasury Secretary Steven Mnuchin told Congress on Wednesday that the U.S. Financial Crimes Enforcement Network (FinCEN) is set to release new requirements related to cryptocurrencies.","Mnuchin offered few details on the move when speaking before the Senate Finance Committee. However, he remarked that \"s<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">pecifically on cryptocurrencies, we are spending a lot of time on this, on both an interagency basis and with the regulators.\"<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We're about to roll out some significant new requirements at FinCEN,\" he <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/xrp_hodl_\/status\/1227679936015667201?s=20\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a> during the hearing, though he offered no specifics on the timing of the move.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We want to make sure that technology moves forward, but on the other hand, we want to make sure that cryptocurrencies aren't used for the equivalent of old Swiss secret number bank accounts,” he added.<\/span>","Later in the hearing, Mnuchin remarked that the effort is being undertaken <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“so that law enforcement can see where the money is going and that this isn’t used for money laundering.”<\/span>","He also notably spoke about stablecoins, which are digital assets tied or pegged to government-issued currencies. Mnuchin seemed to strike a positive tone on the topic, remarking that<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;\"we do think technology can be used to reduce payment processing quite considerably, particularly for small dollar payments cross-border.\" He also commented briefly on central bank-issued digital currencies, which Federal Reserve chairman Jerome Powell <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/55522\/fed-chair-powell-says-facebooks-libra-really-lit-a-fire-on-the-question-of-a-digital-dollar\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">spoke about<\/a> during his Congressional appearance this week.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In July 2019, Mnuchin delivered a White House <a href=\"https:\/\/home.treasury.gov\/news\/press-releases\/sm731\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">press briefing<\/a> on regulatory issues associated with cryptocurrencies, hinting at possible new requirements.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Cryptocurrencies, such as Bitcoin, have been exploited to support billions of dollars of illicit activity like cybercrime, tax evasion, extortion, ransomware, illicit drugs, human trafficking,” he argued in the July statement.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We will not allow digital asset service providers to operate in the shadows and will not tolerate the use of cryptocurrencies in support of illicit activities,” he continued.<\/span> <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“To be clear: FinCEN will hold any entity that transacts in Bitcoin, Libra, or any other cryptocurrency to its highest standards.”<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Federal Reserve","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"billions of dollars","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"U.S. Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mnuchin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"July 2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Congress","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Senate Finance Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FinCEN","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"White House","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jerome Powell","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Steven Mnuchin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S. Financial Crimes Enforcement Network (FinCEN","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Libra","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Yilun Cheng","The Block"]}