{"summary":"The combined company will manage over CAD$350 million in customer assets, making it one of the larger crypto trading platforms in Canada.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/172467\/coinsquare-set-to-acquire-coinsmart-merging-the-two-trading-platforms","publishDate":"2022-09-23T13:37:44","id":10468,"type":null,"title":"Coinsquare set to acquire CoinSmart, merging the two trading platforms","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Coinsmart and CoinSquare, two Canadian crypto trading platforms, are set to merge following an acquisition by Coinquare.","The planned acquisition and integration will see Coinsquare manage over CAD$350 (approx. $258 million), per the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.newswire.ca\/news-releases\/coinsmart-announces-acquisition-by-coinsquare-creating-one-of-canada-s-largest-crypto-asset-trading-platforms-835599859.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announcement<\/a> on Thursday.","The deal will see CoinSmart hold a 12% ownership stake in Coinsquare on a pro forma basis.&nbsp;","Shares in CoinSmart rose after the open on Friday, trading around CAD$0.32 shortly after the market open, up from a close of CAD$0.18 on Thursday. Shares were trading at CAD$0.19 at the time of writing, per <a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/chart\/?symbol=NEO%3ASMRT\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">data<\/a> via TradingView.","","","CoinSmart CEO <span class=\"xn-person\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Justin Hartzman, said the firm is looking to build<\/span>&nbsp;one of the largest regulated crypto asset trading platforms in&nbsp;<span class=\"xn-location\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Canada. He went on to say despite the<\/span> transaction will provide \"the torque needed to be in a favourable position entering the next bull run.\"","Coinsquare, CEO <span class=\"xn-person\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Martin Piszel, echoed Hartzman, adding that the firm's products will be \"<\/span>backed by the highest standards of regulation in the industry.\" Coinsquare is currently working towards gaining approval to become <span class=\"xn-location\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Canada's<\/span>&nbsp;first crypto asset trading platform regulated as an Investment Industry Regulatory Organization of&nbsp;<span class=\"xn-location\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Canada<\/span> (IIROC) dealer and marketplace member.","The firm previously faced wash trading <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/72582\/canadian-regulator-settles-charges-with-coinsquare-as-the-exchange-admitted-to-wash-trading\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">charges<\/a> from Canada's regulator, eventually settling with the Ontario Securities Commission (OSC).","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Canada","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"TradingView","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Justin Hartzman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$258 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"12%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"CoinSmart","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ontario Securities Commission (OSC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Martin Piszel","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Hartzman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Investment Industry Regulatory Organization of&nbsp;<span class=\"xn-location\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Canada<\/span> (IIROC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coinquare","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}