{"summary":"Worldcoin, an identity-focused crypto project, faces huge operational challenges, co-creator Sam Altman said today at a conference.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/250924\/sam-altman-says-worldcoin-faces-huge-operational-challenges-as-demand-grows","publishDate":"2023-09-13T23:19:04","id":10484,"type":null,"title":"Sam Altman says Worldcoin faces huge operational challenges as demand grows","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Worldcoin <\/span><span class=\"articleTooltip\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"\/price\/248504\/worldcoin-wld-usd\" class=\"articleTooltip__link\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"><img src=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2023\/10\/worldcoin.jpeg\" alt=\"\" title=\"\" class=\"articleTooltip__tokenImage\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">WLD<\/span> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText articleTooltip__tokenText_price articleTooltip__tokenText_negative\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">\n      -0.46%\n    <\/span><\/a> <!----><\/span><\/span>, an identity-focused crypto project, faces huge operational challenges, co-creator Sam Altman said today at a conference.<\/span><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“The operational challenges are obviously huge [when] you think about what it takes to get these orbs manufactured,” Altman, who is also CEO of ChatGPT creator OpenAI, said on a panel at Token 2049 in Singapore.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“The other [challenge] is, of course, overcoming that kind of biometrics resistance — for lack of a better word — that some people feel when they first hear about the product,” Altman added. “But again, both of those I think are trending well.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Worldcoin project, officially launched on July 24, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/241871\/worldcoins-plan-to-decentralize-orb-production-sparks-illicit-data-harvesting-concerns\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">encourages users to prove their identity online<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> by signing up for a World ID via an iris scan. It has deployed “orbs” in dozens of cities around the world, predominantly in the Global South.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Alex Blania, co-founder of Worldcoin, said on the same panel that talking to regulators and policymakers worldwide has become a major part of his job after the project went live.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We had a really crazy, crazy surge in the weeks after launch,” Blania said. “The craziest thing for us was that there were long, long lines of people waiting to set up pretty much everywhere. And that was really hard to manage.”&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Blania added that the team is “ramping back up” and “just scaling” while talking to more policymakers.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Concerns over data privacy have dogged the project since well before its launch, but Blania reiterated that Worldcoin doesn’t store the data once the iris scan is done.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Your data is deleted,” Blania said. “You actually stay completely anonymous, which is a very, very powerful thing, given I do believe that we have to figure this out globally — some kind of verification mechanism on the Internet. And I think World ID is a chance to do that in a really, truly privacy-preserving way.”<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Blania","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Alex Blania","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Blania","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Token 2049","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"today","content":"DATE"},{"type":"July 24","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sam Altman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Worldcoin","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Worldcoin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Altman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"” Altman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"-0.46%","content":"PERCENT"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}