{"summary":"While first rising to prominence for the actual art, the week of Art Basel Miami Beach has increasingly taken on a tech and web3 vibe, with numerous side events springing up around the city.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/189245\/art-basel-doodleputt-pussy-riot-the-blocks-guide-for-the-crazy-web3-week-ahead-in-miami","publishDate":"2022-11-26T09:45:54","id":10529,"type":null,"title":"Art Basel, DoodlePutt, Pussy Riot: The Block&#x27;s guide for the crazy web3 week ahead in Miami","category":["PEOPLE"],"content":["Miami's <a href=\"https:\/\/www.miamibeachfl.gov\/art-week-miami-beach\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">busiest week of the year<\/a> is about to unfold, with the global jet set due to storm the city just after Thanksgiving for seven straight days of nonstop art and parties anchored by the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.artbasel.com\/miami-beach\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Art Basel Miami Beach<\/a> fair. The week is both loved and feared by locals, many of whom worry about how impossible it will be to be everywhere, at once. The FOMO is real.","While first rising to prominence for the actual art, the week has increasingly taken on a tech and web3 vibe, with numerous side events springing up around the city. Whether you want to collect <a href=\"https:\/\/www.artbasel.com\/stories\/mint-your-own-nft-at-art-basel-miami-beach?lang=en\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">individualized NFTs<\/a>, test out a decentralized ride-sharing application or just do some good old-fashioned networking, The Block has got you covered. Here's what we're looking at:","eMerge Americas, Florida Funders, &amp; Carve Comms host <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">La Casa<\/strong>, an <a href=\"https:\/\/www.lacasamiami.co\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">invitation-only event<\/a> at Cerveceria La Tropical in Wynwood to “underscore the theme that the #MiamiTech community is a welcoming home, featuring a robust support system, for both newcomers and long-standing residents.” <a href=\"https:\/\/www.lacasamiami.co\/speakers\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Speakers include<\/a> Miami-Dade County Mayor Daniella Levine Cava, City of Miami mayor Francis Suarez, sports influencer Jake Paul, Passes CEO Lucy Guo, and Thoma Bravo founder &amp; Managing Partner Orlando Bravo.","<a href=\"https:\/\/exchange.art\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Exchange.ART<\/strong><\/a>, a fine art marketplace on Solana, debuts an <a href=\"https:\/\/www.paperlesspost.com\/go\/4BvD0JGUrygyzlFVWPnl3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">inaugural presentation<\/a> at a 6,300-square-foot space next to the Miami Beach Convention Center at 7 p.m. EST. Dubbed “NFTs: Bagatelle or Art?” the exhibition is “designed to explore the intersection of art, technology and emerging cultural trends and bridge the gap from the digital art realm into the physical world.” Curated by Haley Karren, the event will highlight over 40 prominent Solana artists from the Exchange.Art platform including Laura El and John Lê.","Doodles will be “reimagining” a 20,000-square-foot complex in Wynwood including an outdoor lounge and live entertainment. The “<a href=\"https:\/\/doodles.app\/events\/doodleputt\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">DoodlePutt<\/strong><\/a>” experience features a 9-hole mini-putt course “that brings to life the Doodles universe.”","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ARTECHOUSE Miami<\/strong> previews an immersive art exhibition celebrating the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.eventcreate.com\/e\/artechouse-pantone-2023-preview\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Pantone Color of the Year 2023<\/a>. “The exhibition, which cost $1 million to create, will feature immersive rooms of colors, textures, and interactions that plunge attendees into an array of visual, auditory, and tactile experiences to present not only the Pantone Color of the Year 2023, but also to draw out its many implications.”","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Institute of Contemporary Art<\/strong> (ICA Miami) is going punk, with Yuga Labs’ CryptoPunks <a href=\"https:\/\/icamiami.org\/calendar\/first-fridays-miami-art-week-edition-2022-ft-pussy-riot\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">hosting a Pussy Riot concert<\/a> to celebrate the unveiling of Punk #305, which is being donated to the museum’s permanent collection. The free event is open to the public with required RSVP courtesy of CryptoPunks. CryptoPunk holders can receive VIP entry via TokenProof.","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">(Updates to add Dec. 3 Tech Runs event.)<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Laura El","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"John Lê","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"ICA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Miami","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Institute of Contemporary","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dade County","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Thoma Bravo founder &amp; Managing Partner Orlando Bravo","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dec. 3","content":"DATE"},{"type":"7 p.m. EST","content":"TIME"},{"type":"Francis Suarez","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Beach Convention Center","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Punk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Art Basel Miami Beach","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jake Paul","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"VIP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cerveceria La Tropical","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Haley Karren","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"TokenProof","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lucy Guo","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Daniella Levine Cava","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Florida Funders, &amp; Carve Comms","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wynwood","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["CRYPTOPUNKS","INTERNET","NFT ARTISTS","YUGA LABS"],"authors":["Nathan Crooks","The Block"]}