{"summary":"Web3 finance platform Integral closed an $8.5 million round led by Electric Capital.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/171429\/web3-finance-platform-integral-closes-8-5m-round-led-by-electric-capital","publishDate":"2022-09-20T15:07:31","id":10602,"type":null,"title":"Web3 finance platform Integral closes $8.5m round led by Electric Capital","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Web3 finance platform Integral has closed an $8.5 million funding round led by Electric Capital.&nbsp;","Integral, which describes itself as a \"real-time finance platform for web3 enterprises,\" estimates that its clients have processed $5 billion in \"crypto accounting transactions\" in the past five months using its tools.&nbsp;","\"Real-time finance is essential for web3 companies,\" Integral founder Gui Laliberte said in a company <a href=\"https:\/\/www.prnewswire.com\/news-releases\/integral-announces-8-5m-raise-for-real-time-web3-accounting-tools-301628696.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">statement<\/a> and <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/laliberteg\/status\/1572231075946168321\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Twitter<\/a> thread. \"In web2, insights come 7-30 days after the month-end. In web3, 30 days could be the difference between owning&nbsp;<span class=\"xn-money\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$10 million<\/span>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<span class=\"xn-money\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$5 million<\/span> worth of crypto assets.\"","Electric Capital has<a href=\"https:\/\/www.electriccapital.com\/investments\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> invested<\/a> in an array of web3 projects including Celo, dYdX, Kraken and Magic Eden, among others.","\"Real-time finance is essential for any serious project in web3 and for any web2 company that is starting to explore web3,\" Electric Capital Co-founder <span class=\"xn-person\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Avichal Garg said in a statement. \"<\/span>All companies and protocols will need fast, scalable financial tools to stay ahead of the competition.\"&nbsp;","Other investors participating in the raise included former Coinbase chief technology officer <span class=\"xn-person\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Balaji Srinivasan<\/span>, Anchorage Digital co-founder Diogo <span class=\"xn-person\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Mónica <\/span><span class=\"xn-person\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">and Roham Gharegozlou, CEO of Dapper Labs.<\/span>","Earlier today, another web3 accounting platform called Tres separately <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/171172\/web3-accounting-software-tres-raises-7-6-million-in-seed-funding\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/a> it had raised $7.6 million in a seed round led by Boldstart Ventures.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Anchorage Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Roham Gharegozlou","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"\" Electric Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$8.5 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$5 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$7.6 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Electric Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"30 days after the month","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Dapper Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Avichal Garg","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Diogo <span class=\"xn-person\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Mónica","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Balaji Srinivasan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Boldstart Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gui Laliberte","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$10 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$5 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Magic Eden","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Kristin Majcher","The Block"]}