{"summary":"Sen. Lummis points to her bill with Sen. Gillibrand as providing regulations that would have prevented the FTX liquidity crunch earlier today. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/184515\/sen-lummis-points-to-ftx-binance-as-catalyst-for-her-crypto-legislation","publishDate":"2022-11-08T18:59:46","id":1062,"type":null,"title":"Sen. Lummis points to FTX-Binance as catalyst for her crypto legislation","category":["POLICY"],"content":["At least one senator is calling on Congress to reconsider crypto legislation following Binance's bailout of FTX earlier today.","\"Market manipulation, lending activity, and whether customer funds and assets were appropriately safeguarded are just a few of the many issues my colleagues and I need to consider in the coming days,\" wrote Sen. Cynthia Lummis, R-Wyo., in a statement.&nbsp;","Lummis pointed to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/177371\/pieces-of-crypto-bill-could-pass-in-six-months-authors-lummis-and-gillibrand-say\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">her bill<\/a><a class=\"Ui2TZ WCMfob oRJe3d\" tabindex=\"0\" role=\"link\" data-ti=\"overview\" data-ved=\"2ahUKEwj6qo3v35_7AhU_EVkFHTLNDuoQnZMFegQIXhAC\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"yKMVIe\" role=\"heading\" aria-level=\"1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> with Sen. Kirsten Gillibrand, D-N.Y., as providing regulations \"essential to ensuring customers are protected while still promoting responsible innovation.\"<\/span><\/a>","FTX's <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/184176\/ftx-appears-to-have-stopped-processing-withdrawals-on-chain-data-show\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">liquidity crunch<\/a> has already come to the attention of federal regulators and Congress, where a bill tightly associated with FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried has been a core of recent crypto legislation. The <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/184436\/bankman-frieds-priority-crypto-bill-dead-after-ftx-sells-to-binance\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">outlook for that bill is grim<\/a>.","But with midterm elections tonight expected to turn out at least a Republican House of Representatives under a Democratic administration, Congress seems set for months of legislative limbo.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"N.Y.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Republican House of Representatives","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kirsten Gillibrand","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Wyo.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Congress","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cynthia Lummis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Binance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["CONGRESS"],"authors":["Kollen Post","The Block"]}