{"summary":"A hacker has stolen four Bored Apes and 87 other NFTs after promoting a fake airdrop through the Bored Ape Instagram account.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/143328\/bored-ape-instagram-account-hacked-nfts-worth-2-8-million-stolen","publishDate":"2022-04-25T12:54:24","id":10647,"type":null,"title":"Bored Ape Instagram account hacked: NFTs worth $2.8 million stolen","category":["NFTS"],"content":["A hacker has stolen 91 NFTs worth at least $2.8 million through a phishing attack targeting Bored Ape Yacht Club owners today. It was carried out through the official Bored Ape Instagram account.","\"<span class=\"css-901oao css-16my406 r-poiln3 r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">There is no mint going on today. It looks like BAYC Instagram was hacked. Do not mint anything, click links, or link your wallet to anything,<\/span>\" <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/BoredApeYC\/status\/1518590210686308354\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweeted<\/a> Bored Ape Yacht Club.","When the Instagram account was accessed, it was used to post a fake update claiming there was a LAND airdrop and users had to connect their wallets to claim the airdrop. This was taking advantage of the Bored Ape roadmap, which includes a metaverse game that will contain virtual land. When users connected to their wallets — and likely approved a transaction — the website stole their NFTs.","According to blockchain data, the hacker's wallet — which has <a href=\"https:\/\/etherscan.io\/address\/0x8c7934611b6ad70fbea13a1593de167a4689b9a9#tokentxnsErc721\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">been identified<\/a> with this phishing attack — holds 91 NFTs. According to <a href=\"https:\/\/app.zerion.io\/0x8c7934611b6ad70fbea13a1593de167a4689b9a9\/nfts\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">data<\/a> from Zerion, the NFTs are worth at least $2.8 million based on the floor prices of the respective collections.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This was the fake announcement on the Bored Ape Yacht Club Instagram account. Image: Instagram.<\/span>","Among the stolen items are four Bored Apes, six Mutant Apes and three Bored Ape Kennel Club NFTs (the latter two being official derivative projects). The hacker also stole one CloneX and items from other up-and-coming collections like EightBit, Alien Fren, and Toxic Skull Club among others.","\"<span class=\"css-901oao css-16my406 r-poiln3 r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">We will be in contact with the users affected and will post a full post mortem on the attack when we can. For now I would like to stress that 2FA was enabled on the account,\" tweeted Bored Ape co-founder Garga.<\/span>","Despite <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/tech\/2022\/04\/25\/at-least-13m-in-nfts-stolen-after-bored-ape-yacht-club-instagram-discord-hacked\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reports<\/a> and <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/MoonOverlord\/status\/1518603843616968704\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweets<\/a> that there were more than 50 Bored Apes and Mutant Apes stolen, Garga said that it was just 10.","Today’s incident is the latest high-profile NFT theft to occur following the hacking of a BAYC-related platform. Earlier in April, Bored Ape’s <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/140102\/bored-ape-yacht-club-confirms-its-discord-was-hacked\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Discord server was hacked<\/a> and a similar phishing attempt was made but the hacker only succeeded in stealing one Mutant Ape. Although many Bored Ape holders have lost their NFTs due to a variety of other phishing attacks and <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/135032\/nft-marketplace-opensea-hit-with-1-million-bored-ape-lawsuit\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">NFT marketplace issues<\/a>.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Bored Ape","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Toxic Skull Club","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bored Ape Yacht Club","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BAYC Instagram","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bored Ape Instagram","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Garga","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bored Ape Yacht Club Instagram","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alien Fren","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$2.8 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Mutant Apes","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Zerion","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bored Ape Kennel Club","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Osato Avan-Nomayo","The Block"]}