{"summary":"Berkovitz was reportedly lobbied by disgraced FTX founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/197666\/sec-general-counsel-dan-berkovitz-to-step-down","publishDate":"2022-12-23T05:39:43","id":10651,"type":null,"title":"SEC general counsel Dan Berkovitz to step down","category":["REGULATION"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Securities and Exchanges Commission general counsel Dan Berkovitz will step down effective Jan. 31. While known as a decentralized finance hardliner, reports indicate that in his previous role at the CFTC he met and dined with disgraced FTX founder Sam Bankman-Fried.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Berkovitz was lobbied by Bankman-Fried just before joining the SEC, the Washington Examiner <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.washingtonexaminer.com\/news\/ftx-sam-bankman-fried-washington-dc-emails-crypto\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. Bankman-Fried currently faces a prison sentence of as much as 115 years stemming from an eight-count indictment.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"After thirty-four years of public service, it is time for me to pursue new and different challenges and opportunities,\" Berkovitz <a href=\"https:\/\/www.sec.gov\/news\/press-release\/2022-235\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a> in an SEC announcement. He <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/118919\/outgoing-cftc-commissioner-dan-berkovitz-named-as-sec-general-counsel\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">joined<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> the SEC in November 2021 after leaving his role as a commissioner at the Commodity Futures Trading Commission.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Megan Barbero, a former Department of Justice attorney who is currently the SEC’s principal deputy general counsel, will take his place.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Berkovitz had previously <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/107769\/cftc-commissioner-criticizes-defi-decries-lack-of-intermediaries\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">criticized<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> decentralized finance for lacking intermediaries to protect investors, calling it \"a Hobbesian marketplace.\"<\/span>","<span data-v-628af130=\"\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Disclaimer: Beginning in 2021, Michael McCaffrey, the former CEO and majority owner of The Block, took a series of loans from founder and former FTX and Alameda CEO Sam Bankman-Fried. McCaffrey resigned from the company in December 2022 after failing to disclose those transactions.<\/em><\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"four years","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Department of Justice","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Exchanges Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jan. 31","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Megan Barbero","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Commodity Futures Trading Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CFTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"December 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Michael McCaffrey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"November 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Dan Berkovitz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Washington Examiner","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Berkovitz","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["CFTC","SEC"],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}