{"summary":"Michael Cahill explores advancing Pyth Network for real-time data delivery, and the hurdles faced in onchain trading.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253782\/cahill-pyth-network","publishDate":"2023-10-02T08:01:03","id":10673,"type":null,"title":"How Pyth Network is trying to revolutionize a $6 billion Wall Street business","category":["INFRASTRUCTURE"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 85<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 5 of The Scoop was recorded with <b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro and Douro Labs CEO Michael Cahill.<\/b><\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on <a href=\"https:\/\/www.youtube.com\/channel\/UCqjFueYMJ78eF6G0lGLzzpQ\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Youtube<\/a>, <\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a>,<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Please send feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"3f4f505b5c5e4c4b7f4b575a5d53505c54115c50\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm\/?e=BLOCK2163236529\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Michael Cahill is the CEO of Douro Labs, where he oversees the development and acceleration of the Pyth Network — an oracle network for real-time financial market data delivery to smart contract applications.","In this episode, Cahill unpacks the unique advantages of Pyth Network over other oracle providers and explains what obstacles currently stand in the way of replicating the centralized trading experience on-chain.","According to Cahill, DeFi is \"very close to feature parity with some of the backend elements of derivatives trading on centralized exchanges — what we haven't yet cracked is the user experience.\"","Pyth Network was <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/115640\/solana-data-oracle-pyth-network-going-live\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">incubated<\/a> by Jump Trading before going live on Solana mainnet back in August of 2021.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Douro Labs","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Michael Cahill","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cahill","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"August of 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Pyth Network","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}