{"summary":"Much of Alameda&#x27;s VC investments and Bahamas real estate were paid with FTX user funds, an expert testified in court.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/258277\/inside-sbfs-trial-alameda-paid-for-loans-vc-deals-and-bahamas-properties-with-ftx-user-funds-expert-tells-court","publishDate":"2023-10-18T18:43:00","id":10696,"type":null,"title":"Inside SBF&#x27;s trial: Alameda paid for loans, VC deals and Bahamas properties with FTX user funds, expert tells court","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Transactions to and from Alameda Research's bank accounts show it often used FTX customer money to pay back loans, fund political donations, invest in other companies and buy property, an expert witness for the prosecution testified in the ongoing criminal trial of Sam Bankman-Fried on Wednesday.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Peter Easton, an accounting professor at the University of Notre Dame, told the court he analyzed bank and crypto transactions between the FTX exchange, its sister trading company Alameda Research and third parties. Easton said he had prior experience with crypto, as he worked on the a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/235926\/sec-lawsuit-over-whether-xrp-is-a-security-will-go-to-trial\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">court case<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> between the Securities and Exchange Commission and Ripple Labs.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Easton gave an emphatic \"Oh yes!\" when he was asked by Assistant U.S. Attorney Nicolas Roos if customer money had been spent.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">For example, right before FTX invested <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/business\/2022\/12\/19\/ftxs-bankman-fried-gave-ex-jane-street-traders-who-formed-modulo-capital-400m\/?utm_term=organic&amp;utm_campaign=coindesk_main&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_content=editorial&amp;utm_source=twitter\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$400 million<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in Modulo capital, a hedge fund founded by former Jane Street traders, Alameda Research accounts received funds from FTX's treasury, Easton said, and then transferred them to Modulo.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"All of the purchase of Modulo Capital was made using customer funds,\" he said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Similar chains of transactions preceded FTX's investments in the mining company <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/191919\/alameda-invested-1-15-billion-into-crypto-miner-genesis-bloomberg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Genesis Digital Assets<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, Anthony Scaramucci's hedge fund <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/168848\/ftx-ventures-to-take-30-stake-in-skybridge-capital-cnbc\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">SkyBridge Capital<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, banking app <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/business\/2022\/03\/21\/ftx-invests-100m-in-banking-app-dave-forms-partnership-for-crypto-payments\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Dave<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, PR firm K5, AI startup Anthropic and Robinhood shares, as well as the <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/decrypt.co\/76584\/ftx-ceo-sam-bankman-fried-why-bought-out-binance-investment-shares-exit\/#:~:text=FTX%20bought%20out%20Binance's%20shares,how%20we%20run%20our%20businesses.%22\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">buyout of FTX’s own shares<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> from Binance, Easton said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">He said that according to his analysis, FTX and Alameda's purchases of real estate in the Bahamas also followed that pattern. Same was true for FTX's political donations, except that they would go through the accounts of FTX executives like Nishad Singh or Ryan Salame.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">That included contributions to political action committees GMI, Mind the Gap (led by Bankman-Fried's mother Barbara Fried) and an advocacy group Guarding Against Pandemics, led by Sam's brother Gabriel Bankman-Fried.&nbsp;<\/span>","When Alameda paid back the money it borrowed from institutional lenders like BlockFi, Bitgo, Genesis, Abra, Maple Finance, Anchorage, Celsius, Nexo, Voyager, TrueFi and Ledn, at least parts of those payouts came from FTX's customer deposits shortly before the transaction, Easton said.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BlockFi, Celsius, Genesis and Voyager have since filed for bankruptcy themselves.&nbsp;<\/span>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">(With reporting assistance from Zack Abrams.)<\/em>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Gabriel Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Zack Abrams","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Peter Easton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Anchorage","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Abra","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Easton","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Anthony Scaramucci","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bitgo","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"University of Notre Dame","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Celsius","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$400 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Sam","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Genesis","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Nexo","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Dave","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"SkyBridge Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ryan Salame","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Maple Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Robinhood","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nicolas Roos","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Barbara Fried","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Voyager","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Nishad Singh","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Easton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"GMI","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Celsius","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bahamas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["FTX","SBF TRIAL"],"authors":["Anna Baydakova","The Block"]}