{"summary":"There could be more enforcement actions headed toward crypto exchanges and decentralized finance projects, said the SEC&#x27;s David Hirsch.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/251929\/sec-official-says-more-crypto-exchanges-could-face-charges-report","publishDate":"2023-09-19T16:24:08","id":10727,"type":null,"title":"SEC official says more crypto exchanges could face charges: report","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">There could be more enforcement actions headed toward cryptocurrency exchanges and decentralized finance projects, according to David Hirsch, head of the Securities and Exchange Commission's Crypto Assets and Cyber Unit.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Hirsch said the agency could bring new charges against crypto brokers, dealers, exchanges, clearing agencies and others who don’t make proper disclosures or register with the agency, according to a report from <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/policy\/2023\/09\/19\/us-secs-crypto-enforcement-chief-warns-more-charges-coming-to-exchanges-defi\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CoinDesk<\/span><\/a>. Hirsch spoke Tuesday at the Securities Enforcement Forum Central in Chicago.&nbsp;<\/span>","Hirsch said the SEC was aware of and investigating firms involved in similar activity to those that prompted agency suits against Coinbase and Binance a few months ago.&nbsp;","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">DeFi, too, may come into the spotlight, CoinDesk cited Hirsch as saying.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The SEC has forged ahead in bringing high profile cases against crypto exchange <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/244886\/binance-asks-for-protective-order-over-claims-sec-is-conducting-fishing-expedition\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance<\/a> and then Coinbase a day later back in June. <\/span><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">It's also been involved in a lengthy dispute with Ripple Labs.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Recently, too, the agency brought two <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/250820\/sec-goes-after-stoner-cats-nft-show-known-for-ashton-kutcher-and-jane-fonda\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">cases<\/span><\/a> against NFT projects.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Some companies including Grayscale Investments and Ripple have fought back, with three judges in the U.S. Court of Appeals for the D.C. Circuit <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/246115\/court-hands-grayscale-win-in-long-running-suit-against-sec\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s5\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ruling<\/span><\/a> in August that the SEC has to re-review Grayscale's bid for a spot bitcoin ETF after the asset management firm sued the agency last year following its rejection of the conversion of its flagship GBTC fund.<\/span>","<span class=\"s6\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The case involving Ripple ended in a mixed verdict. <\/span><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The judge there <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/239559\/sec-faces-wake-up-call-after-ripple-ruling-though-appeal-likely\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s7\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ruled<\/span><\/a> in July that some of Ripple's sales, called programmatic, of XRP did not violate securities laws because of a blind bid process in place for them. She also ruled that other direct sales of the token to institutional investors were securities, leaving a partial win for the SEC.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Grayscale","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. Court of Appeals","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hirsch","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ripple Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"David Hirsch","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Grayscale Investments","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"CoinDesk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"June","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Chicago","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"XRP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"D.C.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Securities Enforcement Forum Central","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["SEC"],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}