{"summary":"SINGAPORE, 11 May 2022 — Amber Group, the leading global digital asset platform, today announced its entry into the metaverse with the launch of","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/146412\/amber-group-announces-q3-2022-launch-of-openverse-the-gateway-into-the-metaverse","publishDate":"2022-05-12T09:00:47","id":10724,"type":null,"title":"Amber Group Announces Q3 2022 Launch Of Openverse, The Gateway Into The Metaverse","category":["SPONSORED"],"content":["<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">SINGAPORE, <\/b><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">11 May <\/b><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">2022<\/b><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> — <\/span><a href=\"http:\/\/ambergroup.io\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Amber Group<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, the leading global digital asset platform, today announced its entry into the metaverse with the launch of Openverse, a Web3 enablement platform for creators, brands and businesses. A culmination of Amber Group’s multi-disciplinary expertise in digital architecture and blockchain-native infrastructure, Openverse serves as a gateway to the metaverse, empowering Web2 creators, brands and businesses with tools and services to transition into Web3.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">With the metaverse economy projected to reach <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/ir.citi.com\/gps\/x5%2BFQJT3BoHXVu9MsqVRoMdiws3RhL4yhF6Fr8us8oHaOe1W9smOy1%2B8aaAgT3SPuQVtwC5B2%2Fc%3D\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$13 trillion<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> by 2030, Openverse marks Amber Group’s venture into Web3 community building. Due to launch in Q3 2022, Openverse is a significant milestone in Amber Group’s plans to aid businesses, industries and societies as they transition into Web3. As a one-stop platform, Openverse will create entry points into the metaverse by delivering end-to-end creative and digital infrastructures for creators, brands and businesses.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Digital assets are the first step in realising a decentralised future where people are empowered to create and connect with online communities, unlocking new digital experiences. While there has been a lot of interest in the metaverse, it remains largely conceptual. With Openverse, we are taking a solid step towards creating this digital reality for all. Backed by our expertise and partnerships within the digital asset ecosystem, Openverse is at the forefront of onboarding businesses and communities into the metaverse, unlocking the true potential of decentralisation,” said Amber Group's Chief Executive Officer, Michael Wu.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Openverse is designed to be a Web3 enablement platform, supported by <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">leading real-time 3D rendering technology to create an experiential digital world for all users<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. The platform will <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">be accessible on mobile, desktop and VR platforms<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, and will come equipped with features such as <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">real-time content interaction, gameplay, customizable digital avatars and an NFT valuation system. Openverse will also leverage Amber Group’s flagship digital asset platform, WhaleFin, for its crypto financial services, creating synergies with the company’s thriving&nbsp; consumer business line to expand the reach of its digital asset services.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We are excited to launch Openverse, and convert the possibilities of the metaverse into reality in the next few months. As we develop a gateway for everyone to journey into the metaverse together, we are also building a strong line-up of partnerships with gaming studios, sporting brands, digital artists and creators in an effort to bridge the gap between physical and virtual economies. Not only will this encourage more Web2 users to migrate into the metaverse, it will also herald a new era for digital assets worldwide,” said Openverse’s Chief Executive Officer, Jo Xu.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">-END-&nbsp;<\/span>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Media Contact<\/b>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stella Wang<\/span>","<a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection#2f5f5d6f4e424d4a5d485d405a5f014640\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"42323002232f20273025302d37326c2b2d\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/span><\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","&nbsp;","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Amber Group<\/b>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Amber Group is a leading digital asset platform operating globally with offices in Asia, Europe, and the Americas. The firm provides a full range of digital asset services spanning investing, financing, and trading. Amber Group is backed by prominent investors including Sequoia, Temasek, Paradigm, Tiger Global, Dragonfly, Pantera, Coinbase Ventures, and Blockchain.com.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">For more information, please visit<\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.globenewswire.com\/Tracker?data=6k7qLOEeQso5NV8kAhm4BJdHJDAVKmFS0ZSwnM-QCEsDLtC2CTSjTq9mGsGiHCy9MFZisbH067n1WR-TCe_MfhQoHxGrUM0OF9TabU0VrJY=\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> www.ambergroup.io<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This post is commissioned by Amber Group<\/i><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;and does not serve as a testimonial or endorsement by The Block. This post is for informational purposes only and should not be relied upon as a basis for investment, tax, legal or other advice. You should conduct your own research and consult independent counsel and advisors on the matters discussed within this post. Past performance of any asset is not indicative of future results.<\/i><\/span><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Tiger Global","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Amber Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Openverse","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Stella Wang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$13 trillion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Asia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dragonfly","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Pantera","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SINGAPORE","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2030","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sequoia","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Openverse","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Michael Wu","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Jo Xu","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Paradigm","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Temasek","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"May <\/b><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Americas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Coinbase Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Openverse marks Amber Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sponsored","The Block"]}