{"summary":"Count this as another big exit at cryptocurrency exchange operator Coinbase.  On Wednesday, Bloomberg News&#x27; Julie Verhage reported that the firm&#x27;s chief","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/3851\/coinbases-chief-policy-officer-is-leaving-and-fannie-maes-former-general-counsel-is-taking-his-place","publishDate":"2018-11-21T13:22:31","id":10734,"type":null,"title":"Coinbase&#x27;s chief policy officer is leaving, and Fannie Mae&#x27;s former general counsel is taking his place","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["Count this as another big exit at cryptocurrency exchange operator Coinbase.&nbsp;","On Wednesday,&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bloomberg News'&nbsp;<\/em>Julie Verhage reported that the firm's chief policy officer, Michael Lempres, is leaving to join venture capital investor and Coinbase-backer Andreessen Horowitz. Lempres, who was previously general counsel at Bitnet Technologies, joined Coinbase in 2017 as its chief legal and risk officer. In September, he took on the policy role, which put him in charge of communicating Coinbase-friendly policy positions with financial regulators.","“As chief legal and risk officer during a time of tremendous growth for Coinbase, Mike was instrumental in building the company’s legal and compliance functions and driving our vision of trust through compliance,” the firm told <em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bloomberg<\/em> in an email. “We wish him the best in his new position with Andreessen Horowitz.” A spokesperson for the firm confirmed the report to&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block.&nbsp;<\/em>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">THE REPLACEMENT<\/strong>","The&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bloomberg&nbsp;<\/em>piece did not report on Lempres' replacement. But&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block&nbsp;<\/em>can confirm that Brian Brooks, who joined as chief legal and risk officer this year, is taking Lempres' spot. Previously, Brooks worked at Fannie Mae, the mortgage giant, as its general counsel and executive vice president. At Fannie, he led a 200-person legal and policy team. He was also a managing partner at O'Melveny &amp; Meyers in Washington D.C., <a href=\"https:\/\/blog.coinbase.com\/welcome-brian-brooks-coinbases-new-chief-legal-officer-a23ce203454e\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">according to a blog post<\/a>.&nbsp;","Readers might recall Adam White — who led the build out of Coinbase's institutional business — left to join Intercontinental Exchange's Bakkt as its COO earlier this year.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Michael Lempres","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Fannie Mae","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Intercontinental Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"O'Melveny &amp; Meyers","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Washington D.C.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Brian Brooks","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Adam White","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Brooks","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Fannie","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lempres","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Julie Verhage","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Andreessen Horowitz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bloomberg News","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mike","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bitnet Technologies","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}