{"summary":"The Asia-based crypto exchange said it hopes to get the full license within six months and expand its payment tool BitCheck once approved.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/263275\/xrex-obtains-in-principle-approval-for-major-payment-institution-license-in-singapore","publishDate":"2023-11-16T19:30:04","id":10781,"type":null,"title":"XREX obtains in-principle approval for Major Payment Institution license in Singapore","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">XREX, an Asia-based crypto exchange specializing in cross-border payments, obtained in-principle approval in Singapore for a Major Payment Institution (MPI) license.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">XREX said in a statement shared with The Block that the Monetary Authority of Singapore has given the company initial approval for a license that would eventually allow it to offer <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">digital payment token products and services in the city-state.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The license — once obtained in full — will<\/span> <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">allow the company to expand BitCheck, a payment tool that supports fiat, stablecoins and other cryptocurrencies.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Our engagements with the MAS have shown us time and again why they are internationally revered as a leading central bank and financial regulator,\" Christopher Chye, chief executive officer of XREX Singapore, told The Block in a written statement. \"They are thorough but never overbearing, strict but never high-handed, and risk-averse but never without business sensibilities.\"&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Chye added, \"We look forward to partnering with the MAS to acquire the full license within six months.\"<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Wayne Huang, co-founder and Group CEO of XREX, said that XREX Singapore will become the primary provider of products in APAC, while XREX Taiwan will still play an essential role in the company’s product design, engineering, research and threat analysis functions.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Serving as the headquarters for the Asia Pacific region, XREX Singapore will also turn its eye to its neighboring emerging markets, where access to USD liquidity may not always be easily within reach,” <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Chye added.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Singapore is considered a relatively crypto-friendly jurisdiction with many global companies in the crypto and web3 space setting up their bases in the country. However, the city-state has over the past year endured several crises involving crypto players, including the failures of <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253618\/three-arrows-capital-co-founder-su-zhu-apprehended-in-singapore-bloomberg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Three Arrows Capital<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/222930\/vauld-creditor-protection-extension-fifth\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Vauld<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> and <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/262629\/distressed-crypto-lender-hodlnaut-starts-liquidation-in-singapore\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Hodlnaut<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">MAS appears to remain committed to playing ball with crypto firms. Last month, the regulator <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253755\/coinbase-granted-full-license-in-singapore\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">handed Coinbase a full MPI license<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> after granting <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/176064\/crypto-exchange-coinbase-gets-license-in-singapore\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">in-principal approval<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> late last year. In June, Circle also <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/233409\/circle-mpi-singapore\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">obtained an MPI license<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Wayne Huang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"MPI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"APAC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Asia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Taiwan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Vauld","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Monetary Authority","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"June","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Circle","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Christopher Chye","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Asia Pacific","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["ASIAN REGULATION"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}