{"summary":"Binance Labs, the VC arm of the crypto exchange Binance, has committed to a $5 million investment in Curve DAO tokens.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/244183\/binance-labs-commits-5-million-to-invest-in-curve-dao-tokens","publishDate":"2023-08-10T11:06:01","id":10791,"type":null,"title":"Binance Labs commits $5 million to invest in Curve DAO tokens","category":["CRYPTO ECOSYSTEMS"],"content":["Binance Labs, the venture capital and incubation arm of the cryptocurrency exchange Binance, has committed to a $5 million investment in Curve DAO tokens.","Yi He, co-founder of Binance and head of Binance Labs, announced the collaboration that will also see Curve Finance deploy to the Binance-backed BNB Chain.","The investment appears to be part of recent OTC deals done by Curve founder Michael Egorov with notable figures in the crypto space. Among these, Huobi’s co-founder Jun Du <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/242925\/huobi-co-founder-jun-du-buys-10-million-crv-from-michael-egorov\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">acquired<\/a> 10 million CRV tokens, while Tron’s founder Justin Sun <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/242455\/justin-sun-buys-2-9-million-crv-tokens-in-an-otc-deal-announces-partnership-with-curve\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">bought<\/a> 5 million CRV at a cost of $2 million.","“Given the recent events that have impacted the protocol, Binance Labs has offered our full support to Curve through our investment and strategic collaboration. We view this cooperation as a starting point and look forward to working together to further propel the growth of the DeFi ecosystem,” He said.","So far, Egorov has sold more than 156 million CRV tokens for a total of $46.4 million, according to <a href=\"https:\/\/dune.com\/spotonchain\/crv-founder-sold-crv-via-otc\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">on-chain data<\/a> compiled by Spotonchain on Dune Analytics. The transactions appear to be strategically aimed at reducing the potential liquidation risks that Egorov faces across various decentralized finance platforms due to a stablecoin debt of <a href=\"https:\/\/debank.com\/profile\/0x7a16ff8270133f063aab6c9977183d9e72835428\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$50 million<\/a>, according to DeBank.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Egorov","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"CRV","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$46.4 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"DeBank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Justin Sun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$2 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Curve Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Michael Egorov","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Dune Analytics","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jun Du","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Huobi’s","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$5 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$50 million","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["ASSETS","DEXS"],"authors":["Vishal Chawla","The Block"]}