{"summary":"On December 22nd The Block&#x27;s Director of Research, Larry Cermak will host a panel discussion on institutional DeFi adoption.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/84641\/curv-webinar-draft","publishDate":"2020-12-17T17:34:22","id":10823,"type":null,"title":"The Block Presents: Challenges for institutional DeFi adoption — brought to you by Curv","category":["THE BLOCK"],"content":["On December 22nd The Block’s Director of Research, Larry Cermak will host&nbsp;a panel discussion on institutional DeFi adoption. As a precursor to the event <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/genesis\/84749\/challenges-for-institutional-defi-adoption\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"nofollow noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">view our latest research<\/a> piece exploring the hurdles faced by institutions participating in DeFi.","You can register for the event and learn more about our panelists below:&nbsp;","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" title=\"Challenges for institutional DeFi adoption — brought to you by Curv | The Block\" src=\"https:\/\/app.livestorm.co\/p\/f5f26675-2a62-4985-9e5d-9a1f7c1d6ad3\/form\" width=\"100%\" height=\"360\" frameborder=\"0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><u data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Our Panelists:<\/u><\/strong>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Itay Malinger <\/strong>- Co-founder and CEO at Curv","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stani Kulechov<\/strong> - Founder and CEO at Aave","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Phil Kelly<\/strong>- Head of Business Development at ConsenSys","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Vance Spencer<\/strong> - Co-founder at Framework Ventures","___________________________________________________________________________________________________________","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This event is brought to you by Curv. <\/strong>","Curv is the world’s most trusted digital asset security infrastructure that is delivered as a fully scalable, enterprise-grade and compliant cloud service. Curv’s multi-party computation (MPC) technology simultaneously provides institutions the protection, instant availability, and total autonomy over digital assets required to thrive in the digital economy.","The company is the only cloud-based, MPC wallet provider for institutional digital assets and the first of its kind to achieve both SOC2 Type II Certification and ISO 27001 accreditation. Curv also provides additional peace of mind by insuring up to $50M of digital assets backed by Munich Re, the only Internet-connected crime insurance policy to date and one of the largest policies in the market. Curv is swiftly being adopted by leading exchanges, custodians, OTC desks, brokers, traditional financial institutions and digital asset managers. Learn more about Curv’s new institutional DeFi solution: <a href=\"https:\/\/www.curv.co\/curv-defi\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"nofollow noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">www.curv.co\/curv-defi<\/a>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Itay Malinger","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"ISO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block’s Director of Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Phil Kelly","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Framework Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Munich","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Larry Cermak","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"MPC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$50M","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Vance Spencer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"December 22nd","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Head of Business Development","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sponsored","The Block"]}