{"summary":"The SEC has reportedly opened talks with Grayscale over the firm&#x27;s application to convert its flagship fund into a spot bitcoin ETF","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/262279\/the-sec-has-opened-talks-with-grayscale-over-its-bid-for-a-spot-bitcoin-etf-conversion-report","publishDate":"2023-11-08T16:35:33","id":10844,"type":null,"title":"The SEC has opened talks with Grayscale over its bid for a spot bitcoin ETF conversion: report","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Securities and Exchange Commission has opened talks with Grayscale Investments over the firm's application to convert its flagship fund into a spot bitcoin exchange-traded fund, according to a report.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Grayscale has been in contact with both the SEC's Division of Trading and Markets and the Division of Corporation Finance, following a court ruling that the agency has to re-review the firm's bid for a spot bitcoin ETF, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/policy\/2023\/11\/08\/us-sec-said-to-open-talks-with-grayscale-on-spot-bitcoin-etf-push\/?utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_campaign=headlines\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CoinDesk<\/span><\/a> reported on Wednesday, citing a person familiar with the situation.<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Three judges in the U.S. Court of Appeals for the D.C. Circuit <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/246115\/court-hands-grayscale-win-in-long-running-suit-against-sec\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ruled<\/span><\/a> in August that the SEC has to re-review Grayscale's bid for a spot bitcoin ETF after the asset management firm sued the agency last year following the rejection of its plan for the conversion of its flagship GBTC fund. The court specifically addressed the SEC's differential treatment of spot bitcoin ETFs and similar funds based on futures contracts, which the regulator has approved.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Grayscale sub<\/span><span class=\"s5\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">mitted a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/258299\/grayscale-submits-new-filing-to-sec-in-attempt-for-spot-bitcoin-etf-approval-following-pivotal-court-ruling\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">fresh filing<\/span><\/a> a few weeks ago for the fund ahead of the court's release of a<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;formal <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/258767\/us-court-confirms-grayscale-ruling-says-sec-must-re-review-bid-for-spot-bitcoin-etf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">mandate<\/span><\/a> to assert the August ruling.<\/span><\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">SEC Chair Gary Gensler said that the agency was still reviewing the court's decision during a Senate Banking Committee hearing in <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/250526\/gensler-says-sec-is-reviewing-grayscale-ruling-spot-bitcoin-etf-applications\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">September<\/span><\/a>. <span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Multiple firms have filed for spot bitcoin ETFs, including BlackRock and Fidelity. Some experts say the Grayscale court decision could tip a decision into their favor.&nbsp;<\/span><\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Gensler also told a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/258226\/sec-chair-gensler-says-agency-staff-doing-work-on-multiple-bitcoin-etf-filings\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reporter<\/span><\/a> last month that the Division of Corporation Finance gives feedback, while the Division of Trading and Markets looks at the filings.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"This is a time tested process that goes back decades. The staff of the SEC, it's called the Disclosure Review Team, but in that group, they respond and give feedback to potential issuers,\" Gensler said.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"D.C. Circuit","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BlackRock","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. Court of Appeals","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Division of Corporation Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fidelity","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Grayscale Investments","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"the Division of Corporation Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Disclosure Review Team","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gary Gensler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gensler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Division of Trading","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Senate Banking Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}