{"summary":"Several crypto stocks traded down throughout the day on Wednesday, while crypto bank Silvergate bucked the trend.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/187768\/crypto-firms-rush-to-allay-genesis-contagion-fears-as-stocks-crater","publishDate":"2022-11-16T16:54:14","id":10854,"type":null,"title":"Crypto firms rush to allay Genesis contagion fears as stocks crater","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["Crypto-related stocks plunged as Genesis became the latest victim of the FTX fallout.&nbsp;","<span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitcoin was trading at $16,593, up 0.7% from $16,479 earlier in the day. Ether gained a modest 0.5% to trade at $1,213 at 4:40 p.m. ET, up from $1,206 earlier in the day.<\/span>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/chart\/?symbol=COINBASE%3ABTCUSD\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BTCUSD chart by TradingView<\/a><\/span><\/em>","<span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Contagion from FTX's collapse spread across the industry, affecting several major players.<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Genesis Global Capital announced today that it would halt all customer withdrawals and loan originations on its platform after taking a significant hit from the fallout of Three Arrows Capital (3AC) and FTX. <\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Shortly afterward, crypto exchange Gemini announced its Earn unit would be unable to meet customer redemptions within the five-day time frame set in the firm's service-level agreement. Five hours later, the exchange&nbsp;<\/span><span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">went offline, blaming the outage on its servers' problems.<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> It's back online now.<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In response to the Genesis news, multiple firms have come forward to make statements about their exposure. <\/span>","\"The market seems to have digested the news extremely well under the circumstances,\" said David Weisberger, CoinRoutes CEO. The issue now, and for a while, is that lending markets have seized up.&nbsp;","\"Personally, it feels like the bottoming process for bitcoin is well underway but might not be over yet,\" he said. He concluded that it takes time for meaningful bottoms to form before saying, \"on a multi-year timeframe, I am very bullish.\"","Coinbase closed down 12%, according to Nasdaq data via TradingView. Equities were down across the board. The S&amp;P 50o 0.83%, and the Nasdaq 100 dropped 1.45%.","Block closed down 5%, and Michael Saylor's MicroStrategy slipped 1.2%.","Silvergate bucked the trend, adding 6.7%. Silvergate avoided a two-day downtrend as a result.&nbsp;","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/symbols\/NYSE-SI\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">SINYSE chart by TradingView<\/a><\/span><\/em>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"6.7%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"TradingView","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"0.7%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"0.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"12%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"S&amp;P","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1.2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$1,213","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"crypto exchange Gemini","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"4:40 p.m. ET","content":"TIME"},{"type":"Michael Saylor","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$1,206","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$16,593","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"0.83%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1.45%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"David Weisberger","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$16,479","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Genesis Global Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MicroStrategy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nasdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN","COINBASE","EQUITY MOVERS","ETHEREUM","FTX","SAM BANKMAN-FRIED"],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","Sam Venis","The Block"]}