{"summary":"The deal between the bankrupt crypto firms could pave the way for FTX and Alameda Research to reclaim assets.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/218239\/judge-signs-off-on-voyager-agreement-to-reserve-445-million-after-alameda-suit","publishDate":"2023-03-08T17:24:39","id":10856,"type":null,"title":"Judge signs off on Voyager agreement to reserve $445 million after Alameda suit","category":["THE BLOCK"],"content":["A federal judge approved a stipulation between Voyager Digital and FTX, which includes an <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/215526\/voyager-agrees-to-reserve-445m-after-suit-from-alameda-research\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">agreement<\/span><\/a> that Voyager will set aside $445 million after an FTX entity sued it for loan repayments.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","The deal between the bankrupt crypto firms could pave the way for FTX and Alameda Research to reclaim assets.","Alameda Research, FTX’s sibling company that also filed for bankruptcy protection, sued Voyager for $445 million in loan repayments in January.<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span><\/span>","Judge John Dorsey approved the stipulation between FTX and Voyager on Wednesday after an FTX hearing in the U.S. Bankruptcy Court for the District of Delaware was canceled earlier in the day. Dorsey also approved Katherine Stadler, a shareholder at the law firm Godfrey &amp; Kahn, as the fee examiner in the FTX case.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","The unsecured creditors committees in the Voyager and FTX bankruptcy cases are also part of the deal.","As part of the stipulation, the parties agreed to participate in non-binding mediation and establish a framework for the litigation of remaining disputes. The deal illustrates how intertwined some large digital asset firms are.","<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Alameda lawsuit could have a significant impact on Voyager customers. <\/span>Another federal judge presiding over the Voyager case approved a plan for Binance.US to buy Voyager assets this week.","Voyager customers could see a 73% recovery under the restructuring plan, but that percentage would drop to 48% if the FTX and Alameda claims are successful, lawyers say.","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.<\/i>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S. Bankruptcy Court","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"John Dorsey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Voyager","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"73%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Godfrey &amp; Kahn","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"48%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$445 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Voyager Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Katherine Stadler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"the District of Delaware","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Stephanie Murray","The Block"]}