{"summary":"Former IcomTech executive Marco Ruiz Ochoa pleaded guilty on Wednesday for his role in what prosecutors call a crypto Ponzi scheme. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253268\/former-icomtech-executive-pleads-guilty-over-role-in-crypto-ponzi-scheme","publishDate":"2023-09-27T11:59:28","id":10869,"type":null,"title":"Former IcomTech executive pleads guilty over role in crypto Ponzi scheme","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Former IcomTech executive Marco Ruiz Ochoa pleaded guilty on Wednesday over his role in what prosecutors called a crypto Ponzi scheme.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IcomTech, an alleged crypto mining and trading company, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.justice.gov\/usao-sdny\/us-v-david-carmona-et-al-22-cr-551-jlr-icomtech\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">promised<\/span><\/a> investors profits in exchange for their purchase of \"purported cryptocurrency-related investment products.\" Ochoa, 35, along with others promised profits from the companies’ crypto trading and mining arm that they said would result in daily returns.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IcomTech’s crypto trading and mining business did not exist, prosecutors said, and investor money was used for other schemes and personal expenditures.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Today’s guilty plea sends a clear message that we are coming after all of those who seek to exploit cryptocurrency to commit fraud,\" Damian Williams, U.S. Attorney for the Southern District of New York, said in a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.justice.gov\/usao-sdny\/pr\/ceo-cryptocurrency-ponzi-scheme-icomtech-pleads-guilty\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">statement<\/a>.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Promoters for IcomTech showed up to events in expensive cars and wearing luxury clothes in a move to appear successful, prosecutors said.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"The atmosphere of these events was festive and designed to generate excitement about the schemes,\" they said.<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">When investors began trying to withdraw money in 2018, they were then met with excuses, delays and hidden fees.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Despite these complaints, IcomTech promoters, including Ochoa, continued to promote IcomTech and accept victims’ investments,\" prosecutors said. <\/span><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">By the end of 2019, IcomTech collapsed.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ochoa pled guilty on Wednesday to one count of conspiracy to commit wire fraud, which carries a maximum sentence of 20 years in prison.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Commodity Futures Trading Commission also brought charges against Ochoa, and other IcomTech executives including David Carmona, Juan <\/span><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Arellano Parra and Moses Valdez in May.&nbsp;<\/span><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The CFTC said the group targeted Spanish-speaking communities.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Juan <\/span><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Arellano Parra","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Damian Williams","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"David Carmona","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Moses Valdez","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ochoa","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Marco Ruiz Ochoa","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Commodity Futures Trading Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CFTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"the Southern District of New York","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["COURT HEARINGS","CRIME"],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}