{"summary":"In part two of this breaking news episode of The Scoop, Evgeny Gaevoy and Ki Jung Ju examine the relationship between FTX and Alameda.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/185182\/ftxs-demise-part-2-with-wintermutes-evgeny-gaevoy-and-cryptoquants-ki-young-ju","publishDate":"2022-11-10T05:00:33","id":10876,"type":null,"title":"FTX&#x27;s demise part 2 with Wintermute&#x27;s Evgeny Gaevoy and CryptoQuant&#x27;s Ki Young Ju","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 110<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 4 of The Scoop was recorded live with <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro<\/strong>,<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Wintermute Founder and CEO Evgeny Gaevoy, and CryptoQuant Co-founder and CEO Ki Jung Ju.<\/strong><\/i><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests can be sent to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"ee9e818a8d8f9d9aae9a868b8c82818d858d9c979e9a81c08d8183\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i><\/span>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK3736715052\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/184727\/inside-ftxs-demise-with-framework-ventures-co-founder-vance-spencer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">part one<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> of The Scoop’s coverage of the on-going controversy surrounding FTX and Alameda, Framework Venture co-founder Vance Spence suggested that FTX must have a very large hole in their balance sheet to be forced to turn to their biggest competitor for a buyout.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">We now know that FTX likely has upwards of an $8 billion hole in its balance sheet, which CEO Sam Bankman-Fried is <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/185163\/ftx-ceo-bankman-frieds-top-priority-fundraise\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">attempting to fill<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> through fundraising efforts.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In part two of this breaking news episode of The Scoop, Evgeny Gaevoy, Founder and CEO of crypto market-making firm Wintermute, and Ki Jung Ju, Co-Founder and CEO of crypto data provider CryptoQuant, examine FTX's demise with Framework Ventures Co-founder Vance Spencer. They discuss the relationship between FTX and Alameda, as well as what comes next for the crypto industry when the dust finally settles.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">According to Ju, whose company CryptoQuant specializes in analyzing on-chain data, there have been many substantial transfers between FTX and Alameda:<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Digging into their wallets, FTX and Alameda's wallets, and there are many significant flows between those entities… I think there are many untransparent or shady deals between FTX and Alameda…”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">While the full extent of the relationship between FTX and Alameda remains unknown for now, Gaevoy also says that the connection between the two companies was improper:<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“It turned out that there was this massive moral hazard — there were way more connection points than should have been morally possible, and it ended with a spectacular, spectacular blowup.”<\/span>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors <a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Tron, <\/em><\/a><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.ledn.io\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ledn<\/a><\/em><\/b><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nAbout Tron<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/b><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TRON is dedicated to accelerating the decentralization of the internet via blockchain technology and decentralized applications (dApps). Founded in September 2017 by <a href=\"https:\/\/www.hejustinsun.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">H.E. Justin Sun<\/a>, the TRON network has continued to deliver impressive achievements since MainNet launch in May 2018. July 2018 also marked the ecosystem integration of <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bittorrent.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BitTorrent<\/a>, a pioneer in decentralized web3 services boasting over 100 million monthly active users. The TRON network completed full decentralization in December 2021 and is now a community-governed DAO. | <a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/hackathon\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TRONDAO<\/a> | <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/trondao\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Twitter<\/a> | <a href=\"https:\/\/discord.gg\/tron\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Discord<\/a> |<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Ledn<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ledn was founded on the unshakeable conviction that digital assets have the power to democratize access to the global economy. We help you to experience the real life benefits of your Bitcoin without having to sell it. Start a savings account, take out a loan, or double your Bitcoin. For more information visit <a href=\"https:\/\/www.ledn.io\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ledn.io<\/a><\/span><\/em>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"BitTorrent","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wintermute","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gaevoy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Evgeny Gaevoy","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ki Jung Ju","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"May 2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"September 2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"H.E. Justin Sun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"July 2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Framework Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"December 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Framework Venture","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ledn<\/a><\/em><\/b><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nAbout Tron<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/b><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TRON","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wintermute Founder","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ledn<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ledn","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Vance Spencer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$8 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Vance Spence","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}