{"summary":"Group One, a trading firm specializing in options trading, took a position that includes the option to buy 1.26 million shares of MicroStrategy.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/200693\/microstrategy-sells-13-5-stake-to-trading-firm-group-one","publishDate":"2023-01-10T15:30:08","id":10892,"type":null,"title":"Options trading firm Group One takes position in MicroStrategy","category":["FINANCE FIRMS"],"content":["Options trading firm Group One took a \"beneficial ownership\" position in MicroStrategy that includes the option to buy 1.26 million shares of Class A common stock, according to a&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.microstrategy.com\/en\/investor-relations\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">document filed<\/a> with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission.","Microstrategy shares closed up 8.6%.&nbsp;","MicroStrategy is one of the largest holders of bitcoin, with a total of about <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/198220\/microstrategy-sold-bitcoin-worth-11-8-million-for-tax-benefits\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">132,500 BTC as of Dec. 28<\/a>.&nbsp;","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/crypto-markets\/public-companies\/microstrategy-bitcoin-holdings\/embed\" title=\"MicroStrategy Bitcoin Holdings\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Based in Chicago, Group One has been in business since 1989 and mostly operates in the options trading market, it says on its website. It maintains a physical presence on the Chicago Board Options Exchange, New York Stock Exchange Amex and Arca and Nasdaq PHLX.","The firm didn't immediately respond to a request for comment.&nbsp;","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">(Corrects earlier story that referred to the purchase as an equity stake.)<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"8.6%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Microstrategy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1989","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Chicago Board Options Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chicago","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"New York Stock Exchange Amex","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dec. 28","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Nasdaq PHLX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MicroStrategy","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["EQUITY MOVERS","MICROSTRATEGY"],"authors":["Catarina Moura","The Block"]}