{"summary":"The Block&#x27;s Frank Chaparro chats with Blockchain Association executive director Kristin Smith.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/103423\/the-threat-right-now-is-not-yellen-kristin-smith-on-crypto-rumors-and-dc-policy","publishDate":"2021-04-30T12:24:53","id":10909,"type":null,"title":"&#x27;The threat right now is not Yellen&#x27;: Kristin Smith on crypto rumors and DC policy","category":["REGULATION"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 25 of Season 3 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block’s Frank Chaparro and Blockchain Association executive director Kristin Smith.<\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"89f9e6edeae8fafdc9fde1ecebe5e6eae2eafbf0f9fde6a7eae6e4\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/bakkt.onelink.me\/FTbR\/c2043775\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bakkt<\/a>, Kraken, and Exodus<\/strong><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/bakkt.onelink.me\/FTbR\/c2043775\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bakkt®<\/em><\/a><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;unlocks the $1.2+ trillion of digital assets that is currently held in cryptocurrencies, rewards and loyalty points, gaming assets and merchant stored value. We began in 2018 with the vision to bring trust and transparency to digital assets. Through the Bakkt Warehouse and Bakkt Bitcoin Futures and Options contracts, we serve institutional clients in an end-to-end regulated market with true price transparency. For consumers, Bakkt aggregates digital assets to enable instant liquidity and to empower users to trade, transfer and pay however they want.&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/bakkt.onelink.me\/FTbR\/c2043775\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Visit Bakkt.com<\/a>&nbsp;for more information<\/em><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Kraken<\/strong><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Whether you’re an experienced crypto trader or just starting out, Kraken has the tools to help you achieve financial freedom. With 50+ cryptocurrencies to choose from, industry-leading security and a wide variety of features to suit any investing strategy, Kraken puts the power in your hands to buy, sell and trade digital assets. Visit&nbsp;<\/em><a href=\"http:\/\/kraken.com\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kraken.com<\/em><\/a><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;to get started&nbsp;today.<\/em><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Exodus<\/strong><\/span>","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK6831704307\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","It was a tweet heard 'round the crypto world.&nbsp;","A breaking news account fired off, in all caps, an unsubstantiated headline that the U.S. Treasury Department was set to crack down on a number of unknown banks for their activity in the crypto market. Soon after the tweet's release, several industry insiders — including the Blockchain Association's Kristin Smith — <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/KMSmithDC\/status\/1384249698215624709?s=20\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">threw cold water<\/a> on its key claim.&nbsp;","\"There's a lot of rumors going around that don't have any truth of foundation,\" Smith said.&nbsp;","In this episode of The Scoop, Smith unpacked the erroneous rumor, why U.S. Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen isn't making bitcoin a priority right now, how crypto policy works, and why crypto market participants should be concerned about the Financial Action Task Force decision coming this June.","As Smith put it during the interview:","\"The thing that we do have to worry about at Treasury isn't coming from the top people as I said but Treasury's interaction with the Financial Action Task Force or the FATF. The FATF has proposed something that is fairly scary ... if adopted would require a lot of different entities in the U.S. to register as money services businesses.\"","Smith went on to add: \"The threat right now is not Yellen.\"","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Blockchain Association","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bakkt Warehouse","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S. Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. Treasury Department","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1.2+ trillion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Kristin Smith","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Janet Yellen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Season 3","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FATF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kraken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Smith","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"June","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Financial Action Task Force","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Yellen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN"],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}