{"summary":"On-chain data shows roughly 5.5 million OKB — worth roughly $244 million — was removed from the token&#x27;s supply.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/233929\/okx-okb-burn-244-million","publishDate":"2023-06-09T02:23:40","id":10930,"type":null,"title":"OKX burns $244 million of its exchange token, OKB, in record supply cut","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["Crypto exchange OKX has repurchased and burned the largest value of its exchange token, OKB, since it started the monthly program.","According to on-chain data from Dune collected by user @sankin, roughly 5.5 million tokens — worth roughly $244 million — were removed from the token's supply.","OKX <a href=\"https:\/\/www.okx.com\/help-center\/okb-buy-back-and-burn-report-2023-03-01-2023-5-31\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">claims<\/a> the value of the burn was around $258 billion when calculated at a 90-day average price.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The value of OKB burned by OKX has set a new record. Source: <a href=\"https:\/\/dune.com\/sankin\/okb-buy-back-and-burn-report\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Dune\/@sankin<\/a><\/span>","Chinese reporter Colin Wu <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/WuBlockchain\/status\/1667011756072501248\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">noted<\/a> that this set another new record for OKB value burned.","OKX describes OKB as a \"global utility token issued by the OKX Blockchain Foundation\" that lets holders \"enjoy benefits including discounts, exclusive access, and more.\"&nbsp;","To date, 64,042,314.70 tokens have been burned by the crypto exchange since it started the process in May 2019.","The token's price is flat on the day, trading up a slight 0.29% on OKX.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The price of OKB is down more than 2% on OKX over the past week. Source: <a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/symbols\/OKBUSDT\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TradingView<\/a><\/span>","Exchange tokens are in the spotlight following the United States Securities and Exchange Commission's <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/233652\/sec-binance-and-us-affiliate-redirected-billions-in-customer-assets-to-zhaos-funds\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">suing<\/a> Binance on various charges relating to the sale of unregistered securities.","Driven by the news, Binance's BNB has declined nearly 15% over the past week.","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This article has been updated with additional context.<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$244 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"TradingView","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Colin Wu","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"OKX Blockchain Foundation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"United States Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"OKB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"OKX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"15%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"0.29%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$258 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"May 2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Binance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dune\/@sankin","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["OKX"],"authors":["Adam James","The Block"]}