{"summary":"Two senior Google Cloud employees breakdown Google&#x27;s crypto strategy.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/222760\/google-cloud-web3-strategy","publishDate":"2023-03-25T05:00:51","id":11001,"type":null,"title":"How Google is helping web3 startups focus on what they do best","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 28<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 5 of The Scoop was recorded at Paris Blockchain Week with <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro and Google Cloud's Web3 Head of Strategy Rich Widmann and Web3 Engineering Director James Tromans.<\/strong><\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a>,<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Feedback and revision requests can be sent to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"bfcfd0dbdcdecccbffcbd7daddd3d0dcd4dccdc6cfcbd091dcd0d2\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm\/?e=BLOCK8948966267\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In this episode — recorded at Paris Blockchain Week 2023 — Google Cloud's Web3 Head of Strategy Rich Widmann, and Web3 Engineering Director James Tromans break down Google's crypto strategy and how Google Cloud's <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/180458\/google-cloud-announces-blockchain-node-service-starting-with-ethereum\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Blockchain Node Engine<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> is making it easier for web3 developers to focus solely on building their products.<\/span>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">During this episode, Chaparro, Widmann, and Tromans also discuss:<\/span><\/i>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors <i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"http:\/\/Circle.com\/Scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Circle<\/a>, <a href=\"https:\/\/railgun.app.link\/thescoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Railgun<\/a>, <a href=\"https:\/\/flare.network\/?utm_source=TDE&amp;utm_medium=Podcast&amp;utm_campaign=TheBlock\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Flare Network<\/a><\/i><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em><\/b><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nAbout Circle<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Circle is a global financial technology company helping money move at internet speed. Our mission is to raise global economic prosperity through the frictionless exchange of value. Visit <a class=\"c-link\" href=\"http:\/\/circle.com\/Scoop\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-stringify-link=\"http:\/\/Circle.com\/Scoop\" data-sk=\"tooltip_parent\" aria-describedby=\"sk-tooltip-398\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Circle.com\/Scoop<\/a> to learn more.<\/em><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Railgun<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Railgun is a private DeFi solution on Ethereum, BSC, Arbitrum and Polygon. Shield any ERC-20 token and any NFT into a Private Balance and let Railgun’s zero-knowledge cryptography encrypt your address, balance and transaction history. You can also bring privacy to your project with Railgun SDK, and be sure to check out Railgun with partner project <a href=\"https:\/\/railway.app.link\/thescoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Railway Wallet<\/a>, also available on iOS and Android. Visit <a href=\"https:\/\/railgun.app.link\/thescoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Railgun.org<\/a> to find out more.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Flare<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Flare is an EVM-based Layer 1 blockchain designed to allow developers to build applications that can use data from other blockchains and the internet. By providing decentralized access to a wide variety of high-integrity data from other blockchains and the internet, Flare enables new use cases and monetization models. Build better and connect everything at <a href=\"https:\/\/flare.network\/?utm_source=TDE&amp;utm_medium=Podcast&amp;utm_campaign=TheBlock\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Flare.Network<\/a>.<\/em><\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Railgun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Google Cloud","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Paris","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Rich Widmann","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Widmann","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Railgun<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Railgun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Blockchain Node Engine","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"20","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Flare Network<\/a><\/i><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em><\/b><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nAbout Circle<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Circle","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"James Tromans","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Railgun SDK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}