{"summary":"Binance has surpassed 150 million users, despite facing an ongoing legal battle with U.S. regulators, according to CEO Changpeng Zhao.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/242975\/binance-150-million-users-cz","publishDate":"2023-08-03T09:16:00","id":11036,"type":null,"title":"Binance user base surges to 150 million, CZ says — despite US regulatory lawsuits","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Crypto exchange Binance has surpassed 150 million registered users, according to co-founder and CEO Changpeng \"CZ\" Zhao — despite facing an ongoing legal battle with the United States regulators. The milestone comes with Binance's re-entry in Japan and a license in Dubai earlier this week, Zhao <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/cz_binance\/status\/1687061963094814720\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweeted<\/a>.","In May, Binance's user base was <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/230140\/binance-capital-connect-vip\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">128 million<\/a>&nbsp;— meaning the crypto exchange has gained 22 million users in just three months, despite ongoing global regulatory scrutiny.&nbsp;","Binance and Zhao were sued by the Commodity Futures Trading Commission in March for allegedly operating an \"illegal\" exchange and a \"sham\" compliance program. Subsequently, in July, the Securities and Exchange Commission&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/233206\/sec-binance-showdown-sends-shockwaves-through-crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">sued<\/a> Binance, Zhao and Binance.US for allegedly breaking U.S. securities laws. The U.S. Department of Justice is also<a href=\"https:\/\/www.semafor.com\/article\/08\/02\/2023\/us-prosecutors-worry-binance-charges-could-cause-run-on-exchange\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> reportedly<\/a> considering fraud charges against Binance but is worried it could cause a run on the exchange and hurt users.","Elsewhere, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/235129\/binance-is-under-investigation-in-france-for-alleged-money-laundering-le-monde\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">France<\/a> is also reportedly investigating Binance because of alleged money laundering. In recent weeks and months, Binance has also&nbsp;exited&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/235084\/binance-exits-the-netherlands\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">the Netherlands<\/a>, deregistered entities in&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/234617\/binance-cyprus-deregister\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Cyprus<\/a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/235425\/binance-deregisters-in-uk-amid-regulatory-woes\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">the U.K.<\/a>, withdrawn its license application in&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/236405\/binance-austria-withdraws-license-application\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Austria<\/a> and was ordered to stop operating in <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/236239\/belgium-regulator-orders-binance-to-stop-services-in-country\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Belgium.<\/a>","Yet, Binance's market share keeps growing. It remains the world's largest crypto exchange, with nearly 65% market share in spot trading volumes today, according to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/crypto-markets\/spot\/no-usd-support-exchange-volume-market-share\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Data Dashboard<\/a>.","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/crypto-markets\/spot\/no-usd-support-exchange-volume-market-share\/embed\" title=\"No USD Support Exchange Volume Market Share\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Zhao remains committed to \"keep building.\" Last month, he <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/237907\/binance-cz-crypto-trading-volumes\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a> Binance is doing “a lot of preparation” to ready its systems for higher crypto trading volumes over the next six to 18 months. Zhao expects a volume surge based on historical patterns and events, including the upcoming Bitcoin halving next year.","Binance did not immediately respond to The Block’s request for comment on the new user base milestone.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"earlier this week","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Netherlands","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Austria","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"France","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"65%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.K.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Cyprus","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Japan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S. Department of Justice","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Commodity Futures Trading Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dubai","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block's Data Dashboard","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Belgium","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"United States","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Binance","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE","CZ"],"authors":["Yogita Khatri","The Block"]}