{"summary":"The startup intends to build out &quot;buy now pay later&quot; payment models for non-fungible tokens (NFTs), a growing trend.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/157591\/nft-financing-platform-supermojo-raises-6-million-in-seed-funding","publishDate":"2022-07-14T12:34:05","id":11196,"type":null,"title":"NFT financing platform Supermojo raises $6 million in seed funding","category":["METAVERSE & NFT"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Supermojo, a financing platform for non-fungible tokens (NFTs), announced Thursday that it raised $6 million in seed funding.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The funding round was led by BH Digital, DRW Venture Capital, Intersection Growth Partners and Neuberger Berman, with additional participation from Sfermion, Arca, Gemini, Everyrealm, Arrington Capital, BlockFi Ventures, Circle Ventures, Crossbeam Venture Partners, Draper, FJ Labs, FBG Capital, OP Crypto, Red Beard Ventures and Ripple, according to a release shared with The Block.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Supermojo's platform features a buy now pay later (BNLP) service for NFTs. BNPL a process in which a user pays a portion for a product outright and pays the rest in later installments, often with interest.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“The NFT market needs to welcome new users in order to keep scaling. NFT marketplaces and storefronts have yet to offer the payment methods most people are familiar with when buying online,” said Supermojo CEO Amir Sarhangi in the statement, adding that BNLP is one familiar payment method for most users. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Our team at Supermojo is committed to providing a more seamless, intuitive, and accessible NFT purchasing, financing, and custody experience for the next wave of NFT users, from checkout to resale,\" Sarhangi said.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BNLP became popular through traditional finance spaces via the company <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/124608\/klarna-acquisition\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Klarna<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, but has crept into NFT financing as seen with the DeFi lender Teller recently launching <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/156419\/defi-lender-teller-launches-buy-now-pay-later-feature-for-bored-apes-and-other-nft-projects\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">NFT BNLP<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> features. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Supermojo was founded by Sarhangi and Craig DeWitt, two former senior employees of distributed ledger startup Ripple.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Arca","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Everyrealm","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Crossbeam Venture Partners","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Arrington Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Red Beard Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Klarna","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gemini","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Amir Sarhangi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sfermion","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Circle Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Draper","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BH Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FBG Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sarhangi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Craig DeWitt","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Intersection Growth Partners","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$6 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Neuberger Berman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"DRW Venture Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"OP Crypto","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}