{"summary":"Gulf Binance, the joint venture, plans to first serve users by invitation before opening to the general public early next year.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/263249\/binance-to-start-crypto-exchange-in-thailand-through-joint-venture-with-gulf-energy","publishDate":"2023-11-15T22:50:09","id":11216,"type":null,"title":"Binance to start crypto exchange in Thailand through joint venture with Gulf Energy","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance is preparing to start operating a crypto exchange in Thailand early next year through a joint venture with a unit of Gulf Energy Development.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In a translated&nbsp;<\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/weblink.set.or.th\/dat\/news\/202311\/1391NWS151120231838120570E.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filing<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;to the Stock Exchange of Thailand, dated Wednesday, Gulf Energy Development said Gulf Binance — the joint venture set up by Binance and Gulf Innova — obtained approval from Thailand’s Securities and Exchange Commission to commence operations.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In May, Gulf Binance&nbsp;<\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/232330\/binance-gulf-thailand\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">obtained licenses from Thailand's Ministry of Finance<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to become a digital asset operator regulated by the nation’s SEC. Yesterday's filing gives it the green light to launch.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Gulf Binance’s digital asset platform will provide digital asset exchange and digital asset broker services for both cryptocurrencies and digital tokens, prioritizing security and compliance with SEC regulations,” the company said in the filing.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Gulf Energy added that the exchange will initially be open to users by invitation only, with plans to open to the general public in early 2024.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance and Thailand billionaire Sarath Ratanavadi's Gulf Energy <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/130506\/binance-thailand-gulf-energy-crypto-exchange\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">first reached an agreement about the joint venture<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in early 2022.<\/span>","A Binance spokesperson told The Block that the platform has initially launched as an invitation-only exchange. \"Our plan is to eventually open the exchange to the general public.\"","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Gulf Energy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thailand’s Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gulf Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gulf Binance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gulf Energy Development","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Stock Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gulf Innova","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ministry of Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thailand","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sarath Ratanavadi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Binance","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["ASIAN REGULATION","BINANCE"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}