{"summary":"BTG Pactual&#x27;s crypto platform Mynt is now officially open to the public.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/163885\/btg-pactual-confirms-official-launch-of-brazil-crypto-platform","publishDate":"2022-08-16T14:58:32","id":11210,"type":null,"title":"BTG Pactual confirms official launch of Brazil crypto platform","category":["THE BLOCK"],"content":["Latin America investment bank BTG Pactual confirmed that its crypto trading platform Mynt is officially available to the public, adding yet another layer of competition in the Brazilian market for fintech and banking firms offering digital asset trading within their existing user experiences.","Mynt currently supports trading of five digital assets: bitcoin, ether, Solana, Polkadot and Cardano. People using the platform can invest in cryptocurrencies with as little as 100 Brazilian reais ($19.49).&nbsp;","\"Crypto is a new technology with great potential for transformation, which brings risks and opportunities,\" BTG Pactual's Head of Digital Assets André Portilho said in an August 16 press release. \"We are promoting direct access to investments in the main cryptocurrencies on the market, in a simple and secure way, in a very intuitive and complete platform, with content and financial education,” said Portilho.","One advantage of Mynt is that it offers 24\/7 support from a team available to answer any questions, the crypto-focused executive added. The platform is available through a standalone smartphone app and also has a desktop version.&nbsp;","Media outlets including <a href=\"https:\/\/cointelegraph.com.br\/news\/btg-enters-the-fray-with-mercado-bitcoin-and-binance-and-officially-launches-its-cryptocurrency-exchange\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CoinTelegraph Brasil<\/a> previously reported in late July that Mynt had launched. Portilho said that Mynt became available to the wider market on August 15 in a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.linkedin.com\/feed\/update\/urn:li:activity:6965140267951624193\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">LinkedIn post,<\/a> noting that it had been available to a restricted group since May.&nbsp;","BTG Pactual first <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/118524\/why-btg-pactual-is-launching-a-crypto-platform\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">unveiled <\/a>the idea for Mynt in September 2021, initially planning to offer bitcoin and ether trading by the end of that year.&nbsp;","Brokerage XP, another important Brazilian financial company, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/163649\/major-brazilian-broker-xp-opens-crypto-trading-platform\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">also launched<\/a> a crypto trading platform on August 15. Several other Brazilian fintech and banking companies have also entered the world of crypto in recent months, including Nubank, PicPay and Mercado Libre (known as Mercado Livre in Brazil).&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"André Portilho","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"CoinTelegraph Brasil","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Crypto","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cardano","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"September 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Brazil","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"BTG Pactual","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"August 16","content":"DATE"},{"type":"August 15","content":"DATE"},{"type":"BTG Pactual's Head of Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$19.49","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Mercado Livre","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Portilho","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN"],"authors":["Kristin Majcher","The Block"]}