{"summary":"The crypto exchange founded by the Winklevoss twins is losing its chief technology officer, according to a report.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/261804\/gemini-cto-pravjit-tiwana-leaving-company-bloomberg","publishDate":"2023-11-06T15:32:43","id":11257,"type":null,"title":"Gemini CTO Pravjit Tiwana leaving company: Bloomberg","category":["PEOPLE"],"content":["Crypto exchange Gemini, the company founded by entrepreneur brothers Tyler and Cameron Winklevoss, is losing its chief technology officer, according to Bloomberg.","Formerly at both Amazon and Disney, Pravjit Tiwana will be leaving his role as Gemini's CTO this month, the report said, citing two anonymous sources. Tiwana also served as CEO of Gemini APAC. <br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nTiwana and Gemini did not immediately respond to a request for comment.","The CTO worked to make Gemini's culture more similar to Amazon's in a move that resulted in some employees leaving, according to the report. Tiwana's responsibilities at the firm included overseeing product, engineering and design, the report also said.","For months, Gemini has been <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/259821\/gemini-files-complaint-against-genesis-over-1-6-billion-in-gbtc-shares\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">engaged<\/a> in a&nbsp;long, drawn out fight with Genesis and its parent company <span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Digital Currency Group. The Securities and Exchange Commission has also sued Gemini.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Gemini","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gemini","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Amazon","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Digital Currency Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gemini APAC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tyler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Cameron Winklevoss","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"CTO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Pravjit Tiwana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Disney","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}