{"summary":"FTX roiled markets throughout the week, culminating with the exchange&#x27;s Chapter 11 bankruptcy filing on Friday.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/186542\/the-week-in-markets-crypto-prices-plummeted-as-ftx-unraveled","publishDate":"2022-11-13T16:46:11","id":11276,"type":null,"title":"The week in markets: Crypto prices plummeted as FTX unraveled","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["Crypto prices cratered throughout the week as the FTX controversy played out at breakneck speed.","Bitcoin was trading at $16,500 today, down 23% over the past week, while ether lost 25% in the same period to trade at $1,219, according to data via CoinGecko.","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/chart\/?symbol=COINBASE%3ABTCUSD\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BTCUSD chart by TradingView<\/span><\/a><\/em>","Altcoins also traded down throughout the week. Binance's BNB shed 21% to trade at $274, and Solana's SOL lost 63%. Tether's USDT briefly traded <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/184653\/tethers-usdt-falls-1-below-dollar-peg-amid-market-uncertainty\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">below<\/a> its peg to the U.S. dollar on Thursday amid the market turmoil.","On Sunday, Nov. 6, Binance's CEO Changpeng Zhao revealed plans to sell its FTT tokens. The following day, Sam Bankman-Fried insisted FTX was \"fine.\" By Tuesday, however, Binance had reached a deal to acquire FTX.com.","By Wednesday, Binance's budding acquisition was <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/184636\/binance-backs-out-of-ftx-acquisition-deal\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">off<\/a>. \"Our hope was to be able to support FTX's customers to provide liquidity, but the issues are beyond our control or ability to help,\" Binance said.&nbsp;","From Wednesday onwards, FTX began to quickly unravel, and rumors of emergency fundraising to plug a $9 billion hole were swirling. FTX <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/185083\/ftx-files-for-chapter-11-bankruptcy\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filed<\/a> for Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection, along with more than 100 corporate entities affiliated with the firm, including Alameda Research and FTX US.","Here's a comprehensive <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/186132\/ftx-collapse-timeline-six-days-that-rocked-the-crypto-industry\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">timeline<\/a> of the week and all that happened with FTX.","The U.S. <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/185241\/bitcoin-and-ether-up-as-u-s-inflation-data-below-estimates-at-7-7-in-october\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">inflation<\/a> rate for October was 7.7%, a month-on-month increase of 0.4%. Analysts had predicted an 8% increase for the month, based on FactSet data. In September, inflation increased by 0.4% month-on-month from August.&nbsp;","The report buoyed prices before they crashed again following FTX's collapse.&nbsp;","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">source: bea.gov and federalreserve.gov.<\/span><\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"8%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$1,219","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"TradingView","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nov. 6","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Changpeng Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"25%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$16,500","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FactSet","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sunday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"USDT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"7.7%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"today","content":"DATE"},{"type":"21%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"23%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"0.4%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"63%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$274","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$9 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"October","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Binance","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}