{"summary":"An ECB executive faced backlash from European Parliamentarians on the decision to bring Amazon on to help design the digital euro payment prototype.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/173711\/eu-policymakers-criticize-amazons-role-in-ecbs-digital-euro-development","publishDate":"2022-09-29T12:01:04","id":11325,"type":null,"title":"EU policymakers criticize Amazon&#x27;s role in ECB’s digital euro development","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Members of the European Parliament criticized the European Central Bank’s (ECB) <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/170734\/amazon-among-five-companies-to-develop-digital-euro-prototype-for-the-ecb\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">decision<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to bring in Amazon as a partner in designing the digital euro prototype.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The main concerns MEPs raised in the Economic and Monetary Affairs (ECON) Committee of the European Parliament on Tuesday were Amazon’s “questionable” social and tax policy, including an alleged violation of EU data protection regulations that led to a record <a href=\"https:\/\/www.reuters.com\/business\/retail-consumer\/amazon-hit-with-886-million-eu-data-privacy-fine-2021-07-30\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">fine<\/a> from regulators last year, though Amazon appealed the decision.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Fabio Panetta, a member of the ECB executive board, appeared Thursday before the Parliament in a quarterly exchange between the institutions to deliver an update on the progress made in the ECB’s investigation into the digital euro.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">MEPs took this opportunity to vent their dissatisfaction with having Amazon involved in this process. Center-left MEP Eero Heinäluoma referred to the <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.reuters.com\/business\/retail-consumer\/amazon-hit-with-886-million-eu-data-privacy-fine-2021-07-30\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">€746 million fine<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> the corporate giant received for violating GDPR rules in the EU to question the central bank’s decision.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Panetta tried to quell concerns by explaining that Amazon's current role on the project is not guaranteed to continue in a potential next phase. He also said that the project benefitted from Amazon’s expertise in designing a user interfaces for payments, and that Amazon was not compensated for their work on the project.<\/span>","This drew deeper criticism from c<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">entrist parliamentarian Stéphanie Yon-Courtin. “We know that Amazon wants to be paid with data.” <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Other members of the panel shared Yon-Courtin's concern.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Honestly, I am now more worried than before,” said Jonás Fernández, an MEP from a left-leaning party.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The prototype design phase is scheduled to wrap up in March 2023, and a decision on whether to move forward with implementation of the digital euro project could come in October 2o23.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Panetta originally came to discuss collaboration needed between the private and public sector on the euro-CBDC. He outlined that the ECB aims to replicate “cash-like” privacy features for low-value transactions.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Evelien Witlox, the program director for the ECB’s digital euro project spoke about designing two privacy tiers in the CBDC in an offline and online digital euro. For the offline case, authorities can only monitor things like top-ups but other transactions will simulate the privacy of cash, she said at the Frankfurt Forum on Thursday.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Fabio Panetta","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"European Parliament","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Amazon","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"ECB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"EU","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"March 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Frankfurt","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Courtin","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Jonás Fernández","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Courtin","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"European Central Bank’s (ECB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Eero Heinäluoma","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Parliament","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"October","content":"DATE"},{"type":"euro","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Economic and Monetary Affairs (ECON) Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ups","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["ECB","EUROPEAN PARLIAMENT"],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}