{"summary":"Billionaire investor George Soros’ family office, Soros Fund Management, owns “some” bitcoins, says CEO and CIO Dawn Fitzpatrick.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/119609\/george-soros-family-office-bitcoin-fitzpatrick","publishDate":"2021-10-06T07:04:50","id":11359,"type":null,"title":"George Soros&#x27; family office owns bitcoin, confirms CEO Fitzpatrick","category":["BITCOIN"],"content":["Soros Fund’s CEO and CIO Dawn Fitzpatrick has revealed that the family office owns “some” bitcoins.&nbsp;","The revelation confirms previous reports that said Soros Fund had started trading bitcoin.","Billionaire investor George Soros' family office, Soros Fund Management, has invested in bitcoin, according to Soros Fund CEO\/CIO Dawn Fitzpatrick.","Fitzpatrick told Bloomberg <a href=\"https:\/\/www.youtube.com\/watch?v=d8XVT6-0apw\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">in an interview<\/a> on Tuesday that, \"From our perspective again, we own some coins, not a lot, and the coins themselves are less interesting than the use use cases of DeFi and things like that.”","Fitzpatrick's comments confirm <a href=\"https:\/\/www.thestreet.com\/crypto\/news\/soros-fund-management-is-trading-bitcoin\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">previous reports<\/a> from earlier this year that said Soros Fund has started trading bitcoin, on the basis of anonymous sources. Soros Fund is also an investor in crypto firms such as NYDIG and Lukka, but this appears to be the firm's first public confirmation of having investments in cryptocurrency directly.","\"I’m not sure bitcoin is only viewed as an inflation hedge. Here I think it’s crossed the chasm to mainstream. Cryptocurrencies now have a market cap of over $2 trillion. There’s 200 million users around the world, so I think this has gone mainstream,\" Fitzpatrick added.","In March, Fitzpatrick also shared her views on central bank digital currencies (CBDCs), saying that CBDCs \"are going to be here I think quicker than people expect.\"&nbsp;","At the time, she gave an example of China's CBDC trials and said that the country's digital yuan would be a \"potential threat to other bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies.\" But she added that it will be temporary, saying, \"I don't think they'll be successful in permanently destabilizing bitcoin.\"","Family offices and hedge fund giants have been wading deeper into crypto. Steve Cohen's Point72 Asset Management, for instance, recently <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/119146\/steve-cohens-point72-ventures-leads-35-million-series-c-round-for-zero-hash\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">started investing<\/a> in crypto startups such as Messari and Zero Hash. Billionaire investor Dan Loeb's Third Point fund also <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/business\/2021\/04\/09\/daniel-loebs-17b-hedge-fund-is-keeping-crypto-with-coinbase-and-maybe-even-staking-it\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reportedly<\/a> holds cryptocurrency.","<i data-stringify-type=\"italic\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">For more breaking stories like this, make sure to follow The Block on&nbsp;<\/i><i data-stringify-type=\"italic\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a class=\"c-link\" href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/TheBlock__\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-stringify-link=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/TheBlock__\" data-sk=\"tooltip_parent\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Twitter<\/a><\/i><i data-stringify-type=\"italic\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/i>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$2 trillion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Steve Cohen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"CIO Dawn Fitzpatrick","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lukka","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Soros","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Fitzpatrick","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Third Point","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Soros Fund Management","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dan Loeb","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"George Soros","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"China","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN"],"authors":["Yogita Khatri","The Block"]}