{"summary":"Xianfeng Cheng (aka Mars Cheng), the chief technology officer (CTO) of Huobi Group, is departing the firm after four years. A Huobi spokesperson confirmed","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/51746\/huobi-group-cto-is-leaving-after-four-years-at-crypto-firm","publishDate":"2019-12-30T10:17:35","id":11365,"type":null,"title":"Huobi Group CTO is leaving after four years at crypto firm","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["Xianfeng Cheng (aka Mars Cheng), the chief technology officer (CTO) of <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/49710\/after-a-lackluster-year-huobis-u-s-partner-exchange-is-shutting-down-operations\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Huobi<\/a> Group, is departing the firm after four years.","A Huobi spokesperson confirmed to The Block on Monday that Cheng is leaving in February 2020.","Cheng joined <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/38320\/huobi-backs-blockchain-smartphones-for-cryptocurrency-traders-purchasable-with-huobi-token\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Huobi<\/a> Global in February 2016, according to his <a href=\"https:\/\/www.linkedin.com\/in\/marscheng\/?originalSubdomain=cn\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">LinkedIn<\/a> profile. Before joining Huobi, he held executive roles at the Chinese IT firm OneAPM and lending platform Jimubox, where he served as the chief operating officer and VP of technology, respectively.","It is not clear why Cheng is leaving <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/12419\/huobi-com-lists-xlm-xmr-and-steem-for-trading\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Huobi<\/a> and what are his next plans. The Block has reached out to the spokesperson for further comments and will update this story if we hear back.","Founded in 2013, Singapore-based cryptocurrency firm Huobi is currently the second-largest employer in the industry at around 1,300 staff, according to&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockresearch.com\/org-chart-huobi-group-47591\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block’s research<\/a>.","Founded as a crypto trading platform, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/17322\/huobi-forms-new-team-focused-on-developing-institutional-products-and-services\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Huobi<\/a> has today grown into a conglomerate that oversees at least ten different business lines. Some of these business lines include Huobi Research, Huobi DM (a derivatives trading platform) and Huobi Capital (an investment arm that has invested in over 60 different blockchain projects globally), among others.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2013","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Huobi Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CTO) of <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/49710\/after-a-lackluster-year-huobis-u-s-partner-exchange-is-shutting-down-operations\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Huobi<\/a> Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Huobi spokesperson","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Huobi<\/a> Global","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"February 2016","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Cheng","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"February 2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Mars Cheng)","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Huobi","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["HTX"],"authors":["Yogita Khatri","The Block"]}