{"summary":"Experts say the SEC could rule on filings for a spot bitcoin ETF over the next few months, as deadlines quickly approach.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/262670\/spot-bitcoin-etf-fever-has-analysts-guessing-about-the-secs-decision-timeline","publishDate":"2023-11-10T15:47:26","id":11371,"type":null,"title":"Spot bitcoin ETF fever has analysts guessing about the SEC&#x27;s decision timeline","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Experts are weighing in on the probability of a much-anticipated spot bitcoin exchange-traded fund being approved by the Securities and Exchange Commission.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitcoin <\/span><span class=\"articleTooltip\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"\/price\/248348\/bitcoin-btc-usd\" class=\"articleTooltip__link\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"><img src=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2023\/10\/bitcoin.png\" alt=\"\" title=\"\" class=\"articleTooltip__tokenImage\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">BTC<\/span> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText articleTooltip__tokenText_price articleTooltip__tokenText_negative\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">\n      -0.056%\n    <\/span><\/a> <!----><\/span><\/span> has been <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/261472\/bitcoin-rally-mostly-driven-by-macroeconomic-factors-rather-than-etf-narrative-qcp-says\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">rallying<\/a> amid ongoing excitement that the Securities and Exchange Commission may be getting closer to a decision that could greenlight a spot ETF, rising almost 40% over the past month. The approval process is complex, however, and most analysts can only guess as to just how close the industry might be to getting an answer from the regulator.&nbsp;","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"The SEC will not want to act as kingmaker given the scrutiny it will attract, and this will take a little more time,\" Tim Bevan, CEO of ETC Group, said in an emailed statement, saying he expected the regulator to rule simultaneously on the multitude of applications it's currently reviewing. \"<\/span><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Hence, we believe January is the earliest we are likely to see approval.\"<\/span>","Despite fresh speculation that the SEC is due to soon say something about applications from asset managers inducing BlackRock and Fidelity because of a rebuttal period that ended this week after they were <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253506\/sec-moves-to-again-delay-decision-on-valkyrie-spot-bitcoin-etf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">most recently delayed<\/a> in September, the regulator <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253108\/sec-moves-to-delay-decision-on-ark-21shares-bitcoin-etf-into-next-year\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">had already<\/a> pushed back its decision timeline on the proposed ARK 21Shares Bitcoin ETF until at least Jan. 10.&nbsp;","<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Amid a wave of filings for funds earlier in the year, optimism that approval could be getting closer grew after judges ruled in August t<\/span><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">hat the SEC had to re-review a bid for a spot bitcoin ETF from Grayscale Investments after the asset management firm sued the agency last year following the rejection of its plan for the conversion of its flagship GBTC fund. Bitcoin's price has surged, rising 115% over the past year to currently trade at $37,235, according to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coingecko.com\/en\/coins\/bitcoin\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CoinGecko<\/a>.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ultimately, it's up to the SEC about when and how it makes any decisions, said Vivian Fang, a finance professor at Indiana University.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"It sure can wait until the final deadline, although I personally think it will likely make a decision this year,\" Fang said. \"At least this seems to be priced in by the recent crypto price movements - the market is heating up for near-term approvals of the spot bitcoin ETFs.\"&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/JSeyff\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Analysts<\/a><\/span><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> from Bloomberg Intelligence say there is a significant chance that approvals could start coming in by early January, but noted that a window has since opened up until Nov. 17 for a potential greenlight.&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Even if approvals don't arrive this month, we still believe there's a 90% chance of approval by Jan. 10,\" Bloomberg's James Seyffart and Eric Balchunas said earlier this week on X.<\/span>","<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Nathan Geraci, <\/span><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">president of advisory firm The ETF Store, <\/span><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said it is possible that the SEC takes advantage of the short window.<\/span>","<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Issuing 19b-4 approval orders during this window would help keep the SEC on the path towards batching-up all existing spot bitcoin ETF filings to launch at the same time,\" Geraci said.&nbsp;<\/span><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The first approvals, if they come, would likely be for 19b-4 filings, which are rule changes that allow spot bitcoin ETFs to list and trade on exchanges, he added.<\/span>","The SEC has yet to approve a spot bitcoin fund, although it has approved ETFs based on futures. The regulator declined to comment.&nbsp;","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Updated at 6:10 p.m. ET to include SEC declined to comment&nbsp;<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"90%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"earlier this week","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ETC Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jan. 10","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Grayscale Investments","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"40%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Indiana University","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"X.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Geraci","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tim Bevan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Eric Balchunas","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nov. 17","content":"DATE"},{"type":"James Seyffart","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BlackRock","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The ETF Store","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Vivian Fang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Fidelity","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"115%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg Intelligence","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"-0.056%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"6:10 p.m.","content":"TIME"},{"type":"$37,235","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Nathan Geraci","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"CoinGecko","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["SEC"],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}