{"summary":"Chris Akhavan joins the platform from the blockchain gaming startup Forte and the EA-acquired firm Glu Mobile. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/193083\/magic-eden-hires-its-first-chief-gaming-officer","publishDate":"2022-12-08T12:00:32","id":11380,"type":null,"title":"Magic Eden hires its first Chief Gaming Officer","category":["GAMING"],"content":["The Solana-based NFT platform Magic Eden has hired its first Chief Gaming Officer.&nbsp;","Chris Akhavan joins Magic Eden from Forte, a blockchain-based gaming firm that raised <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/124210\/blockchain-gaming-startup-forte-raises-725-million-series-b-funding\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$725 million<\/a> in Series B funding in 2021. Akhavan served as the firm's Chief Business Officer, in addition to working as the Chief Revenue Officer at the mobile gaming firm Glu Mobile — which was acquired by the video game development firm Electronic Arts in 2021 for $2.1 billion.&nbsp;","At Magic Eden, Akhavan will drive growth of the platform's gaming partnerships and support game development, creator and collector experiences.","\"I think you're gonna see a lot coming soon from us that that really hits on that core concept of adding value to the collector's experience and gamer's experience, and giving people a reason to eventually come to Magic Eden every single day — not just thinking of it as a transactional place, but as a hub for discovering great web3 content,\" Akhavan said in an interview with The Block.","Magic Eden added support for the Polygon Network on Nov. 22, 2022, a move that allows the platform to get in on the burgeoning gaming niche emerging on the blockchain, The Block previously reported.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$725 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Akhavan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"\" Akhavan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Polygon Network","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Forte","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Nov. 22, 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Glu Mobile","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Chris Akhavan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$2.1 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Magic Eden","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["MAGIC EDEN"],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}