{"summary":"In this episode, Alex Gladstein unpacks his new book, &#x27;Hidden Repression: How the IMF and World Bank Sell Exploitation as Development.&#x27;","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/231801\/alex-gladstein-hidden-repression","publishDate":"2023-05-23T10:00:06","id":11419,"type":null,"title":"Human rights activist Alex Gladstein on Bitcoin&#x27;s role in the global south","category":["PEOPLE"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 49<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 5 of The Scoop was recorded with <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro and Human Rights Foundation Chief Strategy Officer Alex Gladstein.<\/strong><\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a>,<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Please send feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"3a4a555e595b494e7a4e525f5856555951145955\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/i>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm\/?e=BLOCK9859826596\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Alex Gladstein is the Chief Strategy Officer for the Human Rights Foundation and a frequent contributor to Bitcoin Magazine.","In this episode, Gladstein talks through his newly released book, <em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Hidden Repression: How the IMF and World Bank Sell Exploitation as Development<\/em>.","According to Gladstein, Western prosperity has come mainly at the expense of developing nations:","\"We should be proud of the American Revolution and we should be proud of our Bill of Rights and we should be proud of democracy — it's definitely part of the reason why we're so successful — but another part of the reason is we've stolen wealth, labor, resources from poor countries for a long time now.\"","In contrast to neocolonial monetary policies which forced many developing nations into \"debt traps,\" Gladstein says bitcoin is a credible neutral alternative:","\"Think about all the digital money we use in the world today that's run by governments and corporations. [Bitcoin] is the only thing where the people have control over the monetary policy, at least in my view, and that's what makes it so interesting.\"","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">During this episode, Chaparro and Gladstein also discuss:<\/em>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsor <i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.cleanspark.com\/theblock\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CleanSpark<\/a>.<\/i><\/b><\/span>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About CleanSpark<\/strong>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CleanSpark (NASDAQ: CLSK) is America’s Bitcoin Miner™. Visit <a href=\"https:\/\/www.cleanspark.com\/theblock\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">cleanspark.com\/theblock<\/a> to learn more about the CleanSpark way.<\/span><\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"IMF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"American Revolution","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"America","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Gladstein","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Human Rights Foundation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"World Bank Sell Exploitation as Development","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitcoin Magazine","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alex Gladstein","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}