{"summary":"In this episode of The Scoop, BlockFi CEO Zac Prince gives a candid recount of the events surrounding his firm&#x27;s liquidation of Three Arrows Capital, as well as his personal philosophy regarding the relationship a crypto lender should have with its customers. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/166594\/blockfi-ceo-shares-lessons-learned-from-liquidating-3ac","publishDate":"2022-08-31T05:00:14","id":11476,"type":null,"title":"BlockFi CEO shares lessons learned from liquidating 3AC","category":["LENDING"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 81<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 4 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro<\/strong> and <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BlockFi Founder &amp; CEO Zac Prince<\/strong>.<\/i><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"fe8e919a9d9f8d8abe8a969b9c92919d959d8c878e8a91d09d9193\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i><\/span>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK3904371077\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Earlier this summer, the <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/152665\/ftx-deribit-bitmex-liquidated-three-arrows-capital\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">collapse<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> of Three Arrows Capital (3AC) sent the crypto lending world into chaos. Many lenders suffered<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> heavy losses due to 3AC exposure and some were forced into bankruptcy<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BlockFi — a prominent crypto lender that was valued at nearly $5 billion during the height of the bull market — was one of the firms that took a big hit when 3AC collapsed, prompting the company's shareholders to approve a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/155516\/blockfi-strikes-680-million-credit-deal-with-ftx-us-outlines-acquisition-path\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$680 million deal<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> with FTX US that outlines a path to a potential acquisition later next year.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In this episode of The Scoop, BlockFi CEO Zac Prince candidly recounted the events surrounding his firm's liquidation of Three Arrows Capital. He also explained his personal philosophy regarding the relationship that a crypto lender should have with its customers.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Prince expressed during the interview that he firmly believes that BlockFi's clients should be given priority consideration:<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"I have a very fundamental belief that in the type of business that Blockfi is, you can't screw over your clients and still have a business, period. That's not an option and that's not something that Blockfi is ever going to do on my watch.\"<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">When asked directly about Three Arrows Capital, Prince responded,<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"I also respect that these are still people and I hope that they're doing okay, but there's a whole mountain of legal and potentially civil and criminal things that they'll be dealing with in the foreseeable future.\"<\/span>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">During this episode, Chaparro and Prince also discuss:<\/span><\/i>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors <a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Tron<\/em><\/a>, <em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.chainalysis.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Chainalysis<\/a>&nbsp;&amp; <\/em><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.iwc.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC Schaffhausen<\/a><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em><\/b>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Tron<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nOn August 1st, 2022, Poloniex launched a faster and more stable trading system along with a <\/em><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">brand new user interface. Poloniex was founded in January 2014 as a global cryptocurrency trading platform. With its world-class service and security, it received funding in 2019 from renowned investors, including H.E. Justin Sun, Founder of TRON. Poloniex supports spot and margin trading as well as leveraged tokens. Its services are available to users in nearly 100 countries and regions with various languages available. For more information visit <a href=\"https:\/\/poloniex.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Poloniex.com<\/a>.<\/em><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/b>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Chainalysis<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nChainalysis is the leading blockchain data platform. We provide data, software, services, and research to government agencies, exchanges, financial institutions, and insurance and cybersecurity companies in over 60 countries. Backed by Accel, Addition, Benchmark, Coatue, Paradigm, Ribbit, and other leading firms in venture capital, Chainalysis builds trust in blockchains to promote more financial freedom with less risk. For more information, visit <a href=\"https:\/\/www.chainalysis.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">www.chainalysis.com<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About IWC Schaffhausen<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC Schaffhausen is a Swiss luxury watch manufacturer based in Schaffhausen, Switzerland. Known for its unique engineering approach to watchmaking, IWC combines the best of human craftsmanship and creativity with cutting-edge technology and processes. With collections like the Portugieser and the Pilot’s Watches, the brand covers the whole spectrum from elegant timepieces to sports watches. For more information, visit <a href=\"https:\/\/www.iwc.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC.com<\/a>.<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Switzerland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$5 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$680 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Coatue","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Chainalysis<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nChainalysis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Benchmark","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Three Arrows Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"IWC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Schaffhausen","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"IWC Schaffhausen<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC Schaffhausen","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"H.E. Justin Sun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Paradigm","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Zac Prince","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"January 2014","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chainalysis<\/a>&nbsp;&amp; <\/em><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.iwc.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC Schaffhausen","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Accel","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Blockfi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"August 1st, 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ribbit","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BlockFi Founder &amp; CEO Zac Prince","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"summer","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["BLOCKFI","CRYPTO","LENDING","THREE ARROWS CAPITAL"],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}