{"summary":"DeFi prime brokerage said FTX acted as the custodian for a majority of its ecosystem tokens.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/187372\/ftx-was-custodian-for-majority-of-tokens-on-defi-lending-platform-oxygen","publishDate":"2022-11-15T17:03:17","id":11490,"type":null,"title":"FTX was custodian for majority of tokens on DeFi lending platform Oxygen","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["DeFi prime brokerage Oxygen said FTX acted as the custodian for the majority of the tokens on its ecosystems, adding that it has sought legal help.","\"Whilst FTX Group did not hold any equity in the MAPS or Oxygen businesses, it did hold a significant proportion of MAPS\/OXY tokens,\" Oxygen said in a <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/Oxygen_protocol\/status\/1592609191960596480\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Twitter thread<\/a>. \"It also acted as custodian for over 95% of the overall supply of our ecosystem tokens — both locked and unlocked.\"","Oxygen is built on Solana and uses on-chain infrastructure called Serum. OXY refers to the governance token for the Oxygen prime brokerage protocol, while MAPS is the token used for the second version of offline mobile mapping app Maps.me, which announced an <a href=\"https:\/\/oxygenprotocol.medium.com\/partnerships-maps-me-4462628add85\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">integration <\/a>with Oxygen in 2021.&nbsp;","FTX's sister trading firm Alameda Research led a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/95912\/alameda-investment-defi-prime-brokerage\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$40m investment<\/a> in Oxygen in February 2021, with participation from Multicoin Capital, Genesis Capital and CMS.","Oxygen, which said it was \"shocked\" by the events surrounding FTX's bankruptcy proceedings.","\"We are considering all options on how to protect the MAPS &amp; OXY ecosystems and have retained legal advisors to assist with this ongoing process,\" Oxygen said.&nbsp;","Former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried told The Block in February 2021 that Oxygen was “a lot less white glove than traditional prime brokerage, that’s sort of how crypto is.\"","Maps.me made its last Twitter <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/maps_me?s=21&amp;t=15XGGIYu7Q5nW6mfaGUUuQ\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">post<\/a> on Oct. 3.","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"CMS","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Oct. 3","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"OXY","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Genesis Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"95%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Multicoin Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"February 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$40m","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Kristin Majcher","The Block"]}