{"summary":"Crypto exchange Zipmex has filed to extend its protection against creditors until next April amid a possible rescue deal. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/188323\/zipmex-files-to-extend-creditor-protection","publishDate":"2022-11-18T11:06:08","id":11504,"type":null,"title":"Zipmex files to extend creditor protection amid rescue deal reports","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["Crypto exchange Zipmex has filed to extend its protection against creditors until next April amid a possible rescue deal.&nbsp;","The Singapore-based exchange briefly <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/158672\/crypto-exchange-zipmex-halts-withdrawals-due-to-volatile-market-conditions\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">halted<\/a> withdrawals in June amid a liquidity crisis triggered by exposure to beleaguered crypto lenders Babel Finance and Celsius. In July, it <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/159982\/zipmex-files-for-protection-against-creditors-in-singapore\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filed<\/a> for protection against creditors in Singapore, and <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/163503\/zipmex-three-month-moratorium-extension\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">extended<\/a> it in August. Now, according to a <a href=\"https:\/\/zipmex.com\/announcements\/moratorium-update-gl-181122\/?utm_campaign=ZM_TH_1122_CrisisComms&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_content=Moratorium\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">statement<\/a> issued today, it's asking to extend the protection until next April 2.&nbsp;","Zipmex Group operates five entities — Zipmex, Zipmex Asia, Zipmex Thailand, Zipmex Indonesia and Zipmex Australia — all of which sought creditor protection from the Singapore High Court.","Since then, the exchange has courted potential investors to rescue it. On August 26, The Block <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/165937\/zipmex-in-advanced-rescue-talks-with-investment-firm-billionaires-son-source\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a> that Zipmex was in advanced talks with the son of Thai billionaire Prayudh Mahagitsiri and Thai investment firm Country Group Holdings. Mahagitsiri later <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/173338\/zipmex-potential-investor-asks-ceo-marcus-lim-to-forfeit-all-his-shares\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">asked<\/a> Zipmex CEO Marcus Lim to forfeit all his shares.&nbsp;","Earlier this month, the exchange was reportedly close to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/182116\/zipmex-close-to-signing-100-million-rescue-deal-in-return-for-a-90-stake\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">signing<\/a> a $100 million rescue package with existing investor V Ventures in return for a 90% stake. Today, CoinDesk <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/business\/2022\/11\/18\/crypto-exchange-zipmex-asks-for-creditor-protection-extension-with-takeover-talks-ongoing\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a> that Zipmex remains in talks with an investor for a takeover deal that may be completed as early as next week.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Prayudh Mahagitsiri","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"90%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Zipmex Australia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"April 2","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Marcus Lim","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$100 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Babel Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Zipmex Asia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Zipmex Indonesia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"CoinDesk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"August 26","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Singapore High Court","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Zipmex Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"June","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Zipmex Thailand","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Country Group Holdings","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Tom Matsuda","The Block"]}