{"summary":"The accused duo allegedly planned to break into the home in the middle of the night and force its residents to provide the code to a bitcoin private key.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/154382\/alleged-plan-to-steal-tens-of-millions-of-dollars-in-bitcoin","publishDate":"2022-06-27T23:05:25","id":11500,"type":null,"title":"Two charged for alleged plan to steal tens of millions of dollars in bitcoin from New York home","category":["LEGAL"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Last Thursday, two men were arrested in Virginia for their alleged plan to steal tens of millions of dollars in Bitcoin from a Westchester County home. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Between May 18 and May 24, 2020, the accused allegedly planned to break into the home in the middle of the night and force its residents to provide the code to a private key.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Dominic Pineda and Shon Morgan, the defendants, were indicted on Friday and charged with conspiracy to commit Hobbs Act robbery, which carries a maximum term of twenty years in prison.&nbsp;<\/span>","“As alleged in the indictment, the defendants participated in a violent plan to break into a family’s home in the middle of the night and force its residents to provide the code to what the defendants believed was tens of millions of dollars in Bitcoin currency,\" US Attorney Damian Williams said in a statement.","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.justice.gov\/usao-sdny\/pr\/two-men-charged-plan-commit-home-invasion-robbery-tens-millions-dollars-bitcoin\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The indictment<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> was unsealed on Friday in White Plains federal court, where the case will be handled.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Westchester County","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Virginia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"May 18","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"May 24, 2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"White Plains","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Damian Williams","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"night","content":"TIME"},{"type":"tens of millions of dollars","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Dominic Pineda","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Hobbs","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Shon Morgan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["CRIME"],"authors":["Sam Venis","The Block"]}