{"summary":"Attorney for one of the defendants in the FTX case had asked the court to delay the bankruptcy process until the discovery of how FTX became insolvent became clear.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/263231\/judge-denies-motion-by-ftx-lawyers-to-delay-the-bankruptcy-process-to-find-out-what-happened-to-ftx","publishDate":"2023-11-15T16:26:15","id":11532,"type":null,"title":"Judge denies motion by lawyers to delay the bankruptcy process to &#x27;find out what happened to FTX&#x27;","category":["BANKRUPTCY"],"content":["<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Correction:<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> A previous version of this story incorrectly stated that Lawrence Gebhardt was a lawyer representing FTX. He actually represents one of the defendants in the bankruptcy case who was involved in FTX’s business dealings. We also incorrectly mentioned a lawyer who is not involved in the case. We regret the errors.<\/span><\/i>","Attorney for Brandon Williams, one of the defendants in the case of the bankrupt crypto exchange FTX, <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">argued that to figure out how exactly FTX became insolvent, the Delaware bankruptcy court needs to delay the bankruptcy proceedings for \"a month or two months.\"&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Brandon Williams was a managing director at Cosima Capital who helped facilitating the acquisition of FTX Europe by FTX and is one of the defendants in the bankruptcy case. <\/span>Sam Bankman-Fried and FTX paid around $323.5 million for the acquisition of Swiss Company DAAG, which then became FTX Europe and for which FTX overpaid, FTX lawyers argue.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">On Wednesday, attorney Lawrence Gebhardt representing Williams asked the court to delay the process because the discovery of the circumstances of the case will be “expensive and requiring a lot of travel,” as important parties of the case are located in different parts of the world.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">For example, FTX former attorney Dan Friedberg, who is one of the defendants in the case, is based in Washington, another former counsel Can Sun is in the Bahamas and Sam Bankman-Fried, the former CEO recently <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/261240\/sam-bankman-fried-convicted-on-all-counts-report\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">convicted<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> of fraud, is in prison, Gebhardt said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“They all need to be deposed,” he said, explaining that back in November 2022, just days before the <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/185083\/ftx-files-for-chapter-11-bankruptcy\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">bankruptcy<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, FTX’s own attorneys from Sullivan and Cromwell <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.coinage.media\/s2\/why-sbf-thinks-sullivan-and-cromwell-sold-him-out\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said FTX was solvent<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. “We need to find out what happened in that year between November of 2021 and October of 2022 that caused FTX to become insolvent,” Genhardt said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In response<\/span>, attorneys for the bankruptcy estate<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> said that the defense had all the time it needed to join the discovery of facts and was notified about all the documents available for processing on September 21.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Asked by the Judge John Dorsey whether Gebhardt received the letter on Sept. 21, Gebhardt said “I don’t think I got it,” weirdly echoing the testimony Sam Bankman-Fried gave in the New York criminal court two weeks ago, in which he <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/260107\/inside-sbfs-trial-sam-wasnt-sure-nearly-one-hundred-and-fifty-times\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">could not recall<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> most of what the prosecutor asked him.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The judge denied the motion. “If the discovery is as complex as it is said to be, it needs to be started now, not delayed,” Dorsey said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">On November 2, former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried was <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/261240\/sam-bankman-fried-convicted-on-all-counts-report\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">convicted<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> of defrauding the customers, lenders, and investors of FTX as the exchange funneled its users and investors money to its affiliated trading firm Alameda Research. <\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"John Dorsey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Williams","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Delaware","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"October of 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Cosima Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Genhardt","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"November of 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$323.5 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"September 21","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Swiss Company DAAG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gebhardt","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Brandon Williams","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Dorsey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"November 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Washington","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"November 2","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Lawrence Gebhardt","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sullivan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Dan Friedberg","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sept. 21","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Cromwell","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bahamas","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Anna Baydakova","The Block"]}