{"summary":"Paystand, a U.S. blockchain-enabled B2B payments firm, bought Mexican accounts payable startup Yaydoo, Axios reported.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/160996\/b2b-blockchain-payments-firm-paystand-buys-mexicos-yaydoo-axios","publishDate":"2022-08-02T13:10:18","id":11605,"type":null,"title":"B2B blockchain payments firm Paystand buys Mexico&#x27;s Yaydoo: Axios","category":["MERGERS & ACQUISITIONS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Paystand, a US blockchain-enabled B2B payments firm, bought Mexican accounts payable startup Yaydoo,<\/span><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Axios<\/span><\/i><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> reported.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">No deal terms were disclosed. The companies did not immediately return requests for comment.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Paystand operates in the US and Canada, while Yaydoo is focused on Spanish-speaking Latin America, including Colombia, Peru and Chile. Combined, the companies serve 500,000 customers, and have processed more than $5 billion in payment volume.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The companies will continue to operate independently, but will cross-sell products.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In July 2021, Paystand <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/techcrunch.com\/2021\/07\/23\/paystand-banks-50m-to-make-b2b-payments-cashless-and-with-no-fees\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">raised $50 million<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in a Series C round, bringing its total funding to $85 million from NewView Capital, with participation from SoftBank’s SB Opportunity Fund and King River Capital, according to TechCrunch. Yaydoo <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/techcrunch.com\/2021\/08\/02\/yaydoo-secures-20m-aims-to-simplify-b2b-collections-payments\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">raised<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> a $20 million Series A round in August 2021 <\/span>co-led by Base10 Partners and monashees, alongside SoftBank’s Latin America Fund and Leap Global Partners.","&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Canada","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Peru","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Latin America","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"August 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$5 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$85 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"SoftBank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Paystand","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Leap Global Partners","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"King River Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Colombia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Chile","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$20 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"July 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"NewView Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$50 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Base10 Partners","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Christiana Loureiro","The Block"]}