{"summary":"A federal bankruptcy judge on Wednesday terminated FTX&#x27;s naming-rights deal with Miami-Dade county for the downtown arena where the NBA&#x27;s Miami Heat play, the Miami Herald reported.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/201244\/bankruptcy-judge-terminates-ftx-naming-rights-for-miami-heat-arena-miami-herald","publishDate":"2023-01-11T16:05:03","id":11618,"type":null,"title":"Bankruptcy judge terminates FTX naming rights for Miami Heat arena: Miami Herald","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["A federal bankruptcy judge on Wednesday terminated FTX's naming-rights deal with Miami-Dade county for the downtown arena where the NBA's Miami Heat play, the Miami Herald <a href=\"https:\/\/www.miamiherald.com\/sports\/nba\/miami-heat\/article271042867.html#featured-carousel-2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a>.","The order states that Miami-Dade county will stop using the FTX name immediately and plans to remove all signs from the arena, the paper said.","Officials in Miami-Dade County said <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/186209\/miami-to-yank-ftx-name-from-iconic-downtown-stadium\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">in November<\/a> that they would find a new naming rights partner and work to terminate business relationships with FTX after it filed for bankruptcy. Known as the FTX Arena since a $135 million naming rights deal was announced about two years ago, the complex sits in the heart of downtown Miami and also hosts non-basketball events.","Spokespersons for Miami-Dade county and the Miami Heat did not immediately respond to emailed requests for comment.","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"NBA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Miami","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"FTX Arena","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dade County","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$135 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Miami Herald","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Nathan Crooks","The Block"]}