{"summary":"Crypto prices remained mostly flat after the market opened on Tuesday, with Dogecoin rising by 8.1%. Bitcoin was trading around $23,100, down about 0.3%","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/207107\/crypto-prices-flat-while-dogecoin-rallies","publishDate":"2023-01-31T10:21:37","id":11643,"type":null,"title":"Crypto prices flat, while Dogecoin rallies","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Crypto prices remained mostly flat after the market opened on Tuesday, with Dogecoin rising significantly by 8.1%, outperforming the top 10 coins.","Bitcoin fell 0.3% to $23,117 around 9:50 a.m. EST, according to TradingView data.","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/chart\/q0HITX89\/?symbol=COINBASE%3ABTCUSD\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BTCUSD chart by TradingView<\/a>","Ether also declined 0.3% to around $1,583. BNB rose 1.1%, while Cardano's ADA fell 0.7%. Polygon's MATIC was up 1.7% in the past 24 hours after falling yesterday.","Dog-themed memecoins both rose, with Dogecoin and shiba inu up 8.1% and 0.5%, respectively.&nbsp;","Silvergate shares rose 4.5% to around $13 by 10:00 a.m., according to Nasdaq data, rising alongside most other crypto stocks.","Jack Dorsey's Block rose 2.2% to trade around $82, while MicroStrategy increased 2.5%. Coinbase was also up, rising by 1%.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"past 24 hours after falling yesterday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"8.1%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"TradingView","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"4.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$13","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$23,117","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"0.7%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"0.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"10:00 a.m.","content":"TIME"},{"type":"0.3%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$82","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Cardano","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"1.7%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Dogecoin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$1,583","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2.2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"1.1%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"9:50 a.m. EST","content":"TIME"},{"type":"Jack Dorsey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"ADA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MicroStrategy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nasdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["ANALYST REPORTS","BNB","COINBASE","CRYPTO BANKS AND LENDERS","DATA PROVIDERS","DOGECOIN","ECONOMIC INDICATORS","EQUITY MOVERS","ETHEREUM","SHIBA INU"],"authors":["Sam Venis","The Block"]}