{"summary":"Peter Marton, who led the New York State Department of Financial Services’ virtual currency unit, is leaving. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/252622\/new-york-state-regulators-virtual-currency-chief-peter-marton-to-depart","publishDate":"2023-09-22T12:15:38","id":11651,"type":null,"title":"New York state regulator&#x27;s virtual currency chief Peter Marton to depart","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Peter Marton, who led the New York State Department of Financial Services’ virtual currency unit, is leaving.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Marton had been the deputy superintendent of virtual currency at the state’s regulatory watchdog since December 2021, according to his <a href=\"https:\/\/www.linkedin.com\/in\/peter-marton-37180942\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">LinkedIn<\/a>. Before, he was a director of digital assets at the Promontory Financial Group, which is connected to IBM consulting.<\/span>","<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Pete Marton is an extraordinary talent and has been integral to the Department’s transformation of the Virtual Currency Unit over the last two years,\" NYDFS Superintendent Adrienne Harris said in an emailed statement.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Harris added that the department had added more than 60 virtual currency experts to its team, and said she is confident that the team will continue to deliver \"best-in-class results for New York.\"<\/span>","<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Attracting and developing top talent will always mean our staff are offered great new opportunities. We wish Pete all the success and happiness in his new future role,\" Harris said.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The department is looking to fill Marton's position by Oct. 9, according to a job <a href=\"https:\/\/www.dfs.ny.gov\/system\/files\/documents\/2023\/09\/dep_sup_vc_ns_ri_nyc_20231009.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">listing<\/span><\/a>.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">NYDFS has been particularly active in regulating crypto for years, having launched its BitLicense regime in 2015. <\/span><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A slew of firms have virtual currency licenses in the state including Coinbase, Circle Internet Financial and Robinhood Crypto, according to its <a href=\"https:\/\/www.dfs.ny.gov\/virtual_currency_businesses\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">site<\/span><\/a>, although some firms have <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/130119\/xapo-closes-shop-in-new-york-gives-up-bitlicense\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">closed<\/span><\/a> up shop in the state.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">On Monday, the regulator proposed bolstering its oversight of crypto firms looking to list coins in the state. Under the proposed guidance, crypto firms would h<\/span><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ave certain standards on how they assess risk, including fraud, price manipulation and whether there is enough liquidity to meet customer demand.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2015","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Robinhood Crypto","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Pete Marton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Promontory Financial Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Peter Marton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Harris","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Marton","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Marton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"last two years","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Oct. 9","content":"DATE"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"December 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Pete","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"IBM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Department","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Adrienne Harris","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Circle Internet Financial","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York State Department of Financial Services","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}