{"summary":"The price swing comes as Trump is set to be arraigned in the U.S. District Court for the Southern District of New York this afternoon.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/224819\/trump-nft-sales-arraignment","publishDate":"2023-04-04T12:08:21","id":11657,"type":null,"title":"Trump NFT sales jump 450% after ex-president’s arraignment; still a fraction of December peak","category":["LEGAL"],"content":["Sales of former President Donald Trump’s NFT collection jumped by 450% on Tuesday, after his arraignment in Manhattan.","Nearly $70,000 worth of the Trump-emblazoned <a href=\"https:\/\/collecttrumpcards.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">digital cards<\/a> changed hands in the last 24 hours, according to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.cryptoslam.io\/trumpdigitaltradingcards\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CryptoSlam data.<\/span><\/a><span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","The price swing came as Trump was arraigned in a Manhattan courtroom on Tuesday afternoon. The former president, who is running to reclaim his old job, was indicted by a grand jury last week likely over alleged hush money payments to porn actress Stormy Daniels.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","Still, the price spike is relatively small compared to the action just months ago. The former president’s 45,000-item NFT collection <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/195680\/donald-trump-nft-collection-sells-out-within-hours\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">sold out<\/span><\/a> within hours when it debuted in December, driving $3.53 million in sales. Sales <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/224229\/donald-trump-indictment-nft-trading-card-sales\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">jumped<\/span><\/a> 500% last week — hitting $50,000 — after the news broke that Trump had been indicted.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","For his part, Trump has said there was “no crime by Trump” in posts on his Truth Social social media platform. He derided the indictment as a “witch hunt.”<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","The various Trump NFT cards include illustrated portraits of the former president surrounded by gold bars, posing with a \"Trumpworld\" sign in the style of the \"Hollywood\" sign, as a superhero with lasers shooting out of his eyes, and as an astronaut.&nbsp;","<i data-stringify-type=\"italic\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Correction: This story has been updated to correct which court the arraignment is being held in.<\/i>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Trump NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"last 24 hours","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Trump","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Daniels","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$50,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$3.53 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"December","content":"DATE"},{"type":"500%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"450%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Donald Trump","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$70,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Trump","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Manhattan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Trump”","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"afternoon","content":"TIME"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Stephanie Murray","The Block"]}