{"summary":"The do-do-do-do-drop will take place at the end of August.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/165474\/fin-tech-baby-shark-creators-announce-second-nft-drop","publishDate":"2022-08-24T12:25:28","id":11675,"type":null,"title":"Fin Tech: Baby Shark creators announce second NFT drop","category":["NFTS"],"content":["Just when you thought it was safe to dive back into the metaverse, the makers of Baby Shark announced a second non-fungible token (NFT) collection based on the franchise. Doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo.","The show, which was made famous via a <a href=\"https:\/\/en.wikipedia.org\/wiki\/Baby_Shark\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">viral song<\/a> that is the most viewed video in YouTube history and will now reign in your head for the next week or so, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.prnewswire.com\/news-releases\/baby-sharks-second-nft-collection-is-set-to-launch-on-leading-nft-marketplace-makersplace-301611360.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a> on Wednesday that the collection's presale, available to a select and oh so lucky group of fans, will be available to mint at the end of August. It will then be open for public sale <span class=\"xn-chron\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sept. 1.&nbsp;<\/span>","The first Baby Shark NFT drop in December made a splash, selling out in an instant, according to The Pinkfong Company, which is behind the phenomenon that has become the theme song of parental nightmares.","It will be comprised of 10,000 computer generated images featuring Baby Shark and his family: Baby Shark, Mommy Shark, Daddy Shark, Grandma Shark and Grandpa Shark, released in three parts.&nbsp;","NFT holders will be able to customize and\/or mint new items and be given eligibility for exclusive airdrops and entry into raffles for prizes like tickets to Baby Shark events, merchandise and custom digital content. Collectors will also have priority access to limited goods and immersive experiences both online and offline.","NFT marketplace MakersPlace will play host to the drop.&nbsp;","Baby Shark is not the first kids-focused project to stray into the metaverse and try to build out a web3 presence. The YouTube hit CoComelon, which is known for nursery rhymes, also said it would mint NFTs on the Flow blockchain via Zigazoo, a social media network for children. Zigazoo <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/154486\/social-media-network-for-kids-raises-17-million-for-web3-projects\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced in June<\/a> it had raised $17 million in a Series A fundraise led by Liberty City Ventures to develop its web3 offerings.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Mommy Shark","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Daddy Shark","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sept. 1","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Grandma Shark","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"December","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Grandpa Shark","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Liberty City Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"June","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Shark NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Pinkfong Company","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$17 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Baby Shark","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Baby Shark","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Lucy Harley-McKeown","The Block"]}