{"summary":"Crypto exchange Bitget has started operations in Brazil.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/187661\/bitget-starts-operations-in-brazil-infomoney","publishDate":"2022-11-16T13:54:23","id":11725,"type":null,"title":"Bitget starts operations in Brazil: InfoMoney","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["Singapore-based crypto exchange Bitget has started operating in Brazil, financial publication InfoMoney <a href=\"https:\/\/www.infomoney.com.br\/mercados\/bitget-corretora-cripto-do-messi-chega-oficialmente-ao-brasil-e-libera-pix\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a>.&nbsp;","Bitget will start enabling deposits in Brazilian reais today, InfoMoney said. The exchange will accept deposits through Brazil's popular public instant payment system, Pix. It plans to start offering withdrawals in Brazil on Nov. 30.","The exchange will not offer derivatives products in Brazil, as the country's securities and exchange commission (CVM) requires special licenses for those services.&nbsp;","Bitget currently operates in Argentina, Colombia, Mexico and Venezuela, InfoMoney reported. The company says it has more than 2 million users in 50 countries. The exchange <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/185565\/crypto-exchange-bitget-to-increase-headcount-25-by-year-end-despite-market-conditions\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">plans<\/a> to increase its headcount to 1,000 employees by the end of the year, despite volatile market conditions.&nbsp;","&nbsp;","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Venezuela","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Brazil","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Mexico","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Argentina","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Colombia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Pix","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Nov. 30","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"CVM","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Kristin Majcher","The Block"]}