{"summary":"The Block recaps Biden administration&#x27;s wide array of crypto and digital asset-related reports. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/170770\/here-are-all-of-the-biden-administrations-crypto-reports","publishDate":"2022-09-16T14:17:49","id":11744,"type":null,"title":"Here are all of the Biden administration&#x27;s crypto reports","category":["POLICY"],"content":["A trio of reports released Friday morning by the Biden administration represent a key step in the federal government's efforts to lay out a comprehensive approach for American crypto policy and oversight.&nbsp;","As of today, some eight publications, including the three from the Treasury, have been published since Biden's executive order. The White House characterized President Joe Biden's <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/136888\/bidens-executive-order-on-digital-assets-drops-in-four-hours-but-we-have-it-early?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">March executive order<\/a> as \"outlining the first ever, whole-of-government approach to addressing the risks and harnessing the potential benefits of digital assets and their underlying technology.\"","The Biden administration's reports are linked below, with summaries of each report. You can also read The Block's coverage of a call from the Treasury Department to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/170620\/treasury-recommends-double-down-on-crypto-enforcement-but-with-more-guidance\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"double down\"<\/a> on regulation, take <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/170664\/biden-administration-takes-a-step-closer-towards-a-digital-dollar\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">another step towards a digital dollar<\/a>, and of the one report that's still pending: recommendations on <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/170629\/fsoc\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">how to plug regulatory gaps<\/a> from the Financial Stability Oversight Council.&nbsp;","&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"morning","content":"TIME"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Joe Biden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Biden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"American crypto","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"White House","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Treasury Department","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Financial Stability Oversight Council","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Michael McSweeney","The Block"]}