{"summary":"","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/43844\/agatha-bacelar-2020-congressional-candidate-on-the-scoop","publishDate":"2019-10-31T16:30:53","id":11749,"type":null,"title":"The Scoop sits down with 2020 Congressional candidate and blockchain enthusiast Agatha Bacelar","category":["PODCASTS"],"content":["<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Presenting episode 26 of <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/the-scoop-podcast\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Scoop<\/a>, The Block’s flagship podcast. Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on <a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/a>, or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection#35455a515654464175415d5057595a565e56474c45415a1b565a58\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"87f7e8e3e4e6f4f3c7f3efe2e5ebe8e4ece4f5fef7f3e8a9e4e8ea\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/span><\/a>.<\/em>","Agatha Bacelar is a 27-year-old Brazilian-American running for Congress in California’s 12th District, a seat currently held by House Speaker Nancy Pelosi. Bacelar is not your typical Congressional candidate. With a degree from Stanford University and a professional background in blockchain, Bacelar is aiming to make tech regulation an important conversation in politics. In this conversation she discusses how she got into politics, her time working at Democracy Earth, her stance on universal basic income, and why now is the time to run against the most powerful Democrat in the country. I hope you enjoy the episode.","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK4285663690\" width=\"100%\" height=\"200\" frameborder=\"0\" scrolling=\"no\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>"],"entity":[{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"California","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bacelar","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Congress","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Agatha Bacelar","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nancy Pelosi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Stanford University","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"House","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}