{"summary":"Amber Group reduced its expectations to seek $100 million in additional funding from investors at a lower, $3 billion valuation.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/183368\/amber-group-reduces-valuation-seeks-additional-100-million-bloomberg","publishDate":"2022-11-04T18:19:37","id":11799,"type":null,"title":"Amber Group reduces valuation, seeks additional $100 million: Bloomberg","category":["INVESTMENTS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto trading platform Amber Group lowered its valuation to the $3 billion at which it previously raised, as the company seeks an additional $100 million from investors.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Tumultuous market conditions caused crypto trading platform Amber Group to reduce its valuation as the company pursues a new funding round.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Amber Group now seeks $100 million at the same $3 billion valuation it previously raised, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2022-11-04\/crypto-firm-amber-group-seeks-100-million-funds-at-flat-valuation#xj4y7vzkg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bloomberg<\/a> first reported, citing anonymous sources. The company in February was valued at $3 billion as it <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/134947\/crypto-platform-amber-group-hits-3-billion-valuation-in-latest-raise\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">raised<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> $200 million, led by wealth fund Temasek, and joined by Sequoia China, Pantera Capital, Tiger Global Management, True Arrow Partners and Coinbase Ventures.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Amber <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/145431\/amber-group-is-raising-again-after-securing-200-million-in-february\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">attempted<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to raise again at a much higher valuation between $5 billion-$8 billion, but given a general slump in the crypto market, those funds never materialized.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The adjustments for Amber extend beyond fundraising efforts. Amber recently <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/169008\/amber-group-cuts-10-of-staff\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">cut<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> as many as 10% of its staff citing the bear market.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Cautious even with a 25% climb in revenue, the company’s head of business development, Annabelle Huang, previously <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/171734\/amber-to-remain-prudent-in-crypto-winter-as-revenue-climbs\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">told<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> The Block that the company will be prudent while bearish conditions persist.<\/span>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/crypto-markets\/prices\/crypto-total-marketcap\/embed\" title=\"Crypto Total Marketcap\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Markets slumped after a peak just over $3 trillion in November 2021, data from The Block Research show. <\/span>","<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Annabelle Huang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$3 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Sequoia China","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Amber Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$100 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"The Block Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"True Arrow Partners","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$5 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"10%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"February","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Temasek","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Amber","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Pantera Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tiger Global Management","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"25%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$3 trillion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Coinbase Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$200 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"November 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$8 billion","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Jeremy Nation","The Block"]}