{"summary":"From multi-platinum artist to cryptocurrency entrepreneur, the mononymous Akon has chased lofty ambitions. On this episode of The Scoop, project co-founders Akon and Jon Karas defend the project&#x27;s viability.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/63607\/a-conversation-with-akon-the-multi-platinum-artist-working-on-a-crypto-to-bring-change-to-africa","publishDate":"2020-05-01T13:19:50","id":11795,"type":null,"title":"A conversation with Akon, the multi-platinum artist working on a crypto to bring change to Africa","category":["THE BLOCK"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 16 of Season 2 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with Frank Chaparro, Ryan Todd, and Akcoin co-founders Akon and Jon Karas.<\/i>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/a>, or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to&nbsp;<a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection#bcccd3d8dfddcfc8fcc8d4d9ded0d3dfd7dfcec5ccc8d392dfd3d1\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"6818070c0b091b1c281c000d0a04070b030b1a11181c07460b0705\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/span><\/a>.<\/em>","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK4004053018\" width=\"100%\" height=\"200\" frameborder=\"0\" scrolling=\"no\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","From multi-platinum performing artist to crypto-entrepreneur, the mononymous Akon has long chased lofty ambitions.","The Senegal-native's Akoin project is the singer's latest lofty endeavor. The aptly-named cryptocurrency was founded to democratize financial-services in Africa, where traditional banking infrastructure is scarce. Indeed, the project harkens back to the ICO boom of 2017 when celebrities made headlines in the mainstream press for promoting a digital currency fundraise – drawing the attention and occasional ire of regulators.","In this episode of The Scoop, Akon – the chief visionary of Akoin – and Akoin president Jon Karas join The Block's Frank Chaparro and Ryan Todd to defend the project's viability. Akon and Jon position Akoin not as the answer to the financial inefficiencies of the world but as a last-mile solution to financially unify a continent long hindered by corruption and monetary instability.","In this episode, we also discuss:&nbsp;","&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Akon","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ryan Todd","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Senegal","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Akon","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jon position Akoin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Akoin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Africa","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Akcoin","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jon Karas","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","Ryan Todd","The Block"]}