{"summary":"Sam Bankman-Fried&#x27;s lawyers ask for names to be hidden of two co-signers citing harassment concerns. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/198939\/bankman-fried-asks-for-250-million-bond-co-signers-to-remain-anonymous","publishDate":"2023-01-03T14:19:27","id":11804,"type":null,"title":"Bankman-Fried asks for co-signers of $250 million bond to remain anonymous","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sam Bankman-Fried's lawyers asked for the identities of two guarantors of his $250 million bond to be redacted and not be publicly disclosed, citing concerns of threats and harassment. <\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Mark Cohen and Christian Everdell of law firm Cohen &amp; Gresser LLP, who are representing the former FTX CEO, made that request on Tuesday in a letter to <\/span><span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">U.S. Judge Lewis Kaplan.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“In recent weeks, Mr. Bankman-Fried’s parents have become the target of intense media scrutiny, harassment, and threats,” Everdell and Cohen said in the court document. “Among other things, Mr. Bankman-Fried’s parents have received a steady stream of threatening correspondence, including communications expressing a desire that they suffer physical harm.”<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">They said there is a “serious cause for concern that the two additional sureties would face similar intrusions on their privacy as well as threats and harassment if their names appear unredacted on their bonds or their identities are otherwise publicly disclosed.”<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kaplan granted that request during Bankman-Fried's arraignment this afternoon, according to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.wsj.com\/articles\/sam-bankman-fried-pleads-not-guilty-to-fraud-and-other-offenses-11672774004?mod=markets_lead_pos3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Wall Street Journal<\/a>, though federal judge acknowledged that media organizations could challenge the ruling. The former crypto mogul pleaded not guilty during his court appearance. Bankman-Fried's trial is now scheduled to begin Oct. 2, according to reports.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The cryptocurrency exchange failed spectacularly in November, and subsequently filed for bankruptcy protection. In addition to criminal charges related to the operations of FTX and the multinational group of companies that Bankman-Fried owned, he also faces civil charges from the Securities and Exchange Commission and Commodity Futures Trading Commission. The disgraced crypto mogul was released last month on the $250 million bond, which was secured in part by the equity in his family home and by the signatures of his parents, as well as the two anonymous co-signers, who are on the hook for that money if he flees.&nbsp;<\/span>","<i data-stringify-type=\"italic\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Updated with Judge Kaplan's granting of anonymity to the additional co-signers of Bankman-Fried's bail bond and with the tentative trial date.&nbsp;<\/i>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"this afternoon","content":"TIME"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$250 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Oct. 2","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Kaplan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Fried","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cohen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission and Commodity Futures Trading Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Everdell","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Christian Everdell","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Cohen &amp; Gresser LLP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mark Cohen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Lewis Kaplan","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["SAM BANKMAN-FRIED"],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}