{"summary":"Financial officials said today at the Hong Kong Fintech Week that regulators may soon issue circulars on tokenization to ensure customer protection.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/260611\/hong-kong-plans-to-target-tokenization-with-new-regulatory-requirements-officials-say","publishDate":"2023-11-01T23:57:13","id":11815,"type":null,"title":"Hong Kong plans to target tokenization with new regulatory requirements, officials say","category":["REGULATION"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Hong Kong is expected to issue more policy papers and circulars on tokenized assets, stablecoins and cryptocurrency trading, as the city continues efforts to create a web3 hub in Asia.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Christopher Hui, Secretary for Hong Kong’s Financial Services and the Treasury, said today at Hong Kong Fintech Week that the government continues to encourage web3 innovation and the <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/252265\/hong-kong-blocks-access-to-jpexs-website-and-app-amid-probes\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">recent crackdowns on the JPEX crypto exchange<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> have not damaged its resolve.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We have been asked many times whether JPEX will affect our determination to grow the web3 market,” Hui said. “The answer is a clear no.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Hui added that the <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Securities and Futures Commission will soon release circulars on intermediaries engaging in tokenized securities-related activities and tokenization of SFC-authorized investment products.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Another area the regulators are focusing on is exploring how to expand their remit to cover buying and selling of virtual assets beyond trades taking place on trading platforms, according to Hui.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Meanwhile, the Hong Kong Monetary Authority and the Financial Services and the Treasury Bureau will soon issue another joint consultation on the regulatory regime for stablecoin issuers, Hui added.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Eddie Yue, chief executive of the HKMA, said today at the event that use cases such as tokenized bonds have already gone beyond the proof of concept stage and have been adopted in real transactions.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“In fact, we, ourselves, assisted the government to issue the world's first-ever tokenized government green bond earlier this year in order to demonstrate the compatibility of Hong Kong's legal and regulatory environment with this very new issuance format,” Yue said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Yue added that the government is already discussing with the industry “to explore the next tokenized issuance in order to open up new possibilities.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Moving forward, we can expect a rise in the tokenization of differences in order to support the gradual adoption of tokenization,” Yue said. “I will also expect that there will be increased use of blockchain-based payment methods, including things like stablecoin wallets or tokenized deposits offered by the banks.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Julia Leung, chief executive officer of the SFC, also said that the regulator plans to issue two circulars about tokenization later today.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">One circular will be on “identifying the risks with this new technology” and “what regulators expect from intermediaries when they are doing the due diligence, doing their transfer or primary issuance of it,” Leung said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Leung added that another pending circular will focus on the SFC’s requirements for issuing authorized funds. “There will be additional safeguards — all the expectations that we have on it.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“It is all about making sure that the assets are being safely custody transferred and the ownership records are there because this is, after all, a new technology,” Leung said.<\/span>","\"While we are supportive of the industry, experimenting, making more of these use cases, we also see new risks associated with it in the innovative technology, particularly in the transfer, the ownership and the recordkeeping of these tokens.\"","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Julia Leung","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Securities and Futures Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hong Kong Monetary Authority","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SFC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Hong Kong’s Financial Services","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"today","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Yue","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Eddie Yue","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Asia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Financial Services","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hui","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Treasury Bureau","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Leung","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Christopher Hui","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"HKMA","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["ASIAN REGULATION","CRYPTO","TRADFI BANKS"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}