{"summary":"Hal Finney’s Twitter, an important part of Bitcoin’s history and culture, is seeing new activity carried out by his wife Fran to ensure the account doesn’t get deleted.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/195873\/hal-finneys-twitter-account-sees-new-activity-in-attempt-to-preserve-a-piece-of-bitcoins-culture","publishDate":"2022-12-16T17:53:13","id":11811,"type":null,"title":"Hal Finney’s Twitter account sees new activity in attempt to preserve a piece of bitcoin’s culture","category":["PEOPLE"],"content":["Hal Finney’s Twitter account, an important part of bitcoin culture and its community, is seeing new activity to avoid being deleted from the platform.","Finney died in 2014, and his dormant account has been a part of bitcoin’s early history many have fought to keep alive.","The activity on Finney’s account was flagged <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/lopp\/status\/1603845036201938965?s=20&amp;t=zzgMPyTOtEp3BWV0U1JVVA\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">in a tweet<\/a> by prominent bitcoin advocate and Casa CEO Jameson Lopp, who was unsure if the account had been compromised. Finney’s widow, Fran, <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/halfin\/status\/1603847718039744512?s=20&amp;t=zzgMPyTOtEp3BWV0U1JVVA\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">confirmed<\/a> she began tweeting from the account to prevent its deletion.","Twitter CEO Elon Musk tweeted last week the platform would soon start deleting around <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/elonmusk\/status\/1601124608282742785?s=20&amp;t=i1Q7IBUS8KagAjr1bC-ixA\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">1.5 billion inactive accounts.<\/a>","\"If @halfin (Hal Finney’s twitter) is automatically deleted in some blanket-rule sweep, it will be extremely sad. Lots of history will be lost with this rule,” <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/cobie\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweeted<\/a> UpOnly podcast host Cobie.","This isn’t the first time Finney’s account has faced possible deletion. In 2019, former Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey made an <a href=\"https:\/\/decrypt.co\/12534\/why-twitters-purge-of-old-accounts-is-bad-for-bitcoin\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">exception<\/a> for Finney’s account when Twitter began removing accounts that were inactive for more than six months.","Finney is a <a href=\"https:\/\/decrypt.co\/12534\/why-twitters-purge-of-old-accounts-is-bad-for-bitcoin\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">notable person<\/a> in the bitcoin community for being the first to receive a bitcoin transaction from Satoshi Nakamoto, the cryptocurrency’s pseudonymous creator.","Finney also identified early on two of the biggest challenges, which have now come to fruition, bitcoin would face during its lifespan, <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/twobitidiot\/status\/1601232210287218688\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweeted<\/a> Messari founder Ryan Selkis. These challenges he predicted were adding more <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/96232\/congress-crypto-anonymity-domestic-terrorist-financing-hearing\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">anonymity<\/a> to bitcoin, and <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/172842\/bitcoin-mining-represents-0-1-of-global-greenhouse-gas-emissions-study-finds\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reducing its CO2 emissions.&nbsp;<\/a>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2014","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Finney","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Elon Musk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Satoshi Nakamoto","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jameson Lopp","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Hal Finney","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Finney","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Casa","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ryan Selkis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jack Dorsey","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Mike Truppa","The Block"]}