{"summary":"Cryptocurrency exchange Huobi will shut down its operations in Thailand after it was delisted as a licensed digital trading platform.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/152427\/crypto-exchange-huobi-to-close-down-its-thai-unit-after-regulatory-problems","publishDate":"2022-06-16T08:43:27","id":11824,"type":null,"title":"Crypto exchange Huobi to close down its Thai unit after regulatory problems","category":["ASIA"],"content":["Cryptocurrency exchange Huobi will close down its operation in Thailand after it was delisted as a licensed digital trading platform by local regulatory authorities.&nbsp;","According to<a href=\"https:\/\/www.huobi.co.th\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> a statement<\/a> released by the Thai arm of Huobi, it will permanently shut down its platform on July 1. Huobi is an exchange initially founded in China that allows its users to trade digital assets including BTC and ETH.&nbsp;","Its operations had already been suspended in another ruling by SEC Thailand <a href=\"https:\/\/www.sec.or.th\/TH\/Pages\/News_Detail.aspx?SECID=9474&amp;NewsNo=97&amp;NewsYear=2565&amp;Lang=TH\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">in September<\/a> and it had since urged clients to withdraw their assets from the platform. The company said there are still assets on the platform.&nbsp;","“We have been trying our best efforts to contact all customers to withdraw assets,” Huobi said. “However, there is still an amount of out of reach customers which we couldn't contact with.\"&nbsp;","Huobi's struggle with regulators stands in contrast to some competitors. After some initial problems with regulators in Europe, competitor Binance was recently approved <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/149278\/binance-italy-wins-approval-to-operate-as-crypto-service-provider\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">in Italy<\/a> and <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/145117\/france-approves-binance-to-operate-digital-asset-trading-services\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">France.<\/a> Earlier this month,<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/150055\/ftx-launches-licensed-crypto-exchange-service-in-japan\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> FTX launched a licensed trading platform<\/a> in Japan.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"France","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Japan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Huobi","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thailand","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Italy","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"July 1","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Huobi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"China","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["HTX"],"authors":["Tom Matsuda","The Block"]}