{"summary":"ConsenSys has raised $200 million from investors including Coinbase, HSBC and Marshall Wace, tipping its valuation to over $3.2 billion.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/124615\/consensys-raise","publishDate":"2021-11-17T10:07:46","id":1185,"type":null,"title":"ConsenSys closes $200 million raise at $3.2 billion valuation","category":["WEB3"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ConsenSys, a New York-based company that develops and invests in projects built on the Ethereum blockchain, has raised $200 million, tipping its valuation to over $3.2 billion, according to an announcement. Its investors include HSBC, Coinbase Ventures and Marshall Wace. ParaFi and Thirdpoint also invested in the raise.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Last month, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.ft.com\/content\/1773d1ed-0df0-46c1-9732-223c4012bc48\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Financial Times<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;reported that the company was raising funds in a round that would value it $3 billion, some six months after raising a $65 million fund from Mastercard and JPMorgan in April.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ConsenSys is known for its plethora of blockchain products, including developer tool Infura and wallet browser extension MetaMask. Both have seen rapid growth in the past year with Infura <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/business\/2021\/11\/10\/consensys-tool-infura-user-numbers-grow-250-in-under-a-year\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">growing 250% from 100k to 350k users<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> and Metamask’s monthly user base numbering 21 million.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“ConsenSys has been at the heart of Web3 and developing products for [users] from literally day zero,” said Lex Sokolin global fintech co-head and head economist at Consensys.&nbsp;<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“I mean, more so than anyone. This is an ecosystem that we have largely seeded and built. And now we're in the process of helping people scale it out.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Hinting at the company’s post-funding plans, CEO and co-founder Joseph Lubin recently floated <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/cryptoslate.com\/consensys-co-founder-tantalizes-the-possibility-of-a-metamask-token\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">the prospect of a MetaMask native token<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> —&nbsp;a plan that Sokolin was unable to confirm or deny. He added, however, that it was very exciting to him that the community was so enthused about tokens across ConsenSys’ product range.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">According to a statement released on Wednesday, the company plans to use the $200 million to enhance its presence in Asia.&nbsp;Marshall Wace partner Amit Rajpal, who oversees the hedge fund's operations in Asia, led its investment in ConsenSys.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ConsenSys is supporting ten CBDC projects worldwide with six in the Asia Pacific region, notably in Hong Kong, South Korea and Singapore.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“When a company like Marshall Wace talks about Asian expansion, I think the signal is probably deeper engagement with [Asian] regulators, institutional partners, institutional asset managers and financial players to provide access to retail and institutional users for ConsenSys,” said Sokolin.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Aside from its Asian plans, the company will further focus on driving mainstream adoption of NFTs and will hire 400 new people.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The new hires come after previous employee culls. In February 2020, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/btcmanager.com\/consensys-fires-14-staff-organizational-shakeup\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">the company fired 20% of its staff<\/span><\/a>&nbsp;to make it more attractive to outside investors. P<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">revious restructuring efforts <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/thenextweb.com\/news\/consensys-blockchain-layoffs\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">occurred in 2018.<\/span><\/a>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">According to <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/business\/2021\/11\/02\/consensys-shareholders-readying-legal-action-over-share-valuation\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Coindesk,<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> a group of these former employees and shareholders are currently readying legal action over improperly valued assets during a transfer between ConsenSys Inc and ConsenSys AG —&nbsp;its investment arm also known as Mesh.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We believe that these shareholders are confused on a number of key factual points,” a ConsenSys spokesperson told Coindesk.&nbsp;<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We have been working to share information with them that we think will further clarify the record and give them a greater understanding of matters they do not yet accurately understand.”<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"HSBC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"South Korea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$3 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Lex Sokolin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"20%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"fintech","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Asia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"ConsenSys Inc","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"February 2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$200 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Amit Rajpal","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$3.2 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$65 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Mastercard","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"ConsenSys AG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Marshall Wace","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Joseph Lubin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"250%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Coinbase Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coindesk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Financial Times","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Asia Pacific","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sokolin","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["ETHEREUM"],"authors":["Tom Matsuda","The Block"]}