{"summary":"Crypto exchange Coinbase is strengthening leadership positions in Europe despite turbulent market conditions.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/190213\/coinbase-strengthens-european-arm-with-new-hires","publishDate":"2022-11-28T05:20:06","id":11855,"type":null,"title":"Coinbase strengthens European arm with new hires: Bloomberg","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto exchange Coinbase is reinforcing its European senior positions with a series of new hires and promotions, Bloomberg <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2022-11-28\/coinbase-coin-names-four-new-executives-to-lead-emea-expansion-efforts\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reports<\/a>.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto.com’s former general manager has come on board as country director for Ireland. The new director of controls in Germany is Michael Schroeder, leaving behind his position at smaller crypto exchange Bittrex as chief compliance and risk officer. In the UK, Elke Karskens is moving from senior director of marketing to regional director.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The new hires come after, one week ago, Coinbase shares <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/188833\/coinbase-shares-hit-all-time-low-monday-as-centralized-exchanges-deal-with-ftx-fallout\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">hit<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> an all-time low. Earlier in November, Coinbase <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/185626\/coinbase-layoffs-more-than-60-recruiting-onboarding-employees\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that the company was laying off more than 60 employees. The exchange’s chief product officer, Surojit Chatterjee, will also be stepping down effectively at the end of the month following reorganization.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"UK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Michael Schroeder","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Germany","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Surojit Chatterjee","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ireland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Elke Karskens","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["COINBASE"],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}