{"summary":"The crypto community is stepping up to help victims of the tragic natural disaster in Turkey by opening a multisig wallet on BNB Chain.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/209269\/turkish-rock-star-and-charity-establish-crypto-donation-wallet-for-earthquake-support","publishDate":"2023-02-07T07:59:10","id":1186,"type":null,"title":"Turkish rock star and charity establish crypto donation wallet for earthquake support","category":["PEOPLE"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The crypto community is stepping up to help victims of the tragic natural disaster in Turkey by opening a multisig wallet on BNB Chain for earthquake support. So far, over $170,000 in donations have been <a href=\"https:\/\/bscscan.com\/address\/0xB67705398fEd380a1CE02e77095fed64f8aCe463\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">made<\/a>, predominantly in the stablecoin BUSD.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Turkish rock star Haluk Levent <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/haluklevent\/status\/1622770388286439425\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">asked<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> his 6.7 million Twitter followers if he should open a crypto account for people to deposit donations to the non-governmental and non-profit organization Ahbap, also known as the Dude Association. 82.9% of those responding to the poll selected “open a crypto account, bro.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Co-founder of web3 analytics platform Lytera, Baki Er, jumped on the idea, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/LibraryDefi\/status\/1622918592617500672\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">calling<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> it “the moment we’ve all been waiting for,” referring to Ahbap as the “most trusted charity in Turkey” and encouraging the community to donate to the multisig.&nbsp;<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Famous digital artist Murat Pak also offered to help the cause, explaining he was trying to put together an NFT campaign for Turkey and Ahbap.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The tragic 7.5 magnitude <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">earthquake<\/span>&nbsp;—<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;the worst Turkey has witnessed since 1939 — has also affected Syria, Cyprus, Jordan, Lebanon, Iraq, Georgia and Armenia, with over 5,000 dead.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Armenia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Turkey","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Jordan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Lebanon","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Haluk Levent","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"82.9%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Georgia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Baki Er","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Cyprus","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Murat Pak","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1939","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Syria","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$170,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Dude Association","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Iraq","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["BNB CHAIN","BUSD","DECENTRALIZED INFRASTRUCTURE","WALLETS"],"authors":["James Hunt","The Block"]}