{"summary":"CNBC&#x27;s loudest financial advisor appears frustrated by the current investment landscape and thinks bitcoin is of no interest.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/255712\/jim-cramer-thinks-mr-bitcoin-is-about-to-go-down-big","publishDate":"2023-10-10T13:17:54","id":11868,"type":null,"title":"Jim Cramer thinks &#x27;Mr. Bitcoin is about to go down big&#x27;","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["Reliably excitable, and oftentimes drastically wrong, TV personality and financial advisor Jim Cramer waxed negative on Tuesday when brainstorming potential investment opportunities.&nbsp;","After rebuffing gold, Cramer turned his attention to bitcoin as a possible alternative place to invest some money.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"I can't be in something where Mr. <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitcoin <\/span><span class=\"articleTooltip\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"\/price\/248348\/bitcoin-btc-usd\" class=\"articleTooltip__link\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"><img src=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2023\/10\/bitcoin.png\" alt=\"\" title=\"\" class=\"articleTooltip__tokenImage\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">BTC<\/span> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText articleTooltip__tokenText_price articleTooltip__tokenText_negative\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">\n      -0.056%\n    <\/span><\/a> <!----><\/span><\/span> is about to go down big,\" he said during CNBC's \"Squawk on the Street.\"<\/span>","It wasn't clear if Cramer's comments about \"Mr. Bitcoin\" could have been a reference to Sam Bankman-Fried's criminal trial happening right now in New York, but either way, the TV host is bearish on the bitcoin's prospects.","After his bitcoin comments, Cramer segued into a mini-rant on billionaires, Vladimir Lenin and Leon Trotsky. He also talked about how the current era is \"perilous,\" while explaining how his job is to go on television and try and give people advice on how to invest their money, even if options seem limited.","The one-time Goldman Sachs employee has traditionally been bearish on crypto, especially given regulatory scrutiny in the United States. Meanwhile, bitcoin <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/255525\/bitcoin-braces-for-fresh-volatility-amidst-geopolitical-uncertainty\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">is expected<\/a> to remain volatile throughout this month.","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/255272\/bitcoin-maintains-support-level-above-27000-as-long-term-holders-step-in\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitcoin's<\/a> price is maintaining a support level north of $27,000 thanks to a dynamic between short and long-term holders.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Vladimir Lenin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"CNBC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cramer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"-0.056%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Goldman Sachs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Leon Trotsky","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"United States","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Jim Cramer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$27,000","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}