{"summary":"Charting the course of blockchain’s future, the TRON Builder Tour blends hands-on workshops with dynamic discussions, celebrating successes and sparking anticipation for what lies ahead.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/247554\/tron-builder-tour-highlights-onward-to-stanford-princeton-and-barcelona","publishDate":"2023-08-28T09:01:02","id":11878,"type":null,"title":"TRON Builder Tour Highlights: Onward to Stanford, Princeton, and Barcelona","category":["SPONSORED"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Charting the course of blockchain’s future, the <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TRON Builder Tour<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> blends hands-on workshops with dynamic discussions, celebrating successes and sparking anticipation for what lies ahead.<\/span>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Reflecting on Successful Stops<\/b>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">New York City<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">: At Rooftop93 on July 16th, 2023, TRON Builder Tour participants enjoyed an interactive workshop, with some even launching a utility token on TRON's testnet. The buzz around <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/hackatron\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">HackaTRON Season 5<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> (S5) was palpable.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Los Angeles<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">: On July 28th, the LA crowd at IRL Alpha Studio engaged in ice breakers before delving into the HackaTRON S5 introduction and a token workshop. Conversations highlighted TRON's promise for stablecoins and the unbanked.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Miami<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">: On August 24th, TRON DAO's event at Savage Labs celebrated HackaTRON S5. With a workshop on TRON and $500 in engagement bounties by <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.huobi.com\/en-us\/huobiventures\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Huobi Ventures<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, it was a night to remember.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Upcoming Anticipated Stops<\/b>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stanford<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">: Palo Alto gears up for an unforgettable evening on August 29th. Teaming up with Huobi Ventures, this stop promises workshops, insights, and pitching platforms. With a $500 bounty from Huobi Ventures and exciting SWAG raffles to win merchandise, attendees are in for a treat. Moreover, standout pitches might catch Huobi Ventures’ eye for potential investments.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Princeton<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">: September 23rd sees the tour at Princeton University. Teaming with the Princeton Blockchain Club, this stop boasts a staggering $8500 prize pool, including a $1000 bounty from Huobi Ventures and $7500 from TRON DAO. A symbiosis of learning and competition, attendees can anticipate riveting workshops and generous rewards.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Barcelona<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">: On October 1st, 2023, TRON’s innovation descends on Spain. Barcelona’s attendees are in for a hands-on learning experience, juxtaposed with community engagement. The combined bounty and grant pool from Huobi Ventures and TRON DAO totals $3000, with $500 being dedicated towards bounties and $2500 representing the TRON DAO developer grants. This stop promises a deep dive into TRON’s capabilities and a platform for visionary projects.<\/span>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Wrapping it Up<\/b>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The TRON Builder Tour’s journey epitomizes the synergy between innovation and community. Don’t miss the upcoming events. Mark those dates, register for <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/lu.ma\/TBTstanford\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stanford<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/lu.ma\/TBTPrinceton\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Princeton<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, and keep an eye out for Barcelona’s registration. Immerse yourself in the Web3 world and be at the forefront of the blockchain revolution.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This post is commissioned by TRON<\/i><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;and does not serve as a testimonial or endorsement by The Block. This post is for informational purposes only and should not be relied upon as a basis for investment, tax, legal or other advice. You should conduct your own research and consult independent counsel and advisors on the matters discussed within this post. Past performance of any asset is not indicative of future results.<\/i><\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"New York City","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"August 29th","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$500","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Huobi Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Miami","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"IRL Alpha Studio","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"August 24th","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$1000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$3000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Savage Labs celebrated HackaTRON S5","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Spain","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Princeton University","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$7500","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Barcelona","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Princeton","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Palo Alto","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"S5","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Los Angeles","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"July 28th","content":"DATE"},{"type":"TRON","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"October 1st, 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Stanford","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$8500","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$2500","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"July 16th, 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Princeton Blockchain Club","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"TRON DAO","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sponsored","The Block"]}