{"summary":"Founders Fund and Electric Capital led the round, with additional participation from Stani Kulechov, Sandeep Nailwal, Elad Gil, and more. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/261776\/smart-contract-governance-platform-llama-raises-6-million-in-seed-funding","publishDate":"2023-11-06T14:11:36","id":11879,"type":null,"title":"Smart contract governance platform Llama raises $6 million in seed funding","category":["DEALS"],"content":["Smart contract governance platform Llama raised $6 million in seed funding.&nbsp;","Venture capital firms Founders Fund and Electric Capital led the round, which had additional participation from Aave founder Stani Kulechov, Polygon co-founder Sandeep Nailwal, Twitter former vice president of corporate strategy <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/158018\/lines-web3-messaging-platform-raises-4-million-seed-round\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Elad Gil<\/a>, Stripe president of product and business Will Gaybrick, Coinbase protocol specialist Viktor Bunin, Anchorage Digital co-founder and CEO Nathan McCauley, Zeitgeist's Sina Habibian, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/164111\/dcg-backs-cybersecurity-company-dwallet-labs-in-5-million-round\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Amplify Partners<\/a>, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/251101\/investment-firm-reverie-launches-20-million-crypto-venture-fund\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Reverie<\/a> and <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/173478\/former-revolut-employees-raise-3-5-million-to-build-crypto-investment-app\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">FJ Labs<\/a>.&nbsp;","The firm plans to hire more engineers and pay for infrastructure costs using the fresh funds, Llama co-founder Shreyas Hariharan told The Block.","Llama offers smart contracts full-stack governance and access control for better security and efficacy, encoding roles, permissions and execution strategies for on-chain actions, it wrote in a statement.","\"In Llama, decentralization is achieved through access control. Each governance participant is granted the minimum amount of power to perform the function they are best suited to do,\" Hariharan said in a statement.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Anchorage Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nathan McCauley","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Hariharan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Electric Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Viktor Bunin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sina Habibian","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sandeep Nailwal","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Amplify Partners","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Zeitgeist","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Will Gaybrick","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$6 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Llama","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Llama","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Elad Gil","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Stani Kulechov","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Shreyas Hariharan","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["SEED &AMP; PRE-SEED"],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}