{"summary":"Episode 28 of Season 2 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block’s Frank Chaparro and Larry Cermak, director of research at The Block.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/72517\/larry-cermak-breaks-down-why-the-twitter-hackers-are-amateurish","publishDate":"2020-07-21T17:18:35","id":11885,"type":null,"title":"Larry Cermak breaks down why the Twitter hackers are amateurish","category":["THE BLOCK"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 28 of Season 2 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block’s Frank Chaparro and Larry Cermak, director of research at The Block.<\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"aedec1cacdcfdddaeedac6cbccc2c1cdc5cddcd7dedac180cdc1c3\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode of The Scoop is brought to you by Bitstamp, the original global cryptocurrency exchange. Since 2011, Bitstamp has been a cornerstone of the industry, earning the trust of over four million individuals and top financial institutions looking for a reliable trading venue. <\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Whether you’re trading on our web platform, mobile app or industry-leading APIs, Bitstamp gives you the professional-grade tools you need to execute your strategy.&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/bitstamp.net\/app?r=pro%E2%80%93&amp;utm_source=Website&amp;utm_medium=podcast&amp;utm_campaign=theblock&amp;utm_content=ctaapp\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Download the Bitstamp app<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or visit&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.bitstamp.net\/pro\/?utm_source=Website&amp;utm_medium=podcast&amp;utm_campaign=theblock&amp;utm_content=ctaweb\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitstamp.net\/Pro<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;to learn more and start trading today!<\/i>","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK2821445972\" width=\"100%\" height=\"200\" frameborder=\"0\" scrolling=\"no\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","The Block spends a lot of time on Twitter, combing the signal from the noise and looking out for market-moving memes. Sometimes that pays off.","On Wednesday, our Director of Research Larry Cermak noticed a tweet from a well-known trading account, @AngeloBTC, alerting its followers that it was launching a paid group. Cermak thought that was strange, and suspected that the account had probably suffered a hack.","An hour later, Binance's Twitter account posted a tweet that left virtually no doubt it had been hacked. \"We have partnered with CryptoForHealth and are giving back 5000 BTC to the community,\" the tweet said, adding a link that it said its followers could use to see more information.","At first, Cermak and the rest of the team thought it might be a coincidence. Perhaps Binance and AngeloBTC were just both having a bad day? But once Binance CEO Changpeng Zhao's tweeted the same exact message, The Block began <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/71906\/twitter-account-hacks-timeline\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">connecting the dots<\/a>.","It wasn't long before celebrity accounts including tech pundit Elon Musk and presidential candidate Joe Biden fell victim to the far-reaching hack. The accounts displayed similar messages, each expressing a desire to \"give back\" by matching BTC payments to three different addresses.","It took Twitter two and a half hours to remedy the breach, in part by temporarily disabling tweeting from all verified accounts.&nbsp;By Thursday morning, the hack was front-page news, and now the platform is in the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/72056\/congress-is-raising-hell-about-twitters-account-hacks-but-its-probably-just-a-sideshow\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">crosshairs of Congress<\/a> and the Federal Bureau of Investigation.&nbsp;","On this week's episode of The Scoop, Cermak explained out how The Block first picked up on the biggest Twitter hack in history, and what the early hours of information gathering looked like. He also touched on:","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen to this week's episode on Apple, GooglePlay, Spotify, Stitcher or wherever you listen to podcasts.<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2011","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Cermak","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Congress","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Director of Research Larry Cermak","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Changpeng Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Federal Bureau of Investigation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Elon Musk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Twitter","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Larry Cermak","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"morning","content":"TIME"},{"type":"Bitstamp","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Joe Biden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Binance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Aislinn Keely","The Block"]}