{"summary":"Rep. Tom Emmer, R-Minn., is trying his hand to be the next House Speaker as the leadership saga continues. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/258959\/crypto-friendly-rep-tom-emmer-takes-a-shot-at-house-speaker-role-as-drama-continues","publishDate":"2023-10-23T10:50:42","id":11897,"type":null,"title":"Crypto-friendly Rep. Tom Emmer takes a shot at House Speaker role as drama continues","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">U.S. Rep. Tom Emmer, R-Minn., who has been friendly toward crypto and critical of regulators, is trying his hand at becoming the next House Speaker as a leadership saga continues.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Emmer, along with eight other candidates, including Rep. Byron Donalds, R-Fla., and Pete Sessions, R-Texas, announced their bids for House Speaker on Sunday.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">House Majority Whip Emmer has introduced bills over the past few years including one to create a new definition for tokens and another that would ban the Federal Reserve from issuing a direct CBDC. He has also been supportive of a bill that takes a comprehensive approach at a regulatory framework for crypto, while <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253305\/gensler-takes-heat-from-lawmakers-over-his-approach-to-regulating-crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">slamming<\/span><\/a> Securities and Exchange Commission Chair Gary Gensler for taking a \"regulation by harassment approach\" toward digital assets.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Former House Speaker Kevin McCarthy, R-Calif., reportedly nominated Emmer, telling NBC's \"Meet the Press\" on <a href=\"https:\/\/www.nbcnews.com\/meet-the-press\/meet-press-october-22-2023-n1307654\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sunday<\/span><\/a> that the Minnesota Republican needs to get elected this week. McCarthy was ousted earlier this month<\/span><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> following a power struggle with lawmakers including Rep. Matt Gaetz, R-Fla.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Since McCarthy's vacancy, Rep. Patrick McHenry, R-N.C., has taken over his post temporarily, which some have said wasted precious time needed to move certain crypto bills forward. Two of those bills advanced out of the House Financial Services Committee, which McHenry leads, but are essentially stalled until a House Speaker is chosen.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Two in the recent pool of candidates, Donalds and Sessions, have also voiced support for crypto innovation.<\/span>","<span class=\"s5\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Many innovators who use blockchain tech want to do business here, but stay away due to uncertainty caused by Congressional inaction &amp; an overzealous SEC. We've been the global financial epicenter but are quickly becoming a place that innovators avoid. It's time to take action,\" Donalds posted in July on X. <\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Emmer is the frontrunner, but that doesn't guarantee he will become speaker, Ron Hammond, <\/span><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">director of government relations at the Blockchain Association, <\/span><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">posted on X.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Other tries from lawmakers, including from Rep. Jim Jordan, R-Ohio, and Steve Scalise, R-La., to become House speaker have failed to get the needed votes over the past few weeks. <\/span><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The House is expected to meet Monday and vote as early as Tuesday for House speaker, according to news reports.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A few House Financial Services Committee hearings are scheduled for this week, including one on Wednesday from its digital asset subcommittee titled \"<\/span><span class=\"s5\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Modernizing Financial Services Through Innovation and Competition.\"&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s5\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Other hearings this week will discuss Hamas and sanctions evasions, with another to focus on Iran's access to funds.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">It is not clear what specifically lawmakers plan to discuss, but some, including Sen. Elizabeth Warren, D-Mass., have said they are <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/258183\/sen-elizabeth-warren-joins-more-than-100-lawmakers-to-ask-biden-about-plans-to-prevent-crypto-financed-terrorism\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">concerned<\/span><\/a> about how Hamas raised millions of dollars through crypto ahead of attacks in Israel.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Federal Reserve","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Blockchain Association","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Donalds","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Emmer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Pete Sessions","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kevin McCarthy","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Minnesota","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"House Speaker","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gary Gensler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ron Hammond","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Israel","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Modernizing Financial Services Through Innovation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"La.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"millions of dollars","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"House Financial Services Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"McHenry","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Elizabeth Warren","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sunday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Mass.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Fla.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Tom Emmer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NBC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jim Jordan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Byron Donalds","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Patrick McHenry","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ohio","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"McCarthy","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Texas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"House","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hamas","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"House Majority Whip Emmer","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Steve Scalise","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Minn.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Calif.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Matt Gaetz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Iran","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["HOUSE FINANCIAL SERVICES COMMITTEE"],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}