{"summary":"Bitcoin mining company Bitdeer bought Singaporean maximum-security vault Le Freeport for $28.4 million, according to Bloomberg.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/171010\/bitcoin-miner-bitdeer-bought-singaporean-maximum-security-vault-le-freeport-report","publishDate":"2022-09-19T10:07:45","id":11926,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin miner Bitdeer bought Singaporean maximum-security vault Le Freeport: Report","category":["BITCOIN"],"content":["Bitcoin miner Bitdeer has bought Le Freeport, a Singaporean maximum-security vault, according to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2022-09-19\/chinese-crypto-tycoon-backed-bitdeer-buys-asia-s-fort-knox\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bloomberg<\/a>.","The deal, which closed in July, was worth S$40 million ($28.4 million), sources told Bloomberg.","Previously owned by Swiss art dealer Yves Bouvier, Le Freeport was also a repository for fine art, precious gems, and gold and silver bars.","Bitdeer did not immediately respond to a request for comment from The Block.","The company has been aiming to go public since last year when it announced a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/124760\/jihan-wus-bitcoin-mining-outfit-bitdeer-plans-public-listing-via-4-billion-spac-merger\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$4 billion SPAC deal<\/a> with blank-check firm Blue Safari Group Acquisition Corp. The deadline for the deal has been delayed three months from September 14 to December 14, according to a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.sec.gov\/Archives\/edgar\/data\/1853084\/000110465922097966\/tm2225156d1_ex99-1.htm\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">US Securities and Exchange Commission filing<\/a> from this month.","The company is led by Jihan Wu, who previously co-founded bitcoin mining manufacturer Bitmain. Wu <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/92580\/jihan-wu-letter-officially-step-down-bitmain\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">stepped down<\/a> from the company in early 2021.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$4 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"S$40 million ($28.4 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Yves Bouvier","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SPAC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitdeer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"September 14","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Jihan Wu","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Freeport","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"December 14","content":"DATE"},{"type":"US Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Blue Safari Group Acquisition Corp","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Catarina Moura","The Block"]}