{"summary":"The sports betting exchange will go live on Solana mainnet in time for the soccer World Cup, offering customers fee-free betting to mark its opening.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/183538\/betdex-to-go-live-on-solana-mainnet-before-world-cup-in-qatar-exclusive","publishDate":"2022-11-06T10:30:38","id":11949,"type":null,"title":"BetDEX to go live on Solana mainnet before World Cup in Qatar: Exclusive","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["BetDEX, a sports betting exchange built on a blockchain, will open on Solana mainnet on Nov. 17.","The sports betting exchange will go live at the beginning of the FIFA World Cup in Qatar, said Varun Sudhakar, the firm's CEO. Users will be able to place bets on football matches, with no fees for bets placed on World Cup matches.","<span lang=\"EN-US\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BetDEX is currently available in countries across Europe, Asia, South America and Africa. The sports exchange is fully licensed and regulated in the Isle of Man under the Online Gambling Regulation Act.&nbsp;<\/span>","The FIFA World Cup in Qatar has come under <a href=\"https:\/\/www.skysports.com\/football\/news\/12098\/12738524\/jurgen-klopp-to-media-on-qatar-world-cup-award-in-2010-we-let-this-happen-but-you-more-than-i\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">scrutiny<\/a> in the build-up to the tournament. Concerns have been raised over the conditions workers have had to endure to build the stadiums required to host the tournament, among other issues.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"South America","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Nov. 17","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FIFA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Varun Sudhakar","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Africa","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Asia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Qatar","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Europe","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}