{"summary":"New Sui Foundation order book DeepBook is meant to help developers “build apps that exchange tokens seamlessly.”","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/239162\/sui-foundation-launches-order-book-for-building-defi-tools","publishDate":"2023-07-12T10:29:47","id":12003,"type":null,"title":"Sui Foundation launches order book for building DeFi tools","category":["LAYER 1S"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sui Foundation, the organization developing the Sui blockchain, launched a decentralized order book that it said is a “one-stop shop for trading digital assets.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Dubbed DeepBook, Sui Foundation expects the new order book to help developers “build apps that exchange tokens seamlessly.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sui Foundation’s Managing Director Greg Siourounis believes DeepBook provides the basic base for building any DeFi tool built on the blockchain. Mysten Labs and MovEX helped with the technical aspects of DeepBook, the organization said in a statement.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Combining Sui’s unique capacity for parallelized transactions with a public on-chain order book allowed the community to create a trading facility that is uniquely transparent, scalable and usable by every DeFi project on the network,” Siourounis also said in the statement.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The work could help to reduce the dependency crypto traders might have on centralized exchanges like Binance or Coinbase.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“At a basic level, DeepBook makes many of the benefits offered by traditional centralized exchanges available in Sui’s decentralized network,” it said in the statement.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Centralized crypto exchanges act as intermediaries between buyers and sellers … [and] also retain control over users’ private crypto wallet keys ,\" it continued. \"As a result, in the event of a hack or a shutdown, these users could face the loss of their entire holdings.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Meant to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/168532\/mysten-labs-sui-blockchain-fundraise-ftx-ventures\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">compete against<\/a> blockchains like Ethereum and Solana, Sui was created by Mysten Labs, which is run by co-founder and CEO Evan Cheng, former head of research and development at Meta’s crypto wallet Novi Financial. Mysten's valuation eclipsed $2 billion last year after a Series B round which raised $300 million.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Sui blockchain","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sui Foundation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Meta’s crypto","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Greg Siourounis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sui","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Evan Cheng","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sui","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Mysten Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Novi Financial","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$300 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"DeepBook","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$2 billion","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["SUI"],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}