{"summary":"The defense hopes to present evidence that shows &#x27;positive investment outcomes&#x27; stemming from Bankman-Fried’s 2022 investment in Anthropic.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/255810\/sam-bankman-frieds-lawyers-seek-to-introduce-evidence-about-anthropic-stake","publishDate":"2023-10-10T23:49:10","id":12013,"type":null,"title":"Sam Bankman-Fried’s lawyers seek to introduce evidence about Anthropic stake","category":["PEOPLE"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Lawyers for Sam Bankman-Fried have asked the court to approve the use of evidence related to his investment in Anthropic, an artificial intelligence startup that recently raised fresh funding.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.courtlistener.com\/docket\/66631291\/317\/united-states-v-bankman-fried\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">letter<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> submitted to <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Judge Lewis A. Kaplan, Bankman-Fried’s counsel said the <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/255359\/sbfs-prosecutors-seek-to-forbid-any-mention-of-anthropic\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">prosecutors’ Sunday request to exclude mentions of Anthropic<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> “miscasts the relevance of the evidence.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Evidence of the current value of the Anthropic investment is squarely relevant to rebutting the Government’s opening statement and testimony to date, as well as Mr. Bankman-Fried’s good-faith,” the attorneys for the failed crypto exchange founder wrote in the filing.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">His lawyers added that the prosecutors have “repeatedly” raised Alameda’s venture investments during the trial and argued that Alameda’s and Bankman-Fried’s investments were, among other things, “risky” and “losing money.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In response, Bankman-Fried’s attorneys said that they should be allowed to elicit testimony from Caroline Ellison about the portfolio nature of venture capital investing. “Here, the significant appreciation in Anthropic since last year reflects this important context and is relevant to testimony that the Government has elicited from Ms. Ellison concerning expected value analyses,” the lawyers continued.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In its Sunday <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.courtlistener.com\/docket\/66631291\/315\/united-states-v-bankman-fried\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filing<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, the Department of Justice said that Bankman-Fried invested about $500 million in 2022 in Anthropic “using funds that the Government alleges were stolen from FTX customers.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Evidence regarding the current value of the defendant’s investments could only be used to support the argument that FTX customers and\/or other victims will ultimately be made whole, which the Court has recognized is an impermissible purpose,” the DOJ added.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Anthropic raised fresh funds from Google and other investors last week that could <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/254667\/anthropics-new-raise-could-mean-full-payout-for-ftx-creditors-lawyer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">potentially boost its valuation to as much as $30 billion<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, The Information <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theinformation.com\/articles\/openai-rival-anthropic-in-talks-to-raise-2-billion-from-google-others-as-ai-arms-race-accelerates\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> last week.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Such an increase in valuation could “make it possible” for FTX to log a “100% recovery rate” in assets as part of the failed crypto exchange’s bankruptcy proceedings&nbsp;<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">given Bankman-Fried’s stake in the company<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, Kunchou Tsai, managing partner of Taiwan-based Enlighten Law Group, recently told The Block.<\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Sunday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ellison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Department of Justice","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Caroline Ellison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Taiwan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$500 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"100%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Government","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lewis A. Kaplan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kunchou Tsai","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"DOJ","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Enlighten Law Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$30 billion","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["FTX","SAM BANKMAN-FRIED","SBF TRIAL"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}