{"summary":"Binance CEO Changpeng Zhao reportedly warned colleagues that the proverbial &quot;crypto winter&quot; isn&#x27;t over, and the months ahead won&#x27;t be easy.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/194868\/binance-ceo-crypto-winter-memo","publishDate":"2022-12-14T04:34:13","id":12048,"type":null,"title":"Binance CEO warns colleagues &#x27;crypto winter&#x27; isn&#x27;t over: Bloomberg","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["Binance CEO Changpeng Zhao warned colleagues at the world's biggest crypto exchange that the proverbial \"crypto winter\" isn't over, and the months ahead won't be easy, according to Bloomberg.&nbsp;","“While we expect the next several months to be bumpy, we will get past this challenging period — and we’ll be stronger for having been through it,” Bloomberg <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2022-12-14\/binance-ceo-zhao-warns-bumpy-road-ahead-in-message-to-his-staff\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a> the executive as saying in an internal memo.","Zhao — who often goes simply by his initials, CZ — blamed the collapse of high-profile competitor FTX for adding \"a lot of extra scrutiny and tough questions\" on Binance. On Tuesday, a U.S. grand jury <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/194667\/disgraced-former-ftx-ceo-sam-bankman-fried-criminally-indicted\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">charged<\/a> former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried with committing or conspiring to commit fraud on FTX’s customers and lenders, as well as money laundering. He was reportedly <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/194768\/bankman-fried-denied-bail-remanded-to-custody-in-the-bahamas-reuters\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">denied<\/a> bail and remanded to the custody of the Bahamas Department of Corrections.","Also on Tuesday, Binance experienced a record amount of bitcoin and ether withdrawals as uncertainty surrounding the liquidity of centralized exchanges grows. The outflows <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/194511\/binance-resumes-usdc-stablecoin-withdrawals-after-temporary-pause\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">caused<\/a> a temporary USD Coin withdrawal freeze, though CZ largely <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/194398\/binance-ceo-usdc-outflow\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">dismissed<\/a> concerns that the exchange has liquidity issues.","Meanwhile,&nbsp;the U.S. Justice Department continues to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/193988\/justice-department-weighs-charging-binance\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">consider<\/a> charging Binance for possible money laundering and criminal sanctions violations, Reuters reported on Monday.&nbsp;&nbsp;","<i data-stringify-type=\"italic\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Disclaimer: Beginning in 2021, Michael McCaffrey, the former CEO and majority owner of The Block, took a series of loans from founder and former FTX and Alameda CEO Sam Bankman-Fried. McCaffrey resigned from the company in December 2022 after failing to disclose those transactions.<\/i><span class=\"c-message__edited_label\" dir=\"ltr\" data-sk=\"tooltip_parent\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bahamas Department of Corrections","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Changpeng Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. Justice Department","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Reuters","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"December 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Michael McCaffrey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE","CZ"],"authors":["Adam James","The Block"]}