{"summary":"Uniswap Labs said that Cunningham was joining the team due to her belief in “the potential of decentralized exchange and in Uniswap Labs’s commitment to fairer markets.”","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/152253\/former-nyse-president-joins-uniswap-labs-as-advisor","publishDate":"2022-06-15T13:44:58","id":1206,"type":null,"title":"Former NYSE president joins Uniswap Labs as advisor","category":["DEX"],"content":["Former New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) president Stacey Cunningham has joined Uniswap Labs as an advisor, according to Wednesday a <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/Uniswap\/status\/1537081901839695872\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweet<\/a> by Uniswap Labs.","According to her <a href=\"https:\/\/www.linkedin.com\/in\/stacey-cunningham-3400885\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">LinkedIn<\/a>, Cunningham has spent almost a decade at the NYSE. She served as president from May 2018 to December 2021 and remains a member of its board. She was the NYSE’s first female president.","Uniswap Labs — the developer behind the Uniswap decentralized cryptocurrency exchange — said that Cunningham was joining the team due to her belief in “the potential of decentralized exchange and in Uniswap Labs’s commitment to fairer markets.”","“Stacey’s seen how it’s done in TradFi — and she’s excited about working with our team toward a better system in DeFi,” Uniswap Labs said.","As with many crypto companies that have seen an influx of hires from TradFi over the past year, Cunningham isn’t the only establishment figure Uniswap Labs has tapped recently.","In October 2021, Uniswap Labs hired former Obama spokesperson Hari Sevugan as its new communications chief. The previous June it also welcomed <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/109143\/decentralized-exchange-uniswap-has-hired-its-first-chief-operating-officer\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Mary-Catherine Lader as its first COO<\/a>. Lader previously led a team-building sustainable investing tools for portfolio management tool Aladdin at BlackRock.<u data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/u>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Catherine Lader","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BlackRock","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cunningham","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Hari Sevugan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"New York Stock Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Uniswap","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Obama","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"October 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"NYSE","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"December 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Uniswap Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"June","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Mary","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"May 2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Stacey Cunningham","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["UNISWAP"],"authors":["Callan Quinn","The Block"]}