{"summary":"Cryptocurrency prices traded flat on Tuesday alongside other risk assets ahead of Federal Reserve Chair Jerome Powell&#x27;s speech this afternoon.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/209334\/crypto-markets-tread-water-ahead-of-fed-speech","publishDate":"2023-02-07T10:35:14","id":12083,"type":null,"title":"Crypto markets tread water ahead of Fed speech","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Cryptocurrency prices were little change alongside other risk assets ahead of Federal Reserve Chair Jerome Powell's speech this afternoon at the Economic Club of Washington.","Bitcoin was trading at $22,962 at 10:05 a.m. EST, up about 0.4% over the past day, according to TradingView data.&nbsp;","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/chart\/q0HITX89\/?symbol=COINBASE%3ABTCUSD\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BTCUSD chart by TradingView<\/a>","Ether rose 0.4%, up to $1,638. Binance's BNB gained 0.3%, Ripple's XRP lost 0.5%, and Solana's SOL traded flat.","Chair Powell's annual sit-down with Carlyle Group's David Rubenstein is \"something the market is not pricing in fully,\" according to QCP Capital's market update, which said it it was impossible to tell if Powell's view of markets was hawkish or dovish at the FOMC press conference last week.","\"Hopefully ... [the] interview will clear things up for everyone,\" QCP said. \"Especially his view on financial conditions, and whether he thinks the rally has gotten out of hand.\"","The Nasdaq traded down, with the 30-stock index down 0.4% and the <span id=\"LiveBlogArticle-QuoteInBody-2\" class=\"QuoteInBody-quoteNameContainer\" data-test=\"QuoteInBody\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">S&amp;P 500 dropping<\/span>&nbsp;0.2%.","Coinbase shares shed 5.7% to trade around $70 by 10:05 a.m. EST, according to Nasdaq data.&nbsp;","Silvergate was down about 8% to just under $18.&nbsp;","Block fell about 0.8% to trade below $82, while MicroStrategy dropped over 1.6% to $277.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"8%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"TradingView","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1,638","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"1.6%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"0.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"S&amp;P","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Powell","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"0.3%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Carlyle Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$18","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$82","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"David Rubenstein","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"5.7%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$22,962","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Washington","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"0.8%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"0.4%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"0.2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Economic Club","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jerome Powell","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"last week","content":"DATE"},{"type":"10:05 a.m. EST","content":"TIME"},{"type":"FOMC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$277","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$70","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"MicroStrategy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nasdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["ANALYST REPORTS","BITCOIN","BNB","CRYPTO BANKS AND LENDERS","ECONOMIC INDICATORS","FEDERAL RESERVE","HEDGE FUNDS","WEALTH MANAGERS"],"authors":["Sam Venis","The Block"]}