{"summary":"The Block&#x27;s Aislinn Keely, Kollen Post and Frank Chaparro talk about regulation and recent policy developments around crypto.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/113091\/are-looming-regulations-putting-an-end-to-bitcoins-wild-west-days","publishDate":"2021-07-30T12:44:05","id":12102,"type":null,"title":"Are looming regulations putting an end to bitcoin&#x27;s &#x27;Wild West&#x27; days?","category":["PODCASTS"],"content":["<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">44<\/strong> of Season 3 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block’s Frank Chaparro and Aislinn Keely, Editor of Wonk Talk &amp; Kollen Post, Senior Politics Report at The Block.<\/em>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This is the first edition of The Scoop’s policy focused series, Policy Scoop.<\/em>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"6c1c03080f0d1f182c1804090e00030f070f1e151c1803420f0301\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors&nbsp;<a href=\"http:\/\/eventussystems.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Eventus<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"http:\/\/kraken.com\/scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kraken<\/a>, and&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.exodus.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Exodus<\/a><\/strong>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Eventus is the leading global provider of multi-asset class trade surveillance, transaction monitoring and market risk solutions. Eventus offers a powerful, award-winning trade surveillance platform that is easy to deploy, customize and operate. Eventus is proven in the most complex, high-volume and real-time environments and supports many of the industry’s leading crypto exchanges including Coinbase, Gemini, ErisX and OSL. The company’s rapidly growing client base relies on Eventus’ responsive support and product development teams to overcome its most pressing regulatory challenges.<\/em>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Kraken<\/strong>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Whether you’re an experienced crypto trader or just starting out, Kraken has the tools to help you achieve financial freedom. With 50+ cryptocurrencies to choose from, industry-leading security and a wide variety of features to suit any investing strategy, Kraken puts the power in your hands to buy, sell and trade digital assets. Visit&nbsp;<\/em><a href=\"http:\/\/kraken.com\/scoop\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kraken.com<\/em><\/a><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;to get started today.<\/em>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Exodus<\/strong>","&nbsp;","Signs point to the looming specter of regulation slowly bringing the days of bitcoin and crypto's \"Wild West\" to an end. The only question, perhaps, is if not now, then when?","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"We’re getting to a boiling point,\" The Block's Aislinn Keely told The Scoop.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">On this policy report episode of The Scoop, host Frank Chaparro is joined by The Block’s policy and regulatory reporters — Editor of Wonk Talk Aislinn Keely and Senior Politics Reporter Kollen Post — for an update on where the United States currently sits on the digital asset policy front.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Post and Keely touched on how regulators will be tackling exchanges first. \"It’s not necessarily that we’re waiting for exchange regulation, but the way crypto will be regulated is going to be related to on\/off ramps and that happens to be centralized exchanges right now,\" Keely told The Scoop.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Keely and Post also covered what a Gensler-led SEC looks like, citing Elizabeth Warren’s letter to the SEC questioning <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/110820\/liz-warren-sec-crypto-exchanges-gensler\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">how the US plans<\/a> to regulate exchanges.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Keely and Post noted the potentially risky domino effect of agency mandates on policies such as those that targeted crypto startup BlockFi, particularly in instances for which crypto products mimic savings accounts and securities and don’t have the provision of FDIC backing.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Post noted that if the NY investigation of Tether becomes a federal case, it could change the narrative of the White House’s coverage of digital assets in terms of how much cash the Senate wants to monitor the ecosystem. As of this podcast’s publication, The Block received<\/span> <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/112877\/white-house-says-crypto-tax-enforcement-will-help-pay-for-bipartisan-infrastructure-deal?utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_medium=social\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">new details<\/span><\/a> <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">stating that an upcoming infrastructure bill in the U.S. Senate will in fact be partially paid for by enhanced tax enforcement of cryptocurrency.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Keely also clarified where the US currently stands on Central Bank Digital Currency or CBDC. Keely said that the US is still on the perceived “losing side” relative to countries like China, which is in the process of developing a digitized version of the yuan. The US government has not made any final decisions on whether it will issue a digital dollar.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This podcast also covers:<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"White House","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kraken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"OSL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gensler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Post","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Policy Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"United States","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Elizabeth Warren","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gemini","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Aislinn Keely","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Keely","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FDIC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. Senate","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Central Bank Digital Currency","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"China","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Wonk Talk &amp; Kollen Post","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Senate","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN"],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}