{"summary":"Coinciding with financial concerns and actions from the Bank of England, bitcoin and ether trading volume has increased against the pound.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/176484\/crypto-traders-flock-to-trade-against-the-pound-amid-uk-financial-woes","publishDate":"2022-10-12T04:58:22","id":12112,"type":null,"title":"Crypto traders flock to trade against the pound amid UK financial woes","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["Financial turbulence in the UK following last month's announcement of unfunded tax cuts has caused a spike in trading of crypto against the British pound.&nbsp;","UK government bonds and the pound have tumbled since Chancellor of the Exchequer Kwasi Kwarteng's Sept. 23 \"<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theguardian.com\/uk-news\/2022\/sep\/23\/kwasi-kwarteng-mini-budget-key-points-at-a-glance\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">mini budget<\/a>.\" The surge in yields on longer-term government debt spilled over into a crisis for pension funds as they were forced to rapidly adjust their portfolios — before the Bank of England (BOE) responded with a package of bond buying to ease the pressure.&nbsp;","British assets fell again today after BOE Governor Andrew Bailey <a href=\"https:\/\/www.reuters.com\/world\/uk\/bank-englands-bailey-tells-pension-funds-they-have-3-days-rebalance-2022-10-11\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">cautioned<\/a> pension funds that support will end in three days. A later <a href=\"https:\/\/www.ft.com\/content\/87a5b7bf-6786-427f-89d6-96b736dcb814\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">report<\/a> from Financial Times, citing bankers briefed by the BOE, said the emergency bond-buying program could continue past this week's deadline&nbsp;","This turmoil in the UK has coincided with a notable increase in bitcoin trading against the nation's currency. Volume increases have been particularly clear on the centralized crypto exchange Bitfinex.","BTC\/GBP volume, measured in BTC, has increased alongside financial worries in the UK","Additionally, ether volumes have increased against the pound — most notably, again, on Bitfinex.","There has also been a notable increase in ETH\/GBP volume, measured in ETH","While some are <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/CL207\/status\/1580087109725351936\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">speculating<\/a> that this data shows UK investors are fleeing into crypto, that may not necessarily be the case.","\"Ultimately, when GBP is volatile, some traders could make more money arbitraging against BTC\/USD pairs,\" explained The Block's VP of Research, Larry Cermak.","\"So it doesn’t necessarily mean people are buying BTC or ETH and dumping GBP,\" he continued. \"It could also just mean market makers and traders are trying to arbitrage the difference.\"","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"ETH\/GBP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"VP of Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bank of England (BOE","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Andrew Bailey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BOE","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Larry Cermak","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"GBP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sept. 23","content":"DATE"},{"type":"last month","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Financial Times","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kwasi Kwarteng","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN"],"authors":["Adam James","The Block"]}