{"summary":"Binance saw a significant uptick in withdrawals today following news that its founder pleaded guilty to criminal charges in the U.S.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/264204\/binance-saw-1-billion-in-net-outflows-over-the-last-24-hours","publishDate":"2023-11-22T03:05:48","id":12159,"type":null,"title":"Binance saw $1 billion in net outflows over the last 24 hours","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The world’s largest crypto exchange saw an uptick in withdrawals around the time that CEO Changpeng Zhao pled guilty to criminal charges.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance, the world’s largest crypto exchange, saw a significant uptick in withdrawals during news that its founder <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/264013\/binance-us-press-conference-settlement\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">pleaded guilty to criminal charges<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in the U.S.<\/span>","<a href=\"https:\/\/defillama.com\/cexs\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Data<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> from DefiLlama showed that Binance’s 24-hour outflows topped $1 billion as of 3:30 p.m. Hong Kong time on Wednesday. The exchange's net outflows over 7 days amounted to $703.1 million.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Of the total outflows experienced by Binance, $605.9 million came across the Ethereum, <span class=\"articleTooltip\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"\/price\/248351\/bnb-bnb-usd\" class=\"articleTooltip__link\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"><img src=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2023\/10\/bnb-icon2_2x.png\" alt=\"\" title=\"\" class=\"articleTooltip__tokenImage\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">BNB<\/span> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText articleTooltip__tokenText_price articleTooltip__tokenText_negative\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">\n      -0.23%\n    <\/span><\/a> <!----><\/span> chain, Avalanche, Fantom and Polygon networks, according to separate data compiled by&nbsp;<\/span><\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/pro.nansen.ai\/exchange-flows\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Nansen<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The withdrawals come after Binance co-founder Changpeng Zhao pled guilty on Tuesday to violating the Bank Secrecy Act and <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/264120\/binance-names-richard-teng-as-new-ceo-as-founder-cz-admits-mistakes\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">stepped down as the company’s CEO<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. Binance has since <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/264174\/meet-richard-teng-a-primer-on-the-new-ceo-of-worlds-largest-crypto-exchange\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">appointed Richard Teng as CEO<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">As part of the plea deal, Zhao agreed to pay a $50 million fine. Binance will also pay a $4.3 billion fine after it pled guilty to several counts including money laundering, conspiracy to conduct an unlicensed money transmitting business, and sanctions violations.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Meanwhile, OKX enjoyed net inflows of $152 million in the past 24 hours, giving it the largest daily inflow today, followed by Bybit’s $50.9 billion and Bitstamp’s $30.5 million, according to DefiLlama.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance’s native token BNB fell 9.1% in the past 24 hours to trade at $234.3, CoinGecko <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.coingecko.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">data<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> showed.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Jason Atkins, chief commercial officer of crypto market maker Auros, told The Block that there is a second-order effect around market sentiment as “developments, such as the fines levied on Binance by the DOJ, are indicative of the positions of various regulatory bodies when it comes to historical infractions.”&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We anticipate that this will accelerate the outflow of projects, exchanges, founders and firms from direct U.S. regulatory purview,” Atkins said. “Compliance will now be a non-negotiable so as to minimize lapses in the AML and KYC requirements in the U.S., irrespective of the country of incorporation.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Despite the heavy blow dealt to its business in the U.S., Binance has already&nbsp;<\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/264182\/binance-looks-to-next-50-years-as-cz-steps-down\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tried to frame a vision for its future<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. “<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">[When] Binance first launched, it did not have compliance controls adequate for the company that it was quickly becoming, and it should have,” the company said in a blog post published today. “Over the past two years, we have worked hard to restructure our organization and personnel and upgrade our systems.”<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$605.9 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$30.5 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$1 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Changpeng Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Fantom","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nansen","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Richard Teng","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"KYC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Atkins","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"AML","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DOJ","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"-0.23%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"9.1%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$152 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$703.1 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Jason Atkins","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"3:30 p.m.","content":"TIME"},{"type":"$50.9 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"OKX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$4.3 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"DefiLlama","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$234.3","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Binance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$50 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"the U.S.","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE","CZ"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}