{"summary":"Failed cryptocurrency trading platform FTX has launched a portal for creditors to file their claims to the exchange.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/238994\/ftx-claims-portal-goes-live-allowing-creditors-to-submit-their-claims","publishDate":"2023-07-11T14:08:18","id":12151,"type":null,"title":"FTX claims portal goes live, allowing creditors to submit their claims","category":["BANKRUPTCY"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Failed cryptocurrency trading platform FTX has launched a customer <a href=\"https:\/\/claims.ftx.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">claims portal<\/a>. This lets individual clients access their account information and then file a petition that will be included in the company’s Chapter 11 bankruptcy proceedings, according to the site.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The portal is for customers who had accounts with FTX.com, FTX.us, Blockfolio, FTX EU, FTX JP and crypto exchange Liquid. Last month, a U.S. <a href=\"https:\/\/storage.courtlistener.com\/recap\/gov.uscourts.deb.188450\/gov.uscourts.deb.188450.1793.0.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">court said<\/a> customers should file their claims by September 29.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"You will be directed to the Kroll Restructuring Administration platform to confirm your balances as of the Petition Date, and, if necessary, submit an electronic proof of claim<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,” the portal's instructions said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">It appears customer account balances are being calculated as of November 11, 2022.<\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"November 11, 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Blockfolio","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX EU","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"September 29","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kroll Restructuring Administration","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}