{"summary":"The EU and the US swapped crypto policy insights on stablecoins and other issues during a joint financial forum in Brussels last week. Representatives","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/158799\/eu-us-swap-policy-intel-on-european-crypto-regulation-stablecoins","publishDate":"2022-07-20T15:43:34","id":12213,"type":null,"title":"EU, US swap policy intel on European crypto regulation, stablecoins","category":["REGULATION"],"content":["The EU and the US swapped crypto policy insights on stablecoins and other issues during a joint financial forum in Brussels last week.","Representatives from the two governments met as part of an EU–US Joint Financial Regulatory Forum from July 13-14, <a href=\"https:\/\/home.treasury.gov\/news\/press-releases\/jy0882\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">the US Treasury announced.<\/span><\/a> Participants discussed the EU’s new Markets in Crypto-Assets Regulation (MiCA) deal,&nbsp; <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/155232\/eu-reaches-agreement-on-final-landmark-crypto-regulation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">which was finalized<\/span><\/a> at the end of June.","EU participants included representatives from the European Commission and the European Banking Authority, among others. On the American side, officials and staff came from the US Treasury and agencies, including the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Commodity Futures Trading Commission and Securities and Exchange Commission.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","The US also shared policy updates on the country’s work around stablecoins and other digital assets. Participants “took stock of discussions around the development of potential central bank digital currencies.” The forum is expected to meet again early next year.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"US Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"European Banking Authority","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"July 13","content":"DATE"},{"type":"EU","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Commodity Futures Trading Commission and Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"14","content":"DATE"},{"type":"European Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Brussels","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"June","content":"DATE"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"last week","content":"DATE"},{"type":"US","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Crypto","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"EU–US Joint Financial Regulatory Forum","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["FEDERAL RESERVE"],"authors":["Stephanie Murray","The Block"]}