{"summary":"AssangeDAO, a collective of cypherpunks formed last week, has won the bid for Julian Assange x Pak NFT dubbed Clock for $53 million.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/133616\/assangedao-wins-julian-assange-x-pak-nft-for-53-million","publishDate":"2022-02-09T09:05:08","id":12275,"type":null,"title":"AssangeDAO wins Julian Assange x Pak NFT for $53 million","category":["NFTS"],"content":["AssangeDAO, a collective of cypherpunks formed last week in an attempt to free WikiLeaks founder Julian Assange, has won the bid for an NFT created by Julian Assange and digital artist Pak — essentially making a large donation to his cause.","AssangeDAO <a href=\"https:\/\/juicebox.money\/#\/p\/assangedao\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ended up raising<\/a> 17,422 ether ($56 million) from its community to bid on <a href=\"https:\/\/censored.art\/clock\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">the NFT dubbed Cloc<\/a>k and has now won the NFT by putting in the <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/AssangeDAO\/status\/1491362926531612672?s=20&amp;t=dZNmh34ijHyg7felpdnS7g\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">highest offer<\/a> worth 16,593 ether ($53 million).","\"This is an important moment in DAO history,\" Rachel Rose O'Leary, a core contributor of AssangeDAO — who is also co-founder and developer of DarkFi and a former CoinDesk journalist — told The Block. \"AssangeDAO has executed its final bid: a max bid of its entire treasury on the Clock NFT.\"","AssangeDAO offered the maximum bid it could for the NFT. On Tuesday, Gabriel Shipton, Julian Assange's brother and a core contributor of AssangeDAO, <a href=\"https:\/\/forum.assangedao.org\/t\/assange-family-unit-maximum-bid\/73\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">submitted a proposal<\/a> on the DAO's governance forum that AssangeDAO must put its max bid on the Clock NFT. \"We believe that this is the best outcome for AssangeDAO to assist Julian Assange's liberation,\" he wrote in the proposal at the time.","While many within the AssangeDAO community were against the max bid, Assange's family expressed their support, and the key players signed off on the transaction, said O'Leary, who has <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/132991\/a-dao-trying-to-free-julian-assange-has-raised-4-million-and-counting\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">partial control<\/a> over the funds held by AssangeDAO.","The Clock NFT won by AssangeDAO is part of Pak x Julian Assange's NFT collection called <a href=\"https:\/\/censored.art\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Censored<\/a>.","Clock is a single NFT. It is a muted timer counting the number of days Assange has spent in prison. Assange was arrested in 2019 in London and faces potential extradition to the US. Proceeds raised from the NFT sale will go toward Assange's legal fees.","The second part of the Censored NFT collection was an open edition, exhibiting buyers' <a href=\"https:\/\/censored.art\/message\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tokenized messages<\/a>. Anyone could choose to pay whatever they want for a tokenized message. Over 29,000 tokenized messages were created by buyers or \"vanguards\" in the edition. They can be viewed <a href=\"https:\/\/opensea.io\/collection\/censored-pak-assange\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">on OpenSea here<\/a>.","Vanguards or collectors <a href=\"https:\/\/censored.art\/vanguards\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">paid<\/a> a total of 670 ether (over $2 million). The entire amount <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/muratpak\/status\/1491416269513687042?s=20&amp;t=Zb0CBYlign6ccsphHHFkrQ\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">will go to<\/a> human rights, freedom of information, digital privacy, child education, and health organizations.","AssangeDAO's governance token Justice is also liquid now, meaning contributors can claim it and trade it on decentralized exchanges such as Uniswap and SushiSwap.","One <a href=\"https:\/\/app.uniswap.org\/#\/swap?inputCurrency=ETH&amp;outputCurrency=0x59d1e836F7b7210A978b25a855085cc46fd090B5\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Justice token<\/a> is currently trading at around $0.0038 on Uniswap, up 20% from the initial price during the fundraising period.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Rachel Rose O'Leary","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gabriel Shipton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$0.0038","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Julian Assange","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$2 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"20%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Clock NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$53 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"O'Leary","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Assange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"WikiLeaks","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DAO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"London","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$56 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"token Justice","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["DAOS"],"authors":["Yogita Khatri","The Block"]}