{"summary":"The revised bill will help clarify that powers relating to financial promotion and regulated activities can be relied on to regulate crypto assets.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/179906\/uk-lawmakers-voted-to-include-crypto-rules-in-finance-regulation-bill","publishDate":"2022-10-26T06:10:23","id":1228,"type":null,"title":"UK lawmakers voted to include crypto rules in finance regulation bill","category":["REGULATION"],"content":["UK lawmakers voted to include recently added amendments that <a href=\"https:\/\/publications.parliament.uk\/pa\/bills\/cbill\/58-03\/0146\/220146.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">expand<\/a> the regulatory oversight of crypto assets in a major finance bill.","The revised bill will help clarify&nbsp;that powers relating to financial promotion and regulated activities can be relied on to regulate crypto assets and activities relating to crypto assets,&nbsp;Andrew Griffith, financial services minister, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/178970\/uk-government-includes-new-crypto-amendment-in-finance-regulation-bill\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a> on Oct. 21, when the amendments were first added. The bill also defines what a crypto asset is, Griffith said.","The vote on the Financial Services and Markets Bill passed in the UK's lower house of parliament on October 25 and now faces further rounds of scrutiny from lawmakers.&nbsp;<span class=\"ContentPasted1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">If passed into law, the new amendments will broaden the country’s framework for regulating crypto, handing more oversight powers to the Financial Conduct Authority and Treasury.<\/span><span class=\"Apple-converted-space ContentPasted1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"ContentPasted1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">At the moment, the FCA relies in part on anti-money laundering requirements when deciding on the registrations of crypto firms. <\/span><span class=\"Apple-converted-space ContentPasted1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","The Financial Services and Markets bill's framework already <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/158648\/uk-treasury-unveils-plan-to-regulate-stablecoins-in-financial-services-and-markets-bill\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">focuses<\/a> on stablecoins, and the broader framework will tie the UK closer to the EU’s comprehensive Markets in Crypto-Assets regulation.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"UK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Financial Conduct Authority and Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Griffith","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Oct. 21","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FCA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Andrew Griffith","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"EU","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Crypto","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Financial Services","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"October 25","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["UK PARLIAMENT"],"authors":["Benjamin Robertson","The Block"]}