{"summary":"The fate of a spot bitcoin ETF has been hanging in the balance, but Galaxy&#x27;s Novogratz thinks the product will soon be approved.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/258171\/novogratz-thinks-bitcoin-etfs-will-be-approved-this-year","publishDate":"2023-10-18T11:03:16","id":12285,"type":null,"title":"Novogratz thinks bitcoin ETFs will be approved this year","category":["REGULATION"],"content":["Galaxy Digital Holdings CEO Michael Novogratz is confident spot bitcoin exchange-traded funds will be approved by the end of this year.","\"It's gonna get approved,\" Novogratz said during <a href=\"https:\/\/www.youtube.com\/watch?v=EFVO8hGGA54\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">an interview<\/a> on CNBC. \"We think it happens this year, in 2023.\"","<span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The pressure to approve a spot bitcoin ETF has been mounting, especially after Grayscale Investments <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/247947\/bitcoin-price-soars-after-grayscale-win-in-dispute-with-sec\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s5\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">secured a court win<\/span><\/a> in August, with three judges in the U.S. Court of Appeals for the D.C. Circuit ruling that the Securities and Exchange Commission had to re-review its bid for a spot bitcoin ETF. The SEC <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/256450\/bitcoin-rises-as-friday-draws-to-close-without-sec-appeal-of-grayscale-ruling\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">doesn't plan<\/a> on appealing that ruling, but what happens next has yet to crystalize.<\/span>","Pressed by CNBC's reporter to give tangible reasons why his argument makes sense and isn't just wishful thinking, Novogratz cited the recent court decision. \"The SEC lost in court ... the judge has said, 'What are you talking about SEC? You have a futures ETF and you're saying you can't have a cash ETF. That makes intellectually zero sense,'\" he said. \"That puts SEC on the back foot.\"","If Novogratz proves right, it would certainly benefit his firm, which has partnered with Invesco on a spot bitcoin ETF application.","<span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Last month, lawmakers <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253093\/lawmakers-urge-sec-chair-gensler-to-allow-spot-bitcoin-etfs-immediatelyv\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">pressed<\/span><\/a> SEC Chair Gary Gensler to allow for a spot Bitcoin ETF following the ruling, <\/span><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">arguing a regulated spot bitcoin ETF would increase investor protection by making access to bitcoin more transparent and safer.<\/span><\/span><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Besides Grayscale, top financial firms including BlackRock and Fidelity are also seeking to offer a bitcoin ETF product to their clients.<\/span>","\"The American public wants this,\" Novogratz said. \"BlackRock, the largest asset manager in the world is out publicly saying 'We're going to get this done.\"&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"BlackRock","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. Court of Appeals","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fidelity","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Grayscale Investments","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CNBC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Galaxy Digital Holdings","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Novogratz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gary Gensler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Michael Novogratz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Invesco","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"D.C.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"\" Novogratz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["SEC","SPOT BITCOIN ETF"],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}