{"summary":"LimeWire has already partnered with more than 100 artists, a company spokesperson told The Block.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/156133\/limewire-teams-up-with-brandy-travis-barker-nicky-jam-and-others-to-launch-nfts","publishDate":"2022-07-06T15:16:02","id":12303,"type":null,"title":"LimeWire teams up with Brandy, Travis Barker, Nicky Jam and others to launch NFTs","category":["NFTS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">LimeWire is teaming up with a slew of artists, including Travis Barker, Brandy, Nicky Jam and Dillon Francis, to launch non-fungible token (NFT) collections on its platform, the company announced on Wednesday.&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Formerly known as a peer-to-peer file sharing website, LimeWire recently made a comeback as a “digital collectibles marketplace” focused on music tracks, videos, digital artwork and fan experiences.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">LimeWire has already partnered with more than 100 artists, a company spokesperson told The Block. Of these, 25 are larger “headliners,” including acts like Travis Barker, Brandy, Nicky Jam, Aitch, Dillon Francis, FitLit Club feat. Jim Jones, Maino, Dave East, Fabolous, Gramatik, 7 Aurelius and Elijah Blake.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The first LimeWire artist drop will be a collection of seven NFTs on July 7 from Grammy-winning producer 7 Aurelius, which were inspired by Kanye West’s Netflix documentary “Jeen-Yuhs.\" Those collectibles will consist of “masterpiece A.I.” images, short films and songs, according to the press announcement. After that, the next scheduled drops are from Gramatik on July 10 and Elijah Blake on July 12.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Drops from Travis Barker and Nicky Jam — two of the biggest artists releasing NFT collections on LimeWire’s platform — have not been scheduled yet. However, they “will also take place within the next few weeks” according to the spokesperson.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Blink-182 drummer Travis Barker will launch his first NFT collection on LimeWire's platform, which will focus on behind-the-scenes studio footage. One lucky person will also be able to buy an 3D, animated NFT of Barker’s drum set that comes with the physical instrument.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Brandy’s collection will be a collaboration with the Probably Nothing project from restaurateur and <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/probablynothing.io\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">NFT creator <\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Jeremy Fall. This NFT collection will include a “collaborative” bouquet of flowers and feature spoken word from Brandy about mental health issues, said LimeWire's statement.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">LimeWire was born in the early 2000s as a peer-to-peer file sharing platform. It was especially popular for downloading music files before smartphone apps like Spotify, Apple Music and Tidal became ubiquitous. The company <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/136939\/limewire-announces-comeback-as-web3-nft-marketplace?utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_medium=social\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">revealed in March<\/a> that it would be making a comeback to focus on digital collectibles, and in <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/142661\/limewire-raises-10-million-in-private-token-sale-to-grow-music-linked-nft-platform\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">April announced<\/a> a $10.4 million token sale raise led by Kraken Ventures, Arrington Capital and GSR.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">LimeWire has officially picked Algorand to be its blockchain partner for its NFT collections, a spokesperson confirmed, noting that “t<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">he majority of NFTs minted directly on the LimeWire platform will be minted via Algorand.” However, the company did launch a collection of NFT avatars called “LimeWire Originals” using the Ethereum blockchain.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Arrington Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"GSR","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Maino","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Netflix","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dave East","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Brandy","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Nicky Jam","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Apple Music","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gramatik","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Barker","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Grammy","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Dillon Francis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jim Jones","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Algorand","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FitLit Club","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fabolous","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"July 10","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Aurelius","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"July 7","content":"DATE"},{"type":"July 12","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Jeremy Fall","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Travis Barker","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"LimeWire","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Elijah Blake","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Aitch","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2000s","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Kraken Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$10.4 million","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Kristin Majcher","The Block"]}