{"summary":"His attorneys said that the prosecutors’ request to revoke his bond after he shared private diaries belonging to Caroline Ellison with the press was based on “thin” factual ground.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/242689\/sam-bankman-fried-claims-dojs-request-to-revoke-bail-raises-free-speech-concern","publishDate":"2023-08-02T00:22:11","id":12333,"type":null,"title":"Sam Bankman-Fried claims DoJ’s request to revoke bail raises free-speech concern","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Lawyers of former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried argued Tuesday that&nbsp;<\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/242004\/doj-sbf-revoke-bond-filing\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">prosecutors' request<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> last week to revoke his bail was based on “thin” factual basis and said such a move would violate his right to free-speech.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bankman-Fried’s attorneys <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.courtlistener.c\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said in a filing<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to a federal judge that the Department of Justice was “wrong” and that “its version of events mischaracterizes the facts and removes them from their proper context to cast Mr. Bankman-Fried’s actions and intentions in the most negative light possible.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">DoJ prosecutors last Friday <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/storage.courtlistener.com\/recap\/gov.uscourts.nysd.590940\/gov.uscourts.nysd.590940.184.0.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filed<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> a written submission in an effort to revoke Bankman-Fried's bond after the disgraced FTX founder shared private diaries written by former Alameda Research CEO Caroline Ellison with the New York Times.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“What the defendant may not do, and what he has now done repeatedly, is seek to corruptly influence witnesses and interfere with a fair trial through attempted public harassment and shaming,\" the DoJ said in the filing.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">However, Bankman-Fried’s lawyers pushed back, saying that his contact with the NYT reporter was not an attempt to intimidate Ellison or taint the jury pool.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“It was a proper exercise of his rights to make fair comment on an article already in progress, for which the reporter already had alternate sources,” his attorneys said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bankman-Fried’s defense team argued that detaining Bankman-Fried based on his communications with a reporter “raises serious First Amendment concerns.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“As the Government concedes, criminal defendants have a right to talk to the press about their case to influence their public image and try to protect their reputation, as long as the communications are not calculated to pervert the course of justice,” the filing said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bankman-Fried’s attorneys also said that detaining him at the Metropolitan Detention Center would “make it impossible for him to fully participate in his defense,” as the facility is in a “staffing crisis.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The lawyers added that the prison does not permit inmates to have internet access, which would cut him off from key parts of the discovery entirely.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Department of Justice","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ellison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"New York Times","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Caroline Ellison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NYT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Government","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Metropolitan Detention Center","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"DoJ","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}