{"summary":"Pantera Capital co-Chief Investment Officer Joey Krug has left the venture capital and investment firm, CoinDesk reported, citing a letter sent out to","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/208607\/pantera-exec-joey-krug-leaves-crypto-investment-firm-coindesk","publishDate":"2023-02-03T15:15:45","id":12331,"type":null,"title":"Pantera exec Joey Krug leaves crypto investment firm: CoinDesk","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Pantera Capital co-Chief Investment Officer Joey Krug has left the venture capital and investment firm, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/business\/2023\/02\/03\/crypto-vc-firm-pantera-loses-cio-joey-krug\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CoinDesk <\/span><\/a>reported, citing a letter sent out to partners on Friday.&nbsp;","Krug joined Pantera Capital in 2017 and oversaw the firm’s early-stage token <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/180381\/pantera-capitals-early-stage-token-fund-is-down-71-this-year-exclusive\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">fund<\/a>, which lost a considerable amount of its value last year. Krug recently <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/206821\/pantera-returns-to-altcoins-after-seeking-haven-in-bitcoin-ether\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a> 2022 was a “very brutal year for risk assets.”<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","A new executive management committee will absorb Krug’s responsibilities, Pantera founder and Chief Executive Officer Dan Morehead wrote in the letter.&nbsp;","“While Joey is a friend and we are naturally sad to see him leave, we expect the transition to be seamless,” Morehead said.","Krug and Pantera did not immediately respond to requests for comment.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"CoinDesk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Pantera Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Joey Krug","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Pantera","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Dan Morehead","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"” Morehead","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Pantera","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Krug","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Joey","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Stephanie Murray","The Block"]}