{"summary":"More crypto business and innovation should be moved into the traditional banking industry, at least according to some bankers and a former bank regulator.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/168063\/digital-assets-belong-in-traditional-banking-ex-u-s-regulator-says","publishDate":"2022-09-06T12:35:42","id":12343,"type":null,"title":"Digital assets belong in traditional banking, ex-U.S. regulator says","category":["BLOCKCHAIN"],"content":["More crypto business and innovation should be moved into the traditional banking industry, at least according to some bankers and a former bank regulator.","“The federal government doesn’t want basically unregulated third parties basically creating their own currency,” Gene Ludwig, a former top U.S. banking regulator who now runs a regulatory consultancy firm, said at the Bank Policy Institute annual conference in New York on Tuesday.","Instead of experimenting with a central bank digital currency, regulators should “allow banks to play more aggressively in the crypto market,” Ludwig said. “If we’re going to allow crypto at all, the banking industry is the right place to do it, because it is regulated.\"","But regulators might view increased exposure to digital assets warily, cautioned Jeremiah Norton, managing member of Chain Bridge Partners, a regulatory advisory firm.","“I think the coin argument is the most tricky and fraught with peril,” said Norton, with U.S. regulators telling banks, \"'If you’re thinking about thinking about crypto, come to us first.’”","“I don’t see a lot of running room for algorithmic players in the regulated space anytime soon,\" Norton said.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gene Ludwig","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Chain Bridge Partners","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Norton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ludwig","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bank Policy Institute","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jeremiah Norton","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Colin Wilhelm","The Block"]}