{"summary":"Crypto prices shrugged off the dramatic news that the CFTC sued Binance, which kicked off the week, while e new drama surrounding Arbitrum is boiling up.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/224434\/crypto-prices-steady-arbirtrumdao-drama-whats-coming-markets","publishDate":"2023-04-02T15:43:25","id":1237,"type":null,"title":"Crypto prices steady, Arbitrum DAO drama and what&#x27;s coming down the line in markets","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["Crypto prices shrugged off the Commodity Futures Trading Commission's case against Binance early in the week as bitcoin clocked its best quarter since 2021.","Bitcoin was trading at $28,200, up about 2.6% over the past week, according to Coinbase data via TradingView.&nbsp;The first quarter of the year saw bitcoin jump more than 70% as risk assets rallied, leading to its best quarter since the first of 2021.&nbsp;","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/crypto-markets\/prices\/price-performance-ytd\/embed\" title=\"Price Performance (YTD)\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Binance and CEO Changpeng Zhao are being <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/223015\/cftc-sues-binance\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">sued<\/a> by the CFTC for allegedly violating federal laws and not registering the exchange in the U.S.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> The r<\/span>egulator's move caused crypto prices to dip at the top of the week before shrugging off the news. The BNB coin fell about 3% to $314 over the past week.","Ether was up about 3.2% over the past seven days, trading around $1,800. Ripple's XRP added around 18% <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/217017\/ripple-industry-wait-to-see-if-xrp-case-will-be-a-small-splash-or-a-tsunami-for-crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">following news from its case with the SEC<\/a>, although a verdict is still some time off. Cardano's ADA added over 8%, and dogecoin jumped 7.5% in the same period.","The price of ARB fell to $1.18, down 7.2% over the past 24 hours, according to data via <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coingecko.com\/en\/coins\/arbitrum\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CoinGecko<\/a>.","The drop followed the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/224444\/arbitrum-sells-tokens-aip1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">news<\/a> that the Arbitrum Foundation had begun selling ARB tokens for stablecoins before the community had formally ratified its budget.&nbsp;","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.coingecko.com\/en\/coins\/arbitrum\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ARBUSD price chart by CoinGecko<\/span><\/a>","With the first quarter of 2023 over and done with, several <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bls.gov\/ces\/publications\/news-release-schedule.htm#:~:text=*%20The%20Employment%20Situation%20report%20is,the%2012th%20of%20the%20month.\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">key economic indicators<\/a> lie ahead in April for the U.S. Traders and the Fed will keenly watch next Friday's U.S. jobs report. Any signs of a softening labor market could impact interest rate expectations.&nbsp;","Inflation data for March on April 12 will also prove pivotal to any potential Fed pivots or pauses. An advanced estimate of first-quarter GDP will be released on April 27.&nbsp;","There's no Fed decision in April, with the next FOMC interest rate decision expected on May 3. The CME's FedWatch tool <a href=\"https:\/\/www.cmegroup.com\/markets\/interest-rates\/cme-fedwatch-tool.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">shows<\/a> markets are split on whether the Fed will pause or increase by 25 basis points again.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"70%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"8%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"TradingView","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fed","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"7.2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"3.2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Changpeng Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"April 27","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"CME","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"7.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$1,800","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"May 3","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"3%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2.6%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$314","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"April 12","content":"DATE"},{"type":"first quarter of 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$28,200","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"18%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Commodity Futures Trading Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Arbitrum Foundation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CFTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FOMC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ADA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CoinGecko","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1.18","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN","BNB","CRYPTO MOVERS","CZ","ECONOMIC INDICATORS","EQUITY MOVERS","ETHEREUM"],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}