{"summary":"Ark Invest purchased shares in Coinbase Global Inc. yesterday — the same day the United States-based crypto exchange announced that it was suing the SEC.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/228072\/cathie-wood-ark-invest-coinbase-sec-lawsuit","publishDate":"2023-04-25T03:45:23","id":12383,"type":null,"title":"Ark Invest buys nearly $8.6 million in Coinbase as exchange sues SEC","category":["EQUITIES"],"content":["Ark Invest, an American investment management firm run by CEO Cathie Wood, purchased more shares in Coinbase Global Inc. yesterday — the same day the United States-based crypto exchange <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/228047\/coinbase-sues-the-sec-for-answer-on-rule-specific-to-digital-assets\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/a> that it was suing the Securities and Exchange Commission.","The ARK Innovation ETF purchased 122,083 shares in Coinbase, while the ARK Next Generation Internet ETF added 20,327 shares, according to a trade notification shared via email. The ARK Fintech Innovation ETF, meanwhile, bought 14,633 shares.","The total value of the share purchased amounts to nearly&nbsp;$8.6 million at current prices.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Coinbase's share price is down more than 18% over the past week. Source: TradingView<\/span>","Coinbase's lawsuit against the SEC <a href=\"https:\/\/www.sec.gov\/rules\/petitions\/2022\/petn4-789.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">follows<\/a> a petition for a rulemaking that the company filed with the U.S. securities regulator last summer. It looks to force the agency to provide a yes or no to Coinbase's&nbsp;request for the commission to draft and approve a digital asset-specific rule.","\"From the SEC’s public statements and enforcement activity in the crypto industry, it seems like the SEC has already made up its mind to deny our petition,\" the company's <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coinbase.com\/blog\/coinbase-takes-another-formal-step-to-seek-regulatory-clarity-from-sec-for\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">chief legal officer Paul Grewal<\/a> wrote in a blog post about the filing. \"But they haven’t told the public yet. So the action Coinbase filed today simply asks the court to ask the SEC to share its decision.\"","Coinbase can file another lawsuit to try to make a federal court force the SEC to make a new rule — if the regulator declines.","As The Block reported earlier today, Coinbase CEO Brian Armstrong <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/228065\/coinbase-stand-with-crypto-campaign-sec\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">backed<\/a> an NFT project to signal \"unity for the crypto community seeking sensible crypto policy\" almost immediately after the exchange sued the SEC.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Coinbase Global Inc.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"TradingView","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fintech Innovation ETF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$8.6 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"18%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Brian Armstrong","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"CEO Cathie Wood","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"last summer","content":"DATE"},{"type":"United States","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Paul Grewal","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["INVESTMENT FIRMS"],"authors":["Adam James","The Block"]}