{"summary":"Solana Foundation&#x27;s Head of Strategy explains how Solana&#x27;s tech advancements are debunking myths about its architecture flaws.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/262710\/solana-breakpoint-federa","publishDate":"2023-11-12T06:47:15","id":1241,"type":null,"title":"Solana strategy exec claims work done during the bear market is paying off","category":["LAYER 1S"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 96<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 5 of The Scoop was recorded with <b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro and Solana Foundation Head of Strategy Austin Federa.<\/b><\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on <a href=\"https:\/\/www.youtube.com\/channel\/UCqjFueYMJ78eF6G0lGLzzpQ\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Youtube<\/a>, <\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a>,<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Please send feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"3c4c53585f5d4f487c4854595e50535f57125f53\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm\/?e=BLOCK7689051913\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Austin Federa is Head of Strategy at the Solana Foundation.","In this episode of The Scoop recorded live at Solana Breakpoint 2023, Federa unpacks some of Breakpoint's biggest announcements and explains how Solana builders persevered through the depths of the bear market to continue enhancing Solana's tech.","According to Federa, Solana's recent performance enhancements have rectified many of the problems that plagued Solana's performance throughout the 2021 bull run.&nbsp;","\"I think you saw a lot of 'thinkfluencers' tweeting 18 months ago that Solana's architecture was somehow fundamentally flawed and they could never get this thing stable because of 'original sins' in the code base — and like most most radical statements on Twitter, it turns out to really not be substantively true.\"","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors <a href=\"https:\/\/www.paypal.com\/crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">PayPal.<\/em><\/a><\/b><\/span>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Make your crypto move with PayPal. Get started today at <a href=\"https:\/\/www.paypal.com\/crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">PayPal.com\/crypto<\/a><\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Solana Foundation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"PayPal","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Solana Breakpoint 2023","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Austin Federa is Head of Strategy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Federa","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Solana Foundation Head of Strategy Austin Federa","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Breakpoint","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"' tweeting 18 months ago","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}