{"summary":"South Korea’s official intelligence agency said North Korean hackers remain a threat, local media reported.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/245850\/north-korean-hackers-stole-over-180-million-in-crypto-during-h1-2023-report","publishDate":"2023-08-17T05:01:50","id":12425,"type":null,"title":"North Korean hackers stole over $180 million in crypto during H1 2023: report","category":["SECURITY"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">North Korea continues to pose a significant threat in the realm of cryptocurrency exploits, as hackers from the country have illegally accumulated at least $180 million in the first six months of this year, according to the South Korean national intelligence agency.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">South Korea’s National Intelligence Service disclosed the figure during a press briefing today, as <a href=\"https:\/\/www.asiatoday.co.kr\/view.php?key=20230817010008575\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a> by local media outlet Asia Today.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">North Korean hacking organization, Lazarus Group, is among the most sought-after suspects in numerous crypto-related hacks. CoinsPaid, an entity linked to crypto payments processor Alphapo, disclosed that it endured a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/241607\/lazarus-group-suspected-by-coinspaid-of-37-million-hack\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$37 million exploit<\/a> last month, <a href=\"https:\/\/coinspaid.com\/tpost\/0zx28tmj51-coinspaid-is-back-to-processing-after-be\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">suspecting<\/a> Lazarus Group as the culprit of the attack.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The U.S. government <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/141985\/us-government-connects-north-korean-hacking-group-with-last-months-600-million-ronin-exploit\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">identified<\/a> Lazarus as the principal offender in last year’s $600 million hack on Ronin, the blockchain that operates the play-to-earn game known as Axie Infinity. This group has been involved in theft from cryptocurrency users for several years.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Lazarus","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Axie Infinity","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"South Korea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"North Korea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Lazarus Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"National Intelligence Service","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$37 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Ronin","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$600 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Asia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$180 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Alphapo","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["ANTI-MONEY LAUNDERING","EXPLOITS","HACKS"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}