{"summary":"The latest episode of The Scoop was recorded remotely with Frank Chaparro, Ryan Todd and Michael Moro, CEO at of Genesis Global Trading and Genesis Capital.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/61169\/genesis-global-trading-hit-the-brakes-on-crypto-credit-extension-and-asks-clients-to-stay-fully-collateralized","publishDate":"2020-04-07T18:04:16","id":12436,"type":null,"title":"As coronavirus anxiety sweeps markets, Genesis Capital hit the brakes on crypto credit extension","category":["BITCOIN"],"content":["<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 11 of Season 2 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with Frank Chaparro, Ryan Todd and Michael Moro, CEO at of Genesis Global Trading and Genesis Capital<\/em><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. <\/em>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/a>, or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to&nbsp;<a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection#0c7c63686f6d7f784c7864696e60636f676f7e757c7863226f6361\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"f5859a9196948681b5819d9097999a969e96878c85819adb969a98\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/span><\/a><\/em>","<iframe src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK7920929908\" width=\"100%\" height=\"200\" frameborder=\"0\" scrolling=\"no\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The cryptocurrency market continues to exhibit signs of volatility. As such, Genesis Global Trading – an institutional over-the-counter cryptocurrency trading and lending firm – decided to hit the pause button on credit extension amidst the coronavirus-tied market chaos.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Recently, Genesis has started to extend credit on a client-by-client basis but is acting gingerly in the market it helped pioneer – at least for a few weeks to figure out where the crypto credit market stands. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Moreover, while Genesis pulls back, its rivals have been willing to give out loans at significantly reduced collateral.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In this episode of the Scoop, Genesis CEO Michael Moro discusses the firm's rationale behind these critical decisions, a recent phone call it received from its regulator FINRA, and how the need for employees to work remotely has impacted its business.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Michael Moro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ryan Todd","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Genesis Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Genesis Global Trading","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FINRA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}