{"summary":"With AI-powered bots swarming social media and dominating news headlines one company asks the question: What if they had pets?","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/193147\/defense-against-an-ai-bot-apocalypse-give-them-pets","publishDate":"2022-12-07T21:14:12","id":12537,"type":null,"title":"Defense against an AI-bot apocalypse: Give them pets","category":["NFT COLLECTIONS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">One new company may have come up with our best hope of preventing AI bots from ushering in an apocalypse: Give them pets to play with.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">That’s the concept behind augmented reality start-up Anima’s new project called Onlybots, a platform where bots — or humans masquerading as bots — can obtain AR-powered virtual pets. The pets, which are also NFTs minted on Ethereum, are now trading on OpenSea. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Wednesday’s initial drop of unique AR creatures sold out almost immediately, according to Anima, causing the newly minted group of digital assets to crack OpenSea’s top 10 trending collections on its first day of availability. The company said the first two batches of about 500 pets sold out in less than an hour. At the time of writing, Openbots ranked fifth on OpenSea’s trending collections list.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“[Bots] are very much in the zeitgeist right now. Elon Musk was obsessed with them. ChatGPT is probably the biggest story in tech this week,” said Anima cofounder Alex Herrity. “But we don’t really think about ‘What do bots want? What would make them happy?’”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">After having previously worked on Fortnite, Herrity founded Anima last year with $500,000 in pre-seed financing led by Coinbase. He’s joined by cofounder Neil Voss, who worked at Nintendo in the 1990s. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">With Onlybots, human users capable of pretending to be AI bots by failing a questionnaire and reCAPTCHA can acquire chunky Lego-like, augmented-reality digital creatures that can then be superimposed over the real world using a smartphone. While technically Amina has created the pets for humans to enjoy, AI bots can also acquire the digital creatures, according to Herrity.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Although Wednesday’s initial launch quickly sold out, Anima plans to release more on top of adding additional functionality and animation based in part on what people choose to do with the virtual pets.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“This initial batch is aimed at the collectors,” said Herrity, adding that Anima’s long-term plan extends far beyond creating virtual NFT pets. He says Anima wants to build a platform people can use to create their own AR-powered digital assets.<\/span>","Whether Anima's virtual pets can save the world from a bot apocalypse remains to be seen.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Alex Herrity","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"tech this week","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Nintendo","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Herrity","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"1990s","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$500,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Elon Musk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Herrity","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"OpenSea","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Neil Voss","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Fortnite","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Anima","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["AR"],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}