{"summary":"NYDIG&#x27;s Head of Bank Solutions Patrick Sells chats with The Block&#x27;s Frank Chaparro during the latest episode of The Scoop podcast.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/112788\/nydig-is-unleashing-bitcoin-financial-products-onto-thousands-of-regional-banks","publishDate":"2021-07-28T12:24:27","id":12547,"type":null,"title":"NYDIG is unleashing bitcoin financial products onto thousands of regional banks","category":["BITCOIN"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode&nbsp;<\/i><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">43<\/strong><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> of Season 3 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block’s Frank Chaparro and Patrick Sells, Head of Bank Solutions at NYDIG.<\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"ddadb2b9bebcaea99da9b5b8bfb1b2beb6beafa4ada9b2f3beb2b0\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors&nbsp;<a href=\"http:\/\/eventussystems.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Eventus<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"http:\/\/kraken.com\/scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kraken<\/a>, and&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.exodus.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Exodus<\/a><\/strong>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Eventus is the leading global provider of multi-asset class trade surveillance, transaction monitoring and market risk solutions. Eventus offers a powerful, award-winning trade surveillance platform that is easy to deploy, customize and operate. Eventus is proven in the most complex, high-volume and real-time environments and supports many of the industry’s leading crypto exchanges including Coinbase, Gemini, ErisX and OSL. The company’s rapidly growing client base relies on Eventus’ responsive support and product development teams to overcome its most pressing regulatory challenges.<\/em>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Kraken<\/strong>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Whether you’re an experienced crypto trader or just starting out, Kraken has the tools to help you achieve financial freedom. With 50+ cryptocurrencies to choose from, industry-leading security and a wide variety of features to suit any investing strategy, Kraken puts the power in your hands to buy, sell and trade digital assets. Visit&nbsp;<\/em><a href=\"http:\/\/kraken.com\/scoop\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kraken.com<\/em><\/a><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;to get started today.<\/em>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Exodus<\/strong>","&nbsp;","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Access to bitcoin was once a case where “no one wants to be first, but everyone wants to be second”. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Now, New York Digital Investment Group, or NYDIG, won’t stop until it’s able to put bitcoin within reach of every American.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Patrick Sells, Head of Bank Solutions at NYDIG, explained during the most recent episode of The Scoop how the firm has been <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/109556\/nydig-expands-its-play-to-bridge-bitcoin-and-banking-with-new-partnerships\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">amping up its partnerships<\/a> in order to roll out their bitcoin products now that there is interest being expressed from regional banks. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">To that end, NYDIG has teamed up with banking service providers, <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">including NCR, Alkami, Fiserv, Allied Payment, Q2, First Foundation, and others.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“I think if we kind of pause today and you fast forward to 12 months, you would see over a thousand institutions rolling out NYDIG products,\" he said, referring to the results these partnerships will yield. \"I think we'll see that number grow as we move forward through the next 12 months.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Much of what NYDIG has offered to banks is centered around bitcoin purchases, but the ambitions appear to be broader. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sells discussed NYDIG’s ability to offer credit card solutions and retail lending. Sells said they could offer a service that converts unused hotel points into bitcoin <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“allowing people to have points and convert those to Bitcoin, that's in some ways the lowest friction path possible from an entry point standpoint or from allowing gift cards to be converted into Bitcoin.\"<\/span>","He went on to say:","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“I think there's a lot in this space that we're working on to be able to power a range of these types of kind of interesting and innovative loyalty and rewards programs. And also even like bringing the gamification, which we could talk about, like how corporates are thinking about using Bitcoin in that regard.”<\/span>","NYDIG is working on providing a way to make it easier for clients to leverage their bitcoin holdings to get approved for loans, according to Sells. Today, most lenders don't consider bitcoin as collateral or a traditional asset.&nbsp;","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">As Sells put it: \"Any type of fiat financing for a home, a car, a line of credit, whatever, credit underwriting doesn't take into account your bitcoin, right?\"&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Patrick Sells","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Fiserv","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alkami","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gemini","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"First Foundation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NYDIG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kraken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"OSL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NCR","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"New York Digital Investment Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Head of Bank Solutions","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN"],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}