{"summary":"When now-defunct crypto exchange FTX acquired the portfolio tracking platform Blockfolio in 2020, it reportedly used its own exchange token, FTT, to fund the takeover.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/197397\/ftx-blockfolio-ftt","publishDate":"2022-12-22T05:10:11","id":12541,"type":null,"title":"FTX funded 94% of Blockfolio takeover with its FTT token: Bloomberg","category":["MERGERS & ACQUISITIONS"],"content":["When now-defunct crypto exchange FTX acquired the portfolio tracking platform Blockfolio in 2020, it used its own exchange token, FTT, to fund the takeover, according to Bloomberg.","Roughly 94% of the $84 million deal was paid in FTT tokens — which FTX created — Bloomberg <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2022-12-22\/ftx-paid-for-blockfolio-deal-mostly-in-ftt-token-it-invented\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a>, citing financial statements it obtained.&nbsp;","The financial details of FTX's purchase of Blockfolio were previously unclear, though it was widely reported at the time that the exchange paid with a combination of cash, crypto and equity.","The news follows a late complaint yesterday from the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission which <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/197387\/ftx-ftt-token-security-sec\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">claims<\/a> FTT is a security. It&nbsp;specifically noted that FTX used proceeds from the FTT token sale to fund its business efforts.","FTX co-founder and former CEO Sam Bankman-Fried is currently in FBI custody <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/197342\/bankman-fried-in-fbi-custody-ellison-wang-plead-guilty-and-are-cooperating\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">following<\/a> a barrage of charges. Additionally, FTX co-founder Gary Wang and Caroline Ellison, the former CEO of sister trading firm Alameda Research, have both pleaded guilty to criminal charges.","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Caroline Ellison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"94%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$84 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"FBI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gary Wang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["FTX","PRIVATE COMPANY M&AMP;A"],"authors":["Adam James","The Block"]}