{"summary":"Financial institutions need to be on the lookout for suspicious activity connected to financing terrorist organizations, officials said.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/258785\/fincen-issues-warning-about-virtual-currency-being-used-to-finance-terrorist-organizations","publishDate":"2023-10-20T13:45:58","id":12549,"type":null,"title":"FinCEN issues warning about virtual currency being used to finance terrorist organizations","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Financial institutions need to be on the lookout for suspicious activity connected to financing terrorist organizations, such as Hamas, the Treasury Department said in an alert.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Treasury Department's Financial Crimes Enforcement Network issued that <a href=\"https:\/\/www.fincen.gov\/sites\/default\/files\/2023-10\/FinCEN_Alert_Terrorist_Financing_FINAL508.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">warning<\/span><\/a> on Friday, citing Hamas' reliance on \"fundraising campaigns involving virtual currency and fictitious charities raising both fiat and virtual currency.\"&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">FinCEN also said that virtual asset service providers should report suspicious transactions linked to Hamas as soon as possible.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"As part of a whole-of-government response, the U.S. Department of the Treasury (Treasury) is taking all steps necessary, including by issuing this Alert and engaging with foreign counterparts, to deny Hamas the ability to raise and use funds worldwide,\" FinCEN said.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The warning comes shortly after a report from the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.wsj.com\/world\/middle-east\/militants-behind-israel-attack-raised-millions-in-crypto-b9134b7a?mod=e2tw\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">WSJ<\/span><\/a> said that Hamas, along with other militant groups, used <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/257914\/reports-of-hamas-crypto-use-could-blunt-impact-of-coinbase-lobbying-efforts-berenberg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">crypto as a financing tool<\/span><\/a> ahead of attacks in Israel earlier this month. Sen. Elizabeth Warren, D-Mass., along with more than a hundred other lawmakers including both Democrats and Republicans, said they were concerned about how Hamas raised millions of dollars through crypto in a letter sent to the Biden administration on Tuesday.&nbsp;<\/span>","Chainalysis&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/258284\/chainalysis-says-some-reports-might-be-overestimating-cryptos-role-in-terrorist-financing\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said Wednesday<\/a>&nbsp;that some recent reports about the supposed use of crypto by terrorist groups might be overstating metrics and using \"flawed analyses.\"","\"Terrorist organizations have historically used and will likely continue to use traditional, fiat-based methods such as financial institutions, hawalas, and shell companies as their primary financing vehicles,\" it wrote.","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">FinCEN announced a notice of proposed rulemaking on Thursday that would label crypto mixers as a money laundering concern, in an effort to combat bad actors including Hamas, <\/span><span class=\"s5\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Palestinian Islamic Jihad and the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea<\/span><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, according to a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.fincen.gov\/news\/news-releases\/fincen-proposes-new-regulation-enhance-transparency-convertible-virtual-currency\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">statement<\/span><\/a>.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"This is FinCEN’s first ever use of the Section 311 authority to target a class of transactions of primary money laundering concern, and, just as with our efforts in the traditional financial system, Treasury will work to identify and root out the illicit use and abuse of the CVC ecosystem,\" said &nbsp;FinCEN Director Andrea Gacki on Thursday.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Written comments on the proposal are due within 90 days.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S. Department of the Treasury (Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mass.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"fiat","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Andrea Gacki","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"WSJ","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Korea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"CVC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FinCEN","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Treasury Department","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hamas","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hamas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Israel","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"millions of dollars","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Treasury Department's Financial Crimes Enforcement Network","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Biden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Elizabeth Warren","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["CRIME","SANCTIONS"],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}