{"summary":"Lawmakers wrote a letter to Board of Governors Vice Chair Lael Brainard on Wednesday, asking for clarification the Fed&#x27;s thinking around a potential digital dollar, including whether curtailing the use of digital assets is part of the Fed&#x27;s motivation.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/168637\/house-republicans-press-fed-on-digital-dollar","publishDate":"2022-09-08T11:03:00","id":12577,"type":null,"title":"House Republicans press Fed on digital dollar","category":["POLICY"],"content":["Republicans on the House Financial Services Committee want more information from the Federal Reserve System on a potential US Central Bank Digital Currency, ahead of a deadline set by President Joe Biden’s executive order on digital assets.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","Lawmakers wrote a <a href=\"https:\/\/republicans-financialservices.house.gov\/uploadedfiles\/2022-09-07_fsc_gop_letter_to_vice_chair_brainard_final_final.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">letter<\/span><\/a> to Board of Governors Vice Chair Lael Brainard on Wednesday, asking for clarification the Fed's thinking around a potential digital dollar, including whether curtailing the use of digital assets is part of the Fed's motivation.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","Brainard testified in May on the potential impacts of a Fed-issued digital currency. She told a banking industry conference on Wednesday that the central bank still <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/168366\/fed-needs-to-answer-key-questions-around-digital-dollar-brainard\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">needs to answer key questions<\/a> around the possible creation of a digital dollar and suggested that a decision was not imminent.&nbsp;&nbsp;","The lawmakers, led by the committee's top Republican Rep. Patrick McHenry (R-N.C.), want more information on whether Fed leadership believes it needs Congressional approval to move forward with a digital dollar, and whether the Fed would create accounts for individual Americans a move that could significantly disrupt the banking industry.&nbsp;","During her May testimony, Brainard said that the Fed would need support from Congress and the executive branch to issue a digital currency. Republicans signing the letter pressed for an explicit answer as to whether that meant the Fed thought a digital dollar would require a new law from Congress.&nbsp;","“In your opinion, does support mean an explicit law from Congress authorizing the Fed to issue a digital currency?,” the lawmakers wrote.","The officials requested Brainard respond in writing by Sept. 30.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Board of Governors","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fed","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Lael Brainard","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Congress","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Patrick McHenry","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"US Central Bank Digital Currency","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sept. 30","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Brainard","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Federal Reserve System","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"House Financial Services Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Joe Biden","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["HOUSE FINANCIAL SERVICES COMMITTEE"],"authors":["Stephanie Murray","The Block"]}