{"summary":"Prime Trust and some of its affiliates have filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection, the company said today.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/244875\/crypto-custodian-prime-trust-files-for-bankruptcy-protection","publishDate":"2023-08-14T22:17:00","id":12583,"type":null,"title":"Crypto custodian Prime Trust files for bankruptcy protection","category":["BANKRUPTCY"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto custodian Prime Trust LLC and some of its affiliates have filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection in the U.S. Bankruptcy Court for the District of Delaware, the company said today.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.businesswire.com\/news\/home\/20230814192136\/en\/Prime-Trust-LLC-Files-Voluntary-Chapter-11-Petitions\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">statement<\/a>, Prime Trust said the filing follows the appointment of John Guedry as receiver for the company and the appointment of John Guedry, John Wilcox, and Michael Wyse as the sole members of a special restructuring committee.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Las Vegas-based company said it continues to manage its business as “debtors-in-possession” under the supervision and direction of the special committee.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“The Company intends to file a number of motions with the Bankruptcy Court designed to facilitate the Company’s orderly evaluation of all strategic alternatives, including potentially a sale of the Company’s assets and operations as a going concern,” Prime Trust said, adding that these motions may include requests to continue to pay wages and provide benefits to ongoing employees as usual.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The company’s <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/cases.stretto.com\/public\/X274\/12458\/PLEADINGS\/1245808152380000000027.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filing<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> showed that Prime Trust’s estimated liabilities amounted to between $100 million and $500 million, with estimated assets worth of $50 million to $100 million. The number of its creditors came in between 25,001 and 50,000, according to the filing.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The entities filed for bankruptcy protection were Prime Trust LLC, Prime Core Technologies Inc., Prime IRA LLC and Prime Digital, LLC, the filing showed.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Prime Trust began offering services to crypto firms in 2018, but it has recently <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/236014\/bitgo-says-its-terminating-acquisition-of-prime-trust\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">lost some clients<\/a>, including crypto exchange Binance.US, which was sued by the Securities and Exchange Commission earlier this year.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The company’s leadership recently tried to sell the firm, but those efforts stalled. In June, crypto custodian BitGo <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/233878\/bitgo-reaches-deal-to-buy-crypto-custodian-prime-trust-coindesk\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that it had reached a preliminary deal to acquire Prime Trust but <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/236014\/bitgo-says-its-terminating-acquisition-of-prime-trust\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">retracted<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> the decision two weeks later.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Also in June, <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">fiat onramp service Stably said in a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/support.stably.io\/en\/articles\/8039846-prime-trust-halting-deposit-withdrawal?_ga=2.224471130.1963557396.1687454592-813931187.1687454592&amp;_gl=1*1iirsmx*_ga*ODEzOTMxMTg3LjE2ODc0NTQ1OTI.*_ga_R2T8PD7439*MTY4NzQ1NDU5Mi4xLjEuMTY4NzQ1NDcxMS41My4wLjA.\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">notice<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that Prime Trust had to halt deposits and withdrawals of both fiat and cryptocurrency following an order from the Nevada Financial Institution Division, The Block previously <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/236042\/prime-trust-halted-deposits-withdrawals-after-order-from-nevada-regulator\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Updates to add more details.<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S. Bankruptcy Court","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bankruptcy Court","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Las Vegas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$100 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"LLC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"today","content":"DATE"},{"type":"John Wilcox","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Prime Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Prime Trust LLC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$500 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Michael Wyse","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"District of Delaware","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"” Prime Trust","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Prime Core Technologies Inc.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"June","content":"DATE"},{"type":"John Guedry","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nevada Financial Institution Division","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Prime IRA LLC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Prime Trust","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$50 million","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["BANKRUPTCY FILINGS"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}