{"summary":"Trading firm Alameda Research is launching a permissioned pool in Clearpool&#x27;s ecosystem.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/171630\/hold-alameda-research-joins-clearpools-permissioned-pool-ecosystem","publishDate":"2022-09-22T09:00:20","id":12588,"type":null,"title":"Alameda Research joins Clearpool’s permissioned pool ecosystem","category":["INSTITUTIONAL INVESTORS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto trading firm Alameda Research is launching a permissioned borrower pool on Clearpool.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Investment management firm Apollo Capital and decentralized finance (DeFi) trading platform Compound Capital will be the first lenders to contribute to the Alameda pool, according to a statement from Clearpool today.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Clearpool offers liquidity for decentralized marketplaces, focused on institutional capital. Their permissioned pools are adapted for borrowers and lenders with higher know-your-customer (KYC) requirements.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Proprietary trading firm Jane Street and institutional investment company BlockTower are already part of Clearpool’s permissioned pool ecosystem in a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/news+\/147301\/meet-clearpool-the-lending-platform-at-the-forefront-of-defi-2-0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">partnership<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that was announced in May.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“The demand for KYC-compliant lending and borrowing is increasing and Clearpool is leading the way with its sophisticated blockchain-enabled infrastructure,” Jakob Kronbichler, chief commercial officer and co-founder of Clearpool, said in the press release.&nbsp;<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We have a long pipeline of lenders and borrowers ready to join the Clearpool ecosystem with our new permissioned pool product soon ready to launch.”<\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Clearpool","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Jakob Kronbichler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Apollo Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jane Street","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}