{"summary":"The crypto custodian is launching its services in Hong Kong as it continues to expand in Asia-Pacific, CNBC reported.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/259947\/standard-chartered-backed-zodia-custody-expands-in-hong-kong-report","publishDate":"2023-10-30T00:16:38","id":12597,"type":null,"title":"Standard Chartered backed-Zodia Custody expands in Hong Kong: report","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Zodia Custody, <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">a Standard Chartered-backed digital asset custodian, is launching its services in Hong Kong.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CNBC <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.cnbc.com\/2023\/10\/30\/standard-chartered-owned-crypto-firm-zodia-launches-in-hong-kong.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> today that the UK-headquartered firm is making a foray into the Hong Kong market, following recent expansion in other jurisdictions in the Asia Pacific region.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Julian Sawyer, chief executive officer of Zodia, told the media outlet that Hong Kong’s large demand from institutions makes it an ideal market to target.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Earlier this month, Zodia said that it had&nbsp;<\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/257697\/zodia-custody-expands-institutional-digital-asset-services-to-australia\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">expanded its institutional services to Australia<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. The company said in a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/zodia.io\/zodia-custody-launches-saf3-in-australia\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">statement<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> at the time that its platform will serve as a portal connecting institutions to digital asset exchanges and enabling the secure storage of their assets in bank-grade cold wallet storage.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Last month, Zodia announced that it has started to <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/250383\/zodia-custody-to-offer-institutional-grade-digital-asset-services-in-singapore\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">offer institutional-grade digital asset services in Singapore<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to tap into the country’s growing digital asset market.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Zodia Custody, backed by Standard Chartered, SBI Holdings and Northern Trust, is also registered with the UK’s Financial Conduct Authority.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Hong Kong in June launched its crypto retail trading licensing scheme in an attempt to position itself as a major crypto hub in Asia. Earlier this month, Hong Kong’s <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/254862\/hong-kong-police-sfc-form-task-force-to-track-suspicious-crypto-activities-amid-jpex-probes\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Securities and Futures Commission<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> said that it has <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/258733\/hong-kong-regulator-updates-policy-for-virtual-asset-activities\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">updated its regulatory framework<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> with two additional investor protection measures.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"UK’s Financial Conduct Authority","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Zodia","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SBI Holdings and Northern Trust","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Asia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Zodia","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Futures Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Australia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"June","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Zodia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Julian Sawyer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Asia Pacific","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Standard Chartered","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["SECURITY FIRMS","WALLET MAKERS","WALLETS"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}