{"summary":"The Sandbox and Saudi Arabia signed a memorandum of understanding but without revealing details explaining the scope of the agreement. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/209458\/saudi-arabia-the-sandbox-agree-to-collaborate-on-metaverse-projects","publishDate":"2023-02-07T15:59:23","id":12596,"type":null,"title":"Saudi Arabia, The Sandbox agree to collaborate on metaverse projects","category":["METAVERSE & NFT"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Metaverse gaming platform The Sandbox and Saudi Arabia have come to an understanding of some sort. Details were not provided. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sandbox co-founder and COO Sebastien Borget took to LinkedIn to announce the news. “It was a true honor to sign our [memorandum of understanding] partnership … between The Sandbox and the Saudi Arabia Digital Government Authority,” he wrote. “We look forward to exploring, advising and supporting mutually each other in activations of the Metaverse!”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Borget and Saudi Arabia’s DGA inked the memorandum while attending the Leap Tech Conference in the Saudi capital of Riyadh. Borget said by email that he could not reveal anything further regarding his company’s agreement with the Saudi Arabian government, but details would be forthcoming in the “coming weeks.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">While Sandbox has yet to achieve anything close to mass adoption, it is considered by many executives and investors to be an early leader in the development of the metaverse. The digital platform is a virtual space where users ​​<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">can create their own mini-universe inside the game.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The company raised $93 million in a Series B round led by SoftBank's Vision Fund in 2021 and then less than six months later was said to be <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/142466\/the-sandbox-gears-up-to-raise-400-million-at-a-4-billion-valuation-report\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">trying to raise<\/a> an additional $400 million, for a valuation of $4 billion.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In the Middle East, both <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/167798\/saudi-arabias-central-bank-hires-former-accenture-exec-as-crypto-chief\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Saudi Arabia<\/a> and the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/158413\/dubais-metaverse-strategy-plans-to-add-4-billion-to-economy-by-2027\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">United Arab Emirates<\/a> have, in recent years, been pursuing policies and investments related to cryptocurrency, web3 and the metaverse. The Saudi Arabian DGA “is the authority concerned with everything related to digital government,” according to a government website.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Saudi Arabia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Middle East","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"then less than six months later","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Saudi","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$4 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Riyadh","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SoftBank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"COO Sebastien Borget","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$93 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"United Arab Emirates","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Leap Tech Conference","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$400 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Saudi Arabia Digital Government Authority","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Saudi Arabian DGA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DGA","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["THE SANDBOX"],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}