{"summary":"Teraform Labs CEO Do Kwon is also facing fines for alleged tax evasion, according to local media reports.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/147606\/south-korea-investigates-financial-crimes-crypto-terra-luna-kwon-crash","publishDate":"2022-05-18T11:11:53","id":12617,"type":null,"title":"South Korea revives &#x27;Grim Reaper&#x27; financial crimes unit to investigate Terra&#x27;s collapse","category":["ASIA"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A specialized financial crimes unit has been tasked with investigating last week’s collapse of the Terra blockchain’s main cryptocurrencies while founder Do Kwon faces hefty tax fines, according to South Korean media reports.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The group, consisting of prosecutors and employees from the Financial Services Commission and the Financial Supervisory Service, will investigate the methods Terraform Labs used to attract investors, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/news.sbs.co.kr\/news\/endPage.do?news_id=N1006755351&amp;plink=ORI&amp;cooper=NAVER\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">SBS News<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> reported on Wednesday.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The unit’s accuracy and clinical approach has earned it the nickname \"Yeouido Grim Reaper,\" after the Yeouido financial district of Seoul. It is coming back into operation to investigate Terra after being disbanded two years ago, according to SBS News.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/146444\/terra-luna-and-ust-how-we-got-here\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Terra ecosystem fell into chaos<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> last week after its stablecoin offering, TerraUSD (UST), de-pegged — causing the price of Terra’s native token Luna to plummet in value as supply soared to protect the peg. Kwon is now <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/147558\/do-kwon-puts-his-terra-revival-plan-to-the-vote\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">proposing<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> forking Terra to revive the network.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A <a href=\"https:\/\/n.news.naver.com\/mnews\/article\/015\/0004700627?sid=101\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">separate report<\/a> in Edaily said Kwon is facing a tax bill of 100 billion won ($78 million) for evading corporate and income tax payments.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The investigation related to the formation of the Luna Foundation Guard (LFG) in Singapore, a relocation of the company's headquarters which appeared to be for tax purposes, according to Edaily.&nbsp;<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">It found that despite the legal entity relocating to Singapore, LFGs management continues to be carried out by domestic companies and residents in South Korea.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Korean tax authorities are also preparing a separate 100 billion won fine to LFG, according to the report.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kwon and LFG didn’t immediately respond to requests from The Block to comment on the reports. <\/span>","<i data-stringify-type=\"italic\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">For more breaking stories like this, make sure to follow The Block on&nbsp;<\/i><i data-stringify-type=\"italic\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a class=\"c-link\" tabindex=\"-1\" href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/TheBlock__\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-stringify-link=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/TheBlock__\" data-sk=\"tooltip_parent\" data-remove-tab-index=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Twitter<\/a><\/i><i data-stringify-type=\"italic\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/i>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"SBS News","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"South Korea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Luna Foundation Guard","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Financial Services Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Financial Supervisory Service","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kwon","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Edaily","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"LFG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"100 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Terra","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$78 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"UST","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Seoul","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"two years ago","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["DO KWON"],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}