{"summary":"Sam Bankman-Fried’s attorneys want to ask him about the involvement of lawyers in FTX’s operations as part of his testimony, a Wednesday filing showed.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/259570\/sbfs-attorneys-want-to-quiz-him-about-ftxs-lawyers-to-demonstrate-good-faith","publishDate":"2023-10-26T03:06:07","id":12619,"type":null,"title":"SBF’s attorneys want to quiz him about FTX’s lawyers to demonstrate ‘good faith’","category":["PEOPLE"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sam Bankman-Fried’s lawyers have asked permission to quiz the failed crypto exchange founder on the involvement of FTX’s counsel in certain operations, with Bankman-Fried&nbsp;<\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/259447\/former-ftx-ceo-sam-bankman-fried-will-take-the-stand-on-thursday\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">expected to testify starting Thursday<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.courtlistener.com\/docket\/66631291\/338\/united-states-v-bankman-fried\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">letter<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> submitted to Judge Lewis A. Kaplan, Bankman-Fried’s attorneys also asked to elicit testimony on his knowledge of certain industry practices, and his “intentions and beliefs on November 12, 2022, to rebut the inferences from <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/255661\/sbfs-lawyers-want-to-cross-examine-gary-wang-on-300-million-in-alameda-loans\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Gary Wang’s testimony<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that Mr. Bankman-Fried directed the transfer of assets to Bahamian regulators on that date, over the objections of FTX’s in-house and outside legal counsel, in an effort to retain control of FTX.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Specifically, the defense team noted that the prosecutors have argued that the use of auto-deletion policies is evidence of Bankman-Fried’s fraudulent and criminal intent. In response, his lawyers said that his understanding that auto-deletion policies were “instituted under the guidance of lawyers” would be directly relevant to rebutting the inference.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The defense attorneys also said that Bankman-Fried’s understanding as to the involvement of counsel in the formation of the North Dimension entities and opening of its account at Silvergate Bank would be “directly relevant to his good faith belief that there was nothing improper about using Alameda-controlled entities to accept FTX customer deposits.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">His lawyers also intend to ask him about his knowledge that lawyers were involved in structuring and documenting the loans made from Alameda to FTX executives.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“At a minimum, Mr. Bankman-Fried should be permitted [to] testify in his defense regarding the involvement of counsel on these topics to counter any implication from the testimony elicited to date that he failed to act in good faith with respect to these matters,” his defense team said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Meanwhile, Judge Kaplan <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.courtlistener.com\/docket\/66631291\/339\/united-states-v-bankman-fried\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">denied<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on Wednesday a request from Bankman-Fried’s lawyers to <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/259446\/sbf-lawyers-want-help-from-fbi-agents-as-they-seek-to-shift-narrative-in-court\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">have FBI special agents Luke Booth and Kristin Allain testify<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in court on Thursday.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The defense <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.courtlistener.com\/docket\/66631291\/332\/united-states-v-bankman-fried\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">FTX’s former co-founder Gary Wang and head of engineering Nishad Singh testified inconsistently with what they earlier told the FBI. <\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Silvergate Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Kaplan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nishad Singh","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FBI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Luke Booth","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kristin Allain","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Lewis A. Kaplan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"North Dimension entities","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gary Wang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"November 12, 2022","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["FTX","SAM BANKMAN-FRIED","SBF TRIAL"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}