{"summary":"OKX’s chief marketing officer told the media outlet that it’s exploring possibilities to expand into India — despite regulatory uncertainties.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/248618\/crypto-exchange-okx-plans-to-enter-india-hire-local-staff-coindesk","publishDate":"2023-09-01T00:07:57","id":12635,"type":null,"title":"Crypto exchange OKX plans to enter India, hire local staff: CoinDesk","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Cryptocurrency exchange OKX is planning to enter India and hire local staff despite regulatory uncertainties, CoinDesk <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/business\/2023\/09\/01\/okx-planning-web3-foray-into-india-chief-marketing-officer-says\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> today.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Haider Rafique, chief marketing officer of OKX, told the publication that it intends to expand its wallet services by tapping into the country’s developer community, adding that OKX currently has about 200,000 wallet users there. That’s about 5% of India’s web3 users, according to the report.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Rafique said that regulators are more concerned about venues that have fiat on-ramps, “which we do but we don't offer it in India,” adding that once India launches a crypto regulatory framework then “we would like to be the front runners.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">OKX did not immediately respond to The Block’s request for comment.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">While OKX seems optimistic about the outlook in India, regulatory uncertainty remains in the country. Authorities in the country&nbsp;<\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/132552\/india-crypto-tax-30-budget-cbdc-blockchain\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">imposed stiff taxes on crypto gains last year<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> but has not explicitly declared cryptocurrency legal.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Earlier this year, India, as head of the G20 group of nations, released an input note <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/242731\/india-uses-g20-presidency-to-strengthen-global-crypto-regulation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">proposing a path for the development<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> of globally coordinated rules for crypto assets.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In July, the Indian Supreme Court reportedly <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/241983\/india-supreme-court-crypto-regulation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">directed the Union government to record<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> whether or not it intends to establish a federal agency to investigate crypto-related criminal cases, according to Hindustan Times.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">While India’s stance on crypto remains unclear, <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">the Reserve Bank of India <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/175519\/indias-central-bank-to-launch-digital-rupee-pilot\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">continues to study and develop its central bank digital currency<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> — the so-called digital rupee.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"the Reserve Bank of India","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"G20","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Union","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Hindustan Times","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Indian Supreme Court","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"OKX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Rafique","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"India","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Haider Rafique","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["ASIAN REGULATION","OKX"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}