{"summary":"Global asset management firm Brevan Howard is taking over a hedge fund spun off from crypto investment company Dragonfly Capital.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/219012\/brevan-howard-takes-over-dragonfly-capital-crypto-fund-bloomberg","publishDate":"2023-03-11T06:14:19","id":12658,"type":null,"title":"Brevan Howard takes over Dragonfly Capital Crypto Fund: Bloomberg","category":["DEALS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Global asset management firm Brevan Howard is taking over a hedge fund spun off from crypto investment company Dragonfly Capital.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Brevan Howard, which manages more than $30 billion in assets, has entered into an agreement to assume control of Dragonfly’s “Liquid Opportunities” fund, according to unidentified people cited by Bloomberg.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The long-short strategy fund was established in June 2021 and managed by Kevin Hu, Ashwin Ramachandran and Lawrence Diao. Hu’s LinkedIn profile describes his current role as Chief Investment Officer at Nova Digital, a Brevan Howard fund. Liquid Opportunities will operate under Brevan Howard’s crypto and digital assets division, compatible with its active trading approach, Bloomberg reported, citing people familiar with the matter.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">An internal Dragonfly document reviewed by Bloomberg said: “After extensive discussions, we decided that Brevan Howard, one of the largest hedge funds in the world, was the right long-term home for Kevin and his team.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kevin Hu’s move from Dragonfly to Brevan Howard, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/206421\/bh-digital-didnt-just-get-dragonflys-head-of-liquid-strategies-it-got-the-whole-team\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">alongside<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> the rest of its liquid strategies team, was <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/205982\/investment-firm-brevan-howard-adds-senior-leader-to-crypto-division\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> by The Block in January, with a focus on investing in listed digital assets based out of the firm’s new Abu Dhabi office.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"June 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Kevin Hu’s","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kevin Hu","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kevin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ashwin Ramachandran","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nova Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Brevan Howard","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Abu Dhabi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Dragonfly","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Brevan Howard","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Brevan Howard’s crypto","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dragonfly Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$30 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Lawrence Diao","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["ASSET MANAGERS","BLACKROCK","DRAGONFLY CAPITAL","HEDGE FUNDS","INVESTMENT FIRMS","NEW VC FUNDS"],"authors":["James Hunt","The Block"]}