{"summary":"The hottest trends in policy and regulation get broken down on The Scoop.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/225817\/gensler-sec-binance-cftc-bankman-fried","publishDate":"2023-04-12T05:00:52","id":12671,"type":null,"title":"Gensler’s SEC gamble, Binance vs the CFTC, who takes Bankman-Fried’s place in Washington: The Scoop","category":["POLICY"],"content":["Policy and regulation in the U.S. is top of mind in the industry of crypto and digital assets. The Scoop's Frank Chaparro sat down with The Block's policy reporter <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/author\/stephanie-murray\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stephanie Murray<\/a> and broke down the biggest stories and trends from Gary Gensler's big bet against crypto to CBDCs and who takes Sam Bankman-Fried's place in Washington, DC.","From the collapse of FTX, Blockfi, Voyager, Celsius and others, to the aggressive stance regulators are displaying, it's been busy in Washington.","\"We went from big bull market to the collapse of some of the biggest crypto firms that sent ripples through the entire industry,\" Murray said.&nbsp;","\"It's definitely impacted me. And Stephanie, I mean, most of the companies I wrote about are now bankrupt or are out of business, about 50% from Blockfi to FTX to Celsius,\" Chaparro said. \"I'm gonna have to hope on the policy beat, I don't really have much to do these days!\"","For all his faults, Chaparro noted that Sam Bankman-Fried, the disgraced founder of bankrupt FTX, stepped up to represent the industry in Washington, DC, to agitate for change. Chaparro cited Coinbase's Brian Armstrong and Kraken's Jesse Powell as leaders who, while not running apparent frauds, are antagonistic to politicians and may not be great replacements.","\"Whereas Sam was not antagonistic to regulators, but ran a fraud. So what we need is someone who doesn't operate a fraud, and who is not antagonistic to regulators. So there's a Venn diagram there, and somewhere there is a CEO or a figurehead who can fill the gap,\" Chaparro said.&nbsp;","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 35<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 5 of The Scoop was recorded with&nbsp;<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro and The Block's Stephanie Murray.<\/strong><\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a>,<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or wherever you listen to podcasts. Feedback and revision requests can be sent to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"e5958a8186849691a5918d8087898a868e86979c95918acb868a88\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm\/?e=BLOCK9021726591\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors&nbsp;<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"http:\/\/circle.com\/Scoop\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Circle<\/a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.cleanspark.com\/theblock\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CleanSpark<\/a>.<\/i><\/b><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Circle<\/strong>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Circle is a global financial technology company helping money move at internet speed. Our mission is to raise global economic prosperity through the frictionless exchange of value. Visit&nbsp;<a class=\"c-link\" href=\"http:\/\/circle.com\/Scoop\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-stringify-link=\"http:\/\/Circle.com\/Scoop\" data-sk=\"tooltip_parent\" aria-describedby=\"sk-tooltip-398\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">circle.com\/Scoop<\/a>&nbsp;to learn more.<\/em>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About CleanSpark<\/strong>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CleanSpark (NASDAQ: CLSK) is America’s Bitcoin Miner™. Visit&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.cleanspark.com\/theblock\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">cleanspark.com\/theblock<\/a>&nbsp;to learn more about the CleanSpark way.<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Stephanie Murray","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"50%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Kraken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gary Gensler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Brian Armstrong","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"DC","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Washington","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Murray","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"America","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Voyager","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jesse Powell","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Blockfi","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Celsius","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Stephanie","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"the U.S.","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Christiana Loureiro","The Block"]}