{"summary":"The Series A round is led by Liberty City Ventures, alongside some notable angels.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/217659\/serial-entrepreneur-and-ex-diplomat-trevor-traina-raises-25-million-for-goof-proof-web3-superapp","publishDate":"2023-03-07T08:30:45","id":12674,"type":null,"title":"Serial entrepreneur and ex diplomat Trevor Traina raises $25 million for &#x27;goof-proof&#x27; web3 superapp","category":["DEALS"],"content":["Serial entrepreneur Trevor Traina has raised $25 million to build Kresus, a web3 superapp for the everyday consumer that <a href=\"https:\/\/www.kresus.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">promises<\/a> to be \"entirely goof-proof.\"","The Series A round is led by Liberty City Ventures. Other investors in the round include JetBlue Ventures, Craft Ventures, Franklin Templeton as well as angel investors such as Salesforce founder Marc Benioff and the Winklevoss twins, who founded the crypto exchange Gemini, said the company in an email.","Traina, who is the son of shipping magnate and art collector John Traina, is a veteran in the startup space. He has founded five technology companies including IfOnly, an online marketplace that <a href=\"https:\/\/techcrunch.com\/2020\/08\/24\/mastercard-acquired-and-shut-down-ifonly-an-experiences-marketplace-hit-by-covid-19\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">curates<\/a> exclusive experiences which he sold to Mastercard in 2019, and <a href=\"https:\/\/investors.intuit.com\/news\/news-details\/2006\/Intuit-Acquires-StepUp-Commerce\/default.aspx\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">StepUp Commerce<\/a>, a service that aims to convert online shoppers to in-store customers which he sold to Intuit in 2006. Former U.S. President Donald Trump <a href=\"https:\/\/trumpwhitehouse.archives.gov\/presidential-actions\/president-donald-j-trump-announces-intent-nominate-trevor-traina-california-ambassador-extraordinary-plenipotentiary-united-states-america-republic-austria\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">nominated<\/a> Traina to be&nbsp; the U.S. ambassador to the republic of Austria from March 2018 to January 2021.","Kresus's <a href=\"https:\/\/www.kresus.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">website<\/a> describes the app, which hasn't launched yet, as \"part exchange, part wallet and part guide.\"","The funds will be used for continuing to build out the app and enable hiring efforts and key partnerships, the company said.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Winklevoss twins","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Austria","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Traina","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2006","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Mastercard","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Craft Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"January 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"John Traina","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Liberty City Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Intuit","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Donald Trump","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Marc Benioff","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"crypto exchange Gemini","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"StepUp Commerce","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"March 2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$25 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Salesforce","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"JetBlue Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Franklin Templeton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Trevor Traina","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["CAMERON &AMP; TYLER WINKELVOSS","SERIES A"],"authors":["Kari McMahon","The Block"]}