{"summary":"FTX previously stored private keys without encryption, the new FTX chief John Ray III said.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/194706\/ftx-stored-private-keys-without-encryption-the-exchanges-new-chief-said","publishDate":"2022-12-13T14:40:19","id":12691,"type":null,"title":"FTX stored private keys without encryption, the exchange&#x27;s new chief said","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["FTX previously stored private keys to crypto wallets without encryption during Sam Bankman Fried's reign, leaving \"hundreds of millions of dollars\" vulnerable to theft or other malicious activity.&nbsp;","The revelation was part of the prepared <a href=\"https:\/\/financialservices.house.gov\/uploadedfiles\/hhrg-117-ba00-wstate-rayj-20221213.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">testimony<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to the U.S. House Financial Services Committee from from new Chief Executive John Ray III, who said<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;he <\/span>took steps to secure more than $1 billion worth of digital assets.&nbsp;","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Private keys are used to access and authorized funds held in crypto wallets, and they must be carefully stored on systems that simultaneously leverage encryption technology. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">When private keys are stored in an unencrypted fashion, they may have exposed the now-collapsed cryptocurrency exchange to unauthorized transfers, security experts say.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“FTX storing private keys unencrypted would allow any employee with internal systems access, or any external actor who is able to obtain systems access, to move, and\/or steal, customer funds relatively trivially,” Nick Neuman, CEO at non-custodial wallet provider Casa, told The Block.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Since keys were previously stored unencrypted on FTX, there are a variety of ways in which someone can acquire private keys, such as by hacking into a system or phishing attempts.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In November, exchange wallets belonging to FTX were seemingly hacked to the tune of an<\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/halborn.com\/explained-the-ftx-hack-november-2022\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> estimated $300-$400 million,<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> per estimates from security firms: Halborn and PeckShield. While the identity of the hacker has still remained unknown, Bankman-Fried<\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/finance.yahoo.com\/finance\/news\/sam-bankman-fried-says-ftx-203431501.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;spoke<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> of a “disgruntled employee” or a bad actor who may have stolen private keys to its crypto wallets.<\/span>","A month after the crypto exchange he founded filed for bankruptcy protection, U.S. authorities have <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/194667\/disgraced-former-ftx-ceo-sam-bankman-fried-criminally-indicted\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">charged<\/a> the former Bankman-Fried with fraud.","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Nick Neuman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$300","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$1 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"\"hundreds of millions of dollars","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Casa","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. House Financial Services Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"PeckShield","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"John Ray III","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$400 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Vishal Chawla","The Block"]}