{"summary":"Justin Sun, founder of the Tron blockchain, says he remains a diplomat representing Grenada, despite local reports earlier this week saying he no longer holds that status.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/224253\/justin-sun-claims-he-remains-wto-ambassador-for-grenada-shares-screenshots","publishDate":"2023-03-31T07:15:19","id":12695,"type":null,"title":"Justin Sun claims he remains WTO ambassador for Grenada, shares screenshots","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Justin Sun, founder of the Tron blockchain, says he remains a diplomat representing Grenada, despite local reports earlier this week saying he no longer holds that status.","The reports are \"not true,\" Sun told The Block, while sharing a screenshot dated Friday that shows he has an active profile on the World Trade Organization (WTO)'s internal registration website as the ambassador for Grenada. After the publication of this article, Sun changed his story, <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/justinsuntron\/status\/1641800122484019200\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweeting<\/a> \"as my term as the Ambassador of Grenada to the World Trade Organization comes to a close, effective 31 March 2023, I want to express my gratitude for the wonderful experiences and the amazing support that I have received during my time here.\"","","","Sun also shared a screenshot of WTO's \"internal terminal\" that lists him as Grenada's ambassador and permanent representative to the WTO.","","","Earlier this week, the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.onecaribbeanmedia.net\/media-group\/radio\/grenada-broadcasting-network\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Grenada Broadcasting Network<\/a>, jointly owned by the Caribbean Communications Network and the government, <a href=\"https:\/\/gbn.gd\/grenadas-former-wto-ambassador-charged\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a> that Sun had been stripped of his status as ambassador sometime after elections held in June 2022, when the New National Party, which had granted Sun the position, was ousted by the National Democratic Congress.","Sun was appointed as WTO ambassador by the government of Grenada in December 2021. Since his appointment, he has styled himself \"His Excellency\" on his social media accounts. He still maintains the \"H.E.\" label on his verified personal Twitter <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/justinsuntron\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">account<\/a> and his diplomatic Twitter <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/HEjustinsun\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">account<\/a>.","The WTO and the government of Grenada did not immediately respond to The Block's requests for comment.","Sun and Tron were<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/222077\/sec-charges-trons-justin-sun-and-celebrities-including-lindsay-lohan-jake-paul\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> sued<\/a> by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission last week for offering and selling two unregistered crypto tokens, Tronix (TRX) and BitTorrent (BTT). The regulator also alleged that they manipulated the prices of TRX between April 2018 and February 2019.","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Updated to show Sun changed his story after the publication of this article.&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"June 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"BitTorrent","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Justin Sun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"National Democratic Congress","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"World Trade Organization","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"March 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"February 2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"World Trade Organization (WTO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Grenada Broadcasting Network","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"TRX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"December 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Grenada","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"New National Party","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"WTO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Caribbean Communications Network","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"H.E.\"","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April 2018","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["JUSTIN SUN"],"authors":["Yogita Khatri","The Block"]}