{"summary":"FTX revised the derivatives exchange LedgerX auction date for a third time. The exchange is selling the business unit to raise money for creditors.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/221053\/date-for-ftxs-auction-of-ledgerx-revised-for-third-time","publishDate":"2023-03-19T07:30:17","id":1272,"type":null,"title":"Date for FTX&#x27;s auction of LedgerX revised for third time","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["FTX will auction its derivatives exchange LedgerX to bidders on April 4.","The counsel for FTX filed the notice of revised dates on March 18 in U.S. Bankruptcy Court for the District of Delaware.","The auction will now be held on April 4 at the offices of Sullivan &amp; Cromwell and a sale hearing will take place April 12, the filing said. Notice of the successful bidder should occur within one business day of the conclusion of the auction.","The auction had previously been <a href=\"https:\/\/restructuring.ra.kroll.com\/FTX\/Home-DownloadPDF?id1=MTQzODE4OQ==&amp;id2=-1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">scheduled<\/a> for March 7 and then was <a href=\"https:\/\/restructuring.ra.kroll.com\/FTX\/Home-DownloadPDF?id1=MTQ2MDQwOQ==&amp;id2=-1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">revised<\/a> to March 22, according to court filings. A reason for the most recent date revision was not provided.","FTX <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/201953\/ftx-approval-sell-ledgerx\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">secured<\/a> approval early this year to sell business units to raise money for creditors. It is also <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/195579\/ftx-asks-court-permission-to-sell-off-four-businesses-including-ledgerx\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">looking<\/a> to sell Embed Financial Technologies, FTX Japan and FTX Europe. About 117 parties have shown interest in buying entities of FTX, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/200224\/ftx-businesses-including-ledgerx-draw-interest-from-over-100-potential-buyers\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">according<\/a> to a legal filing at the start of this year.","The exchange's U.S. operation <a href=\"https:\/\/www.prnewswire.com\/news-releases\/ftx-us-finalizes-acquisition-of-ledgerx-301407488.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">acquired<\/a> LedgerX in Oct. 2021 and rebranded it as FTX.US Derivatives.","&nbsp;","&nbsp;","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Embed Financial Technologies","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"April 4","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"March 18","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FTX Japan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"April 12","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"March 22","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sullivan &amp; Cromwell","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Oct. 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"March 7","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FTX Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"the District of Delaware","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["COURT HEARINGS","FTX"],"authors":["Kari McMahon","The Block"]}