{"summary":"The tension between Coinbase and the SEC heated up following the regulator’s concerns about its involvement in Celsius Network’s bankruptcy.  ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/252857\/tension-rises-between-coinbase-and-sec-over-celsius-bankruptcy-plan","publishDate":"2023-09-25T14:07:01","id":12742,"type":null,"title":"Tension rises between Coinbase and SEC over Celsius bankruptcy plan","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Tensions between Coinbase and the Securities and Exchange Commission heated up Monday, following fresh concerns from the regulator about the crypto exchange's involvement in Celsius Network’s bankruptcy plan.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Celsius plans to use Coinbase to distribute crypto for international customers and wants the court's approval for a series of agreements with the exchange, the SEC said in a Friday <a href=\"https:\/\/cases.stretto.com\/public\/x191\/11749\/PLEADINGS\/1174909222380000000115.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filing<\/span><\/a>.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"However, the Coinbase Agreements go far beyond the services of a distribution agent, contemplating brokerage services and master trading services that implicate many of the concerns raised in the SEC's District Court action against Coinbase,\" the SEC said.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Coinbase and the SEC have been at odds, especially after the regulator issued a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/222427\/what-comes-next-after-coinbases-wells-notice\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Wells<\/span><\/a> notice to the exchange in March and later filed a lawsuit against it for operating as an unregistered broker and exchange in violation of federal securities laws.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Coinbase is proud to engage with Celsius to distribute crypto back to its customers. I wonder, why would the SEC object to a trusted US public company taking on this role?\" Coinbase Chief Legal Officer Paul Grewal posted on X on Monday.<\/span>","<span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Celsius filed for bankruptcy last year and owes billions of dollars to investors. The SEC <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/239407\/sec-files-lawsuit-against-celsius-and-ex-ceo-alex-mashinsky\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">sued<\/span><\/a> Celsius and its former CEO Alex Mashinsky in July for allegedly raising billions through fraudulent and unregistered sales of \"crypto asset securities,\" repeatedly lying to investors about Celsius' financial standing, and manipulating the price of CEL, the company's native token.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Others, too, have objected to Celsius’ plan over the past few days, including the U.S. Trustee which reiterated concerns from <a href=\"https:\/\/cases.stretto.com\/public\/x191\/11749\/PLEADINGS\/1174908042380000000144.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s5\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">August<\/span><\/a> over whether creditors have enough information to help them make an informed decision to approve the plan or not.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"billions of dollars","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Celsius Network","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alex Mashinsky","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Coinbase Agreements","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Paul Grewal","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"District Court","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["COINBASE","SEC"],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}