{"summary":"The fourth installment of The Scoop’s continued coverage of FTX’s demise examines the legal underpinnings of FTX’s bankruptcy and restructuring process with attorneys Dan Besikof and Mark Shapiro.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/190156\/ftxs-demise-part-4-bankruptcy-experts-weigh-in-on-next-steps-for-ftx","publishDate":"2022-11-28T05:00:49","id":12747,"type":null,"title":"FTX&#x27;s demise part 4: Bankruptcy experts weigh in on next steps for FTX","category":["BANKRUPTCY"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 118<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 4 of The Scoop was recorded live with&nbsp;<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro, Dan Besikof, a Partner at Loeb &amp; Loeb, and Mark Shapiro, a Partner at Shearman &amp; Sterling.<\/strong><\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests can be sent to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"85f5eae1e6e4f6f1c5f1ede0e7e9eae6eee6f7fcf5f1eaabe6eae8\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK4137309231\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/i>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In the fourth installment of The Scoop’s <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/187004\/ftxs-demise-part-3-how-sam-bankman-frieds-crypto-empire-imploded\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">continued coverage<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> of FTX's demise, host Frank Chaparro examines the legal underpinnings of FTX’s bankruptcy and restructuring process with Dan Besikof, a partner at the law firm Loeb &amp; Loeb, and Mark Shapiro, Chair of the Financial Restructuring Group and a partner at the law firm of Shearman &amp; Sterling. In 2008, Shapiro served as the Head of Restructuring for Lehman Brothers, where he guided the sale of the firm's U.S. assets in chapter 11.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">According to Besikof, FTX’s fiduciary will likely attempt to bring money back into the estate through lawsuits:<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“One of the things that they're going to look at is where did money go out where value didn't come back, and to the extent money went out and value didn't come back, that's a natural target for a fraudulent conveyance lawsuit or a fraudulent transfer lawsuit.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">FTX has notified a federal judge it wants BitGo <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/189667\/ftx-asks-court-to-let-bitgo-safeguard-its-assets-during-bankruptcy\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">to custody<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> its $740 million worth of digital assets.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">While the exact situation of FTX’s finances is still uncertain, Shapiro says the sheer amount of money lost by FTX users is likely to prompt regulators to take a more proactive approach going forward:<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Now that it's become so public and so much money has been lost, I think the paternalistic side of the government is going to take over and try to do something about protecting investors.”<\/span>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">During this episode Chaparro, Besikof and Shapiro also discuss:<\/span><\/i>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Tron,&nbsp;<\/em><\/a><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.ledn.io\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ledn<\/a><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em><\/b><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nAbout Tron<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Founded in 2013, Huobi Global is one of the largest virtual asset exchanges in the world. Huobi Global serves millions of users across international markets. Since its establishment, Huobi Global has committed to providing first class virtual asset investment services. Huobi Global's robust infrastructure, product innovation and capital strength provides a truly customer-centric and secure trading environment to help our international users to achieve their investment objectives. Please refer to Huobi's official website for more information: <a href=\"http:\/\/www.huobi.com\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">huobi.com<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Ledn<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong>Ledn was founded on the unshakeable conviction that digital assets have the power to democratize access to the global economy. We help you to experience the real life benefits of your Bitcoin without having to sell it. Start a savings account, take out a loan, or double your Bitcoin. For more information visit&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.ledn.io\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ledn.io<\/a><\/em>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Loeb &amp; Loeb","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$740 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Huobi Global","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2013","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Shapiro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Huobi","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Financial Restructuring Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mark Shapiro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ledn<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong>Ledn","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Besikof","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Besikof","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2008","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ledn<\/a><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em><\/b><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nAbout Tron<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Founded","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dan Besikof","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Head of Restructuring for Lehman Brothers","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Shearman &amp; Sterling","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}