{"summary":"Ripple is looking to gain a license from Ireland as the company seeks to expand its presence in Europe.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/188312\/ripple-seeks-license-from-irish-regulator-cnbc","publishDate":"2022-11-18T09:44:15","id":12889,"type":null,"title":"Ripple seeks license from Irish regulator: CNBC","category":["REGULATION"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto payments company Ripple is seeking a virtual asset service provider&nbsp;license from the Irish regulator as it expands its operations in Europe, according to CNBC.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">When new laws on crypto regulation in the European Union come into force, expected in 2024, Ripple would then be able to “passport” its European license to the rest of the 27 states in the bloc. Ripple will also seek an e-money license “shortly,” <\/span>Ripple general counsel Stuart Alderoty told CNBC.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The U.S.-based company is involved in a dispute with the Securities and Exchange Commission that is driving the company to look for business abroad. “Effectively, Ripple is operating outside of the U.S.,” Alderoty said in the report.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The SEC <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/88912\/sec-ripple-labs-lawsuit-filed-2\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filed<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> a lawsuit against Ripple in 2020 alleging that the sale of its XRP tokens counted as unregistered securities worth $1.3 billion. Ripple’s head of public policy, Susan Friedman, recently <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/186892\/ripple-publishes-proposed-guidelines-for-uk-regulators\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">told<\/a> The Block that they are in the process of filing a reply brief to summary judgment and are expecting a ruling in 2023.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Amid its expansion into Europe, Ripple also <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/187176\/ripple-and-binance-seek-uk-regulatory-licenses-lawmakers-are-told\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">sought<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> licensing from the UK regulator this week. Ripple has about 60 people on the ground in the UK and two in Ireland.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ireland <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/175882\/gemini-expands-into-europe-becomes-first-vasp-in-ireland\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">granted<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> the currently troubled Gemini exchange a virtual asset service provider license in October.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"European Union","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$1.3 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alderoty","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"CNBC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Susan Friedman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Stuart Alderoty","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"October","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ireland","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}