{"summary":"The Tel Aviv Stock Exchange will kick off a five-year strategy to develop a new platform for the trade of digital assets, the public stock exchange","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/179370\/israels-stock-exchange-will-launch-a-platform-for-digital-assets","publishDate":"2022-10-24T09:12:31","id":12896,"type":null,"title":"Israel&#x27;s stock exchange will launch a platform for digital assets","category":["CAPITAL MARKETS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Tel Aviv Stock Exchange will kick off a five-year strategy to develop a new platform for the trade of digital assets, the public stock exchange <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/info.tase.co.il\/Heb\/about_tase\/news\/2022\/Pages\/PR_20221024.aspx\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in a press statement.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"We see in the next five years a critical window of opportunity for the integration of the Israeli Stock Exchange in the technological revolution that the world's capital markets are going through,\" Itai Ben-Zeev, CEO of the exchange, said in the statement. Development of the strategy will start in 2023.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The program looks to bolster TASE’s value proposition by establishing a blockchain-based platform that integrates crypto, including “DLT technologies, tokenization of digital assets of various types and smart contracts.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">By implementing innovative technologies into its infrastructure, the exchange hopes to “strengthen the cooperation and the international profile of the stock exchange,” and notes that “these services and collaborations may include the purchase of holdings in foreign exchanges.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Israeli Ministry of Finance's Office of the Accountant General and the Tel Aviv Stock Exchange <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/177985\/israel-ministry-of-finance-stock-exchange-to-test-use-of-digital-state-bonds\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> last week that they will cooperate to test out digital state bonds — in an ongoing effort to institutionalize crypto in Israel.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Israel is not the only jurisdiction seeking to digitalize financial instruments. In the European Union, the so-called DLT Pilot Regime is set to <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/173191\/security\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">roll out<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in March. The sandbox experiment will encourage both traditional and new-arriving financial players to practice transacting tokenized securities.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"DLT Pilot Regime","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"TASE","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Israeli Ministry of Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Israel","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tel Aviv Stock Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DLT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Israeli Stock Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"European Union","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Itai Ben-Zeev","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}