{"summary":"TRON DAO is actively seeking the sharpest, most innovative developers to come and build on the TRON blockchain.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/187277\/tron-dao-welcomes-the-next-generation-of-blockchain-developers","publishDate":"2022-11-16T08:50:53","id":12927,"type":null,"title":"TRON DAO Welcomes the Next Generation of Blockchain Developers","category":["SPONSORED"],"content":["<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Singapore, Singapore \/ November 16, 2022 \/<\/b><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> – <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TRON DAO<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> is actively seeking the sharpest, most innovative developers to come and build on the TRON blockchain.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The TRON team was present at <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/sf.ethglobal.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ETH San Francisco<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> (ETHSF), a gathering of developers building on Ethereum and the blockchains that bridge it. The TRON team taught in several breakouts and held a meetup luncheon. The developers who attended the <\/span><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TRON Developer Meetup<\/b><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> heard about opportunities to innovate in the TRON ecosystem. ETHSF, a gathering of ETHGlobal, was held at the Palace of Fine Arts in San Francisco on November 4–6, 2022.<\/span>","\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">","<a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/hackathon\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Season 3 of the TRON Grand Hackathon 2022 (#HackaTRON)<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> features the new track “<\/span><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ecosystem<\/b><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.” This track’s purpose is to attract existing Ethereum developers to TRON, encouraging them to consider expanding their reach by leveraging the <\/span><a href=\"http:\/\/bt.io\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BitTorrent Chain<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> (BTTC) cross-chain bridge solution. The BTTC Bridge allows developers to move data over from Ethereum and easily build projects on TRON. One developer noted:<\/span>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“I would say a lot of things are similar when building on and deploying to Ethereum, because the TRON Virtual Machine (TVM) is very similar to the Ethereum Virtual Machine (EVM), in that it uses the Solidity language and supports most EVM smart contracts.”<\/span><\/i>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">There’s now less than a week left to <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/trons3.devpost.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">register for Season 3<\/b><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> of the TRON Grand Hackathon 2022.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Finally, TRON DAO is launching <\/span><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TRON Academy<\/b><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to engage with up and coming blockchain developers. TRON is collaborating with major universities around the world to help talented students tap into TRON opportunities at an early stage. TRON DAO leaders will help mentor college students passionate about blockchain tech. <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/hejustinsun.to\/domain\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">H.E. Justin Sun<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, Founder of TRON, articulated the vision for TRON Academy in this way:<\/span>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“I have been a beneficiary of mentors and teachers through my entrepreneurial journey. They helped accelerate my learning and improve the value I could deliver. I am proud to see the TRON DAO create the TRON Academy program, allowing access to resources for anyone to achieve their individual aspirations and reach their full life potential.”<\/span><\/i>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The official launch of the TRON Academy is occurring in sync with another new #HackaTRON track “<\/span><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Academy<\/b><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,” which looks to empower next-gen innovation with an in-real-life event designed specifically for students. The event took place at a “<\/span><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Hacker House<\/b><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,” located at the <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/goo.gl\/maps\/EVjED6qUBbzFsWeA7\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Derek Bok Center for Teaching and Learning<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on the campus of Harvard University on November 12 and 13, 2022. 200+ students from Harvard, MIT, Yale, UPenn, Princeton, Northeastern, and Boston University attended the event. Each developer team built on TRON and BTTC, developing away the whole weekend for a chance to win a portion of the $74,000 prize pool dedicated specifically to this track.&nbsp;<\/span>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This post is commissioned by TRON and does not serve as a testimonial or endorsement by The Block. This post is for informational purposes only and should not be relied upon as a basis for investment, tax, legal or other advice. You should conduct your own research and consult independent counsel and advisors on the matters discussed within this post. Past performance of any asset is not indicative of future results.<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"San Francisco","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"BitTorrent","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"TRON Academy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"“<\/span><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Hacker House","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"TRON Developer Meetup","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Harvard","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"ETH San Francisco","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Yale","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ethereum Virtual Machine (EVM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MIT","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"November 16, 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Northeastern","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Princeton","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"November 4–6, 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"H.E. Justin Sun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Derek Bok Center for Teaching","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Palace of Fine Arts","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Boston University","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$74,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"TRON Grand Hackathon","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Harvard University","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"November 12 and 13, 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"TRON Grand Hackathon 2022","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"TRON DAO","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sponsored","The Block"]}