{"summary":"Kanpai Pandas has hired UFC fighter Jon Jones to be its brand ambassador and help promote the NFT collections&#x27; new clothing line.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/209054\/mma-bruiser-jon-jones-gets-cuddly-with-cute-panda-nfts","publishDate":"2023-02-06T19:00:30","id":12928,"type":null,"title":"MMA bruiser Jon Jones gets cuddly with cute panda NFTs","category":["METAVERSE & NFT"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Looks like UFC fighter Jon Jones isn’t afraid to get into the octagon with some pandas. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">With about a month to go before his heavyweight title fight, Jones, a famous mixed-martial arts star, inked a deal to become the brand ambassador for the NFT collection Kanpai Pandas. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Jones will not only represent the NFT brand, which has generated more than $7 million in trading volume since launching in April according to OpenSea, he will also be the face of Kanpai Pandas’s new streetwear collection. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kanpai Panda’s push into selling apparel and partnering with the famous UFC fighter follows other top-tier NFT brands’ efforts to diversify. NFT brands want to woo mainstream consumers with products like merchandise and video games after being hit by the slump in prices for NFTs and cryptocurrencies. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Yuga Labs’ Bored Apes Yacht Club, Doodles and Azuki have all recently launched efforts to expand the reach of their brands with new initiatives geared towards moving beyond being digital-asset collections.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Jones also owns multiple NFTs from the collection, according to Kanpai Pandas. The UFC fighter has a heavyweight bout with Ciryl Gane on March 4 in Las Vegas.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The current floor price for Kanpai Pandas’s profile-picture NFTs is more than $3,000 up from $280 in November.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$3,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Jones","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Las Vegas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$7 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Kanpai Pandas","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ciryl Gane","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$280","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Bored Apes Yacht Club","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UFC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jon Jones","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"March 4","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}