{"summary":"Floating Point Group secured registration as a virtual asset service provider (VASP) in the Cayman Islands.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/163369\/crypto-prime-brokerage-floating-point-group-secures-vasp-registration-in-cayman-islands","publishDate":"2022-08-12T21:01:57","id":12923,"type":null,"title":"Crypto prime brokerage Floating Point Group secures VASP registration in Cayman Islands","category":["REGULATION"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto-focused prime brokerage Floating Point Group has secured registration as a virtual asset service provider (VASP) in the Cayman I<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">slands.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“With our current regulatory posture in the Cayman Islands and our business structure, Floating Point Group is able to hold customer assets safely and ensure that its customer's assets are protected from its own creditors in the unlikely event that the company becomes bankrupt,” the firm said in a press statement.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Floating Point Group has about 100 customers and surpassed $10 billion in cumulative customer trading volume earlier this year, co-founder Kevin March said. It recently released a new crypto asset management platform called FlowVault.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Hoboken, New Jersey-based Floating Point Group was founded by MIT students in late 2017. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The company closed a $10 million Series A round in September 2021 with participation from several investors, including Tribe Capital, Coinbase Ventures and Anthony Scaramucci. That funding followed a $2 million seed round backed by investors such as AngelList co-founder Naval Ravikant.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Cayman Islands Monetary Authority recognized the company’s subsidiary Floating Point Group International as a registered VASP on April 21, according to a government database. The self-governing British territory passed a law in 2020 to establish a regulatory framework for digital assets, known as the “VASP Law.”&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“It is incredibly important right now, of all times, to lean into the regulatory frameworks that have been provided for us in each of the places we do business,” John Peurifoy, Floating Point Group CEO and co-founder said in a statement.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Cayman Islands","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Cayman Islands Monetary Authority","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"John Peurifoy","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Floating Point Group International","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"New Jersey","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"September 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tribe Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"VASP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$2 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"April 21","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Anthony Scaramucci","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Naval Ravikant","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$10 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Hoboken","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"MIT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Floating Point Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coinbase Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$10 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Floating Point Group CEO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kevin March","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Kristin Majcher","The Block"]}