{"summary":"The BTC spread activity emerges amid lawsuits and other legal action against BinanceUS from the SEC this week.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/233988\/bitcoin-spreads-soar-20-times-higher-on-binanceus-than-on-coinbase-kraken-kaiko","publishDate":"2023-06-09T13:37:42","id":12930,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin spreads soar 20 times higher on BinanceUS than on Coinbase, Kraken: Kaiko","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Bitcoin spread soared dramatically on BinanceUS, the crypto exchange giant's American affiliate.","The BTC spreads against USDT and USD more than tripled within the past week — compared to modest changes from Coinbase and Kraken. In all, BinanceUS's BTC spread soared 20 times wider than its competitors, according to <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/kaikodata\/status\/1667202370063806465?s=46&amp;t=Se54l14sCsYxHI60OfmIMA\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">crypto data firm Kaiko<\/a>.","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Source: Kaiko, Twitter<\/em>","The activity suggests that users are selling off their BTC after the Securities and Exchange Commission brought a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/233206\/sec-binance-showdown-sends-shockwaves-through-crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">lawsuit<\/a> against Binance, Binance US and Binance CEO Changpeng Zhao.","After the suit, BinanceUS announced a move to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/233566\/binance-us-to-pause-otc-trading-portal-delist-some-trading-pairs-after-sec-suit\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">delist<\/a> over 100 trading pairs and paused its OTC Trading Portal. BinanceUS said late Thursday that it would pause USD deposits ahead of an expected freeze on dollar payments services from its bank partners.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"USDT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kaiko","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Twitter","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"USD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance US","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Changpeng Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"late Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Kraken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE"],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}