{"summary":"Crypto derivatives exchange Bybit announced today the World Series of Trading (WSOT) launch, a bi-annual global crypto trading competition.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/73233\/world-series-of-trading-wsot-to-galvanize-summer-with-monstrous-200-btc-prize-pool","publishDate":"2020-07-30T00:00:26","id":12956,"type":null,"title":"World Series of Trading (WSOT) to Galvanize Summer with Monstrous 200 BTC Prize Pool","category":["SPONSORED"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">While movie theaters may be unusually empty this time of the year, a different kind of summer blockbuster is coming soon, one that promises to bring back the exhilaration of competitive crypto trading with up to <\/span><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">200 bitcoins (BTC) prize pool, 20% off trading fees and up to $9,400 in USDT bonuses.<\/b>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A Blockbuster Competitive Crypto Trading Tournament<\/b>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto derivatives exchange Bybit announced today the World Series of Trading (WSOT) launch, a bi-annual global crypto trading competition. The inaugural edition of the tournament will feature a prize pool of up to <\/span><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">200 BTC,<\/b><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> the largest of any crypto trading tournament by far, and run from August 10 and August 31. <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.bybit.com\/wsot?campaign=wsot&amp;source=tb_en&amp;medium=article&amp;content=reg_page&amp;type=1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Registration begins today.<\/b><\/a>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The global event is open to traders worldwide where Bybit's platform is available. The ranking system of WSOT is based on the profit\/loss ratio, regardless of trading volume, thus paving a level playing ground for all participants.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Following the success of 2019's Bybit Games - BTC Brawl, a competition that drew over 7,000 traders, WSOT will see even more traders battle for the unprecedented <\/span><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">200 BTC prize pool.<\/b><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> WSOT will host some of the biggest names in the crypto trading world and professional poker stars.<\/span>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A Stellar Nursery and an Accretion Disk for Crypto Luminaries<\/b>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The inaugural WSOT rightfully features a space theme and promises to be the largest gathering of crypto trading masters. It is also an ideal avenue for new star traders to emerge and shine.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"The World Series of Trading will be the main tournament of Bybit Games and the crypto trading world. We at Bybit believe in the importance of empowering traders who embody the prowess and passion for crypto trading,\" said Ben Zhou, co-founder, and CEO of Bybit. \"This revolutionary event aims to champion the spirit of competition and fair play, and cultivate camaraderie between crypto derivatives traders worldwide to create positive changes in the crypto space.\"<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">As part of Bybit's commitment to giving back to society, 5% of the total prize pool (including team and individual awards) will be donated to charity.<\/span>","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.bybit.com\/wsot?campaign=wsot&amp;source=tb_en&amp;medium=article&amp;content=reg_page&amp;type=1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Registration for the inaugural WSOT is open now<\/b><\/a><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">!<\/b>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Bybit<\/b>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bybit is a global cryptocurrency derivatives exchange established in March 2018 and registered in the BVI. It is headquartered in Singapore. Bybit has a global user base comprising everyone from individual retail clients to professional derivatives traders.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">We have users worldwide, including North America, Europe, Russia, Japan, South Korea, and Southeast Asia. We are focused on serving everyone from individual retail clients to professional derivatives traders.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">For more information, please visit: <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.bybit.com\/wsot?campaign=wsot&amp;source=tb_en&amp;medium=article&amp;content=reg_page&amp;type=1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">https:\/\/www.bybit.com\/<\/span><\/a>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">For updates, follow Bybit's social platforms on <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/Bybit_Official\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Twitter<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> and <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/t.me\/BybitEnglish\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Telegram<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"South Korea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"20%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"WSOT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Stellar Nursery","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Blockbuster Competitive Crypto Trading Tournament","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bybit","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"March 2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Russia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"USDT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Southeast Asia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"North America","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Japan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Crypto Luminaries","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BVI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ben Zhou","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"August 10","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$9,400","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"August 31","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bybit","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"summer","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sponsored","The Block"]}