{"summary":"Lauren Belive, who previously worked for former President Barack Obama, has joined Ripple as the head of U.S. public policy and government. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253016\/ripple-taps-former-obama-white-house-official-to-head-u-s-public-policy","publishDate":"2023-09-26T12:11:35","id":12985,"type":null,"title":"Ripple taps former Obama White House official to head U.S. public policy","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Lauren Belive, who at one time worked at the White House under President Barack Obama, joined Ripple as the head of U.S. public policy and government.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“My role will be to lead our engagement in Washington and nationally, ensuring that we are not only part of the conversation but driving it forward with clarity and purpose,” Belive said Tuesday on&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.linkedin.com\/feed\/update\/urn:li:activity:7112397888764162049\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">LinkedIn<\/span><\/a>.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"With regulatory landscapes evolving, it's paramount that we advocate for policies that not only support the crypto industry but also the countless individuals and businesses that could benefit from these advancements,\" she continued.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Belive was most recently director of government affairs at SoftBank Group International, and before that, she was head of U.S. government relations at Zoom. She started her career at the <\/span><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">House Oversight and Government Reform Committee, which was then chaired by Rep. Henry Waxman, D-Calif.&nbsp;<\/span>","At the Obama White House, she worked in the Office of Legislative Affairs. She also previously worked on Obama's campaign, according to her LinkedIn profile.&nbsp;","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto firms have bolstered their advocacy efforts in Washington D.C. in a push for a regulatory overhaul they say is needed to keep activity in the U.S. and prevent it from going offshore. Some have criticized the Securities and Exchange Commission's approach to regulating crypto that has been dubbed \"regulation by enforcement.\"&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ripple itself has been in the midst of a lawsuit brought by the regulator over the past few years. The firm secured a partial win in July after a New York district court judge <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/239559\/sec-faces-wake-up-call-after-ripple-ruling-though-appeal-likely\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ruled<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in July that some of Ripple's sales, called programmatic, of <span class=\"articleTooltip\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"\/price\/248352\/xrp-xrp-usd\" class=\"articleTooltip__link\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"><img src=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2023\/10\/xrp-symbol-white-128.png\" alt=\"\" title=\"\" class=\"articleTooltip__tokenImage\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">XRP<\/span> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText articleTooltip__tokenText_price articleTooltip__tokenText_negative\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">\n      -0.79%\n    <\/span><\/a> <!----><\/span> did not violate securities laws because of a blind bid process in place for them. The judge also ruled that other direct sales of the token to institutional investors were securities, leaving a partial win for the SEC.<\/span><\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Other firms too have ramped up efforts in Washington. Coinbase is <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coinbase.com\/blog\/a-call-to-action-mobilizing-52-million-crypto-owners-into-an-army-of-1?__cf_chl_f_tk=Z18uIaKrHFDObSoW4hh3c4Ui7Qi.4jZgvbqoDW_SqhU-1695740110-0-gaNycGzNDlA\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">planning<\/span><\/a> a “Stand with Crypto Day” where innovators, entrepreneurs and developers will meet with lawmakers and government officials on Wednesday in the nation’s capital.&nbsp;<\/span>","&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"SoftBank Group International","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Washington","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Barack Obama","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Washington D.C.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Office of Legislative Affairs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Obama","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Crypto Day”","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"White House","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Henry Waxman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Obama White House","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"House Oversight and Government Reform Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Lauren Belive","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Calif.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"-0.79%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"” Belive","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}