{"summary":"Senator Kelly Loeffler (Republican-Georgia) sold off millions in stock ahead of the recent coronavirus-induced market crash, according to financial disclosures.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/59359\/senator-kelly-loeffler-former-bakkt-ceo-sold-millions-in-stock-before-coronavirus-induced-market-crash","publishDate":"2020-03-20T03:40:12","id":13001,"type":null,"title":"Senator Kelly Loeffler, former Bakkt CEO, sold millions in stock before coronavirus-induced market crash","category":["CAPITAL MARKETS"],"content":["Senator Kelly Loeffler (Republican-Georgia) sold off millions in stock ahead of the recent coronavirus-induced market crash, according to financial disclosures.","The <a href=\"https:\/\/efdsearch.senate.gov\/search\/view\/ptr\/8b915201-8116-4027-9b76-8595ec4ffd85\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">disclosures reveal<\/a> that Loeffler, former CEO of Bakkt, reported the first sale of stock on January 24, the same day her committee, the Senate Health Committee, hosted a private meeting on coronavirus. The Daily Beast first <a href=\"https:\/\/www.thedailybeast.com\/sen-kelly-loeffler-dumped-millions-in-stock-after-coronavirus-briefing?ref=scroll\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a> the news.","The first sale transaction was of stock Resideo Technologies, worth between $50,001 and $100,000. The company’s stock price has declined by more than half since then.","Other sale transactions include stocks of Comcast Corporation, Keysight Technologies, Ross Stores and other companies - worth between $1,275,000 and $3,100,000.","Interestingly, Loeffler <a href=\"https:\/\/efdsearch.senate.gov\/search\/view\/ptr\/8b915201-8116-4027-9b76-8595ec4ffd85\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">initially reported<\/a> many of these sale transactions in the name of her husband - Jeffrey Sprecher, founder, chairman, and CEO of Intercontinental Exchange and chairman of the New York Stock Exchange. Last week, i.e. on March 12, she <a href=\"https:\/\/efdsearch.senate.gov\/search\/view\/ptr\/d1798081-ddcc-48fd-a599-ceb60730a02d\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">amended<\/a> the report to note that most of them were jointly owned.","The amended report lists a total of 22 transactions. There is <a href=\"https:\/\/efdsearch.senate.gov\/search\/view\/ptr\/370492b8-ed0a-4792-b45b-972d5da8a1e5\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">another periodic transaction report<\/a>, also filed on March 12, which shows a total of 25 trades - 23 sale transactions and only two purchase transactions. Many stocks that Loeffler reported selling have lost their value in the recent market crash.","“This is a ridiculous and baseless attack. I do not make investment decisions for my portfolio. Investment decisions are made by multiple third-party advisors without my or my husband’s knowledge or involvement,” <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/SenatorLoeffler\/status\/1240856941435502592?s=20\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Loeffler tweeted<\/a> late Thursday night.","“As confirmed in the periodic transaction report to Senate Ethics, I was informed of these purchases and sales on February 16, 2020 — three weeks after they were made,” she added.","Loeffler was <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/48831\/bakkt-ceo-kelly-loeffler-to-become-georgias-interim-u-s-senator\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">appointed<\/a> as a U.S. Senator to serve Georgia in January. Since then, she has <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/52389\/former-bakkt-ceo-kelly-loeffler-to-help-oversee-cftc-raising-a-possible-conflict-of-interest\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">faced scrutiny<\/a> over possible conflicts of interest. Loeffler’s committee oversees the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC), which regulates her husband’s company, Intercontinental Exchange.","Notably, at the time of her appointment, Loeffler <a href=\"https:\/\/efdsearch.senate.gov\/search\/view\/extension-notice\/regular\/0639409a-3079-4420-8694-6472a8b6640e\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">requested an extension<\/a> for filing the annual financial disclosures report. As a result, a 90-day extension was granted, and a full accounting of her finances will be made public on May 5.","Loeffler is the second senator found to have sold millions in stocks weeks ahead of the market crash. Senator Richard Burr (Republican-North Carolina), who chairs the Senate Intelligence Committee, reportedly <a href=\"https:\/\/www.opensecrets.org\/news\/2020\/03\/burr-unloaded-stocks-before-coronavirus\/?__cf_chl_captcha_tk__=9b335d0edca7edf0b243bff182c110ef84c25cd6-1584689176-0-AWgvdW0iJZE1nvf51bKGWPHr3l4_x8KDauWaMXf0DgGC2PyLIdUd7vgOca0_54EIWEOlL5uNYamqd6d7RIcqKcifwYRawTogTK09PRMRnnKiSpOb_rFNwVrt9JeOJeVXMyRkvjoPak36Vp3ByjOjl4vzP6IOGOEH_1oBP4wsVjiUZ5K-uGpDUuG6p8rFX8BC_8qilpxlJhh9FqeiBRSd8dXKfToRvQ-PUnATlTq0fZmAqL8HR9pVZTsn0GMb5A7-XU637viKE5uQiLnCxhGSgXr7Ci_rQcSnwflMYN7P5x7n0SIwU2dg4NCsROMaOKL2IneS3Lc06lb7owyK2wRBsPweIq4BN6596eq6BMs7b55EEw7h_--RJIdQSfrI4-czqgacml9yk_f6Ni1jPyI1SK0ozIF3gcOLgOmOApEmFexWr4WDaIDBiew1OQ2xoagDTaL6JNLk5nDbSAPqA04sZGmzPSDrkr_Ud8-CGL5Y0UnO\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">sold<\/a> between $500,000 and $1.5 million in stock last month.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"February 16, 2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$1.5 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Intercontinental Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1,275,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$3,100,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Kelly Loeffler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$50,001","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"New York Stock Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"23","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Comcast Corporation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Senate Ethics","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Richard Burr","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Keysight Technologies","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bakkt","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ross Stores","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Senate Intelligence Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Resideo Technologies","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"May 5","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Jeffrey Sprecher","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Georgia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Loeffler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"night","content":"TIME"},{"type":"March 12","content":"DATE"},{"type":"January 24","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$500,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"North Carolina","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$100,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Senate Health Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Yogita Khatri","The Block"]}