{"summary":"The results of the investigation will likely conclude in regulation proposals and will be reviewed by the Treasury.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/183144\/uk-parliament-launches-nft-inquiry","publishDate":"2022-11-04T11:02:52","id":13003,"type":null,"title":"UK parliament committee launches inquiry into risks and benefits of NFTs","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A group within the UK's House of Commons announced an inquiry into the risks and benefits of non-fungible tokens, in a step towards the country's first NFT regulation.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Members of parliament will look into whether \"NFT investors, especially vulnerable speculators, are put at risk by the market,” the Digital, Culture, Media &amp; Sport Committee leading the operation <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/committees.parliament.uk\/committee\/378\/digital-culture-media-and-sport-committee\/news\/174174\/dcms-committee-to-hold-inquiry-into-the-future-of-the-nft-market\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in a statement.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The results of the investigation will likely conclude in regulation proposals and will be reviewed by the Treasury.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“This inquiry will also help Parliament understand the opportunities presented by an exciting new technology which could democratize how assets are bought and sold,” committee chair Julian Knight said in the release.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Prime Minister Rishi Sunak proved a proponent of NFTs in his previous role as Chancellor of the Exchequer when he <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/140451\/uk-treasury-outlines-plan-to-regulate-stablecoins-and-issue-an-nft\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">outlined<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> plans to issue an NFT with the UK’s Royal Mint.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“NFT regulation in the UK is largely non-existent,” the parliament committee added. Crypto regulation in the UK is currently limited to anti-money laundering compliance required to register with the Financial Conduct Authority before a crypto firm can acquire a license.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Regulations such as the Financial Markets and Services Bill, which <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/179906\/uk-lawmakers-voted-to-include-crypto-rules-in-finance-regulation-bill\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">passed<\/a> a vote in the House of Commons last week, is expected to beef up a more comprehensive framework for regulating crypto.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"UK’s Royal Mint","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Financial Conduct Authority","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Financial Markets and Services Bill","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"House of Commons","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UK's House of Commons","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Media &amp; Sport Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Parliament","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Rishi Sunak","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Julian Knight","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}