{"summary":"This week&#x27;s episode features a conversation between The Block&#x27;s Wolfie Zhao and Frank Chaparro.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/110978\/no-way-back-from-chinas-bitcoin-mining-clampdown-says-the-blocks-wolfie-zhao","publishDate":"2021-07-09T16:07:57","id":13055,"type":null,"title":"&#x27;No way back&#x27; from China&#x27;s bitcoin mining clampdown, says The Block&#x27;s Wolfie Zhao","category":["PODCASTS"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode <\/i><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">38<\/strong><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> of Season 3 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block’s Frank Chaparro and The Block’s Asia Editor Wolfie Zhao. <\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on <\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, <\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, <\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, <\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"daaab5beb9bba9ae9aaeb2bfb8b6b5b9b1b9a8a3aaaeb5f4b9b5b7\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors <a href=\"http:\/\/eventussystems.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Eventus<\/a>, <a href=\"http:\/\/kraken.com\/scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kraken<\/a>, and Exodus<\/strong>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Eventus is the leading global provider of multi-asset class trade surveillance, transaction monitoring and market risk solutions. Eventus offers a powerful, award-winning trade surveillance platform that is easy to deploy, customize and operate. Eventus is proven in the most complex, high-volume and real-time environments and supports many of the industry’s leading crypto exchanges including Coinbase, Gemini, ErisX and OSL. The company’s rapidly growing client base relies on Eventus’ responsive support and product development teams to overcome its most pressing regulatory challenges.<\/em>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Kraken<\/strong>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Whether you’re an experienced crypto trader or just starting out, Kraken has the tools to help you achieve financial freedom. With 50+ cryptocurrencies to choose from, industry-leading security and a wide variety of features to suit any investing strategy, Kraken puts the power in your hands to buy, sell and trade digital assets. Visit <\/em><a href=\"http:\/\/kraken.com\/scoop\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kraken.com<\/em><\/a><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to get started today.<\/em>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Exodus<\/strong>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">China banning bitcoin has happened so many times it’s become a meme at this point. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">But with this latest crackdown on China-based miners, there might be no coming back, says The Block’s Wolfie Zhao.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“I think the crackdown on bitcoin mining has never been serious. There were a lot of talks in 2018-2019 but there wasn't anything seriously enforced. But this time it seems like there's no way to go back.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">On the most recent episode of The Scoop, Wolfie Zhao, Asia Editor at The Block, explained to host Frank Chaparro how the most recent ban is tied to sustainability concerns within the government.&nbsp;<\/span>","As Zhao put it:","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"So there is the financial side that is cracking down. Banks are cutting funding channels for OTC desks. The other side is the energy angle, cracking down on bitcoin miners… that’s why we see Shenzhen shutting down power supplies to bitcoin mining farms… they didn't say we're just going to crackdown on big companies that are using fossil fuel power.\"<\/span>","\"They just said we want to crackdown,\" Zhao continued.&nbsp;","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Zhao and Chaparro also explore:&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">For a detailed timeline of China’s crackdown on mining, check out Zhao's full <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/daily\/110499\/a-timeline-of-chinas-bitcoin-mining-crackdown-and-how-it-goes-beyond-environmental-concerns\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">report<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Wolfie Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gemini","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Shenzhen","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Asia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Kraken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"OSL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"OTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block’s Wolfie Zhao","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"China","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN"],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}