{"summary":"Rep. Patrick McHenry said he&#x27;s hopeful stablecoin regulation will advance out of the House Financial Services Committee in the next year.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/176795\/mchenry-hopeful-that-ugly-baby-stablecoin-bill-will-advance","publishDate":"2022-10-12T16:25:31","id":13069,"type":null,"title":"McHenry hopeful that ‘ugly baby’ stablecoin bill will advance","category":["THE BLOCK"],"content":["Rep. Patrick McHenry, R-N.C., is hopeful that a stablecoin bill he is negotiating with House Financial Services Chair Maxine Waters will advance in the coming months, he said during an event on Wednesday.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","“We’ve come up with a pretty ugly baby,” McHenry said, referring to draft stablecoin legislation. “It is a baby nonetheless, and we are grateful and hopeful that this ugly baby can grow and prosper into something that is a little more attractive.”<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","McHenry made the comments during D.C. Fintech Week, a financial conference hosted by the Georgetown University Law Center. McHenry is the top Republican on the committee and poised to become the chair if Republicans retake the House in November.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","For months, Water and McHenry have worked behind the scenes to hash out a deal to regulate stablecoins. A draft of the legislation would create a&nbsp;federal framework around stablecoins and temporarily ban the types of payment coins that are not backed by outside assets. The Treasury Department has also been involved in drafting the bill, McHenry said.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","McHenry noted several areas of disagreement, including determining the appropriate federal regulator, the means by which stablecoins are held and new rules around wallets. The Republican lawmaker said he is encouraged that committee members are nearing a deal, despite operating in a “divided Washington” and a time of “chaos.”","“I’m hopeful for what this means in the coming months,” McHenry said. “I’m optimistic that we will come to terms.”<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Washington","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Patrick McHenry","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"McHenry","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"D.C.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"House Financial Services Chair Maxine Waters","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Treasury Department","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"McHenry","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Georgetown University Law Center","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"House","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["MAXINE WATERS","PATRICK MCHENRY"],"authors":["Stephanie Murray","The Block"]}