{"summary":"Bitcoin traded around $24,595 around the close of traditional markets, after whipsawing earlier in the day. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/219875\/crypto-stocks-rally-as-us-inflation-data-comes-in-line-with-expectations","publishDate":"2023-03-14T18:42:31","id":13087,"type":null,"title":"Crypto stocks rally as US inflation data comes in line with expectations","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Bitcoin soared to its highest point since June before gains were mostly wiped out, trading at $24,595 at 5:55 p.m EDT, up 1.4% on the day, according to data from TradingView.","Ether was up about 0.8% to about $1,700.","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/chart\/q0HITX89\/?symbol=COINBASE%3ABTCUSD\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BTCUSD chart by TradingView<\/a>","On March 22, the U.S. Federal Reserve will announce its rate decision, with the potential to swing markets significantly.","Nomura analysts expect the Fed to cut rates 25 basis points due to \"looming financial stability risk,\" while Grayscale analysts wrote that \"it seems unlikely that the Fed will continue an aggressive rate-raising regime.\"","Altcoins followed a similar trajectory as the larger coins, ending the day close to neutral territory. Binance's BNB was down 0.2% at around 6 p.m EDT, while Cardano's ADA increased 1.1%, and Polygon's MATIC declined 0.9%.&nbsp;","Crypto stocks traded up on the day as U.S. inflation data came in line with expectations.&nbsp;","Coinbase shares gained 5.8% to trade above $62, by 6 p.m. EDT, according to TradingView data. MicroStrategy added 2.8% as it climbed to above $220. Jack Dorsey's Block traded up about 6% to above $73.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"5.8%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"6%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$73","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"TradingView","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fed","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"0.9%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"1.4%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"March 22","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$220","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"6 p.m. EDT","content":"TIME"},{"type":"$1,700","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$62","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2.8%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Nomura","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cardano","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"0.8%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$24,595","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"1.1%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"0.2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Jack Dorsey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. Federal Reserve","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"June","content":"DATE"},{"type":"5:55 p.m EDT","content":"TIME"},{"type":"ADA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MicroStrategy","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sam Venis","The Block"]}