{"summary":"CoinFund, a New York-based web3 investment firm, is looking to raise $250 million in seed funding, according to company filings.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/181832\/web3-vc-firm-coinfund-eyes-250-million-for-seed-investments","publishDate":"2022-11-01T13:49:09","id":13081,"type":null,"title":"Web3 VC firm CoinFund eyes $250 million for seed investments","category":["THE BLOCK"],"content":["CoinFund, a New York-based web3 investment firm, is looking to raise $250 million to invest in seed-stage startups just three months after announcing its previous fund. CoinDesk first reported the news.","The company's Cayman Islands-domiciled funds are looking to raise $130 million and $20 million, while its Delaware-incorporated vehicle is seeking $100 million, according to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.sec.gov\/edgar\/search\/#\/q=Coinfund&amp;dateRange=custom&amp;startdt=2022-10-31&amp;enddt=2022-11-01\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">three separate filings<\/a> on Monday. The documents indicate that the sales have yet to occur, meaning that the funds are at a very early stage.&nbsp;","CoinFund did not immediately respond to a request for comment from The Block.","The firm <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/163993\/web3-investment-firm-coinfund-launches-300-million-fund\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/a> a $300 million fund in August backed by institutional investors including the Teacher Retirement System of Texas, Adams Street Partners and StepStone Group.&nbsp;","Previously, CoinFund has backed the Layer 1 blockchain Solana, web3 indexing protocol The Graph and blockchain infrastructure company Blockdaemon, among other startups. More recently, it's participated in developer platform Hyperlane's <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/172095\/variant-leads-18-5-million-fundraise-for-developer-platform-hyperlane\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$18.5 million round<\/a> and crypto investment app <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/173478\/former-revolut-employees-raise-3-5-million-to-build-crypto-investment-app\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Solvo<\/a>'s $3.5 million round.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Cayman Islands","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Delaware","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$250 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$100 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"StepStone Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$3.5 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Adams Street Partners","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$18.5 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$130 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Texas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Blockdaemon","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"CoinFund","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$20 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$300 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Tom Matsuda","The Block"]}