{"summary":"With the help of KPMG and Blockset by BRD, The Block Research has created a comprehensive report exploring the history, motivations, policy designs and technological implementations of Central Bank Digital Currency worldwide. On July 17th at 11:30am ET \/ 8:30am PT The Block&#x27;s Research analyst Mike Rogers will host a panel with leading Central Bank Digital Currency practitioners. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/71014\/the-block-presents-central-bank-digital-currencies-design-policy-implementation","publishDate":"2020-07-09T13:37:24","id":13088,"type":null,"title":"The Block Presents: Central Bank Digital Currencies - Design, Policy &amp; Implementation","category":["WEBINAR"],"content":["With the help of KPMG and Blockset by BRD, The Block Research has created a comprehensive report exploring the history, motivations, policy designs and technological implementations of Central Bank Digital Currency worldwide.&nbsp;","On July 17th at 11:30am ET \/ 8:30am PT The Block’s Research analyst <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/author\/mrogers_tb\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Mike Rogers<\/a> will host a panel with leading Central Bank Digital Currency practitioners.&nbsp;","You can register for the webinar and learn more about the panelists below:&nbsp;","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" title=\"The Block Presents: Central Bank Digital Currencies - Design, Policy &amp; Implementation | The Block\" src=\"https:\/\/app.livestorm.co\/p\/9df633a4-4c11-42e3-a0d0-a13038562c85\/form\" width=\"100%\" height=\"360\" frameborder=\"0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sheila Warren, Head of Blockchain, Digital Assets and Data Policy | World Economic Forum<\/strong>","Sheila began her career as a Wall Street attorney before turning to philanthropy and non-profit tech over a decade ago. She has represented banks, philanthropists and progressive non-profits. Most recently, she was VP of strategic alliances and general counsel of TechSoup, the global social enterprise that has connected civil society organizations around the world with over $9bn in donated tech-based resources. Previously, Sheila also designed and launched NGOsource, a service focused on international grant making. Sheila is a graduate of Harvard College and Harvard Law.","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Carmelle Cadet, Founder &amp; CEO | Emtech <\/strong>","A passionate advocate for financial inclusion, economic development, and a former Finance and Business Executive at IBM, Carmelle is now the founder and CEO of <a href=\"https:\/\/www.futuremtech.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">EMTECH<\/a>, a Fintech For The Modern Central Bank. The company recently launched a new initiative, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.projectnewdawn.info\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Project New Dawn<\/a>, which presents \"A Digital Cash Infrastructure For All\" concept to address the underbanked problem in the U.S.","With former regulators, technology experts and innovators as Advisors, Carmelle is building a portfolio of modern central bank software that delivers a more inclusive and resilient financial infrastructure.","For the last 3 years, Carmelle worked on Digital Currency technologies and strategies for the purpose of addressing financial inclusion and lowering the cost of cross border payments.","As a thought leader in the Central Bank Digital Currency (CBDC) space, Carmelle engages with Central Banks from Africa to the Caribbean to enable their transition to the digital currency era in an inclusive way. A native of Haiti, she speaks French and Creole.","Carmelle was also selected as an Inspiring Fintech Females 2019 by NYC Fintech Women, and is considered a pioneer in her field.","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">John Kiff, Senior Financial Sector Expert, International Monetary Fund <\/strong>","John Kiff has been a Senior Financial Sector Expert at the International Monetary Fund (IMF) since 2005. Prior to that, he worked at the Bank of Canada for 25 years, where he spent most of his time managing the funding and investment of the government’s foreign exchange reserves, including running its large interest rate and currency swap book. At the IMF he was part of the team that produces the semi-annual&nbsp;<a href=\"http:\/\/www.imf.org\/external\/pubs\/ft\/gfsr\/index.htm\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Global Financial Stability Report<\/a>. More recently he has been focusing on fintech issues, over-the-counter derivatives, and pension risk transfer markets. He has published many&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/scholar.google.com\/citations?hl=en&amp;user=oei4lxIAAAAJ&amp;view_op=list_works&amp;sortby=pubdate\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">articles and papers<\/a>&nbsp;on these topics, and actively tweets on them on Twitter (@<a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/kiffmeister\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kiffmeister<\/a>).","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Robert Bench, Director of Applied Fintech Research, Federal Reserve Bank of Boston<\/strong>","Robert Bench leads the Applied Fintech Research Division for the Federal Reserve Bank of Boston, tasked with performing applied research to inform Federal Reserve System policy and decision makers about the implications of technology on the Federal Reserve’s mission broadly. Robert is an adjunct professor at the Boston University School of Law and a graduate of Boston College and the NortheasternUniversity School of Law.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"International Monetary Fund (IMF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NYC Fintech Women","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Project New Dawn","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"IMF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Boston College","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Applied Fintech Research Division","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bank of Canada","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Robert Bench","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Head of Blockchain","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Caribbean","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"EMTECH","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"KPMG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Federal Reserve System","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Carmelle","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Fintech For The Modern Central Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Central Banks","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"8:30","content":"TIME"},{"type":"Harvard Law","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Senior Financial Sector Expert","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$9bn","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Africa","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Central Bank Digital Currency","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Federal Reserve Bank of Boston","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Federal Reserve","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Creole","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Harvard College","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Emtech","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Robert Bench","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Inspiring Fintech","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July 17th","content":"DATE"},{"type":"NortheasternUniversity School of Law","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"IBM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Boston University School of Law","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2005","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Data Policy | World Economic Forum","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Director of Applied Fintech Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mike Rogers","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sheila Warren","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"International Monetary Fund","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Haiti","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"BRD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"John Kiff","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sheila","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Carmelle","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["The Block","The Block"]}