{"summary":"Digital Asset, the New York-based blockchain company, has found a new chief executive officer to replace Wall Street veteran Blythe Masters, who stepped","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/16430\/digital-asset-picks-new-ceo-after-exit-of-blythe-masters","publishDate":"2019-03-19T09:00:13","id":13180,"type":null,"title":"Digital Asset picks new CEO after Blythe Masters&#x27; exit","category":["LAYER 1S"],"content":["Digital Asset, the New York-based blockchain company, has found a new chief executive officer to replace Wall Street veteran Blythe Masters, who stepped down from the position at the end of 2018, the company announced Tuesday.","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.digitalasset.com\/about\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Yuval Rooz<\/a>, the firm's former chief operating officer, was appointed CEO, according to a press release. Rooz, a former high-frequency trading executive, takes the firm's reins after a number of key personnel exits, including the head of its European business, Gavin Wells, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.risk.net\/risk-management\/6409696\/digital-assets-european-chief-heads-for-the-door\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">who left in March<\/a>. In February, James Powell, its former CIO and CTO, left in February, as reported by <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/digital-asset-loses-second-cto-in-6-months-as-startup-shake-up-continues\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CoinDesk<\/a>.","AG Gangadhar served as temporary CEO during the firm's executive search. \"Along with the rest of the Board, I feel very strongly that Yuval's strategic agility, business acumen, mission-driven orientation and deep belief in our people and products make him uniquely qualified to lead Digital Asset successfully into the future,” the former Uber executive said of Rooz's appointment.&nbsp;","Rooz will have to fill the shoes of Masters, a juggernaut in the blockchain market who led the firm through its expansion globally. The former JPMorgan banker retains her seat on the firm's board.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Yuval Rooz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"February","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Yuval","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Rooz","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"CoinDesk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Blythe Masters","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"James Powell","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gavin Wells","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Board","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Masters","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CTO","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}