{"summary":"A Bahamas probe is investigating FTX executives in connection to client withdrawals after the exchange&#x27;s assets were frozen, Bloomberg reported.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/194359\/bahamas-regulators-investigate-ftx-client-withdrawals-bloomberg","publishDate":"2022-12-12T18:34:50","id":13204,"type":null,"title":"Bahamas regulators investigate FTX client withdrawals: Bloomberg","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Whether or not FTX executives played a role in client withdrawals that took place after the exchange saw its assets frozen is now under investigation by Bahamian authorities, Bloomberg News <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2022-12-12\/bahamas-probes-ftx-local-clients-withdrawals-during-implosion\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a>, citing sources.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">FTX former CEO and co-founder Sam Bankman-Fried was interviewed in his Nassau residence a number of times by investigators, sources with knowledge of the matter told Bloomberg. The probe seeks to better understand if Bankman-Fried and co-founder Gary Wang had knowledge or involvement in the transactions.<\/span>","Bahamian authorities are studying relationships between FTX.com, which is registered locally as FTX Digital Markets Ltd., and sister trading firm Alameda Research.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bankman-Fried is set to provide <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/194205\/overbooked-sam-bankman-fried-to-testify-before-congress-virtually\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">virtual testimony<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> before Congress tomorrow, opting out of an in-person appearance in light of what he said was an “overbooked” schedule.<\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Congress","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nassau","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX Digital Markets Ltd.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gary Wang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg News","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BANKRUPTCY FILINGS","FTX","SAM BANKMAN-FRIED"],"authors":["Jeremy Nation","The Block"]}