{"summary":"Former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried lost his bid again to be released from jail ahead of his trial next week, according to multiple reports. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253445\/sam-bankman-fried-loses-bid-for-temporary-release-from-jail-reports","publishDate":"2023-09-28T11:14:17","id":13226,"type":null,"title":"Sam Bankman-Fried loses bid for temporary release from jail: reports","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried lost a fresh bid to be released from jail ahead of his <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253303\/sam-bankman-fried-can-wear-a-suit-to-court-take-notes-on-laptop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">trial next week<\/a>, according to multiple <a href=\"https:\/\/finance.yahoo.com\/news\/bankman-fried-loses-bid-release-144346439.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reports<\/a>.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Attorneys for Bankman-Fried had <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/252900\/sam-bankman-frieds-counsel-again-asks-for-jail-release-ahead-of-trial\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">asked<\/span><\/a> a New York district court judge on Monday for a temporary release, arguing that it was \"<\/span><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">necessary for the preparation of [his] defense.\"<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"We submit that we are finding it exceedingly difficult as a practical matter to adequately prepare for trial with the restrictions on access currently in place,\" his lawyers had said. \"This is not a point we make lightly but it is the reality of the nature of this case.\"<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Prosecutors argued in a <a href=\"https:\/\/storage.courtlistener.com\/recap\/gov.uscourts.nysd.590939\/gov.uscourts.nysd.590939.295.0.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">letter<\/span><\/a> to Judge Lewis Kaplan on Wednesday that Bankman-Fried's request for release should be denied.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bankman-Fried had resources before he was jailed in August, prosecutors said.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Many of the accommodations provided by the MDC [Metropolitan Detention Center] and the BOP [Bureau of Prisons]—including the use of two personal airgapped computers in different locations for added convenience and the MDC’s hand-receipt and delivery of hard-drive materials to the defendant—are accommodations beyond those accorded to most detainees,\" they said.<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bankman-Fried also lost an <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/252435\/us-court-of-appeals-rejects-sam-bankman-frieds-efforts-for-pre-trial-release\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">appeal<\/span><\/a> to be released from jail ahead of his trial last week in the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit.&nbsp;<\/span><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">He was sent to await trial in <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/244540\/ftx-judge-says-hes-revoking-bail-for-bankman-fried-inner-city-press\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">jail<\/span><\/a> in August after prosecutors accused him of witness tampering by leaking the private diary of former colleague and ex-girlfriend Caroline Ellison to the New York Times and using an encrypted message app to contact a potential witness.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bankman-Fried did score some <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253303\/sam-bankman-fried-can-wear-a-suit-to-court-take-notes-on-laptop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">wins<\/span><\/a> this week, after the judge approved a request that will allow him to change into a suit each morning of his trial. He will also be able to <\/span><span class=\"s5\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">use a laptop in the courtroom, but it won't be connected to the internet.<\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"New York Times","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. Court of Appeals","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Caroline Ellison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Second Circuit","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MDC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Lewis Kaplan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["FTX","SBF TRIAL"],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}