{"summary":"Crypto data infrastructure platform Goldsky has announced a $20 million seed round led by Felicis and Dragonfly Capital.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/169190\/crypto-data-infrastructure-platform-goldsky-raises-20-million-seed-round","publishDate":"2022-09-12T13:00:05","id":13234,"type":null,"title":"Crypto data infrastructure platform Goldsky raises $20 million seed round","category":["INVESTMENTS"],"content":["Crypto data infrastructure platform Goldsky said on Monday that it had closed a $20 million seed round led by VC firms Felicis and Dragonfly Capital.","Investors also included the entrepreneur Elad Gil, Plaid founders Zach Perret and William Hockey, Uniswap Labs, 0x Labs, Zhuoxun Yin of Magic Eden, Alex Xu of Azuki and Robert Leshner of Compound Finance.","Founded by Kevin Li and Jeff Ling, who met while working as engineers at unicorn data company Heap, Goldsky launched last year with an initial $1.4 million in funding.&nbsp;","The company automates the creation of end-to-end data pipelines. This means users can hone in on real-time data across multiple chains, reshape it through a data streaming platform and serve up the final result directly to a website via an API.&nbsp;","This, Goldsky says, solves one of the most costly problems faced by the industry, which is reading and processing data from deployed smart contracts.&nbsp;","“Teams often find themselves doing significant amounts of data engineering to aggregate and process decentralized activity. This can run up tens of thousands of dollars and more importantly, take valuable time away from the core product,” it said in a statement.","The company's current customer base includes POAP, Polymarket and Arweave.","Goldsky is among a clutch of other firms that are fighting for a corner in the blockchain data space. At the end of last year, Nansen, a crypto analytics startup, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/127747\/data-startup-nansen-secures-fresh-funding-at-750-million-valuation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">raised at a $750 million valuation<\/a>, in a round led by Accel. Kaiko, Messari, Coin Metrics, CryptoCompare, Dune Analytics and DappRadar have also raised over the last year.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Robert Leshner of Compound Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alex Xu","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kaiko","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Jeff Ling","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nansen","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Messari","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Goldsky","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"William Hockey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Accel","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Zhuoxun Yin of Magic Eden","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Zach Perret","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Uniswap Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$750 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Dune Analytics","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kevin Li","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$20 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$1.4 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Dragonfly Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Elad Gil","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Callan Quinn","The Block"]}