{"summary":"Meta&#x27;s move now brings digital collectibles, particularly non-fungible tokens, closer to mainstream social media use.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/161497\/meta-expands-digital-collectables-support-on-instagram-to-100-more-countries-adopts-flow-blockchain","publishDate":"2022-08-04T11:11:09","id":13252,"type":null,"title":"Meta expands posting digital assets on Instagram across 100 countries","category":["NFTS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Meta, parent company to the social media platform Facebook, announced on Thursday that it is expanding its Instagram digital asset integration over 100 countries.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Meta’s expansion of digital asset integration brings non-fungible tokens (NFT) into the mainstream, as Instagram has over two billion worldwide active users, according to CNBC.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The regions supporting the expansion include the Americas, Asia-Pacific, the Middle East and Africa, according to an updated post from Meta. Users must connect a digital wallet to the social media platform Instagram to start posting their digital collectibles.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"As of today, we support connections with third-party wallets including Rainbow, MetaMask, Trust Wallet, Coinbase Wallet and Dapper Wallet coming soon,\" Meta wrote in a post.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Meta is also leveraging the Flow blockchain, developed by CryptoPunks creator Dapper Labs, to allow individuals to post their assets minted on the Flow blockchain on Instagram. Meta's currently supported blockchains include Ethereum, Polygon and Flow.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Meta’s move comes three months after the firm first began testing digital asset integration on Instagram. Users can post non-fungible tokens (NFTs) as their profile picture like on Twitter, The Block previously <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/145758\/meta-to-start-testing-digital-collectibles-on-instagram\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Americas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Middle East","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Coinbase Wallet","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CNBC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Pacific","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Africa","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Asia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}