{"summary":"Bitcoin is sustaining a rally first sparked by a false news report on Monday about the supposed approval of a spot ETF.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/257930\/bitcoin-holds-onto-momentum-after-dress-rehearsal-for-possible-spot-etf-approval","publishDate":"2023-10-17T13:29:50","id":1325,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin holds onto momentum after &#x27;dress rehearsal&#x27; for possible spot ETF approval","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitcoin's price held onto momentum first seen yesterday after a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/256622\/bitcoin-price-sees-volatile-monday-spiking-near-30000-following-false-bitcoin-etf-news\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">false report<\/a> about the supposed approval of a spot ETF had crypto markets buzzing.&nbsp;<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The world's largest digital asset by market capitalization climbed 1.5% over the past 24 hours to $28,520 at 12:30 p.m. ET. Conversely, ether has slumped, down around 1% over the same period to $1,578, according to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coingecko.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Coingecko<\/a>.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">On Monday, a false report inaccurately asserted that BlackRock's proposed spot bitcoin ETF had gained approval, causing a surge in trading activity and volatility. While bitcoin pared gains after the report was debunked, it still ended the day higher than where it had started.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Analysts mostly saw the market activity ignited by the false report as a dress rehearsal for what would happen if a spot bitcoin ETF was actually approved.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Yesterday's case showed us that the market is waiting for good news and ready for growth,\" YouHodler Chief of Markets Ruslan Lienkha told The Block. \"<\/span><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spot bitcoin ETFs will be approved sooner or later, and market participants understand that.\"<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This perspective was echoed by BlackRock CEO <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/257826\/blackrocks-larry-fink-says-bitcoin-rumor-rally-shows-pent-up-interest-in-crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Larry Fink<\/a> in an interview with&nbsp;<\/span><a class=\"editor-rtfLink\" href=\"https:\/\/www.youtube.com\/watch?v=3O4pnwq6ddY\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Fox Business<\/span><\/a><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on Monday. He suggested the market reaction to the false report revealed \"the pent-up interest in crypto.\"<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">According to Fink, there was more to Monday's rally than the ETF rumor. He said it suggested a flight to quality spurred by fears of further global unrest.<\/span>","\"I think there's more people running into a flight to quality, whether that is in Treasuries, gold or crypto, depending on how you think of it. And I believe crypto will play that type of role, as a flight to quality,\" The BlackRock CEO added.","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Fink's appraisal of the situation was reinforced by a downturn in U.S. stocks in early trading on Tuesday, as rising bond yields once again weighed in on investor appetite for risk assets. The S&amp;P 500 lost 0.2%, while the Nasdaq Composite slipped 0.4% and the Dow Jones Industrial Average fell 0.1%.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In contrast, the 10-year U.S. Treasury yield topped 4.8%, suggesting investors are factoring in the prospects of tighter Federal Reserve monetary policy. The risk-off sentiment could be amplified if investors consider the economic impact of global unrest, particularly the war in Ukraine, and the Israel-Hamas conflict.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">According to Tuesday's Deutsche Digital Assets <a href=\"https:\/\/deutschedigitalassets.com\/wp-content\/uploads\/2023\/10\/Crypto_Market_Pulse_17_10_2023.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">report<\/a>, performance dispersion among crypto assets continues to be relatively high, with bitcoin outperforming many major altcoins, including ether.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Deutsche Digital Assets analyst André Dragosch said ether has continued to underperform bitcoin for a variety of reasons including the recent release of the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/255683\/bitvm-bitcoin-smart-contracts\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BitVM<\/a> paper by Robin Linus that suggests that \"any computable function can be verified on bitcoin.\"<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Dragosch suggested that the saturation in demand for ETH staking was another factor for the altcoin's underperformance versus bitcoin.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"The size of the ETH entry queue has declined considerably, and that suggests the demand for staking is becoming saturated,\" he said. \"This suggests that staking yields may have found their equilibrium at around ~3.45% p.a.\"<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">According to Ruslan Lienkha, interest from mainstream media and institutional finance also explains bitcoin's recent tendency to outperform ether.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Bitcoin is outperforming ether because we are in the process of a broader adoption of crypto among the general public, so it is quite logical that purchasing bitcoin is usually a new investor's first move,\" the YouHodler analyst said. \"There are just a few investors who start from alternative coins.\"<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$1,578","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S. Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ruslan Lienkha","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Larry Fink","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"S&amp;P","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"3.45%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"André Dragosch","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"0.1%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Fink","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Fox Business","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Israel","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"12:30 p.m. ET","content":"TIME"},{"type":"Deutsche Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"4.8%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"BlackRock","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"1.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"0.4%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$28,520","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"0.2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Robin Linus","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Hamas","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"tighter Federal Reserve","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fink","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nasdaq Composite","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Deutsche Digital Assets","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ukraine","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["ANALYST REPORTS","CRYPTO MOVERS","ECONOMIC INDICATORS","EQUITY MOVERS","RATE DECISIONS"],"authors":["Brian McGleenon","The Block"]}