{"summary":"DeFi trading platform Hashflow raises $25 million in a Series A funding round, bringing the company&#x27;s valuation to $400 million.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/159024\/hashflow-raises-25-million-to-support-structured-product-launch","publishDate":"2022-07-21T13:50:22","id":13250,"type":null,"title":"Hashflow raises $25 million to support structured product launch","category":["DEFI"],"content":["The $25 million Series A funding brings the decentralized finance trading platform’s valuation to $400 million","Hashflow aims to launch structured products by launching decentralized request-for-quote platform by Q4 2022","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Hashflow, the decentralized finance trading platform, raised $25 million in a Series A round to fund its expansion and launch into structured products later this year. <\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The capital infusion brings the company's valuation to $400 million.<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;134233117&quot;:false,&quot;134233118&quot;:false,&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335551550&quot;:1,&quot;335551620&quot;:1,&quot;335559685&quot;:0,&quot;335559737&quot;:0,&quot;335559738&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In an <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/blog.hashflow.com\/hashflow-raises-25m-series-a-from-jump-crypto-wintermute-and-gsr-3f4e6edec28a\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">blog post<\/span><\/a><span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;on Thursday, the company said investors in this round included Electric Capital, Dragonfly Capital Partners, LedgerPrime, Balaji Srinivasan, Jump Crypto, Wintermute Trading, GSR, Kronos Research, Altonomy, Coinbase Ventures, Kraken Ventures, Fabric Ventures, Evernew Capital, Spacewhale Capital, Meltem Demirors, Anthony Sassano and Jason Choi.<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;134233117&quot;:false,&quot;134233118&quot;:false,&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335551550&quot;:1,&quot;335551620&quot;:1,&quot;335559685&quot;:0,&quot;335559737&quot;:0,&quot;335559738&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The newly raised capital will be used “to continue to build and scale — regardless of market conditions,” the firm said in the post on its website. According to Hashflow's <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.hashflow.com\/roadmap\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">roadmap<\/span><\/a><span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, the firm aims to deploy the trading platform on Solana by the third quarter of this year to enable native and cross-chain swaps. <\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">It also is planning to offer structured products in allowed jurisdictions by the fourth quarter of this year, launching decentralized request-for-quote (RFQ) platform “to seamlessly trade structured products,” including options and exchange-traded funds.<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;134233117&quot;:false,&quot;134233118&quot;:false,&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335551550&quot;:1,&quot;335551620&quot;:1,&quot;335559685&quot;:0,&quot;335559737&quot;:0,&quot;335559738&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Founded in 2021, Hashflow offers a decentralized exchange (DEX) that uses an RFQ model. According to the company's <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/docs.hashflow.com\/hashflow\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">website<\/span><\/a><span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, this approach allows professional market makers to manage liquidity pools – rather than relying on automated market makers&nbsp;that are more “capital inefficient, routinely prone to risks […] and cannot price non-spot assets.”<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"GSR","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hashflow","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jason Choi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Electric Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spacewhale Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Anthony Sassano","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Balaji Srinivasan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kronos Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Altonomy","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$400 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"fourth quarter","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$25 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"third quarter","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Evernew Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Fabric Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Meltem Demirors","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Dragonfly Capital Partners","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DEX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wintermute Trading","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jump Crypto","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Coinbase Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kraken Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Kharishar Kahfi","The Block"]}