{"summary":"Trader Joe&#x27;s integration with Arbitrum and BNB Chain follows a trend of other decentralized finance (DeFi) protocols deploying on multiple chains.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/199398\/trader-joe-dex-nft-marketplace-bnb-chain","publishDate":"2023-01-05T07:09:05","id":13293,"type":null,"title":"Trader Joe&#x27;s DEX and NFT marketplace to expand to BNB Chain","category":["METAVERSE & NFT"],"content":["Avalanche-based DeFi trading platform Trader Joe and the associated Joepegs NFT marketplace will deploy on BNB Chain by the end of March.","<span class=\"NormalTextRun SCXW186756962 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This means BNB Chain users will be able to participate in the launch of new NFT collections using the <\/span><span class=\"NormalTextRun SpellingErrorV2Themed SCXW186756962 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Joepegs<\/span><span class=\"NormalTextRun SCXW186756962 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> NFT Marketplace, as well as trade tokens using Liquidity Book, according to a company release.&nbsp;<\/span>","Trader Joe has the highest total trading volume across all applications on Avalanche, but has seen significant decreases since June,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/defillama.com\/dexs\/chains\/avalanche\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">according to DeFiLlama.<\/a> Joepegs has 34,000 users and has facilitated more than $9.5 million in secondary sales, the release added.&nbsp;","\"We believe the efficiency and security of BNB Chain, combined with the user-friendly offerings of the Trader Joe DEX and Joepegs NFT Marketplace, will drive growth and success for the wider NFT and DeFi ecosystem,\" Alvin Kan, director of growth and ops at BNB Chain, said in a statement.&nbsp;","Trader Joe also moved to expand on Ethereum scaling platform Arbitrum <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/191582\/avalanche-dex-trader-joe-is-deploying-on-arbitrum\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">last month,<\/a> the first time it had ventured from Avalanche since its launch in 2021.&nbsp;","Trader Joe's integration with Arbitrum an d BNB Chain follows a trend of other decentralized finance protocols deploying on multiple chains. Protocols such as <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/177141\/decentralized-exchange-protocol-uniswap-v3-is-deploying-on-zksync-2-0\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Uniswap<\/a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/138018\/aave-set-to-launch-third-version-of-its-defi-protocol-across-six-networks\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Aave<\/a> have deployed on several chains over the past year, with the rationale that more chains will result in reaching more users.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Joepegs NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DeFiLlama","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Joepegs NFT Marketplace","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Uniswap","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$9.5 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Joe","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alvin Kan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DEX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Joepegs<\/span><span class=\"NormalTextRun SCXW186756962 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> NFT Marketplace","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"June","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["DEXS"],"authors":["Lucy Harley-McKeown","The Block"]}