{"summary":"With Star Wars NFTs, Disney takes one step closer into the world of crypto in partnership with an a16z-backed startup.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/229576\/star-wars-crypto-toys-coming-through-disney-cryptoys-partnership","publishDate":"2023-05-04T15:18:54","id":13306,"type":null,"title":"Star Wars crypto toys coming through Disney, Cryptoys partnership","category":["METAVERSE & NFT"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">With wannabe Jedis rattling their lightsabers around the world in honor of Thursday's Star Wars Day celebrations, Cryptoys has announced it will be selling — in partnership with Disney — digital toys fashioned after three of the movie franchises' most iconic characters. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Cryptoys, backed by Andreessen Horowitz, Mattel and Dapper Labs, said it will release “15 limited-edition Luke Skywalker, Princess Leia and Darth Vader collectible digital toys.”<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Although The Walt Disney Company is one of the most successful marketers and sellers of merchandise based on famous intellectual property, the Hollywood studio and theme park operator has yet to make a big foray into crypto. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Last year, the media conglomerate <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/172654\/disney-hiring-transaction-lawyer-for-aggressive-nft-and-defi-plans-linkedin-post\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">advertised a job<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> opening for <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">a transaction lawyer to explore emerging technology opportunities, according to a posting on LinkedIn. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Powered by Dapper Labs’ Flow blockchain, consumers can buy Cryptoys Star Wars NFTs for $39.99. Purchases will be possible with Apple&nbsp; Pay and Google Pay, “worldwide,” according to the company.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Mattel","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Darth Vader","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Disney —","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Walt Disney Company","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dapper Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cryptoys","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Princess Leia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Andreessen Horowitz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Star Wars Day celebrations","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Luke Skywalker","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$39.99","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}