{"summary":"Cardano will have its first decentralized stablecoin in January, according to details emerging from the Cardano Summit.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/188772\/cardano-based-decentralized-stablecoin-djed-will-hit-mainnet-in-january","publishDate":"2022-11-21T11:49:43","id":13300,"type":null,"title":"Cardano-based decentralized stablecoin Djed will hit mainnet in January","category":["STABLECOINS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Djed, Cardano's first decentralized stablecoin, will go live on the main network in January.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Developers announced the move at the Cardano Summit event in Lausanne, Switzerland. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Djed is a decentralized stablecoin soft-pegged to the U.S. dollar that will exist on Cardano’s Layer 1 blockchain. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Backed with crypto assets instead of fiat money, Djed has been developed by a firm called Coti in collaboration with Cardano lead developer Input Output.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The stablecoin has been in development for more than a year. Once launched, Cardano users will be able to take ADA — the native cryptocurrency of the Cardano network — and use it as collateral to mint the stablecoin.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The stablecoin is designed to be overcollateralized, meaning that it is backed by excess collateral in the form of cryptocurrency held in a reserve. This is a similar design used by dai, the most popular decentralized stablecoin in the Ethereum ecosystem. Each Djed will require more than 400% in collateral value to be minted.&nbsp;<\/span>","\"Djed takes what's great with crypto as collateral, meaning no fiat in the system, but also takes over-collaterization very seriously,\" Coti CEO Shahaf Bar-Geffen told The Block.&nbsp;","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">At its launch, Djed will be integrated into 40 apps in the Cardano ecosystem, Bar-Geffen said. The launch will also come with the introduction of DjedPay, a service that will let merchants and other crypto players accept Djed payments.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Switzerland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Cardano","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Cardano","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Cardano Summit","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"400%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Geffen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Lausanne","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"ADA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Vishal Chawla","Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}