{"summary":"The crypto project co-created by Sam Altman said that about 9,500 Argentinians verified their World ID in a single day in August.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/248229\/wolrdcoin-hits-single-day-sign-up-record-in-argentina-despite-local-investigation","publishDate":"2023-08-30T22:42:24","id":13345,"type":null,"title":"Worldcoin hits single day sign-up record in Argentina despite local investigation","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Worldcoin, an identity-focused crypto project co-created by Sam Altman, said demand for its World ID service in Argentina remains strong, with sign-ups hit a single day record in August — despite an ongoing probe into the project's handling of data by Argentine authorities.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/worldcoin.org\/blog\/announcements\/demand-world-id-sign-up-record-argentina\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">blog post<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> published today, Worldcoin said that roughly 9,500 Argentinians verified their World ID in a single day. “That’s one verified human in Argentina every 9 seconds,” it said.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Worldcoin project, officially launched on July 24, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/241871\/worldcoins-plan-to-decentralize-orb-production-sparks-illicit-data-harvesting-concerns\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">encourages users to prove their identity online<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> by signing up for a World ID via an iris scan.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">It has deployed its “orbs” in four cities in Argentina — Buenos Aires, Mar del Plata, Cordoba and Mendoza, according to the blog post.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The record numbers comes as Argentine authorities continue to investigate the project over data privacy.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Earlier this month, Argentina’s Public Information Access Agency <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.argentina.gob.ar\/noticias\/la-aaip-investiga-el-tratamiento-de-datos-personales-de-worldcoin-en-argentina\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> it will <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/244289\/argentina-says-its-investigating-worldcoin-over-data-privacy\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"thoroughly analyze\" the processes and practices<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> used in relation to the collection, storage and use of personal data. The agency added that it plans to take unspecified measures to address any problem identified.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kenya — a market in which Worldcoin has already signed up hundreds of thousands of customers — <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/242704\/worldcoin-suspended-in-kenya-one-of-its-biggest-markets-for-sign-ups-so-far\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">suspended Worldcoin earlier this month<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. The Block previously reported that <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/242704\/worldcoin-suspended-in-kenya-one-of-its-biggest-markets-for-sign-ups-so-far\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Worldcoin had signed up more than a quarter of a million people in Nairobi<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, Kenya’s capital city, as of December 2022. <\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Cordoba","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Nairobi","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Kenya","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Mendoza","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"earlier this month","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Mar del Plata","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"July 24","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sam Altman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Worldcoin","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Worldcoin","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Worldcoin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Argentina","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"December 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Public Information Access Agency","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Buenos Aires","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"ups","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["DECENTRALIZED INFRASTRUCTURE","IDENTITY","INTERNET"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}