{"summary":"A new accelerator program will aid up to 10 startups building for applications designed for an open metaverse.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/244250\/outlier-ventures-and-futureverse-to-award-up-to-1-million-to-startups-with-new-accelerator","publishDate":"2023-08-10T13:55:01","id":13353,"type":null,"title":"Futureverse Base Camp with Outlier Ventures to give up to $1M to startups","category":["STARTUPS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Prolific crypto <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">venture capital firm Outlier Ventures and Futureverse, an AI metaverse company, have launched an accelerator program to aid startups building for applications designed for an open metaverse.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Futureverse Base Camp, a 12-week accelerator program, will support participating startups building on the Root Network with $100,000 in development capital, the companies said in a statement. The Root Network is Futureverse’s “<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">public decentralized blockchain network optimized for metaverse apps and experiences.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">On top of mentorship from Outlier and Futureverse, in what will be the first of multiple editions of the program, between six to 10 startups will likely be selected to receive funding between $600,000 to $1 million in total, according to a person familiar with the matter.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Using AI, Futureverse said it possesses a “suite of proprietary” tools designed to help construct and operate an open metaverse bolstered by blockchain technology. The company recently <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">raised $54 million in <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/240321\/ripple-invests-in-round-for-ai-metaverse-company-partnered-with-fifa-and-mastercard\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Series A funding<\/a>. The well known <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">crypto payment solutions provider Ripple Labs participated in the round<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> led by 10T Holdings.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Futureverse has created what we believe to be foundational building blocks and brand partnerships for the open metaverse at scale,” said Outlier Founder and CEO Jamie Burke. “From the early stages of working with them, we have invested in multiple layers of their stack and IP, as they simultaneously partnered with&nbsp; a growing number of portfolio companies coming out of our accelerator.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Outlier has invested in 250 startups, according to the statement.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Futureverse, which was founded by <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Aaron McDonald, Shara Senderoff, Marco Brondani and Daniel Gillespie, <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">has partnerships with <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">high-profile organizations and entrepreneurs like FIFA, Mastercard, Death Row Records, Snoop Dogg and Keanu Reeves.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Outlier and <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Futureverse's <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">accelerator program is slated to kick off in January 2024.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Snoop Dogg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Aaron McDonald","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mastercard","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jamie Burke","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$600,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Daniel Gillespie","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"January 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Futureverse","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Keanu Reeves","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Shara Senderoff","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Marco Brondani","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"10T Holdings","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Futureverse","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$100,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Futureverse Base Camp","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$54 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"FIFA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Outlier Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Death Row Records","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}