{"summary":"Both bankrupt firms reached an agreement in principle to resolve FTX&#x27;s claims against Genesis, lawyers said.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/241864\/ftx-genesis-seek-to-settle-dispute-in-bankruptcy-cases","publishDate":"2023-07-27T23:30:54","id":13364,"type":null,"title":"FTX, Genesis seek to settle dispute in bankruptcy cases","category":["BANKRUPTCY"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bankrupt FTX Trading and Genesis Global Holdco have reached an agreement in principle to settle a dispute surrounding their bankruptcy protection cases, their lawyers said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/restructuring.ra.kroll.com\/genesis\/Home-DownloadPDF?id1=MjEyNDc4Nw==&amp;id2=-1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">letter<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> submitted Thursday to a bankruptcy judge, legal counsels for both firms said they intend to “promptly document the Settlement and file a motion pursuant to Federal Rule of Bankruptcy Procedure 9019(a) for entry of an order approving the Settlement in their respective courts.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The letter, however, did not elaborate on the settlement.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bankrupt FTX has previously claimed that crypto lender Genesis owed the failed exchange as much as $2 billion, a dispute that would likely delay Genesis's own court proceedings, Bloomberg <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2023-07-06\/genesis-s-2-billion-spat-with-ftx-may-delay-creditor-payouts?in_source=embedded-checkout-banner\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> earlier this month.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In January, Genesis <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/190311\/digital-currency-groups-genesis-global-files-for-bankruptcy-protection\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filed<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> for <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection in New York federal bankruptcy court after it <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">took a financial hit following the collapses of crypto hedge fund Three Arrows Capital and FTX last year.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Genesis <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/228128\/genesis-creditors-reject-restructuring-plan\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">owes around $3.6 billion<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to its top 50 creditors, including claims from Gemini, the crypto exchange founded by the Winklevoss twins.<\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Genesis Global Holdco","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Federal Rule of Bankruptcy Procedure","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gemini","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Winklevoss twins","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$3.6 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$2 billion","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}