{"summary":"New amendments to the UK&#x27;s financial bill may lead to stronger regulation of crypto in the country.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/178970\/uk-government-includes-new-crypto-amendment-in-finance-regulation-bill","publishDate":"2022-10-21T10:56:23","id":13372,"type":null,"title":"UK government includes new crypto amendment in finance regulation bill","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The UK’s Financial Services and Markets bill is home to new amendments seeking to regulate crypto and ban unauthorized service providers, following an amendment paper <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/publications.parliament.uk\/pa\/bills\/cbill\/58-03\/0146\/amend\/finserv_rm_pbc_1021.pdf\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">published<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on Friday.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Andrew Griffith, financial services minister, tabled amendments and added a note \"to clarify that the powers relating to financial promotion and regulated activities can be relied on to regulate cryptoassets and activities relating to cryptoassets. Cryptoasset is also defined, with a power to amend the definition.\"<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">If passed, the amendments will give the UK a more comprehensive regulatory framework for crypto. Specifically, it will provide the Financial Conduct Authority and HM Treasury with more oversight powers. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Currently, the UK's crypto regulatory powers are largely in the hands of the FCA, which decides on the registrations of crypto firms according to strict anti-money laundering requirements.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The proceedings on the bill should be concluded on November 3. However, with turmoil following Prime Minister Liz Truss’ resignation on Thursday, changes in the schedule may be anticipated.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Financial Services and Markets bill's framework already <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/158648\/uk-treasury-unveils-plan-to-regulate-stablecoins-in-financial-services-and-markets-bill\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">focuses<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on stablecoins, and the broader framework will tie the UK closer to the EU’s comprehensive Markets in Crypto-Assets regulation.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"UK’s Financial Services","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FCA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"November 3","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Financial Conduct Authority","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"EU","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Financial Services","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Liz Truss","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"HM Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Andrew Griffith","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Crypto","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["FCA"],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}