{"summary":"Former nChain CEO Christen Ager-Hanssen has departed the company after claiming to discover a “conspiracy to defraud nChain shareholders.&quot;","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253741\/nchain-ceo-departs-asserts-craig-wright-is-not-satoshi","publishDate":"2023-09-30T14:38:59","id":13396,"type":null,"title":"nChain CEO departs, asserts Craig Wright is not Satoshi","category":["THE BLOCK"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Former nChain Group CEO Christen Ager-Hanssen has departed the company after claiming to discover a “conspiracy to defraud nChain shareholders orchestrated by a significant shareholder.”&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ager-Hanssen stated in his <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/agerhanssen\/status\/1707884086776279486\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">post on X<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that he no longer believes that nChain chief scientist Craig Wright is the true identity behind Satoshi Nakamoto, the pseudonymous creator of Bitcoin. Ager-Hanssen, in a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/agerhanssen\/status\/1708127218616930489\/photo\/1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">follow-up post<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, posted a screenshot of a report that claims to show evidence of Wright’s browsing history that contradicts Wright’s <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/241466\/craig-wright-loses-appeal-peter-mccormack-bitcoin-libel-case\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">long-running assertions<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that he is Satoshi.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ager-Hanssen also <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/agerhanssen\/status\/1708118753525854369\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">claims<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to have delivered a whistleblower report to the nChain board along with five others, after which all six were either dismissed or suspended from their positions. Ager-Hanssen <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/agerhanssen\/status\/1708145719633215586\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> he plans on releasing the report, which concerns the influence of billionaire Calvin Ayre, who Ager-Hanssen characterizes as a “shadow director\/dictator,” on nChain’s operations.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/nchain.com\/nchain-company-statement\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">statement<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, nChain’s board claimed that “...concerns regarding the recent stewardship of the business, led the board to commission a detailed and independent investigation,” and that prior to the board acting on the results of the investigation, Ager-Hanssen “conducted himself in a serious and inappropriate manner” that prompted his dismissal. <\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Satoshi Nakamoto","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Calvin Ayre","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Craig Wright","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ager","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"nChain Group CEO Christen Ager","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wright","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Satoshi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Hanssen","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Zack Abrams","The Block"]}