{"summary":"With the license in place, the crypto exchange operator plans to expand in Asia, focusing on serving institutions.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/176064\/crypto-exchange-coinbase-gets-license-in-singapore","publishDate":"2022-10-11T05:11:47","id":13407,"type":null,"title":"Crypto exchange Coinbase gets license in Singapore","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto exchange operator Coinbase <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coinbase.com\/blog\/singapore-ipa-announcement\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/a> Monday that it received a license from the Monetary Authority of Singapore (MAS) as it plans to expand in Asia.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The license — an in-principle approval as a major payments institution — allows Coinbase to offer regulated digital payment token (DPT) products and services in the city-state. Coinbase said in a statement that gaining the license \"is an important step, as we plan to launch our full suite of retail, institutional and ecosystem products.\"&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Coinbase is now one of over a dozen crypto firms that have received licenses in Singapore, including <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/137255\/paxos-in-principle-approval-singapore-mas-crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Paxos<\/a>, Crypto.com and DBS Vickers — the brokerage run by Singapore's largest bank DBS. Licensed firms are required to comply with anti-money laundering (AML) and counter-financing of terrorism (CFT) requirements for providing crypto services. Coinbase rival <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/127262\/binance-singapore-halts-licensing-push-amid-investment-in-hg-exchange\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance pulled out<\/a> of Singapore after withdrawing its licensing application in late 2021.&nbsp;<\/span>","Notably, in-principle approvals are not final. A Paxos spokesperson recently <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/137255\/paxos-in-principle-approval-singapore-mas-crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">told The Block<\/a> that the in-principle license allows the company to continue its Singapore operations, while final approval requires further work with regulators and passing an exam.","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Coinbase considers Singapore the hub for institutional business in Asia. The firm said Singapore is the top financial center in Asia and the third in the world after New York and London, and is keen to serve institutional clients, including banks and asset managers, as they show increasing interest in investing directly in digital assets.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Coinbase reportedly already employs 100 people in Singapore, with product engineers forming the largest chunk of those staff. Coinbase's venture unit has also invested in over 15 Singapore-based crypto startups in the past three years and plans to continue backing the local ecosystem.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Singapore plays a critical regulatory and commercial role in APAC and beyond, and serves as our global talent hub; we are excited to continue investing and building for the crypto economy here,\" said Coinbase.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"DPT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Monetary Authority of Singapore (MAS","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"APAC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DBS Vickers","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Asia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"DBS","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"London","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"AML","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["COINBASE"],"authors":["Yogita Khatri","The Block"]}