{"summary":"The move marks Avara&#x27;s second acquisition, following the purchase of web3 social gaming app Sonar in December 2022.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/263372\/aave-rebrands-to-avara-acquires-software-developer-behind-ethereum-wallet-family","publishDate":"2023-11-16T13:08:47","id":13437,"type":null,"title":"Aave rebrands to Avara, acquires software developer behind Ethereum wallet Family","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Blockchain technology firm Aave Companies rebranded to Avara and announced an acquisition of a Los Angeles-based web3 startup.&nbsp;&nbsp;","Avara will now be the parent entity over Aave, Lens, the stablecoin GHO, Sonar and other brands, according to a company release. In addition to the name change, Avara also bought Los Feliz Engineering, the web3 software development startup behind the Ethereum crypto wallet Family and the developer library ConnectKit.","Benji Taylor, the founder of Family, will join Avara as the senior vice president of product and design. The entire Los Feliz engineering team will <a href=\"https:\/\/family.co\/blog\/avara\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">join<\/a> Avara as well.&nbsp;","\"Our transformation to Avara and the integration of Family into our fold are not mere changes in name or structure,\" wrote Avara founder Stani Kulechov in a statement. \"These are significant strides toward our ultimate mission: an open, decentralized internet that’s equitable, inspires participation and fosters innovation.\"","Avara's purchase of Los Feliz Engineering marks the second acquisition during its lifetime. The company <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/192247\/aave-acquires-web3-social-gaming-app-sonar-to-expand-lens-protocol\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">acquired<\/a> the web3 social gaming app Sonar in Dec. 5, 2022 to expand the ecosystem of <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/200859\/lens-protocol-now-lets-creators-issue-token-gated-content\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Lens<\/a>, a decentralized social media platform.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Avara","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Benji Taylor","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Avara","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Los Angeles","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Aave Companies","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Los Feliz","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Los Feliz Engineering","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Stani Kulechov","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Dec. 5, 2022","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["PRIVATE COMPANY M&AMP;A"],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}