{"summary":"FTX was cleared to begin sales of LedgerX, Embed and its European and Japanese units by the judge overseeing the bankruptcy process. More than 100 parties have already expressed interest.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/201953\/ftx-approval-sell-ledgerx","publishDate":"2023-01-13T03:57:40","id":13444,"type":null,"title":"FTX gets judge&#x27;s approval to start selling LedgerX and other units","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Collapse crypto exchange FTX got the judicial green light to begin selling parts of its business, the next step in raising money to repay its more than one million creditors.","LedgerX, Embed and FTX's European and Japanese operations can begin auction processes in the coming days, Judge John Dorsey ruled on Thursday.&nbsp;","More than 100 offers of interest have already come in, the team overseeing the wind up of FTX <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/200224\/ftx-businesses-including-ledgerx-draw-interest-from-over-100-potential-buyers\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">told<\/a> the bankruptcy court earlier this month. The U.S. Trustee, a division of the Department of Justice, earlier<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/199982\/us-trustee-objects-to-ftxs-planned-sale-of-ledgerx-and-other-units-reuters\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> objected<\/a> to any sale process given investigations into FTX are ongoing. The Trustee will be able to review the sale process and file objections, Thursday's ruling said.","A lawyer for FTX <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/201034\/ftx-locates-5-billion-in-cash-and-liquid-crypto-contemplates-sale\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">told<\/a>&nbsp;the court on Wednesday that the firm had so far found around $5 billion in cash, liquid assets and crypto tokens. Any unit sales will add to that pot. It is yet not clear exactly how much money is owed to creditors. Speaking at the same hearing,&nbsp;FTX attorney Andy Dietderich said the exchange's incomplete financial records meant his team was recreating claim values for every customer.","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"John Dorsey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Department of Justice","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"earlier this month","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$5 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Andy Dietderich","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S. Trustee","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["COURT HEARINGS","FTX","PRIVATE COMPANY M&AMP;A"],"authors":["Benjamin Robertson","The Block"]}