{"summary":"The US asked Japan to increase pressure on its cryptocurrency exchanges and miners to sever ties with Russia amid the Ukraine conflict","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/156735\/us-asks-japan-to-help-cut-crypto-miners-links-with-russia-ft","publishDate":"2022-07-09T04:51:48","id":13440,"type":null,"title":"US asks Japan to help cut crypto miners’ links with Russia: FT ","category":["REGULATION"],"content":["<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The US asked Japan to increase pressure on its cryptocurrency exchanges and miners to sever ties with Russia amid the Ukraine conflict, the <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.ft.com\/content\/639be0d5-04a2-4b3a-90eb-a18139f6e769\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Financial Times reported<\/span><\/a><span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on Friday, citing people familiar with the matter.<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The US asked Tokyo specifically to stop its companies' cryptocurrency mining operations in the Irkutsk region in Siberia, two people familiar told the FT. <\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The area is favored for crypto mining operations because of its low temperatures and cheap hydroelectric power. <\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Japan’s Financial Services Agency renewed its demands that the Japanese exchanges they oversee cease any such&nbsp;relationships, people close to three exchanges told the FT.<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Some Japanese exchanges and crypto mining businesses have developed complex networks of subsidiaries to continue their Russian operations, people close to the situation said.<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Tokyo","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Irkutsk","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Japan’s Financial Services Agency","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Russia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Financial Times","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Japan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Siberia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ukraine","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Mike Millard","The Block"]}