{"summary":"The U.S. arm of Bittrex filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection in May.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/260128\/crypto-exchange-bittrexs-u-s-shutdown-approved-at-bankruptcy-court","publishDate":"2023-10-31T00:15:42","id":1348,"type":null,"title":"Crypto exchange Bittrex&#x27;s U.S. shutdown approved at bankruptcy court","category":["BANKRUPTCY"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto exchange Bittrex received court approval for its revised bankruptcy plan to wind down its U.S. operations.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A court <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/casedocs.omniagentsolutions.com\/cmsvol2\/pub_47475\/570bd49f-5d29-4f40-bc76-2ee4d96d1512_515.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filing<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> showed that Judge Brendan Shannon,&nbsp;at a hearing in Delaware on Monday, approved the company’s liquidation plan to repay its remaining creditors.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“As stated on the record at the Hearing, the Court ruled that it would enter a revised Proposed Order, which resolves the SEC’s informal comments,” the filing said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bittrex <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/229861\/bittrex-files-for-bankruptcy-protection-less-than-a-month-after-sec-charges\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;in May after the Securities and Exchange Commission charged it with running an unregistered exchange. The company then <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/244309\/bittrex-settles-with-the-sec-for-24-million\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">settled with the SEC for $24 million<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in August.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">While Bittrex has shut down operations in the U.S., Bittrex Global is still active elsewhere.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In August, <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bittrex Global CEO Oliver Linch <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/245634\/bittrex-global-targets-those-wary-of-us-regulatory-uncertainty-after-sec-settlement\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">assured<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> those increasingly wary of having any connection to the U.S., given regulatory uncertainty in the region, that \"if they want to do business with a non-U.S. regulated digital assets exchange, Bittrex Global is here for you.\"&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bittrex was once one of the largest exchanges in the U.S., with a market share of USD support of nearly 23% at the start of 2018, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/crypto-markets\/spot\/usd-support-exchange-volume-market-share\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">data from The Block<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> show. However, it later collapsed to below 1% in 2021 and hasn't recovered since.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Court","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Delaware","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"23%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Bittrex Global","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Oliver Linch","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bittrex","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Brendan Shannon","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$24 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"1%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Hearing","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["BANKRUPTCY FILINGS"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}