{"summary":"MoonPay has hired additional staff for its concierge service that helps celebrities like Jimmy Fallon jump on the NFT bandwagon.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/150535\/moonpay-builds-out-celeb-concierge-service-with-meta-hire","publishDate":"2022-06-08T02:43:28","id":13517,"type":null,"title":"MoonPay builds out celeb concierge service with Meta hire","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">MoonPay is building out its celebrity non-fungible token (NFT) concierge service following a quiet rollout last year, according to two announcements from new hires joining the team.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Former associate director at Standard Chartered Bank, Charlotte Laborde joined MoonPay in February as strategy lead to the COO. On Tuesday she updated her job title on LinkedIn to concierge manager. Justin Johnson, who held a role as creator partnerships lead for North America at Meta, has also announced joining the team.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block&nbsp;<\/span><a class=\"editor-rtfLink\" href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/125483\/moonpay-concierge-celebrities-nft\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">first reported<\/span><\/a><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on the existence of a beta version of MoonPay’s concierge service late last year, when the company<\/span> described it as a “white glove service for high net worth individuals who want to purchase NFTs in the simplest way without all the hassle of setting up a wallet, buying crypto, using that crypto to purchase an NFT and then taking custody of it.”","The increased emphasis on hiring new people for the service demonstrates MoonPay's designs on the NFT market and a move away from its core business model of crypto onramp infrastructure for payments.&nbsp;","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Previous clients of the service include TV host Jimmy Fallon and rapper Post Malone.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">MoonPay CEO Ivan Soto-Wright told The Block in December 2021 that&nbsp;<\/span><a class=\"editor-rtfLink\" href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/128517\/moonpay-boss-on-how-the-startup-is-guiding-celebs-into-nfts\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Post Malone offered the company the chance to sponsor his upcoming music video<\/span><\/a><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;after it helped him acquire his first Bored Ape Yacht Club NFT. Soto-Wright described the concierge as “creating a really cool cultural conversation.”<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Jimmy Fallon also mentioned purchasing an NFT on-air using MoonPay shortly after his own ape purchase. MoonPay was then mentioned a second time on his show in January during a segment with Paris Hilton.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">But the company’s links to celebrities don’t stop there. MoonPay’s courting of celebrities continued into April when its latest funding round saw almost $87 million in investment from a star-studded list of celebs including Justin Bieber, Bruce Willis, Paris Hilton and Matthew McConaughey.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Its clients' penchant for getting in on the craze as quickly as possible has led to its concierge service <\/span><a class=\"editor-rtfLink\" href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/news+\/137239\/why-is-moonpay-overpaying-so-much-for-bored-apes\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">overpaying for popular NFTs<\/span><\/a><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. According to calculations by The Block in March, MoonPay paid on average an additional 26% for Bored Ape NFTs relative to the collection’s floor price.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Matthew McConaughey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Paris Hilton","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"COO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jimmy Fallon","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bruce Willis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$87 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Bored Ape Yacht Club NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"North America","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Meta","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"February","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Standard Chartered Bank, Charlotte Laborde","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ivan Soto","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Justin Bieber","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Malone","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"December 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"26%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Wright","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Paris Hilton","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Justin Johnson","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Callan Quinn","The Block"]}