{"summary":"The Final installment of The Digital Asset Data and Infrastructure series will take place on June 25th at 12pm ET \/ 9am.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/68491\/digital-asset-data-and-infrastructure-part-iii-a-conversation-with-kpmgs-sam-wyner","publishDate":"2020-06-16T14:07:41","id":13543,"type":null,"title":"Digital Asset Data and Infrastructure Part III: A Conversation with KPMG&#x27;s Sam Wyner","category":["SPONSORED"],"content":["The Final installment of The Digital Asset Data and Infrastructure series will take place on June 25th at 12pm ET \/ 9am. The Block’s Director of News, <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Frank Chaparro <\/strong>will have a 1 on 1 conversation with&nbsp;<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sam Wyner<\/strong>, Director of KPMG’s Blockchain Center of Excellence and co-leader of Cryptoasset Services for KPMG US.","Sam and Frank will explore the complexities and challenges in traditional data and infrastructure faced by both large Financial Services organizations and crypto-first organizations. You can register for the event below:&nbsp;","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" title=\"Digital Asset Data and Infrastructure Part III: A conversation with KPMG's Sam Wyner | The Block\" src=\"https:\/\/app.livestorm.co\/p\/b3c2be79-cd91-4434-9a71-b47562efcea8\/form\" width=\"100%\" height=\"360\" frameborder=\"0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Sam Wyner<\/strong>","Sam is a Director in KPMG’s Blockchain Center of Excellence and co-leads Cryptoasset Services for KPMG US. He has helped small and large financial services institutions and fin techs create strategies and manage risk with emerging technologies including cryptoassets, blockchain and intelligent automation","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"The Digital Asset Data","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frank","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sam Wyner","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"KPMG US","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"KPMG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"June 25th","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Cryptoasset Services","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Financial Services","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Blockchain Center of Excellence","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sponsored","The Block"]}