{"summary":"The Singapore-headquartered firm said that it aims to expand into NFT analytics through the IP acquisition of Origins.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/261341\/web3-firm-treehouse-acquires-origins-to-expand-nft-data-offering","publishDate":"2023-11-03T01:21:48","id":13565,"type":null,"title":"Web3 firm Treehouse acquires Origins to expand NFT data offering","category":["MERGERS & ACQUISITIONS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Singapore-based Web3 data firm Treehouse acquired NFT analytics platform Origins to expand its NFT product offering.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Treehouse <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.prnewswire.com\/news-releases\/treehouse-acquires-origins-to-expand-into-nft-analytics-301976150.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> today the intellectual property acquisition of Origins Analytics, which offers NFT-related data analysis using both on-chain and off-chain data.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">As part of the acquisition, the founding team of Origins, which raised $4 million last year, will join Treehouse to offer services including an algorithmically tagged NFT wallet notification system, NFT analytics bots and NFT wallet profiling API.<\/span>","Treehouse did not disclose the size of the acquisition deal.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In 2021, Treehouse raised $18 million in a seed round from investors including Lightspeed, MassMutual, Binance, Mirana, LeadBlock, Jump, GSR and Wintermute. The firm said it’s currently assessing the possibility of more mergers and acquisitions.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Treehouse is excited to make this move into NFT analytics,\" Brandon Goh, chief executive officer of Treehouse, said in the statement. \"Despite the bear market, Treehouse is expanding and is actively looking to acquire synergetic businesses.''&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Binance","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"GSR","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$4 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$18 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Wintermute","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MassMutual","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lightspeed","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Mirana","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Origins Analytics","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Origins","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Brandon Goh","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Treehouse","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["PRIVATE COMPANY M&AMP;A"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}