{"summary":"The new bill is similar to Senate legislation introduced in September called the Accountability for Cryptocurrency in El Salvador (ACES) Act.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/140772\/us-house-members-introduce-bill-to-mitigate-the-risks-from-el-salvadors-adoption-of-bitcoin","publishDate":"2022-04-05T20:47:48","id":13579,"type":null,"title":"New House bill aims to &#x27;mitigate the risks&#x27; El Salvador&#x27;s adoption of Bitcoin","category":["BITCOIN"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Two US representatives introduced legislation aimed at mitigating the risks to the US of El Salvador adopting bitcoin as legal tender, followin<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">g a S<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">enate bill introduced in February that focuses on the same actions.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The bipartisan House bill, introduced by representatives Norma Torres (D-Calif.) and Rick Crawford (R-Ark.), aims to “mitigate the risks to the United States of El Salvador’s adoption of Bitcoin as legal currency.” It proposes legislation for a so-called Accountability for Cryptocurrency in El Salvador (AC<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ES) Act, the name of the previous Senate bill.&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Global financial institutions have studied and detailed the numerous risks of El Salvador’s adoption of Bitcoin, and the international community acknowledges the potential danger,” Rep. Torres said in a press release. “El Salvador is an independent democracy and we respect its right to self-govern, but the United States must have a plan in place to protect our financial systems from the risks of this decision, which appears to be a careless gamble rather than a thoughtful embrace of innovation.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">According to an <a href=\"https:\/\/torres.house.gov\/media-center\/press-releases\/torres-crawford-introduce-bill-mitigate-risks-el-salvador-s-adoption\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">April 4 announcement<\/a> from Torres’ office, the bill “was introduced as companion legislation” to the Senate bill introduced on <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/134519\/new-us-senate-legislation-mandates-plan-to-mitigate-potential-risks-of-el-salvadors-bitcoin-adoption\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">February 16<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> by Senators Jim Risch (R-Idaho), Bob Menendez (D-N.J.), and Bill Cassidy (R-La.). Like that Senate bill, the House version would also require the State Department to produce a report on El Salvador's bitcoin adoption and a plan to mitigate possible risks.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.congress.gov\/bill\/117th-congress\/house-bill\/7391?s=1&amp;r=1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">more recent bill<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> is denoted H.R. 7391. Like its Senate counterpart, the House version would \"require reports on the adoption of a cryptocurrency as legal tender in El Salvador, and for other purposes.” The bill was referred to the House Committee on Financial Services and House Committee on Foreign Affairs.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Meanwhile, the Senate placed its own version of the bill on its<\/span> <a href=\"https:\/\/www.congress.gov\/bill\/117th-congress\/senate-bill\/3666\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">legislative calendar<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, signaling that it has enough support from lawmakers to warrant further discussion.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Rep. Torres serves as chair of the Central America Caucus, a bipartisan congressional group. Rep. Crawford is the ranking member of the House Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence’s Subcommittee on Counterterrorism, Counterintelligence, and Counterproliferation.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">El Salvador’s president Nayib Bukele, a bitcoin supporter who made the cryptocurrency legal tender last September, responded to the original Senate bill with <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/nayibbukele\/status\/1506823849060577293\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweets<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> challenging the US.&nbsp;<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We are not your colony, your back yard or your front yard,” Bukele said in a February 16 <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/nayibbukele\/status\/1494066643625988107?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1494066643625988107%7Ctwgr%5E%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.theblockcrypto.com%2Flinked%2F134519%2Fnew-us-senate-legislation-mandates-plan-to-mitigate-potential-risks-of-el-salvadors-bitcoin-adoption\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweet<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. “Stay out of our internal affairs.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bukele is scheduled to speak at the Bitcoin 2022 conference in Miami on April 7.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"February 16","content":"DATE"},{"type":"El Salvador","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Miami","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Idaho","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bukele","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"House Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence’s Subcommittee on Counterterrorism","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"N.J.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Torres","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Rick Crawford","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bob Menendez","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"La.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Nayib Bukele","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Counterintelligence","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"United States","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"El Salvador","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Crawford","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"April 4","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Central America Caucus","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"February","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Jim Risch","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"State Department","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"House","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Norma Torres","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"US of El Salvador","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bill Cassidy","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Calif.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"House Committee on Financial Services and House Committee on Foreign Affairs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April 7","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ark.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Senate","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["CONGRESS"],"authors":["Kristin Majcher","The Block"]}