{"summary":"CryptoPunk #110 is the second Punks Legacy Project donation from Yuga Labs.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/210635\/punks-in-the-pompidou-yuga-labs-donates-second-cryptopunk-in-three-months","publishDate":"2023-02-10T10:59:48","id":13655,"type":null,"title":"Punks in the Pompidou: Yuga Labs donates second CryptoPunk in three months","category":["CRYPTO ECOSYSTEMS"],"content":["NFT heavyweight Yuga Labs is attempting to cement its place in French art history with the donation of CryptoPunk #110 to one of the country's leading contemporary art museums.&nbsp;","The <a href=\"https:\/\/cryptopunks.app\/cryptopunks\/details\/110\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">female punk<\/a>, who wears purple lipstick, an earring, smokes a cigarette and sports a mohawk will live in the Centre Pompidou's permanent collection. It is part of the NFT shop's Punks Legacy Project.","CryptoPunk #110 is the second Punks Legacy Project donation from Yuga Labs. CryptoPunk #305 was donated to the Institute of Contemporary Art,&nbsp;<span class=\"xn-location\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Miami<\/span>&nbsp;at <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/187075\/a-cryptopunk-could-soon-be-coming-to-an-art-gallery-near-you\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Art Basel 2022<\/a>.&nbsp;","CryptoPunks are generally considered one of the most valuable assets in the NFT space, which has seen values drop over the past year. The floor price, or the lowest entry point to the collection for buyers, has been consistently rangebound between 60 and 65 ETH (or around $100,000) since September, according to data from <a href=\"https:\/\/nftpricefloor.com\/cryptopunks\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">NFT Price Floor<\/a>.","Since June last year, the CryptoPunks collection has been headed by Noah Davis, the former head of digital art at Christie's auction house, who said that \"aesthetically speaking, Punks are about as chic as Donald Judd furniture or Piet Mondrian paintings,\" and believes that CryptoPunks deserve to be on the walls of contemporary art and design institutions worldwide.","Yuga Labs also owns top collections including Bored Ape Yacht Club, Meebits, Otherdeeds and <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/186646\/yuga-labs-acquires-beeples-10ktf-names-him-advisor\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Beeple’s 10KTF.<\/a>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"CryptoPunk #","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Yuga Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Miami","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"NFT Price Floor","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bored Ape Yacht Club","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Centre Pompidou","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Institute of Contemporary Art","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$100,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Piet Mondrian","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Christie","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"June last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Donald Judd","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Art Basel 2022","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Punks Legacy Project","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Noah Davis","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["CRYPTOPUNKS","YUGA LABS"],"authors":["Lucy Harley-McKeown","The Block"]}