{"summary":"Global credit network, Hiddan Road, announced a $50 million Series A round led by Castle Island Ventures.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/156379\/hidden-road-announces-50-million-series-a-round-led-by-castle-island-ventures","publishDate":"2022-07-07T18:27:04","id":13698,"type":null,"title":"Hidden Road announces $50 million Series A round led by Castle Island Ventures","category":["THE BLOCK"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Hidden Road Partners <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.prnewswire.com\/news-releases\/hidden-road-raises-50-million-in-series-a-led-by-castle-island-ventures-301581877.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on Thursday that it has closed a $50 million Series A round led by Castle Island Ventures.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Citadel Securities, FTX Ventures, Uncorrelated Ventures, Greycroft, XBTO Humla Ventures, Wintermute, SLN Capital, Profluent Trading, Coinbase Ventures among others also joined the round, per the release.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">According to the statement, Hidden Road hopes to solve “many of today's problems in credit intermediation and prime brokerage caused by legacy technology, archaic workflows and conflicts of interest.”&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The firm’s platform is “quantitatively-driven” and provides real-time risk management and “seamless credit across, products and asset classes.” Hidden Road offers prime brokerage, clearing and financing services for both traditional and digital assets.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Matt Walsh, general partner at Castle Island Ventures told The Block: \"Hidden Road is offering a range of products that we see as essential for institutions entering the digital assets market. We are excited to be investing behind this great team.\"<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Wintermute","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Uncorrelated Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Castle Island Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SLN Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Hidden Road","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"XBTO Humla Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Greycroft","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Coinbase Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Citadel Securities","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Matt Walsh","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Hidden Road Partners","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$50 million","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}