{"summary":"An Ethereum address reportedly controlled by Ethereum co-founder Jeffrey Wilcke has transferred 22,000 ether, worth $41.13 million, to Kraken.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/233118\/ethereum-jeffrey-wilcke-kraken","publishDate":"2023-06-05T09:46:26","id":13703,"type":null,"title":"Ethereum co-founder transfers $41 million in ether to address on Kraken","category":["PEOPLE"],"content":["An Ethereum address reportedly controlled by Ethereum co-founder Jeffrey Wilcke has <a href=\"https:\/\/etherscan.io\/tx\/0x9722a93a8684c6cad7374f9aaabc1e74f7493a556985101e7c95a1120eb99605\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">transferred 22,000 ether<\/a>, worth $41.1 million, to an address on the Kraken exchange.","The transfer occurred roughly two hours ago. Multiple sources labeled the address as belonging to Wilcke, including analytics platforms Nansen and Arkham, The Block Research confirmed.","Wilcke's address <a href=\"https:\/\/etherscan.io\/address\/0xa7e4fecddc20d83f36971b67e13f1abc98dfcfa6\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">still holds over 150,000 ether<\/a>, worth nearly $280 million.","As noted by crypto reporter Colin Wu, <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/WuBlockchain\/status\/1665706815685021696\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Wilke's address hadn't transferred ether out for 29 months<\/a>, when 15,000 ether was transferred into Kraken.","The price of ether is down just over 1.25% on the day.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The price of ether has decreased by 2.25% over the past week. Source: TradingView<\/span>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This article has been updated to include the price of ether.<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2.25%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Wilcke","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$41.1 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"TradingView","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Arkham","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Colin Wu","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Jeffrey Wilcke","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nansen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kraken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1.25%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Wilke","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$280 million","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Adam James","The Block"]}