{"summary":"Credix has announced an $11.25 million Series A round to expand in Latin America.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/167685\/defi-investing-platform-credix-raises-11-million-in-series-a-round","publishDate":"2022-09-06T08:57:24","id":13716,"type":null,"title":"DeFi investing platform Credix raises $11 million in Series A round","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Decentralized credit platform Credix said it has secured a $11.25 million Series A round as it seeks to expand in Latin America.","Credix is a Solana-based credit marketplace that matches institutional investors with fintechs in emerging markets. It launched in Brazil in 2021 and hopes to start operations to Mexico and Colombia<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> later this year<\/strong>, the company said in a statement on Tuesday.&nbsp;","Also participating in the round were <span data-ogsb=\"white\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Va<\/span>lor Capital Group, Victory Park Capital and <span lang=\"en-US\" data-ogsc=\"black\" data-ogsb=\"white\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ParaFi Capital<\/span>. The chairman of Itaú Latam, part of the region's biggest bank, Itau, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.linkedin.com\/in\/ricardo-marino-b06268167\/?originalSubdomain=br\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ricardo Villela Marino<\/a> also participated as a private investor.&nbsp;Credix's latest raise builds on a $2.5 million seed round it secured in late 2021, which ParaFi also participated in.&nbsp;","Credix, which describes itself as \"<span data-slate-fragment=\"JTdCJTIyb2JqZWN0JTIyJTNBJTIyZG9jdW1lbnQlMjIlMkMlMjJkYXRhJTIyJTNBJTdCJTdEJTJDJTIybm9kZXMlMjIlM0ElNUIlN0IlMjJvYmplY3QlMjIlM0ElMjJibG9jayUyMiUyQyUyMnR5cGUlMjIlM0ElMjJwYXJhZ3JhcGglMjIlMkMlMjJpc1ZvaWQlMjIlM0FmYWxzZSUyQyUyMmRhdGElMjIlM0ElN0IlN0QlMkMlMjJub2RlcyUyMiUzQSU1QiU3QiUyMm9iamVjdCUyMiUzQSUyMnRleHQlMjIlMkMlMjJsZWF2ZXMlMjIlM0ElNUIlN0IlMjJvYmplY3QlMjIlM0ElMjJsZWFmJTIyJTJDJTIydGV4dCUyMiUzQSUyMmElMjBuZXh0LWdlbmVyYXRpb24lMjBjcmVkaXQlMjBpbmZyYXN0cnVjdHVyZSUyMHRvJTIwZ2l2ZSUyMGJvcnJvd2VycyUyMGluJTIwZW1lcmdpbmclMjBjb3VudHJpZXMlMjBhY2Nlc3MlMjB0byUyMHByZXZpb3VzbHklMjB1bnRhcHBlZCUyMGNhcGl0YWwuJTIwJTIyJTJDJTIybWFya3MlMjIlM0ElNUIlNUQlMkMlMjJzZWxlY3Rpb25zJTIyJTNBJTVCJTVEJTdEJTVEJTJDJTIya2V5JTIyJTNBJTIyZWE0MGFiYjEwMjA0NDgwOGE5MmY4NmQ1ZjQzMmIxZDYlMjIlN0QlNUQlMkMlMjJrZXklMjIlM0ElMjJiYmEwZmFiOTRkMzY0NTcwOWRkODlkYjZmNDZmZmM0NyUyMiU3RCU1RCUyQyUyMmtleSUyMiUzQSUyMmE0Yzc0NWFkNWUxOTRiNWQ4ZGNmYmEzMjE2ZjY5NTUxJTIyJTdE\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">a next-generation credit infrastructure to give borrowers in emerging countries access to previously untapped capital,\" provides opportunities for investors to underwrite individual deals or passively invest through a lower-risk liquidity pool. Fintechs using the platform receive funds in stablecoins, which they then convert to local currency to lend.<\/span>","Emerging markets tend to have low credit penetration, with traditional financial institutions unwilling to finance businesses and individuals perceived to be higher risk. That's created ample opportunity for fintech projects to flourish. Last year, investment in fintech in Latin America reached $5 billion over 120 deals, up from $2 billion and 82 deals the year earlier, according to <a href=\"https:\/\/home.kpmg\/xx\/en\/home\/insights\/2022\/01\/pulse-of-fintech-h2-2021-emerging-markets-latam.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">KPMG<\/a>.","\"We are unlocking global debt capital markets,\" Credix founder and CEO <a href=\"https:\/\/www.linkedin.com\/in\/thomas-bohner-a0165597\/?originalSubdomain=be\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Thomas Bohner<\/a> told The Block. \"DeFi allows us to pool capital more effectively, smart contracts drive waterfalls and automated payment flows, tokenization provides for increased transparency and payment provenance.\"","More than 25 funds are using Credix's platform, which according to the company has enabled more than $20 million in financing.","<span lang=\"en-US\" data-ogsc=\"black\" data-ogsb=\"white\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"We believe <span class=\"markqwuxtytlb\" data-markjs=\"true\" data-ogac=\"\" data-ogab=\"\" data-ogsc=\"\" data-ogsb=\"\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Credix<\/span> is rebuilding an antiquated system through blockchain technology and solving a real-world problem at a critical time for the industry,” ParaFi Capital Managing Partner <\/span><span lang=\"en-US\" data-ogsc=\"black\" data-ogsb=\"white\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.linkedin.com\/in\/ben-forman-b78b2416\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ben Forman<\/a> said.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ben Forman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$2.5 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Latin America","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Brazil","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Victory Park Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$5 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Mexico","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Va<\/span>lor Capital Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ricardo Villela Marino","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Credix","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Credix","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"fintech","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Colombia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Thomas Bohner","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Itaú Latam","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"KPMG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$20 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$11.25 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Solana","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$2 billion","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Kristin Majcher","The Block"]}