{"summary":"FTX filed for bankruptcy yesterday.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/186400\/ftx-digital-markets-co-ceo-staying-on-lawyering-up-sources","publishDate":"2022-11-12T19:24:12","id":13720,"type":null,"title":"FTX Digital Markets co-CEO staying on, lawyering up: Sources","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["FTX Digital Markets CEO Ryan Salame is sticking around the bankrupt company to salvage what's left and has hired lawyers amid the bankruptcy chaos, people familiar with the matter told The Block.","Additionally, former Alameda Research CEO Sam Trabucco, who stepped stepped down in August, is hiring a lawyer. He was replaced by Caroline Ellison, who is among those in Sam Bankman-Fried's inner circle.&nbsp;<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nSalame joined FTX a little more than a year ago, and was head of OTC for Alameda Research for two years prior to that. Salame is staying on in the position to try to salvage what's left of FTX.","FTX filed for bankruptcy yesterday and former CEO Sam Bankman-Fried has not officially been located, though reports say he is in the Bahamas.","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ryan Salame","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Caroline Ellison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bahamas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Trabucco","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Christiana Loureiro","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}