{"summary":"Bitcoin remains below $17,000, ether reclaimed levels above $1,200, while crypto stocks were down in early morning trading.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/196573\/bitcoin-crypto-prices-higher-grayscales-gbtc-discount-to-nav-narrows","publishDate":"2022-12-20T09:59:55","id":13756,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin, crypto prices higher, Grayscale&#x27;s GBTC discount to NAV narrows","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["Crypto prices rose marginally and most crypto-related stocks were lower shortly after the open.&nbsp;","Bitcoin was trading at around $16,800 at 9 a.m. EST, up 0.6% over the past 24 hours, according to TradingView data.&nbsp;","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/symbols\/BTCUSD\/?exchange=COINBASE\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BTCUSD chart by TradingView<\/a><\/span>","Ether was up more than 2.5% to move back above $1,200. Binance's BNB added 0.5%, Ripple's XRP gained 2.5%, and Polygon's MATIC was up 0.7%.&nbsp;","Dog-themed memecoins were trading lower, with dogecoin dropping 4%, and shiba inu down 3.7%.&nbsp;","U.S. stock indices fell with the S&amp;P 500 shedding 0.15% and the Nasdaq 100 losing 0.66%.","Coinbase was down about 1.6%, while shares of Silvergate fell by 1.2% at 9:45 a.m., according to Nasdaq data. MicroStrategy shares were flat, and Block traded down by around 2%.&nbsp;","Grayscale's GBTC fund's discount to net asset value (NAV) narrowed to 46.4% from 48%, according to The Block's data.&nbsp;","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/crypto-markets\/structured-products\/premium-of-gbtc\/embed\" title=\"Daily GBTC Premium\/Discount to NAV\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Grayscale <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/196193\/grayscale-gbtc-etf-return-capital\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">revealed<\/a> yesterday it will explore how to return up to 20% of GBTC's capital to shareholders if it cannot turn the product into an exchange-traded fund (ETF).","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"GBTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"TradingView","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"4%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"0.66%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"9:45 a.m.","content":"TIME"},{"type":"0.7%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"1.6%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"20%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"0.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"S&amp;P","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1.2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$16,800","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"0.15%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"9 a.m. EST","content":"TIME"},{"type":"3.7%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"0.6%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$1,200","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"48%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"46.4%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"MicroStrategy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nasdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}