{"summary":"Crypto prop trading firm Radkl has reportedly lost a key investor in billionaire Steve Cohen.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/160850\/steve-cohen-exits-investment-in-crypto-prop-trading-firm-radkl-bloomberg","publishDate":"2022-08-02T08:35:12","id":13765,"type":null,"title":"Steve Cohen exits investment in crypto prop trading firm Radkl: Bloomberg","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Point72's Steve Cohen has exited his investment in crypto trading firm Radkl, according to a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2022-08-01\/billionaire-steve-cohen-exits-investment-in-crypto-startup-radkl#xj4y7vzkg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">report<\/a> by Bloomberg. <\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A spokesperson from Radkl told Bloomberg that — despite the news — the firm is “extremely well capitalized with its current investors and continues to grow rapidly.”<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Radkl is led by Ryan Sheftel and was born out of New York Stock Exchange market maker GTS. The&nbsp;firm previously said that it planned to be an electronic market maker across crypto exchanges, while also trading on a bilateral basis with other market participants.<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">High-speed trading guru Jim Greco previously worked at the firm, before leaving in January of this year to set up <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/133048\/former-radkl-employees-leave-to-launch-new-quant-hedge-fund\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">F9 Research<\/span><\/a>.<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Greco formed digital asset-focused quant investment fund with other former Radkl employees Allan Erskine and Jason Bell. <\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Despite the Radkl website listing Beatrice O’Carroll as managing director, her LinkedIn suggests she left the firm in June. She did not immediately respond to request for comment. <\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Tuesday’s <\/span><span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announcement<\/span><span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> comes less than a year after it was <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/117715\/steve-cohen-is-backing-a-new-crypto-trading-shop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that Cohen invested in the firm. This wasn't Cohen's only crypto investment at the time, as he <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/117485\/steve-cohen-backed-nft-platform-closes-series-a-at-333-million-valuation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">invested<\/a> in NFT project Recur in September 2021.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Radkl and Point72 did not responded to requests for comment from The Block by the time of publication.<\/span>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Corrects headline to show Cohen has exited the investment.&nbsp;<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"F9 Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jason Bell","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Steve Cohen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Radkl","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Beatrice O’Carroll","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"September 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"New York Stock Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cohen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"June","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ryan Sheftel","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Allan Erskine","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jim Greco","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}