{"summary":"Former FTX lawyer Daniel Friedberg shared information about the crypto exchange and Alameda Research with the SDNY court, the SEC and the FBI.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/199360\/ftx-lawyer-tipped-prosecutors","publishDate":"2023-01-05T04:46:09","id":13822,"type":null,"title":"Former FTX lawyer tipped off US prosecutors on SBF fund abuse: Reuters","category":["LEGAL"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Collapsed crypto exchange FTX's former top lawyer, Daniel Friedberg, shared his knowledge of founder Sam Bankman-Fried’s use of customer funds with U.S. prosecutors.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Friedberg joined a meeting on Nov. 22 in the U.S. Attorney for the Southern District of New York office with Federal Bureau of Investigation, Department of Justice, and Securities and Exchange Commission officials, Reuters <a href=\"https:\/\/www.reuters.com\/business\/finance\/ftxs-former-top-lawyer-aided-us-authorities-bankman-fried-case-2023-01-05\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a>&nbsp;— citing a source close to the matter and confirmed by scheduling emails.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In the meeting, Friedberg explained how FTX’s sister trading firm, Alameda Research, worked.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">FBI agents reportedly contacted Friedberg a few days after the crypto exchange filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection in November. He is not under criminal investigation and expects to be a witness in Bankman-Fried’s trial, which is scheduled for October.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bankman-Fried is charged with fraud and accused of misusing billions of dollars worth of FTX customer funds and funneling them into Alameda.&nbsp;<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">He <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/198982\/bankman-fried-pleads-not-guilty-to-criminal-charges\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">pled<\/a> not guilty in a New York federal court on Tuesday. In contrast, his counterparts, former Alameda Research CEO Caroline Ellison and former FTX CTO Gary Wang,&nbsp;<\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/197342\/bankman-fried-in-fbi-custody-ellison-wang-plead-guilty-and-are-cooperating\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">pled<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> guilty to fraud charges in December.<\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Daniel Friedberg","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Caroline Ellison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Federal Bureau of Investigation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"misusing billions of dollars","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Department of Justice","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FBI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"December","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Friedberg","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Reuters","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"the Southern District of New York","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gary Wang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nov. 22","content":"DATE"},{"type":"October","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}