{"summary":"Kraken NFT holders will get a chance to see their digital collectibles displayed on the rear wing the Williams Racing car.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/223391\/kraken-f1-williams-racing","publishDate":"2023-03-28T12:36:32","id":13866,"type":null,"title":"Kraken to team with F1&#x27;s Williams Racing as its first-ever crypto partner","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["If you've ever wanted to see your NFT race by on a Formula 1 car, now's your chance. Just two days before the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.grandprix.com.au\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Grand Prix in Melbourne<\/a> is due to kick off, Kraken <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/krakenfx\/status\/1640700416156397571\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/a> that it's partnering with Williams Racing to become the team's first-ever official crypto and web3 partner.","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/210408\/secs-targeting-of-kraken-staking-program-sends-shockwaves-through-industry\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kraken<\/a>, which <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/217177\/kraken-is-on-track-to-launch-bank-very-soon-despite-regulatory-weird-place\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">earlier this month<\/a> acknowledged a regulatory \"weird place\" amid the recent shuttering of its on-chain staking services for U.S. clients to settle charges brought by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission, said the partnership will connect racing fans around the world to the crypto community \"on a quest for financial freedom.\"","The crypto exchange said it plans to give selected Kraken NFT holders a chance to see their digital collectibles displayed on the rear wing the Williams Racing car, which will also feature Kraken branding for the remainder of the 2023 FIA Formula One World Championship season. The exchange said it <a href=\"https:\/\/www.kraken.com\/williamsracing\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">will<\/a> to announce additional benefits including exclusive content, fan pop-ups and co-branded merchandise.&nbsp;","\"We’re excited to get the partnership underway to offer our fans cutting-edge crypto and web3 experiences, while also enabling Kraken to reach new institutional clients and businesses through our network and events,” Williams Racing commercial director James Bower said in a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.williamsf1.com\/posts\/315c4334-4ab2-4991-8557-066c8759b776\/williams-racing-and-kraken-announce-global-crypto-partnership\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">statement<\/a>.&nbsp;","While there has been a small drop in crypto-related Formula 1 sponsorship this year amid a broader challenges across the industry, the web3 sector is still \"going strong\" with new brands continuing to join the race, according to<a href=\"https:\/\/rtrsports.com\/en\/blog\/the-275-sponsorship-deals-of-the-2023-formula-1-season\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> RTR Sports Marketing<\/a>.","In 2021, the now defunct exchange FTX <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/118424\/crypto-exchange-ftx-sponsorship-deal-f1-team-mercedes-amg-petronas\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/a> a long-term sponsorship deal with F1's Mercedes-AMG Petronas that was supposed to have spanned multiple race seasons.&nbsp;","Crypto.com, which <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/201947\/crypto-com-cuts-20-of-workforce-amid-sector-wide-layoffs\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">cut 20% of its workforce<\/a> amid sector-wide layoffs earlier this year, continues to be a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.formula1.com\/en\/toolbar\/partners.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">global Formula 1 partner<\/a> along with heavyweights Aramco, AWS, DHL, Heineken, MSC Cruises, Firelli, Qatar Airways, Rolex and Salesforce.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"DHL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"James Bower","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"RTR Sports Marketing","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"20%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Kraken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"AMG Petronas","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Williams Racing","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MSC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Heineken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Firelli, Qatar Airways","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Melbourne","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FIA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kraken NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"AWS","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ups","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Nathan Crooks","The Block"]}