{"summary":"A criminal trial for Alex Mashinsky, the former CEO of Celsius, is set to start in almost exactly a year, according to Bloomberg News.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/254172\/criminal-trial-date-set-for-next-year-for-former-celsius-ceo-mashinsky-bloomberg-news","publishDate":"2023-10-03T13:18:58","id":13877,"type":null,"title":"Criminal trial date set for next year for former Celsius CEO Mashinsky: Bloomberg News","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A criminal trial for Alex Mashinsky, the former CEO of Celsius, is set to start in almost exactly a year. <\/span><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Mashinsky’s trial date is set for Sept. 17, 2024, <span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2023-10-03\/ex-celsius-chief-mashinsky-fraud-trial-set-for-september-2024\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bloomberg News<\/a> reported on Tuesday.<\/span><\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Mashinsky was arrested in July after prosecutors said he defrauded customers and misled them about the crypto lender's profitability. He pleaded not guilty to those criminal charges. The crypto lender filed for bankruptcy last year and owes billions of dollars to investors.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In July, prosecutors <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/239432\/celsius-and-alex-mashinsky-face-slew-of-criminal-regulatory-allegations\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s5\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">accused<\/span><\/a> Mashinsky and the company of <\/span><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">pumping the price of Celsius’s native token using customer assets and repeatedly misleading their customers. Roni Cohen-Pavon, Celsius’ chief revenue officer, was also named in criminal charges, and reportedly pleaded guilty last month.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In July, the Securities and Exchange Commission <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/239407\/sec-files-lawsuit-against-celsius-and-ex-ceo-alex-mashinsky\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">sued<\/span><\/a> the crypto lender and Mashinsky for allegedly raising billions through fraudulent and unregistered sales of \"crypto asset securities,\" repeatedly lying to investors about Celsius' financial standing, and manipulating the price of CEL, the company's native token.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Commodity Futures Trading Commission also filed its own fraud charges against Mashinsky and Celsius.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Mashinsky’s trial date was set a month after some of the former executive’s assets were ordered <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/249474\/former-celsius-ceo-mashinskys-home-and-assets-ordered-frozen-in-criminal-case\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s5\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">frozen<\/span><\/a>, including a home in Texas and funds held at Goldman Sachs, Merrill Lynch and SoFi Bank.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Pavon","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"billions of dollars","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Sept. 17, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SoFi Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alex Mashinsky","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Texas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Commodity Futures Trading Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Merrill Lynch","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Goldman Sachs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Roni Cohen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bloomberg News","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mashinsky","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}