{"summary":"Singapore state investor Temasek Holdings said it is monitoring the FTX situation and is in talks with the exchange as a shareholder.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/184690\/singapore-state-investor-temasek-engaging-with-ftx-as-a-shareholder-reuters","publishDate":"2022-11-09T08:03:37","id":1387,"type":null,"title":"Singapore state investor Temasek engaging with FTX as a shareholder: Reuters","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Singapore government-owned investment firm Temasek said it's monitoring the situation with crypto exchange FTX, one of its investments, according to Reuters.&nbsp;","\"We are aware of the developments between FTX and Binance, and are engaging FTX in our capacity as shareholder,\" Temasek<a href=\"https:\/\/www.reuters.com\/markets\/currencies\/cryptos-attempt-steady-binance-ftx-deal-chills-market-2022-11-09\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> told<\/a> Reuters.","Temasek participated in FTX's $1 billion <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/112014\/ftx-900-million-funding\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Series B<\/a> funding round and its $420 million <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/121428\/ftx-420-million-round-69-investors-tiger-ribbit\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">B-1 round<\/a> in October 2021. It also participated in FTX's $400 million <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/132383\/venture-froth-catapults-ftx-to-32-billion-valuation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Series C<\/a> round in January 2022, which saw the exchange valued at $32 billion.","FTX shocked the world of crypto on Tuesday by announcing it would sell its non-U.S. assets to Binance. FTX's FTT token had tumbled after Binance CEO Changpeng Zhao said it would begin selling off its holdings. He cited \"recent revelations\" for the decision to sell — in a seeming reference to a CoinDesk report that had revealed details of sister firm Alameda Research's balance sheet.","Temasek didn't immediately respond to a request for comment from The Block.","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$32 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$1 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$420 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"January 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Temasek","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Changpeng Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"October 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Reuters","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$400 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"crypto exchange FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["FTX","SOVEREIGN WEALTH FUNDS"],"authors":["Tim Copeland","The Block"]}