{"summary":"BlackRock&#x27;s filing for a spot bitcoin ETF could be a turning point to institutional acceptance, Ark Invest said.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/236415\/blackrock-etf-filing-could-be-turning-point-for-bitcoin-ark-says","publishDate":"2023-06-26T11:41:17","id":13875,"type":null,"title":"BlackRock ETF filing could be &#x27;turning point&#x27; for bitcoin, Ark says","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["BlackRock's <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/235056\/blackrock-takes-giant-leap-toward-spot-bitcoin-etf-with-sec-filing\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filing<\/a> for a spot bitcoin ETF earlier this month could be a \"significant turning point in bitcoin's path to institutional acceptance,\" Ark Invest said in an emailed note on Monday.","\"BlackRock’s decision to file for a Bitcoin ETF signals that large institutional players are positive on the long-term outlook for the digital asset,\" Ark analyst <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/yassineARK\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Yassine Elmandjra<\/a> wrote.&nbsp;","BlackRock's June 15 filing has been followed by other asset managers looking to launch their own spot bitcoin funds including Invesco, WisdomTree and Valkyrie. Ark had previously filed for a similar fund on April 25 with 21 Shares.","\"While it looks much like previous ETF filings, BlackRock worked with Nasdaq to distinguish its application with a unique surveillance-sharing agreement designed to prevent the risk of bitcoin-related market manipulation,\" Elmandjra said. \"Based on our research, however, other applicants will be able to amend their filings with similar agreements at little cost.\"","The price of bitcoin has surged since the BlackRock filing, rising 15.3% over the past week. It's currently trading at $30,410, according to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coingecko.com\/en\/coins\/bitcoin\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CoinGecko<\/a>.&nbsp;","CoinShares, meanwhile, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/236364\/crypto-investment-products-inflows-bitcoin-coinshares\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a> the largest inflows into crypto investment products since July 2022, with $199 million pouring into funds last week. Of that, bitcoin was the biggest winner, with inflows totaling $188 million.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Bitcoin ETF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Elmandjra","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BlackRock","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$199 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"WisdomTree","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$30,410","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"15.3%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$188 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"April 25","content":"DATE"},{"type":"June 15","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Invesco","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CoinGecko","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Yassine Elmandjra","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Nasdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Nathan Crooks","The Block"]}