{"summary":"Cryptocurrency exchange Binance could soon add support for Ukrainian hryvnia (UAH) and Kazakhstani tenge (KZT) for its direct fiat-to-crypto trading","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/45853\/binance-may-soon-add-support-for-ukraine-and-kazakhstans-currencies-for-direct-fiat-to-crypto-trading","publishDate":"2019-11-05T07:00:31","id":13882,"type":null,"title":"Binance may soon add support for Ukraine&#x27;s and Kazakhstan’s currencies for direct fiat-to-crypto trading","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["Cryptocurrency exchange Binance could soon add support for Ukrainian hryvnia (UAH) and Kazakhstani tenge (KZT) for its direct fiat-to-crypto trading facility.","The Block has learned that UAH and KZT currencies were today added to Binance’s application programming interface or API.&nbsp; Last month, when Binance added support for Nigerian Naira (<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/44466\/binances-direct-fiat-to-crypto-trading-facility-goes-live-starting-with-nigerian-naira-pairs\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">NGN<\/a>) on Oct. 24 and Russian ruble (<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/45298\/binance-adds-support-for-russian-rubles-for-direct-fiat-to-crypto-trading\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">RUB<\/a>) on Oct. 31, it had added these two currencies to its API on Sept. 24 and Oct. 29, respectively.","The support for NGN is enabled via a partnership with U.S.-based payments tech firm Flutterwave, while RUB has been integrated through Gibraltar-based electronic payments platform AdvCash.","It remains to be seen which third-party service Binance would choose for UAH and KZT currencies if they are added next. The Block has reached out to Binance for comment and will update this story if they reply.","The direct fiat-to-crypto trading facility was first <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/43960\/binance-com-to-add-fiat-pairs-starting-with-russian-rubles-in-about-two-weeks\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">revealed<\/a> by Binance CEO Changpeng \"CZ\" Zhao on Oct. 21. In a recent Twitter ask-me-anything (AMA) session, CZ said that adding fiat on-ramps around the world is “very important for lowering the barrier to entry” and that users can expect “more pairs very soon.”","Binance <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/41011\/binance-adds-one-more-channel-to-its-fiat-gateway-allowing-users-to-pay-for-crypto-with-debit-and-credit-cards\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">continues to expand<\/a> channels for its fiat gateway. Currently, there are <a href=\"https:\/\/www.binance.com\/en\/buy-sell-crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">six<\/a> such channels - via Koinal, Simplex, Paxos, TrustToken, Flutterwave and AdvCash.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Ukrainian hryvnia (UAH","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Paxos","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"UAH","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Oct. 31","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gibraltar","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"AMA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"RUB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Oct. 21","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Oct. 24","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sept. 24","content":"DATE"},{"type":"NGN","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Oct. 29","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Nigerian Naira (<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/44466\/binances-direct-fiat-to-crypto-trading-facility-goes-live-starting-with-nigerian-naira-pairs\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">NGN","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE"],"authors":["Yogita Khatri","The Block"]}