{"summary":"In this episode of The Scoop, Circle’s Chief Revenue Officer Kash Razzaghi and TBD’s Chief Operating Officer Emily Chiu discuss their new partnership, and explain how their companies’ combined synergy is going to make it easier to move value back and forth between crypto and the real world economy. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/174714\/how-circles-new-partnership-with-tbd-is-connecting-crypto-to-the-real-world","publishDate":"2022-10-05T05:00:32","id":13899,"type":null,"title":"Block and Circle are teaming up to onboard crypto&#x27;s next billion users","category":["STABLECOINS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 95<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 4 of The Scoop was recorded at live at Converge with <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro, Circle's CRO Kash Razzaghi and TBD's Co-Founder &amp; COO Emily Chiu.<\/strong><\/i><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"1f6f707b7c7e6c6b5f6b777a7d73707c747c6d666f6b70317c7072\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i><\/span>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK2776659183\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TBD, the crypto focused arm of Jack Dorsey’s Block, is partnering with Circle, the company behind the USDC stablecoin, to unleash the power of stablecoin payments onto the next billion crypto users.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In this episode of The Scoop, Circle’s Chief Revenue Officer Kash Razzaghi and TBD’s Chief Operating Officer Emily Chiu discuss their new partnership, and explain how their companies’ synergy is going to make it easier to move value back and forth between crypto and the real world economy.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">According to Chiu, the crypto industry is lacking a way to exchange crypto for real world items:<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“The minute you nexus upon the real world and commerce in the real world, you need to solve these really hard problems that haven't yet been solved in the space. That's what TBDex does, and we see USDC and stablecoins as a critical bridge for facilitating these transactions.”<\/span>","One of the first use-cases will be a remittance function that enables payments between the US and Mexico, a corridor that sees billions flow a year.&nbsp;","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TBD hopes its <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/161840\/blocks-mike-brock-on-web5-and-the-role-of-digital-identities\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">digital identity solution<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> will put users in control of both their identity and data as well as who they share it with. As Chiu explains, these digital identity solutions will hopefully promote global economic empowerment:&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Regardless of what identity you have, you can create a self-sovereign identity wallet regardless of who you are, there's no intermediary and you need permission from in order to start transacting and engaging with the global economy.<\/span>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">During this episode, Chaparro, Chiu, and Razzaghi also discuss:<\/span><\/i>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors <a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Tron<\/em><\/a><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em><\/b>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Tron<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/b><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TRON is dedicated to accelerating the decentralization of the internet via blockchain technology and decentralized applications (dApps). Founded in September 2017 by <a href=\"https:\/\/www.hejustinsun.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">H.E. Justin Sun<\/a>, the TRON network has continued to deliver impressive achievements since MainNet launch in May 2018. July 2018 also marked the ecosystem integration of <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bittorrent.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BitTorrent<\/a>, a pioneer in decentralized web3 services boasting over 100 million monthly active users. The TRON network completed full decentralization in December 2021 and is now a community-governed DAO. | <a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/hackathon\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TRONDAO<\/a> | <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/trondao\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Twitter<\/a> | <a href=\"https:\/\/discord.gg\/tron\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Discord<\/a> |<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"BitTorrent","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Co-Founder &amp; COO Emily Chiu","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Razzaghi","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July 2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kash Razzaghi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chiu","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mexico","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Emily Chiu","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jack Dorsey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"December 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"USDC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"May 2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"TBD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"September 2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"H.E. Justin Sun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["CRYPTO","USDC"],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}