{"summary":"On this episode of The Scoop, host Frank Chaparro chats with founders Ari Rubenstein and Ryan Sheftel about the launch of their new crypto firm, Radkl.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/121278\/heres-how-one-of-nyses-largest-market-makers-is-breaking-into-defi","publishDate":"2021-10-20T10:23:29","id":13907,"type":null,"title":"Here&#x27;s how one of NYSE&#x27;s largest market makers is breaking into DeFi","category":["THE BLOCK"],"content":["Episode <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">67 <\/strong>of Season 3 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block’s Frank Chaparro and Ari Rubenstein, Co-Founder and Ryan Sheftel, Co-Founder &amp; CEO at Radkl.","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"f787989394968483b7839f92959b98949c94858e878398d994989a\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors <a href=\"http:\/\/Bakkt.com\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bakkt<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"http:\/\/kraken.com\/scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kraken<\/a>&nbsp;and&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.exodus.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Exodus<\/a><\/strong>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bakkt® unlocks the $1.2+ trillion of digital assets that is currently held in cryptocurrencies, rewards and loyalty points, gaming assets and merchant stored value. We began in 2018 with the vision to bring trust and transparency to digital assets. Through the Bakkt Warehouse and Bakkt Bitcoin Futures and Options contracts, we serve institutional clients in an end-to-end regulated market with true price transparency. For consumers, Bakkt aggregates digital assets to enable instant liquidity and to empower users to trade, transfer and pay however they want. Visit <a href=\"http:\/\/Bakkt.com\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bakkt.com<\/a> for more information<\/span><\/em>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Kraken<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Whether you’re an experienced crypto trader or just starting out, Kraken has the tools to help you achieve financial freedom. With 50+ cryptocurrencies to choose from, industry-leading security and a wide variety of features to suit any investing strategy, Kraken puts the power in your hands to buy, sell and trade digital assets. Visit&nbsp;<\/em><a href=\"http:\/\/kraken.com\/scoop\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kraken.com<\/em><\/a><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;to get started today.<\/em>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Exodus<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Exodus is leading the world out of traditional finance by building beautiful and user-friendly crypto products. Forget having to learn the nuances of different cryptocurrencies. Exodus is designed for everyone and hides the complex details behind a beautiful and intuitive interface.<\/em>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nOn this episode of The Scoop, founder Ari Rubenstein and founder &amp; CEO Ryan Sheftel joined host Frank Chaparro to discuss the launch of their new crypto firm, called Radkl.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Radkl, which was born out of trading firm and New York Stock Exchange market maker GTS, is a new digital asset trading business. GTS currently trades hundreds of thousands of financial instruments algorithmically, which according to GTS accounts for some “five percent of the entire US equity markets by volume.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Radkl’s focus on crypto today means providing liquidity and eventually getting into decentralized finance protocols like staking, among other services it expects to offer for its clients.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Being involved in the liquidity provision, in the AMM protocols, and DeFi is an obvious first start” Said Sheftel. The CEO said that he expects traditional CeFi order books to merge with AMM liquidity, and to have Radkl serve that sector of the market.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Meanwhile, Rubenstein sees the beginnings of crypto firms as a similar kind of disruption and growth potential for traditional businesses to when capital markets went electronic and online.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Rubenstein believes they are early entrants into a growing market, “I think we're going to see a world very soon, Frank, that we see an explosion in a secondary market for things that formerly didn't have secondary markets that now are made by this digitization of of industries that- I don't mean just financial instruments or digital pictures like entities- I mean lots of other things that could ride the backbone of CeFi and decentralized finance.”<\/span>","Hedge fund investor and owner of the Mets Steve Cohen also <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/117715\/steve-cohen-is-backing-a-new-crypto-trading-shop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/a> he will be backing Radkl. Though as of yet, the exact sum of that investment has not been disclosed.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Radkl","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bakkt Warehouse","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Steve Cohen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$1.2+ trillion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Sheftel","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York Stock Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Kraken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Frank","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ari Rubenstein","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"AMM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ryan Sheftel","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Rubenstein","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}