{"summary":"While a retail digital pound is a hot topic of crypto discussion in the UK, wholesale solutions are steadily brewing in the background.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/215707\/wholesale-digital-pound-is-a-question-of-how-not-when-says-bank-of-england","publishDate":"2023-02-28T08:33:54","id":13902,"type":null,"title":"Wholesale digital pound is a question of how, not when, says Bank of England","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">While the UK government and Bank of England are pushing forward their exploration of a retail digital pound, work on a wholesale solution is also a priority — and a far more certain one.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“The question is not should we try and exploit the new technologies for wholesale. We should, and we’re looking at how to do that [...] and what’s the quickest way,” Bank of England Deputy Governor Jon Cunliffe told the Treasury Committee on Tuesday.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">When it comes to a retail solution, the government will only make a decision on whether to implement a central bank digital currency around 2025, with the potential to launch it further down the line.&nbsp;<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">However, Cunliffe said that “it's more likely than not\" that the digital pound will move forward as the central bank looks to fill the gap as the use of physical cash declines.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">After <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/209304\/uks-bank-of-england-launches-digital-pound-project-as-new-form-of-money\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">publishing<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> a consultation paper on the digital pound earlier in February, the Bank of England and HM Treasury are looking to hear public feedback on design choices — including topics of security, resiliency and privacy.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">While the consultation focuses on the kind of CBDC that private individuals may be able to use on a day-to-day basis, Cunliffe reminded the UK Parliament that a wholesale CBDC is “not on the back burner.” <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">He highlighted the Financial Markets Sandbox, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/158648\/uk-treasury-unveils-plan-to-regulate-stablecoins-in-financial-services-and-markets-bill\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">proposed<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> under the Financial Services and Markets bill currently making its way through Parliament, will play a significant role. Work with the Bank of International Settlements’ Innovation Hub also focuses on building rails to tokenize assets.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“At the moment, we see the needs of wholesale and retail as separate,” the central banker added. “It is a much bigger change — societal and economic — than wholesale.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Central banks are racing to study and design possibilities for a central bank digital currency. For the UK, the government is looking to <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/208667\/uk-minister-andrew-griffith-wants-to-pass-finance-regulation-bill-by-easter\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">achieve<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> global financial hub status. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The committee quizzed Cunliffe on whether the rollout of a CBDC is taking too long compared to other global competitors in Europe and Asia.&nbsp;<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“I don't think we are behind other advanced economies,” the deputy governor assured.<\/span>","The Bank of England is renewing its Real-Time Gross Settlement, allowing financial institutions to settle payments. A wholesale CBDC based on decentralized ledger technology may have a link to the renewed RTGS in the future. However, policymakers worry this may slow down the wholesale CBDC rollout process.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We do have to balance speed against getting it right, and there are some really big things at stake here,” Cunliffe said.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2025","content":"DATE"},{"type":"UK Parliament","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"RTGS","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Financial Markets Sandbox","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cunliffe","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bank of England","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"February","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bank of International Settlements’ Innovation Hub","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Time Gross Settlement","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Asia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Treasury Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Financial Services","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"HM Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jon Cunliffe","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Parliament","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"” Bank of England","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["UK PARLIAMENT"],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}