{"summary":"In this episode of The Scoop, The Block Vice President of Research Larry Cermak and Loomdart — a founding member of crypto-native venture firm eGirl Capital — reflect on FTX’s collapse and speculate on what comes next for the crypto industry.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/192707\/crypto-market-has-experienced-an-education-by-fire-says-loomdart","publishDate":"2022-12-07T05:00:39","id":13923,"type":null,"title":"Crypto market has experienced an &#x27;education by fire,&#x27; says Loomdart","category":["CRYPTO ECOSYSTEMS"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 122<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 4 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro and Larry Cermak, and Loomdart, co-founder of eGirl Capital.<\/strong><\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Or click here to watch the full interview on <a href=\"https:\/\/www.youtube.com\/watch?v=zGNiYt1GN_4&amp;t=3038s\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">YouTube<\/a>. Email feedback and revision requests can be sent to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"a7d7c8c3c4c6d4d3e7d3cfc2c5cbc8c4ccc4d5ded7d3c889c4c8ca\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK6445761155\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/i>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In this month's 'Market Pulse' episode of The Scoop, The Block Vice President of Research Larry Cermak and Loomdart, a founding member of crypto-native venture firm eGirl Capital, reflect on FTX’s collapse and speculate on what comes next for the crypto industry.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">According to Cermak, former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried (SBF) is remaining in the Bahamas to stay engaged with local regulators:<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Sam still has connections in the Bahamas and the government is still standing by him … H<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">e just made them look terrible, so they kind of have to go in this direction”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">During a recent <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/192005\/2-hour-sit-down-with-Sam-Bankman-Fried-on-the-FTX-scandal\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">interview<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, SBF confirmed he is still living in the Bahamas, although he is <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/191995\/sam-bankman-fried-takes-aim-at-ftx-ceo-john-ray-in-new-interview\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">not communicating<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> with FTX’s new CEO John Ray.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">While FTX's collapse pushed crypto prices to new yearly lows, Loomdart says it is ultimately better for the long-term health of the industry:&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Crypto is such an open and free ecosystem to where if we don't have this type of education by fire it just keeps getting worse… If FTX didn't blow up now and they managed to keep going — I don’t think that hole was going to shrink.”<\/span>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">During this episode, Chaparro, Cermak, and Loomdart also discuss:<\/span><\/i>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Tron,&nbsp;<\/em><\/a><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.ledn.io\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ledn<\/a><\/em><\/b><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nAbout Tron<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/b><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TRON is dedicated to accelerating the decentralization of the internet via blockchain technology and decentralized applications (dApps). Founded in September 2017 by&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.hejustinsun.com\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">H.E. Justin Sun<\/a>, the TRON network has continued to deliver impressive achievements since MainNet launch in May 2018. July 2018 also marked the ecosystem integration of&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.bittorrent.com\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BitTorrent<\/a>, a pioneer in decentralized web3 services boasting over 100 million monthly active users. The TRON network completed full decentralization in December 2021 and is now a community-governed DAO. |&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/hackathon\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TRONDAO<\/a>&nbsp;|&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/trondao\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Twitter<\/a>&nbsp;|&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/discord.gg\/tron\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Discord<\/a>&nbsp;|<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Ledn<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong>Ledn was founded on the unshakeable conviction that digital assets have the power to democratize access to the global economy. We help you to experience the real life benefits of your Bitcoin without having to sell it. Start a savings account, take out a loan, or double your Bitcoin. For more information visit&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.ledn.io\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ledn.io<\/a><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"BitTorrent","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July 2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Cermak","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Loomdart","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Loomdart","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"December 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Larry Cermak","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bahamas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ledn<\/a><\/em><\/b><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nAbout Tron<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/b><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TRON","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ledn<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong>Ledn","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"John Ray","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"May 2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SBF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"September 2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"H.E. Justin Sun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}