{"summary":"On this week&#x27;s episode of The Scoop, Chavez broke down some of the changes that have occurred at the intersection of health and technology due to the global pandemic.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/70645\/former-goldman-cfo-breaks-down-why-the-digital-dollar-is-better-than-bitcoin-and-stablecoins","publishDate":"2020-07-08T19:05:53","id":13932,"type":null,"title":"Former Goldman CFO breaks down why a digital dollar is better than bitcoin and stablecoins","category":["PODCASTS"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 26 of Season 2 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block’s Frank Chaparro and R. Martin Chavez, a former Goldman Sachs executive and current Stanford professor who also sits on the boards of multiple fintech firms.<\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"3c4c53585f5d4f487c4854595e50535f575f4e454c4853125f5351\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode of The Scoop is brought to you by Bitstamp, the original global cryptocurrency exchange. Since 2011, Bitstamp has been a cornerstone of the industry, earning the trust of over four million individuals and top financial institutions looking for a reliable trading venue. <\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Whether you’re trading on our web platform, mobile app or industry-leading APIs, Bitstamp gives you the professional-grade tools you need to execute your strategy.&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/bitstamp.net\/app?r=pro%E2%80%93&amp;utm_source=Website&amp;utm_medium=podcast&amp;utm_campaign=theblock&amp;utm_content=ctaapp\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Download the Bitstamp app<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or visit&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.bitstamp.net\/pro\/?utm_source=Website&amp;utm_medium=podcast&amp;utm_campaign=theblock&amp;utm_content=ctaweb\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitstamp.net\/Pro<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;to learn more and start trading today!<\/i>","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK7028509212\" width=\"100%\" height=\"200\" frameborder=\"0\" scrolling=\"no\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","R. Martin Chavez left his Goldman Sachs office in December after decades of work bringing new technology to Wall Street, most recently as Goldman's CFO, though his career began in Silicon Valley. Now, he's returned to the tech world, where he serves on the boards of health technology firms and has gotten involved in the conversation around the \"<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/70152\/senators-digital-dollar-hearing\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">digital dollar<\/a>.\"","On this week's episode of The Scoop, Chavez broke down some of the changes that have occurred at the intersection of health and technology due to the global pandemic. For instance, a world in quarantine has breathed new life into the field of telemedicine. He also explained why although he sees bitcoin as \"an amazing research project,\" it doesn't quite qualify as money in his view.","Chavez compared the coronavirus pandemic to the 2008 financial crisis, in that they are both wake up calls for policymakers. He said the pandemic has been a moment to examine how to build better systems, particularly in the health tech and industrial fields.","Meanwhile, it's also illuminated the potential role of a U.S. central bank digital currency as a mechanism for stimulus delivery. While Chavez advocated for a blockchain-based digital dollar, he doesn't think private stablecoins are a suitable stand-in. <b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/b>\"Stablecoins are stable right up until the instant that they're not stable,\" he said.&nbsp;","Here are some of the more specific topics featured in the episode:","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen to this week's episode on Apple, Spotify, Stitcher, GooglePlay or wherever you listen to podcasts.<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2011","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"December","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Chavez","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2008","content":"DATE"},{"type":"R. Martin Chavez","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Goldman Sachs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Goldman","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitstamp","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Stanford","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Silicon Valley","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Aislinn Keely","The Block"]}