{"summary":"Dubbed the Franklin Bitcoin ETF, the fund&#x27;s assets would consist primarily of bitcoin held in custody by Coinbase Custody Trust Company.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/250478\/franklin-templeton-files-with-sec-for-spot-bitcoin-etf","publishDate":"2023-09-12T10:08:42","id":13953,"type":null,"title":"Franklin Templeton files with SEC for spot bitcoin ETF","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/168032\/franklin-templeton-launches-metaverse-etf-for-european-investors\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Franklin Templeton<\/a> became the latest asset manager to file with the Securities and Exchange Commission for a spot bitcoin ETF.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Dubbed the Franklin <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitcoin <\/span><span class=\"articleTooltip\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"\/price\/248348\/bitcoin-btc-usd\" class=\"articleTooltip__link\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"><img src=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2023\/10\/bitcoin.png\" alt=\"\" title=\"\" class=\"articleTooltip__tokenImage\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">BTC<\/span> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText articleTooltip__tokenText_price articleTooltip__tokenText_positive\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">\n      +0.72%\n    <\/span><\/a> <!----><\/span><\/span> ETF, the fund's assets would consist primarily of bitcoin held in custody by Coinbase Custody Trust Company, according to an <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.sec.gov\/Archives\/edgar\/data\/1992870\/000113743923001074\/ftdhts1092023.htm\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">S-1 form<\/a> filed Tuesday.&nbsp;","If approved, shares will be listed and traded on the Cboe BZX Exchange. For bitcoin pricing, the filing mentions use of CME's&nbsp;CF Bitcoin Reference Rate – New York Variant.&nbsp;","Although the industry is eagerly anticipating the first spot crypto ETF, the SEC has yet to approve one. The regulator <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/248595\/sec-moves-to-delay-decisions-on-spot-bitcoin-etfs-from-wisdomtree-invesco-and-valkyrie\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">last month<\/a> moved to delay decisions on the existing proposals for spot bitcoin ETFs as it wades through a wave of recent applications.","Bitcoin's price gained on Tuesday, rising 2.6% to $26,294 at 10:03 a.m. ET, according to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coingecko.com\/en\/coins\/bitcoin\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CoinGecko<\/a>.&nbsp;&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"10:03 a.m. ET","content":"TIME"},{"type":"Coinbase Custody Trust Company","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CF Bitcoin Reference Rate – New York Variant","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2.6%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Cboe BZX Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$26,294","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"+0.72%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"1","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Franklin <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitcoin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"CoinGecko","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Franklin Templeton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"CME","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Nathan Crooks","The Block"]}