{"summary":"AP, Reuters and CNBC among publishers requesting the two co-signers funding Bankman-Fried’s bail bond be made public.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/202060\/media-power-group-files-request-to-reveal-sbfs-secret-bail-signatories","publishDate":"2023-01-13T08:12:05","id":13963,"type":null,"title":"Media power group files request to reveal SBF’s secret bail signatories","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A collection of news media giants <a href=\"https:\/\/s3.documentcloud.org\/documents\/23571576\/unsealing-request-from-media-companies-in-sam-bankman-fried-criminal-case.pdf\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">requested<\/a> that the court handling fallen crypto mogul Sam Bankman-Fried’s criminal case reveal who, other than his parents, signed his $250 million bail bond.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The media outlets on the petition include Associated Press, Bloomberg, the Financial Times, CNBC, Reuters, Insider, Wall Street Journal’s publisher Dow Jones, and the Washington Post’s publisher.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Lawyers from litigation law firm Davis Wright Tremaine argued it is in the public interest to reveal the signatories since Bankman-Fried “stands accused of perpetrating one of the largest financial frauds in history.” They cited common law and the first amendment to public right of the information.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The counsel for the news group said it is willing to be heard at a hearing to make their case.&nbsp;<\/span>","Representatives for Sam Bankman-Fried did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&nbsp;","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bankman-Fried had <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/198939\/bankman-fried-asks-for-250-million-bond-co-signers-to-remain-anonymous\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">asked<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> for two unknown co-signers on his bail to remain anonymous for concerns over their safety. His parents, who had signed the quarter-billion bond, were targeted for harassment and media scrutiny according to the court filing of the anonymity request.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">There would be a “serious cause for concern that the two additional sureties would face similar intrusions on their privacy as well as threats and harassment if their names appear unredacted on their bonds or their identities are otherwise publicly disclosed,” lawyers Mark Cohen and Christian Everdell of law firm Cohen &amp; Gresser LLP wrote on Jan. 3.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bankman-Fried is awaiting trial scheduled for October for criminal charges, following the collapse of his crypto exchange FTX in November.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">He was released from detainment in December thanks to the $250 million bond, which was secured with his parents’ signature and equity in their family home, along with another two anonymous co-signers.&nbsp;<\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Associated Press","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$250 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Washington","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"CNBC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"December","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Jan. 3","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Christian Everdell","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Reuters","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Financial Times","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"October","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Dow Jones","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Davis Wright Tremaine","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Cohen &amp; Gresser LLP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mark Cohen","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["FTX","LAWSUITS","SAM BANKMAN-FRIED"],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}