{"summary":"Binance is partnering with the South Korean city of Busan to promote crypto adoption and industry there.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/165992\/binance-signs-agreement-with-busan-south-korea-to-develop-blockchain-infrastructure","publishDate":"2022-08-26T12:23:49","id":13979,"type":null,"title":"Binance signs agreement with Busan, South Korea to develop blockchain infrastructure","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["Global cryptocurrency exchange Binance has signed an agreement with the city of Busan, South Korea to help develop the city's blockchain infrastructure and support its efforts to boost crypto adoption and business development.","<span class=\"css-6hm6tl\" data-bn-type=\"text\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We are happy to be working with the City of Busan to bring tangible blockchain-related developments that benefit and support the city’s innovation efforts,\" Binance CEO Changpeng Zhao said in a statement. \"<\/span>Through our industry-leading position and technological expertise, combined with the City of Busan’s strong support for the blockchain industry, we hope to help grow crypto adoption within the city and beyond.\"","Binance is also helping the city establish digital asset exchanges within the city through its \"regulatory-free zone.\"&nbsp;","<span class=\"css-6hm6tl\" data-bn-type=\"text\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“With this agreement, we are one step closer to establishing the Busan Digital Asset Exchange as a global integrated platform for digital assets,\" Park <\/span><span class=\"css-6hm6tl\" data-bn-type=\"text\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Heong-joon, Busan's mayor, said in a statement. <\/span><span class=\"css-6hm6tl\" data-bn-type=\"text\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“By making Busan a blockchain-specialized city that is attracting worldwide attention, we will boost a new growth engine for the local economy and make it a global digital finance hub.\"<\/span>","Binance plans to set up an office in Busan later this year, South Korean <a href=\"https:\/\/www.chosun.com\/national\/regional\/yeongnam\/2022\/08\/26\/KGF6NL2XSRFRLJV6657OZJ576A\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">newspaper<\/a> Chosun Ilbo reported.&nbsp;","Busan, a port city home to about 3.4 million people, is a popular beach tourism destination located in the southeast region of the country. Busan is home to a smart city test bed called the Eco Delta Smart City.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"South Korea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"City of Busan","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chosun Ilbo","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Busan","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Heong","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Eco Delta Smart City","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Busan Digital Asset Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Changpeng Zhao","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE"],"authors":["Kristin Majcher","The Block"]}