{"summary":"Uniswap founder Hayden Adams tweeted Sunday that JPMorgan Chase has closed his bank accounts without notice or explanation.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/131314\/jpmorgan-chase-closes-uniswap-founders-bank-accounts","publishDate":"2022-01-24T06:13:55","id":13986,"type":null,"title":"JPMorgan Chase closes Uniswap founder&#x27;s bank accounts","category":["DEFI"],"content":["Uniswap founder Hayden Adams tweeted Sunday that JPMorgan Chase has closed his bank accounts without notice or explanation.","\"I know many individuals and companies who have been similarly targeted simply for working in the crypto industry,\" <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/haydenzadams\/status\/1485294362657443842?s=21\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">wrote<\/a> Adams. \"Thanks for making it a personal.\"","Adams' bank accounts were closed last week. The move comes a few months after the US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) reportedly started investigating Uniswap Labs, the main developer of the world's largest decentralized exchange protocol Uniswap.","In September, the Wall Street Journal <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/116535\/sec-investigating-uniswap-labs-report\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a>, citing \"people familiar with the matter,\" that the SEC enforcement attorneys are investigating Uniswap Labs about how investors use the decentralized exchange protocol and how it is marketed.","At the time, a Uniswap Labs spokesperson told The Journal that the firm is \"committed to complying with the laws and regulations governing our industry and to providing information to regulators that will assist them with any inquiry.\"","Brian Quintenz, the former chairman of the US Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC), who now works as an advisory partner at the crypto-focused investment firm Andreessen Horowitz, weighed in on the matter.","\"Likely a shadow de-banking of crypto by [The Federal Reserve] or [<span class=\"css-901oao css-16my406 r-poiln3 r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Office of the Comptroller of the Currency<\/span>] bank examiners, with direction from the top. If the examiner told a bank that a certain customer is too risky and the bank ended that relationship, the bank is contractually prevented from telling that customer why,\" Quintenz <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/BrianQuintenz\/status\/1485329222453366790?s=20\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweeted<\/a> as a reply to Adams' initial tweet.","This is not the first time JPMorgan Chase has closed an account of a crypto executive or a crypto firm. In 2018, the bank <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/ErikVoorhees\/status\/991729284979900416?s=20\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">closed<\/a> an account of Erik Voorhees, founder of the crypto exchange ShapeShift. The bank has previously also <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/jespow\/status\/991925008350961664?s=20\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">shut down<\/a> an account of crypto exchange Kraken's payroll account.","<i data-stringify-type=\"italic\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">For more breaking stories like this, make sure to follow The Block on&nbsp;<\/i><i data-stringify-type=\"italic\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a class=\"c-link\" tabindex=\"-1\" href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/TheBlock__\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-stringify-link=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/TheBlock__\" data-sk=\"tooltip_parent\" data-remove-tab-index=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Twitter<\/a><\/i><i data-stringify-type=\"italic\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/i>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Sunday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Brian Quintenz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Federal Reserve","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Erik Voorhees","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Adams","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kraken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hayden Adams","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Uniswap Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"US Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Andreessen Horowitz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"US Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["JPMORGAN","TRADFI BANKS","UNISWAP"],"authors":["Yogita Khatri","The Block"]}