{"summary":"Crypto.com will be allowed to offer crypto exchange and broker-dealer services following operational approval, the company said.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/262967\/crypto-com-obtains-license-in-dubai-to-operate-crypto-exchange-services","publishDate":"2023-11-14T03:47:22","id":14002,"type":null,"title":"Crypto.com obtains license in Dubai to operate crypto exchange services","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto.com has obtained a Virtual Assets Service Provider license in Dubai to operate specific crypto activities.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The company said in a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/crypto.com\/company-news\/cryptocom-obtains-full-vasp-licence-from-dubai-vara\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">statement<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that its Dubai entity, CRO DAX Middle East FZE, received the license from Dubai’s Virtual Assets Regulatory Authority, and that Crypto.com will be allowed to offer exchange, broker-dealer, investment, lending and borrowing services following operational approval.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Crypto.com’s VASP Licence is subject to the Company fully satisfying select conditions and localisation requirements defined by VARA, and will be able to commence operations thereafter subject to operational approval notice from the regulator,” the company said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We are excited to showcase more of our industry-leading products to customers across permissible jurisdictions from Dubai, and look forward to working with regulators contributing to this thriving ecosystem,” Kris Marszalek, CEO of Crypto.com, said in the statement.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In June, Crypto.com <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/crypto.com\/company-news\/crypto-com-obtains-major-payment-institution-licence-from-monetary-authority-of-singapore\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">obtained a Major Payment Institution license<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> for Digital Payment Token (DPT) services in Singapore, a year after it received its in-principle approval. The exchange has also <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/241879\/crypto-com-netherlands-binance\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">secured registration in July with the central bank of the Netherlands<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to provide crypto services.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Nomura’s crypto arm Laser Digital also said in August that it had completed the final stage of VARA’s licensing process and <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/242486\/nomura-crypto-laser-digital-dubai-license\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">received a full license in Dubai<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. That allows the firm to <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">provide crypto broker-dealer and asset management services from its Dubai entity.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Laser Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Digital Payment Token (DPT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nomura","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"the Netherlands","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"VASP Licence","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Dubai","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"June","content":"DATE"},{"type":"VARA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kris Marszalek","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Dubai’s Virtual Assets Regulatory Authority","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Virtual Assets Service","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}