{"summary":"The European Union is considering two landmark pieces of crypto regulation this week, with time constraints on the European Council accelerating final compromises.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/154932\/france-races-the-clock-to-finalize-sweeping-new-eu-crypto-regulations-by-midnight-tomorrow","publishDate":"2022-06-29T16:40:00","id":14017,"type":null,"title":"France races the clock to finalize sweeping new EU crypto regulations by midnight tomorrow","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The European Union is about to start what will be, if France gets its way, final debates on the Markets in Crypto Assets regulation.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The French presidency over the European Council — effectively, the union’s upper legislative body — ends tomorrow at midnight. The French leadership is hustling to beat out the clock to move MiCA forward and score a legislative win.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The actual negotiations are ongoing and facts are developing as the deadline approaches.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">MiCA has been in the works for years, but only <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/137720\/europes-landmark-crypto-bill-passes-parliamentary-committee-with-wide-majority\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">passed the European Parliament<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in March. It has, in the interval, been in trilogue debates between the EU’s three governing bodies: European Parliament, Council and the Commission.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Two sources close to the trilogues say that France is likely to seal the deal on the latest version of MiCA, which it plans to consider a major achievement within its presidency.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Czechia will assume the presidency at the beginning of July, but much of the EU goes on vacation from mid-July through August. Consequently, a failure to reach a deal on MiCA tomorrow will likely push back any further negotiations to September.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">According to a note from the French Presidency of the Council seen by The Block, remaining issues to resolve include regulation of “crypto-asset service providers,” or CASPs. Of particular concern is whether the European Securities and Markets Authority (ESMA) will regulate them directly or whether that will fall to the markets regulators of individual countries.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">There are also efforts afoot to exempt non-fungible tokens from some or all requirements of other crypto markets, which would potentially save NFT issuers or platforms from having to register as CASPs. Debates tomorrow will touch on the specifics of those exemptions.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">At the same time, the EU is considering the Transfer of Funds Regulation, or TFR, that similarly <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/139913\/eu-parliament-aml-law-vote-crypto-wallets\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">passed European Parliament<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in March. CoinDesk’s Jack Schickler <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/policy\/2022\/06\/29\/eu-finalizes-crypto-money-laundering-rules\/?utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_campaign=headlines\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reports<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that the EU reached an agreement on TFR late Wednesday evening.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Broadly speaking, the European Council has tempered many of the aspects of the crypto regulations that the crypto industry found most bothersome. Moreover, the finalized version of MiCA and TFR will still require many months of tinkering before regulators will apply them.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Since the regulations left European Parliament, France has been more public in pushing to <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/news+\/142415\/france-emerge-europe-crypto-hub-succeed\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">become a hub for blockchain<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. Just yesterday, French President Emmanuel Macron <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/CFTCjohnson\/status\/1541902093430267905\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">awarded<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> two US regulators tightly associated&nbsp; with cryptocurrency with the Chevalier in the French National Order of Merit award.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"France","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"EU","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Council","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"midnight","content":"TIME"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"TFR","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"European Council","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chevalier","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"French National Order of Merit","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"},{"type":"European Union","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"European Parliament","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Emmanuel Macron","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"evening","content":"TIME"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"European Parliament","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"European Securities and Markets Authority (ESMA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Jack Schickler","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Kollen Post","The Block"]}