{"summary":"Grayscale Investments is being sued by hedge fund Fir Tree Capital Management.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/192682\/hedge-fund-fir-tree-files-lawsuit-against-grayscale-bloomberg","publishDate":"2022-12-06T15:44:05","id":14026,"type":null,"title":"Hedge fund Fir Tree files lawsuit against Grayscale: Bloomberg","category":["CRYPTO INFRASTRUCTURE"],"content":["Hedge fund Fir Tree Capital Management is suing crypto investment fund Grayscale Investments for information to investigate potential mismanagement and conflicts of interest, Bloomberg News <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2022-12-06\/hedge-fund-sues-grayscale-for-details-on-battered-bitcoin-trust\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a>, citing Delaware court documents.&nbsp;","Fir Tree wants to use the the information to push Grayscale to address the large discount it trades at relative to the bitcoin it holds by lowering fees and resuming redemptions, Bloomberg cited sources as saying.&nbsp;","The complaint also alleges that Grayscale investors have been harmed by \"shareholder-unfriendly actions.\"","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/crypto-markets\/structured-products\/premium-of-gbtc\/embed\" title=\"Daily GBTC Premium\/Discount to NAV\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","\"In 2013, we launched Grayscale Bitcoin Trust (GBTC) to provide investors with access to Bitcoin – always with the intention of converting it to an ETF when permitted by U.S. regulators,\" a company spokesperson said in an email to The Block, adding that the company respects the views of shareholders and appreciates \"engaging directly with them on the details of our product structures and operating model.\"","\"We remain 100% committed to converting GBTC to an ETF, as we strongly believe this is the best long-term product structure for GBTC and its shareholders,\" the spokesperson said.","Grayscale is part of the Digital Currency Group (DCG) that has faced challenges after the collapse of the FTX crypto exchange, with sister firm <span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Genesis&nbsp;<\/span><a class=\"editor-rtfLink\" href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/187516\/genesis-halts-customer-withdrawals-in-wake-of-three-arrows-and-ftx-collapses-coindesk\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">halting<\/span><\/a><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> client withdrawals last month.<\/span>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">(Updates with comment from Grayscale in fourth paragraph.)<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Fir Tree Capital Management","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"100%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Delaware","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2013","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Grayscale Investments","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg News","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Digital Currency Group (DCG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Catarina Moura","The Block"]}