{"summary":"Paradigm, one of crypto exchange&#x27;s FTX&#x27;s most notable investors, marked down its investment in the crypto firm to zero, according to two persons familiar with the situation.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/186449\/paradigm-marks-down-ftx-investment-to-zero-sources","publishDate":"2022-11-12T23:17:52","id":14042,"type":null,"title":"Paradigm marks down FTX investment to zero: Sources","category":["CRYPTO INFRASTRUCTURE"],"content":["Crypto investment firm Paradigm has told its limited partners that it marked down its investment in now bankrupt exchange group FTX to zero following its liquidity meltdown, according to two persons familiar with the matter.&nbsp;","The firm, led by former Sequoia investor Matt Huang and Coinbase co-founder Fred Ehrsam, backed FTX and its affiliated firm FTX US.","Paradigm, similar to FTX-backer Sequoia, told investors that it marked down its investment to zero. It invested $290 million in the group of firms tied to former Jane Street trader Sam Bankman-Fried. Despite its investment, Paradigm told investors that it is not a client of FTX and did not have crypto asset exposure to the firm.","Paradigm is one of the most active investors in the crypto market, having <a href=\"https:\/\/techcrunch.com\/2021\/11\/15\/crypto-vc-firm-paradigm-debuts-monster-2-5-billion-fund\/?guccounter=1&amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbS8&amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAANuOZ5EfW4Awg8PI7BbKhm0JgZMtk2bl2VhcnDtUYoZaE4nUxSywC4H8rWQ984lt3VAFLRzpkglNP7FH9Pqel-4tWjG715R9c_GFbJJN5LwIRDTT621094iixCDXfeYwK7raFQ95lFlWA_v544NRcZepwUBB7jjI65XNEw3Xq4Hh\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/a> a $2.5 billion fund launch last year. Known for its academic-based chops in decentralized finance investing, it has backed firms like DeFi wallet Argent, decentralized exchange dYdX, and Gauntlet. It also has backed financial services companies like Ken Griffin's Citadel Securities, which is one of the largest market-making firms in the world.","On Friday, Bankman-Fried <a href=\"https:\/\/www.cnbc.com\/2022\/11\/11\/sam-bankman-frieds-cryptocurrency-exchange-ftx-files-for-bankruptcy.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/a> the firm would file for bankruptcy protection after a week underpinned by the precipitous decline of its native token FTT and reports that it leveraged client assets to make trades via Bankman-Fried's trading firm Alameda Research.&nbsp;","Paradigm declined to comment.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$290 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Paradigm","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Matt Huang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gauntlet","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fred Ehrsam","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$2.5 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Citadel Securities","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sequoia","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ken Griffin","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}