{"summary":"Episode 45 of Season 2 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block’s Frank Chaparro and Brad Garlinghouse, CEO of Ripple.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/84550\/brad-garlinghouse-podcast-xrp-ripple","publishDate":"2020-11-13T14:38:39","id":14075,"type":null,"title":"Brad Garlinghouse explains how regulatory uncertainty around XRP has affected Ripple","category":["PODCASTS"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 45 of Season 2 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block’s Frank Chaparro and Brad Garlinghouse, CEO of Ripple.<\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"12627d767173616652667a77707e7d717971606b62667d3c717d7f\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","&nbsp;","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK9547271308\" width=\"100%\" height=\"200\" frameborder=\"0\" scrolling=\"no\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","CEO Brad Garlinghouse says in what was poised to be a challenging year, Ripple exceeded his expectations for 2020.&nbsp;","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"We aren’t going to grow as fast this year as we thought. However, we’re still getting two production financial contracts a week,\" he said.<\/span>","Indeed, the digital asset and payment system has seen some days this year in which XRP liquidity on Bitso exceeded BTC. But still, an opaque regulatory atmosphere has kept Ripple from reaching its potential, Garlinghouse argued in an interview with The Scoop's Frank Chaparro.","According to Garlinghouse, there isn't a \"level playing field\" for all digital assets in this regulatory climate.","\"Bitcoin was the only one with the hall pass,\" he said.","This creates an atmosphere in which assets without clarity underperform, according to Garlinghouse.","On this week's episode, Garlinghouse discussed how Ripple is \"fighting with one hand tied behind our back,\" as well as:","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Brad Garlinghouse","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Garlinghouse","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Aislinn Keely","The Block"]}