{"summary":"National Australia Bank (NAB) has created a stablecoin called AUDN that will allow its business customers to settle transactions in real-time using Australian dollars on the Ethereum network in mid-year for transactions such as carbon credit trading and remittances.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/203614\/national-australia-bank-creates-stablecoin-called-audn-afr","publishDate":"2023-01-18T18:41:10","id":14089,"type":null,"title":"National Australia Bank creates stablecoin called AUDN: AFR","category":["STABLECOINS"],"content":["National Australia Bank (NAB) is launching a fully backed stablecoin called AUDN.","The stablecoin will launch on the Ethereum network and Algorand blockchain, a smart contract platform similar to Ethereum. NAB plans to launch the stablecoin sometime mid-year.","The stablecoin will be backed one-to-one with Australian fiat, and the money will be held by the NAB.","The stablecoin will primarily be used as a settlement token between multiple transacting parties. For example, AUDN could be used for carbon credit trading, overseas money transfers and repurchase agreements, NAB’s Chief Innovation officer Howard Silby <a href=\"https:\/\/www.afr.com\/companies\/financial-services\/nab-creates-a-stablecoin-in-boost-for-digital-economy-20230117-p5cd8f\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a>. This is known as atomic settlement, something the NAB is attempting to transition to in some markets, according to the Australian Financial Review, which first reported the news.","This is <a href=\"https:\/\/www.afr.com\/companies\/financial-services\/anz-the-first-bank-to-mint-an-australian-dollar-stablecoin-the-a-dc-20220323-p5a743\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">not the first-time<\/a> banks in Australia have tried to launch a stablecoin.","Four banks attempted to create a similar stablecoin product last year. The initiative failed due to competition concerns and the four separate banks being at different stages in their crypto strategies, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.afr.com\/companies\/financial-services\/nab-creates-a-stablecoin-in-boost-for-digital-economy-20230117-p5cd8f\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">according to AFR.<\/a>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Algorand blockchain","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Australian Financial Review","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NAB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Australia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"National Australia Bank (NAB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Howard Silby","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"AFR","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Mike Truppa","The Block"]}