{"summary":"The world’s largest crypto exchange and its founder Changpeng Zhao may submit a motion to dismiss the lawsuit filed in March by the Commodity Futures Trading Commission.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/241220\/binance-boss-plans-to-seek-dismissal-of-cftc-complaint-filing-shows","publishDate":"2023-07-24T23:02:09","id":1411,"type":null,"title":"Binance boss plans to seek dismissal of CFTC complaint, filing shows","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance Holdings and its founder are seeking to dismiss a complaint filed in March by the United States&nbsp;Commodity Futures Trading Commission.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A Monday <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/storage.courtlistener.com\/recap\/gov.uscourts.ilnd.431767\/gov.uscourts.ilnd.431767.53.0_1.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">court filing<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> shows that Binance entities and Changpeng Zhao, founder and chief executive officer of Binance, plan to submit a motion to dismiss the complaint filed by the CFTC in a Chicago federal court. They are accused of numerous violations including operating an illegal digital asset derivatives exchange in the U.S.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Samuel Lim, Binance’s former chief compliance officer, also intends to seek to dismiss the lawsuit, according to the filing.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">As things stand, Binance, Zhao and Lim have until July 27 to submit their responses to the CFTC complaint. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">They also requested an expansion of the page limit of their memoranda of law, \"given the complexity of the CFTC’s Complaint and the number of arguments Defendants anticipate making in support of their Motions to Dismiss,\" according to the filing.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In March, the CFTC <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/223015\/cftc-sues-binance\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">sued<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Binance and Zhao for allegedly breaking derivatives rules and unregistered trading activities in the U.S.&nbsp;<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The agency said in its complaint that Binance had “taken a calculated, phased approach to increase its United States presence despite publicly stating its purported intent to ‘block’ or ‘restrict’ customers located in the United States from accessing its platform.”&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance called the CFTC lawsuit “unexpected and disappointing,” claiming it has been working collaboratively with the agency for more than two years.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Securities and Exchange Commission also <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/233154\/sec-files-suit-against-binance\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">sued<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> the exchange and Zhao last month for allegedly violating securities laws.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Binance","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Zhao last month","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"United States&nbsp;Commodity Futures Trading Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Changpeng Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Samuel Lim","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"CFTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chicago","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"July 27","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"United States","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Binance Holdings","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}