{"summary":"AAX executive Ben Caselin said he has left the crypto exchange, citing a lack of empathy within its management team.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/190260\/aax-crypto-exchange-vp-ben-caselin-resigns-amid-liquidity-crisis?utm_source=cryptopanic&utm_medium=rss","publishDate":"2022-11-28T09:04:21","id":14135,"type":null,"title":"AAX crypto exchange VP Ben Caselin resigns amid liquidity crisis","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["Ben Caselin has resigned from his post as vice president of global marketing and communications at the crypto exchange platform AAX.","Caselin’s departure comes two weeks after the crypto exchange halted operations. AAX reportedly suffered a malicious exploit that saw it unable to verify the account balances of its customers. The <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/8298\/london-stock-exchange-wades-into-crypto-selling-trading-tech-to-hong-kong-exchange\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Hong Kong-based platform<\/a> has since <a href=\"https:\/\/support.aax.com\/en\/articles\/6755918-announcement-of-automatic-liquidation-of-aax-futures-positions\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">liquidated<\/a> the crypto futures trading positions of all of its customers. AAX said the move was necessary to “protect the rights and interests of users.”","Caselin is critical of the steps being taken by AAX. “The way things are handled is without empathy and overly opaque,” said Caselin in a <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/BenCaselin\/status\/1597117107560656897\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">statement<\/a> on Monday. The former AAX executive said the crypto exchange had broken its trust with customers and that “the damage is done.”","AAX’s current liquidity issues are linked to the demise of FTX. AAX previously stated that it experienced massive withdrawals following <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/188980\/ftx-group-has-cash-balance-of-1-24-billion-new-bankruptcy-filing-shows\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">FTX’s bankruptcy<\/a> and it was facing a capital deficit.","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"AAX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Caselin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ben Caselin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Osato Avan-Nomayo","The Block"]}