{"summary":"The Wall Street Journal says Three Arrows Capital has hired legal and financial advisers to consider its options.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/152682\/three-arrows-capital-considers-asset-sales-and-bailout-wsj-reports?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss","publishDate":"2022-06-17T08:58:14","id":14234,"type":null,"title":"Three Arrows Capital considers asset sales and bailout, WSJ reports","category":["INSTITUTIONAL INVESTORS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">After a difficult week, crypto hedge fund Three Arrows Capital (3AC) has hired legal and financial advisers to help work out the best way to manage losses from a broader market selloff in digital assets, according to reports.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">3AC co-founder Kyle Davies <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.wsj.com\/articles\/battered-crypto-hedge-fund-three-arrows-capital-considers-asset-sales-bailout-11655469932?mod=Searchresults_pos1&amp;page=1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">told The Wall Street Journal<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on Friday that the firm was “committed to working things out and finding an equitable solution for all our constituent [sic].”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We have always been believers in crypto and we still are,” Davies said.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Founded in 2012 by former classmates Su Zhu and Davies, 3AC had grown into one of the biggest and best-known crypto hedge funds. Still, last month's <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/146309\/luna-terra-ust-terrausd-markets-crypto-blockchain\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">collapse<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> of the Terra ecosystem resulted in a significant hit for 3AC as its investment in Terra's native luna token sank to almost zero. Davies told the Journal that the firm had put $200 million into Luna.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Davies said that the Terra-Luna situation caught the firm “very much off guard.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The WSJ also reported comments from Davies indicating that the hedge fund is exploring both asset sales and a rescue by another company. It is also trying to reach agreements with creditors, which could buy it time.&nbsp;<\/span>","It has brought on Nichol Yeo, a partner at the law firm Solitaire LLP to advise.&nbsp;","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/152665\/ftx-deribit-bitmex-liquidated-three-arrows-capital?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sources had told The Block<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> earlier on Friday that crypto exchanges FTX, Deribit and BitMEX had liquidated Three Arrows Capital's positions over the past week, after the crypto hedge fund failed to meet margin calls.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The moves come amid a broader crypto market rout that has seen firms struggle to make good on their promises to clients. Earlier on Friday, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/152677\/babel-finance-suspends-withdrawals-citing-unusual-liquidity-pressures?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Babel Finance suspended withdrawals<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, citing “liquidity pressures.” <\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"WSJ","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kyle Davies","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2012","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Babel Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Solitaire LLP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Su Zhu","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Terra","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Terra","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Davies","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nichol Yeo","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$200 million","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["THREE ARROWS CAPITAL"],"authors":["Andrew Rummer","Lucy Harley-McKeown","The Block"]}