{"summary":" It’s the first time NFTs changed wallet addresses in four months, when trouble with Starry Night Capital’s founder Three Arrows Capital began. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/174778\/more-than-300-nfts-moved-out-of-3acs-starry-night-capital-address-for-the-first-time-in-four-months?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss","publishDate":"2022-10-04T14:00:47","id":14264,"type":null,"title":"Over 300 NFTs moved out of 3AC’s Starry Night Capital wallet","category":["NFTS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">More than 300 NFTs, including some worth millions of dollars in crypto, were moved out of an address associated with Starry Night Capital.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The NFT collections represented in the move include Rare Pepe, Fidenza, CrypToadz and works from creator XCOPY, the blockchain data firm Nansen <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/nansen_ai\/status\/1577207056397783042\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweeted<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. In all, the new address to which these NFTs were moved is now worth 625 ETH, or over $839,000.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The developments represent the first time the NFTs have changed addresses in four months when trouble with crypto hedge fund Three Arrows Capital, which helped create Starry Night Capital, first began.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Following the Terra stablecoin ecosystem collapse in May, Three Arrows Capital <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/152665\/ftx-deribit-bitmex-liquidated-three-arrows-capital\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">failed<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to meet margin calls for FTX, Deribit, BitMex and other exchanges. Three Arrows was then liquidated by the New York-based financial advisory firm <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/154809\/three-arrows-capital-liquidation-teneo\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Teneo<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> at the end of June.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Starry Night Capital was launched by Three Arrows founders Su Zhu and Kyle Davies, along with the NFT collector pseudonymously called Vincent Van Dough, in August of 2021, as The Block previously <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/115996\/vincent-van-dough-nft-fund-three-arrows-capital-100-million\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Nansen <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/nansen_ai\/status\/1577207056397783042\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweeted","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kyle Davies","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Starry Night Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"August of 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Su Zhu","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Vincent Van Dough","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fidenza","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Teneo","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Deribit","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Rare Pepe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$839,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"end of June","content":"DATE"},{"type":"millions of dollars","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["THREE ARROWS CAPITAL"],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}