{"summary":"HashKey&#x27;s Jupiter Zheng explains how the crypto industry is maturing in Asia thanks to clear regulation and regional competition.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/261333\/its-a-new-wave-talent-is-flooding-from-asia-gaming-companies-to-crypto-says-hashkey-capital-exec","publishDate":"2023-11-02T23:32:00","id":14273,"type":null,"title":"&#x27;It&#x27;s a new wave:&#x27; Talent is flooding from Asia gaming companies to crypto, says HashKey Capital exec","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 94<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 5 of The Scoop was recorded with <b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro and HashKey Capital Partner of Liquid Funds &amp; Research Jupiter Zheng.<\/b><\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on <a href=\"https:\/\/www.youtube.com\/channel\/UCqjFueYMJ78eF6G0lGLzzpQ\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Youtube<\/a>, <\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a>,<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Please send feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"b6c6d9d2d5d7c5c2f6c2ded3d4dad9d5dd98d5d9\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm\/?e=BLOCK7380419968\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Jupiter Zheng is Partner of Liquid Funds &amp; Research for HashKey Capital — the investment arm of the Hong Kong crypto financial services firm HashKey Group.","In this episode, Zheng explains how the crypto industry is gaining momentum in Asia — particularly in Hong Kong.","Back in September, Hashkey <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/248631\/hashkey-capital-forms-liquid-fund-with-heavy-altcoin-focus-reuters\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/a> it is raising up to $100 million for a new liquid fund with a heavy focus on altcoins.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors <a href=\"https:\/\/www.paypal.com\/crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">PayPal.<\/em><\/a><\/b><\/span>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Make your crypto move with PayPal. Get started today at <a href=\"https:\/\/www.paypal.com\/crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">PayPal.com\/crypto<\/a><\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$100 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"PayPal","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jupiter Zheng is Partner of Liquid Funds &amp; Research for HashKey Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Asia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"HashKey Capital Partner of Liquid Funds &amp; Research Jupiter Zheng","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Zheng","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Hashkey","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"HashKey Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}