{"summary":"The world’s larget cryptocurrency by market capitalization surged to as high as $35,066 at one stage on Tuesday morning in Asia, CoinGecko data showed.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/259100\/bitcoin-ticks-above-35000-as-spot-etf-hype-builds?utm_source=rss&utm_medium=rss","publishDate":"2023-10-23T23:08:07","id":14323,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin ticks above $35,000 as spot ETF hype builds","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitcoin surged to over $35,000 on Tuesday morning in Asia as anticipation builds around the potential approval of spot bitcoin ETFs.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The world’s larget cryptocurrency by market capitalization was trading at $34,883 at around 10:30 a.m. Hong Kong time today, up 14.8% over the past 24 hours, after reaching as high as $35,066, according to <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.coingecko.com\/en\/coins\/bitcoin\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CoinGecko data<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. It's the first time bitcoin has topped the $35,000 threshold since May 2022. The move added to bitcoin’s weekly gain of 22.8%<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We have seen a very quick pick up of the bitcoin price in the past few days and this is the direct result of the heightened anticipation of Bitcoin ETFs this year,” Lucy Hu, a senior trader of Metalpha, a Hong Kong-headquartered digital asset wealth management firm, told The Block.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Another key reason could be the continued escalation of the Middle East conflict, in which institutional investors are allocating bitcoins to their portfolios for risk diversification,” Hu said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Jack Tan, co-founder and CEO of crypto trading service WOO Network, said that bitcoin may “grind higher” in anticipation of spot bitcoin ETFs and “as a hedge against geopolitical turmoil which necessitates more government spending and money printing.”&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We are now past the highs of the fake news pump,” Tan added.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ethereum rose 7.8% over the past 24 hours and gained 13.5% in the week.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The price movements come after <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BlackRock's <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/237563\/blackrock-refile-for-spot-bitcoin-etf-naming-coinbase-as-surveillance-partner\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">highly anticipated spot bitcoin ETF<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, the iShares Bitcoin Trust, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/258041\/blackrocks-spot-bitcoin-etf-appears-on-dtcc-website-with-ticker-ibtc\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">made an appearance on a list<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> maintained by the Depository Trust and Clearing Corporation.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"This is first spot ETF listed on DTCC, none of the others on there (yet),\" Eric Balchunas, senior ETF analyst at Bloomberg, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/EricBalchunas\/status\/1716529570759704832\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on X. \"Def notable BlackRock is leading charge on these logistics (seeding, ticker, dtcc) that tend to happen just prior to launch. Hard not to view this as them getting signal that approval is certain\/imminent.\"<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"14.8%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Middle East","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$35,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$35,066","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"7.8%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"BlackRock","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"May 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"DTCC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"13.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Bitcoin Trust","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Asia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$34,883","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"morning","content":"TIME"},{"type":"10:30 a.m.","content":"TIME"},{"type":"22.8%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Lucy Hu","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jack Tan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Depository Trust and Clearing Corporation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Eric Balchunas","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}