{"summary":"Arbitrum has hired Andrew Saunders as its first chief market officer to lead and oversee all marketing and communications efforts worldwide.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/163800\/arbitrum-hires-its-first-chief-marketing-officer","publishDate":"2022-08-16T10:22:29","id":144,"type":null,"title":"Arbitrum hires its first chief marketing officer","category":["ETHEREUM"],"content":["Arbitrum has hired Andrew Saunders as its first chief market officer. Prior to joining Arbitrum, Saunders was part of Amazon’s global brand marketing team where he helped build the retail giant’s first entertainment and culture marketing practice globally.","Saunder’s career spans across multiple industries. Prior to Amazon, he led brand strategy for Tastemade, was the VP of content innovation at NBCUniversal, and co-founded Creative Artists Agency’s brand partnership division.","At Offchain Labs, Saunders will lead and oversee all marketing and communications efforts worldwide.","“Saunders has a unique, specialized skill set that will be paramount in assisting Offchain Labs with attaining its next level of growth globally,” said Arbitrum CEO Steven Goldfeder.","This comes shortly after Arbitrum's launch of Arbitrum Nova — a chain focused on hyper scalability for gaming and social applications — and partnership announcements with Reddit, FTX, Consensys, P2P, and Quicknode on August 9.","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Reddit","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"August 9","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Amazon","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Saunders","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Steven Goldfeder","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Arbitrum","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Andrew Saunders","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Offchain Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["ARBITRUM","FTX","HIRING"],"authors":["Mike Truppa","The Block"]}