{"summary":"Mintables will make it easier and cheaper for beginners to mint their first NFTs and remove the need for cryptocurrency to do so.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/153271\/quidd-launches-feature-to-mint-and-unmint-digital-collectibles-into-nfts","publishDate":"2022-06-21T09:20:36","id":1440,"type":null,"title":"Quidd launches feature to mint and unmint digital collectibles into NFTs","category":["NFTS"],"content":["Animoca Brands and its digital collectibles market subsidiary Quidd has launched a feature for minting and unminting digital collectibles on the Ethereum blockchain named Mintables, the company announced on Tuesday.","According to a statement from Animoca, Mintables will make it easier and cheaper for beginners to mint their first non-fungible tokens (NFTs) and remove the need for cryptocurrency to do so, while the assets remain interoperable with popular Ethereum NFT marketplaces such as OpenSea and Rarible.","“With Mintables, we are delivering user choice in addition to true digital ownership. Why should the platform decide if a&nbsp;digital item should be on a blockchain, or even which blockchain? The Mintables initiative&nbsp;gives real power to the collectors,” said Michael Bramlage, CEO and co-founder of Quidd.","Animoca Brands <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/34798\/digital-collectibles-market-faces-renaissance-as-platform-targeting-comic-fans-scores-8m-acquisition\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">acquired Quidd<\/a> in 2019. The app focuses on the virtual collecting and trading of collectibles by popular brands, from football teams including Manchester United to shows like Ricky and Morty or Adventure Time. Assets are paid for in fiat.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Ethereum NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Rarible","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Manchester United","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"fiat","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Animoca Brands","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ricky","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"OpenSea","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Animoca","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Michael Bramlage","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2019","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["ANIMOCA BRANDS"],"authors":["Callan Quinn","The Block"]}