{"summary":"Round-the-clock trading became popular with the rise of cryptocurrencies and an increase in retail investor activity during the Covid-19 pandemic.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/markets\/2024\/04\/22\/nyse-asks-market-participants-about-247-trading-for-stocks\/","publishDate":"2024-04-22T15:48:16","id":14472,"type":null,"title":"NYSE Asks Market Participants About 24\/7 Trading for Stocks","category":["Markets"],"content":["The New York Stock Exchange has asked market participants about how they'd feel if the market operated 24 hours a day, the same schedule that cryptocurrencies use, the Financial Times reported.","NYSE, whose roots stretch back to the 18th century, famously signals the start and end of daily trading with bell-ringing ceremonies in the morning and afternoon – though, because of electronic trading, buying and selling has for decades actually taken place before the first bell at 9:30 a.m. and after the second one at 4 p.m. New York time.","But a startup, 24 Exchange, which is backed by billionaire hedge fund manager Steve Cohen, wants to take that a step further as the first stock exchange to allow 24\/7 trading. Several retail brokers like Robinhood already let clients trade day and night.","And cryptocurrencies never stop trading. “Anyone who wants to trade crypto 24\/7 would also like to trade Apple or Microsoft 24\/7,” 24 Exchange’s founder and CEO, Dmitri Galin, told Bloomberg in 2023.","Round-the-clock trading became a popular idea after interest in crypto blew up and retail trading grew tremendously during the Covid-19 pandemic. Increased investor interest from Asia and Europe in U.S. financial assets has also picked up in recent years.","“The world changed with the pandemic and with crypto trading 24\/7. Everybody has the infrastructure and the support to handle trading overnight now,” Brian Hyndman, chief executive of Blue Ocean, an overnight-trading provider, told the Financial Times in December.","Questions in NYSE’s survey included whether participants would prefer overnight trading to take place seven days a week, how investors should be protected from price fluctuations as well as opinions on the staffing of overnight sessions, according to the FT.","The SEC has several months to make a decision on 24 Exchange’s application.","Edited by Nick Baker."],"entity":[{"type":"Brian Hyndman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Blue Ocean","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Steve Cohen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"19","content":"DATE"},{"type":"18th century","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Robinhood","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York Stock Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"4 p.m.","content":"TIME"},{"type":"December","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Asia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Nick Baker","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"NYSE","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Microsoft","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Financial Times","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dmitri Galin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"9:30 a.m.","content":"TIME"}],"hashtag":["NYSE","Trading","Markets"],"authors":["Helene Braun"]}