{"summary":"Reddit co-founder Alexis Ohanian will be investing in decentralized social media that uses the Solana blockchain.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/123763\/reddit-co-founder-to-invest-50-million-in-social-media-on-solana","publishDate":"2021-11-09T09:14:41","id":1447,"type":null,"title":"Reddit co-founder to invest $100 million in social media on Solana","category":["CRYPTOCURRENCY"],"content":["Reddit co-founder Alexis Ohanian will be investing in building out a form of decentralized social media using the Solana blockchain, according to an announcement today.","During a fireside chat with Solana co-founder Raj Gokal, Reddit co-founder Alexis Ohanian said, “One of the reason why i’m here is to announce — I have a venture fund called 776 — we’re earmarking $50 million to invest in the next wave of social, built on Solana.\"","During the chat, Ohanian added that $50 million wasn't enough so that the plan is to increase the initiative to $100 million.","This comes a day after FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/123558\/ftx-ceo-social-media-on-the-blockchain-could-be-absolutely-huge\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said that building social media<\/a> on the blockchain could be \"absolutely huge.\"","During his talk, Bankman-Fried claimed that decentralized social media could solve a lot of pain points. He pointed to pre-existing social media sites, which have massive userbases, and stated that integrations with these sites could help to scale DeFi to millions more users.","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Update: An earlier version of this story misattributed the increase in size to Gokal.<\/em>","<i data-stringify-type=\"italic\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">For more breaking stories like this, make sure to follow The Block on&nbsp;<\/i><i data-stringify-type=\"italic\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a class=\"c-link\" href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/TheBlock__\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-stringify-link=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/TheBlock__\" data-sk=\"tooltip_parent\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Twitter<\/a><\/i><i data-stringify-type=\"italic\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/i>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Solana blockchain","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Reddit","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$100 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alexis Ohanian","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Fried","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gokal","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Raj Gokal","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ohanian","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$50 million","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["CRYPTO","SOLANA"],"authors":["Tim Copeland","The Block"]}