{"summary":"The world’s largest crypto exchange is reevaluating its business in Russia.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/247804\/binance-considers-a-full-exit-from-russia-wsj","publishDate":"2023-08-29T00:04:30","id":1451,"type":null,"title":"Binance considers a full exit from Russia: WSJ","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance, the world’s largest cryptocurrency exchange, is reevaluating its business in Russia as it faces legal risks in the country, according to a report from the <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.wsj.com\/livecoverage\/stock-market-today-dow-jones-08-28-2023\/card\/crypto-giant-binance-considers-russia-exit-lz69D5N6RzLEtlcyKYYT\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Wall Street Journal<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The exchange is weighing different options for its Russia operations, including a full withdrawal from the market, a Binance spokesperson told the media outlet.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Earlier this week, Binance’s peer-to-peer service <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/247546\/binance-delists-five-russian-lenders-on-site-following-scrutiny-wsj\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">removed<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> five sanctioned Russian lenders from its site that had previously given users the means to transfer rubles to each other.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A Binance spokesperson told The Block today that it did not have further comment on the matter.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Also this week, the Journal <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.wsj.com\/finance\/binance-cryptocurrency-russia-sanctions-ddb948c3?mod=article_inline\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance was helping people in Russia to move money abroad. That report came after the U.S. Justice Department’s <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/229711\/doj-binance-russia-sanctions\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">investigations<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> into whether Binance had been used by Russians to evade U.S. sanctions, according to a Bloomberg <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2023-05-05\/binance-faces-us-probe-of-possible-russian-sanctions-violations?leadSource=uverify%20wall\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">report<\/span><\/a>&nbsp;in May<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance currently finds itself in the crosshairs of multiple U.S. regulators, with the Commodities Futures Trading Commission first <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/223015\/cftc-sues-binance\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filing a lawsuit<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> against the firm in March. The Securities and Exchange Commission also <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/233154\/sec-files-suit-against-binance\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">sued<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> the exchange and CEO Changpeng Zhao last month for allegedly violating securities laws.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Commodities Futures Trading Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Changpeng Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S. Justice Department","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Russia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"last month","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Binance","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["ASIAN REGULATION","BINANCE","CFTC"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}