{"summary":"After New York&#x27;s bankruptcy court approved Binance.US&#x27; plan to purchase Voyager&#x27;s assets, the DoJ is making an effort to block the billion-dollar deal. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/218682\/us-doj-appeals-billion-dollar-binance-us-acquisition-of-voyager-assets","publishDate":"2023-03-10T02:15:49","id":1456,"type":null,"title":"US DOJ appeals billion-dollar Binance.US acquisition of Voyager assets","category":["BANKRUPTCY"],"content":["Though New York's bankruptcy court <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/217901\/binance-us-gets-green-light-to-buy-voyager-digital-assets\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">signed off<\/a> on Binance.US' plan to purchase Voyager's distressed assets, the United States government is making an effort to block the billion-dollar deal.&nbsp;","The U.S. Department of Justice's Trustee Office <a href=\"https:\/\/cases.stretto.com\/public\/x193\/11753\/PLEADINGS\/1175303102380000000013.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filed<\/a> an appeal against Binance.US' acquisition of bankrupt crypto lender Voyager Digital's assets roughly one day after New York bankruptcy judge Michael Wiles approved it.","\"Things have to be done,\" Judge Wiles said during the hearing. \"We have creditors who are waiting and who in the midst of all of this uncertainty have no access to property in which they’ve invested, in some cases, their life savings, so we have to take some kind of action,” he added.","The DOJ's appeal follows similar opposition from other regulators — including the Securities and Exchange Commission, which <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/214333\/sec-and-new-york-regulators-push-back-on-binance-uss-acquisition-of-voyager\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filed<\/a> an objection to the deal last month, citing a potential violation of federal securities laws through the unregistered operation of a securities exchange.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Wiles","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S. Department of Justice's Trustee Office","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"DOJ","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Voyager Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"United States","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Michael Wiles","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BANKRUPTCY FILINGS","BINANCE","CRYPTO BANKS AND LENDERS","PRIVATE COMPANY M&AMP;A"],"authors":["Adam James","The Block"]}