{"summary":"The broad-based CoinDesk 20, a liquid index of the biggest tokens, minus stablecoins, was down 3%.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/markets\/2024\/04\/10\/bitcoin-falls-below-69k-ahead-of-us-cpi-cardano-dogecoin-lead-majors-losses\/","publishDate":"2024-04-10T10:38:40","id":14624,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin Falls Below $69K Ahead of U.S. CPI; Cardano, Dogecoin Lead Losses in Altcoins","category":["Markets"],"content":["Bitcoin (BTC) is on the defensive under $69,000, nursing a 2.5% drop on a 24-hour basis, having briefly climbed to a high of $69,300 during the Asian trading hours.","Profit-taking from Monday continued as several major tokens slid lower. Ether and Solana’s SOL lost 2.8% and Cardano’s ADA and dogecoin (DOGE) slumped as much as 4%. BNB Chain’s BNB was the only token in green with a slight 1.8% rise.","The broad-based CoinDesk 20, a liquid index of the biggest tokens, excluding stablecoins, was down 3%.","The Asian session demand for bitcoin and leading altcoins represented trade optimism, FxPro Senior Market analyst Alex Kuptsikevich told CoinDesk in a message, warning of potential volatility explosion following the release of the U.S. consumer price index later Wednesday.","“The U.S. CPI report, which in recent years has caused a spike in volatility comparable to NFP [nonfarm payrolls report], has an impressive potential to influence the market on Wednesday,” said Kuptsikevich.","Still, some analysts said bitcoin correction could be over. Selling pressure from certain long-term wallets seems to have cooled in recent weeks, alongside a bump in demand for spot bitcoin, on-chain analysis firm Glassnode said in a Tuesday report.","“Bitcoin’s strong performance over the last 12 months is supported by a surge in spot trade volume and exchange deposit and withdrawal volumes,” analysts at blockchain data tracking firm Glassnode wrote. “Profit-taking by long-term holders spiked meaningfully into the $73k ATH and has been cooling down in recent weeks. This comes alongside an uptick in new demand brought on by the U.S. spot ETFs.”","The firm defines long-term holders as wallets that keep a token for more than 155 days instead of trading over weekly or daily periods.","Edited by Omkar Godbole."],"entity":[{"type":"Kuptsikevich","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"last 12 months","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2.8%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"3%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Cardano’s ADA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"4%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"1.8%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Omkar Godbole","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$69,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"CoinDesk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. CPI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$69,300","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alex Kuptsikevich","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"ATH","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$73k","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Glassnode","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["Trading","Markets","Invest"],"authors":["Shaurya Malwa"]}