{"summary":"Prime Trust said it will use its Series B funding to develop its cryptocurrency retirement products and build support for tokenized assets.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/153613\/prime-trust-raises-107-million-to-add-new-crypto-products","publishDate":"2022-06-22T11:56:56","id":1478,"type":null,"title":"Prime Trust raises $107 million to add new crypto products","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Digital asset infrastructure firm Prime Trust has raised $107 million in a Series B funding round to expand its product suite.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Investors included FIS, Fin Capital, Mercato Partners, Kraken Ventures, Commerce Ventures, William Blair &amp; Company, Decasonic, University Growth Fund, Gaingels, GateCap Ventures and Seven Peaks Ventures, according to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.prnewswire.com\/news-releases\/emerging-fintech-market-leader-prime-trust-raises-over-100m-in-series-b-funding-to-expand-into-new-offerings-301573003.html\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">the company’s announcement<\/a>.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Prime Trust serves nearly 700 fintech and digital asset clients, including some crypto largest startups like Dapper Labs and Binance US. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The firm had raised $64 million during the Series A funding round in July 2021, so the new round brings the total funds raised to around $170 million.&nbsp;<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“This strategic investment will provide critical operational expertise to further scale Prime Trust into new offerings,” said Prime Trust CEO Tom Pageler, “including wealth products, as well as web3 and DeFi products.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The newly-raised capital will be used to launch the Prime Trust Crypto Individual Retirement Account (IRA). The new platform — which the company claims is the first with a \"seamless, single API integration\" — will allow users to invest retirement funds in cryptocurrencies.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Prime Trust said it will also use the new funds to \"enhance our ability to support tokenized products\" and to invest in the security and stability of its platform.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Mercato Partners","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Decasonic","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$64 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Commerce Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gaingels","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FIS","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dapper Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$170 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Fin Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Prime Trust Crypto Individual Retirement Account (IRA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tom Pageler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$107 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Kraken Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"GateCap Ventures and Seven Peaks Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Binance US","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"William Blair &amp; Company","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Prime Trust","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"University Growth Fund","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Kharishar Kahfi","The Block"]}