{"summary":"The digital assets trading firm said in April it was setting up shop in Abu Dhabi in collaboration with Further Ventures.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/policy\/2024\/05\/07\/qcp-receives-in-principal-approval-from-abu-dhabi-regulator\/","publishDate":"2024-05-07T11:52:59","id":14870,"type":null,"title":"QCP Receives In-Principal Approval From Abu Dhabi Regulator","category":["Policy"],"content":["Digital assets trading firm QCP Capital said it received In-Principle Approval from the Financial Services Regulatory Authority (FSRA) of Abu Dhabi Global Market (ADGM).","The Singapore-based firm is the latest digital assets company to establish a licensed presence in Abu Dhabi. In April, during Token 2049 in neighboring Dubai, it said it signed a partnership with Further Ventures to expand into the Middle East.","“Our intention is to be a responsible player that wants to support market confidence,\" CEO Melvin Deng said in a statement. \"We are proud to be the first Singaporean digital asset market maker and broker-dealer to set up here in the market and hope we can encourage others to venture into this dynamic market.”","Abu Dhabi Global Market is one of the fastest-growing crypto hubs in the region.","“We want to learn from what other players are doing in Abu Dhabi and the region and bring our expertise as a first mover in digital assets to the ecosystem,” Deng said.","Chainalysis reported in October 2023 that most UAE digital asset transactions were large institutional investments.","In December, Coinbase's new blockchain-based financial products for institutional investors also received in-principle approval from the FSRA.","Edited by Sheldon Reback."],"entity":[{"type":"Middle East","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sheldon Reback","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"QCP Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"December","content":"DATE"},{"type":"October 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Melvin Deng","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Financial Services Regulatory Authority (FSRA) of Abu Dhabi Global Market","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Dubai","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Abu Dhabi","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Dhabi Global Market","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Token 2049","content":"DATE"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"UAE","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Abu Dhabi","Abu Dhabi Global Market","Licensing","Singapore","QCP Capital"],"authors":["Sam Reynolds"]}