{"summary":"Bitcoin is back and Breitling puts watches on the blockchain. It's CoinDesk's Markets Daily.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/markets\/2020\/03\/30\/bitcoin-news-roundup-for-march-30-2020\/","publishDate":"2020-03-30T16:00:00","id":14893,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin News Roundup for March 30, 2020","category":["Markets"],"content":["","For early access before our regular noon Eastern time releases, subscribe with Apple Podcasts, Spotify, Pocketcasts, Google Podcasts, Castbox, Stitcher, RadioPublica or RSS.","","","Todays Stories:","","","Bitcoin Diverges From Falling Equities With $500 Price Rise","","","Luxury Watchmaker Breitling Adds Its First Timepieces to a Blockchain","","","World Health Organization Teams With IBM, Oracle on Blockchain-Based Coronavirus Data Hub","","","How a Flurry of 'Digital Dollar' Proposals Made It to Congress","","","Misty Robotics: Say Hello to Your Next Development Platform","","","For early access before our regular noon Eastern time releases, subscribe with Apple Podcasts, Spotify, Pocketcasts, Google Podcasts, Castbox, Stitcher, RadioPublica or RSS.",""],"entity":[{"type":"Blockchain","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Pocketcasts","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"First Timepieces","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"World Health Organization Teams With IBM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Oracle","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Castbox","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$500","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Eastern","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Congress","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["IBM","Watches","CoinDesk Markets Daily","mipasa","Breitling"],"authors":["John Biggs","Adam B. Levine"]}