{"summary":"The Block&#x27;s Frank Chaparro talks to Eric Balchunas, Senior ETF Analyst at Bloomberg Intelligence.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/96507\/bloombergs-etf-whisperer-sec-btc-etf","publishDate":"2021-02-26T17:23:01","id":1490,"type":null,"title":"Bloomberg&#x27;s ETF whisperer says the SEC could approve a BTC ETF","category":["PODCASTS"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 11 of Season 3 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block’s Frank Chaparro and Senior ETF Analyst at Bloomberg Intelligence, Eric Balchunas.<\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"7f0f101b1c1e0c0b3f0b171a1d13101c141c0d060f0b10511c1012\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by Kraken<\/em><\/strong>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Whether you’re an experienced crypto trader or just starting out, Kraken has the tools to help you achieve financial freedom. With 50+ cryptocurrencies to choose from, industry-leading security and a wide variety of features to suit any investing strategy, Kraken puts the power in your hands to buy, sell and trade digital assets. Visit&nbsp;<\/em><a href=\"http:\/\/kraken.com\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kraken.com<\/em><\/a><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;to get started&nbsp;today.<\/em>","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK2091301545\" width=\"100%\" height=\"200\" frameborder=\"0\" scrolling=\"no\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Regulators in Canada approved two bitcoin exchange-traded funds (ETFs) in recent days, marking the first approvals of their kind for North America.","Since launch, the products have seen considerable inflows. With the demand for a bitcoin ETF now proven, many wonder what a Canadian approval could mean for a U.S. offering.&nbsp;","The Scoop spoke with Eric Balchunas, a senior ETF analyst at Bloomberg, about what an approved bitcoin ETF means for the landscape. During this week's episode Balchunas broke down the winding road to approval and why Canada was always likely to be a first.","Now that Canada has its BTC ETFs, he argued that an approval from the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) is just around the corner.","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/b>\"I think it's just a matter of the SEC coming around, and then once they come around mentally, I imagine it will happen pretty quickly,\" he said. \"But again, I'm not in that bubble. I'm not a regulatory analyst. That's just my sense from talking to people.\"","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Canada","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"North America","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kraken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg Intelligence","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Eric Balchunas","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN","COINBASE"],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}