{"summary":"Crypto-related companies looked set to start the week on a positive note.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/markets\/2024\/04\/08\/crypto-stocks-gain-as-bitcoin-tops-72k-for-first-time-since-march\/","publishDate":"2024-04-08T09:19:23","id":14950,"type":null,"title":"Crypto Stocks Gain as Bitcoin Tops $72K for First Time Since March","category":["Markets"],"content":["U.S. crypto-related stocks looked set to start the week on a positive note after bitcoin (BTC) climbed through $72,000 for the first time since mid-March as its reward halving draws closer.","Coinbase (COIN), the only U.S. traded crypto exchange, added 4.9% in pre-market trading, MicroStrategy (MSTR), the largest corporate holder of bitcoin, rose 10% and BlackRock’s bitcoin exchange-traded fund (IBIT), added around 6.5%.","The CoinDesk 20 Index, a measure of the broader crypto market, rose 3.1% over 24 hours.","The halving, which cuts the amount bitcoin miners are paid for adding blocks to the blockchain by 50%, is on track for April 20. After it occurs, they will be rewarded with 3.125 BTC per block.","Among miners, Marathon Digital (MARA) added 5.2% and Hut 8 (HUT), which merged with USBTC at the end of last year, gained 5.6%. Argo Blockchain (ARB), trading on the London Stock Exchange, rose 5%.","Read more: Bitcoin Halving Is a ‘Show Me the Money’ Moment for Miners","Edited by Omkar Godbole."],"entity":[{"type":"4.9%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"BlackRock","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"5.6%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"6.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Omkar Godbole","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"10%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"3.1%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"5.2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Money’ Moment for Miners","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"50%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"April 20","content":"DATE"},{"type":"London Stock Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$72,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"MicroStrategy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Marathon Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Stocks","Markets","US"],"authors":["Sheldon Reback"]}