{"summary":"The UAE's second-most populous emirate has taken the first steps to legalize the operations of decentralized entities such as DAOs.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/policy\/2023\/11\/02\/abu-dhabi-enacts-dlt-framework-for-daos-web3-tradfi-firms\/","publishDate":"2023-11-02T16:29:43","id":14989,"type":null,"title":"Abu Dhabi Enacts DLT Framework for DAOs, Web3, TradFi Firms","category":["Policy"],"content":["Abu Dhabi, the UAE's second-most populous emirate, has taken the first steps to legalize the operations of decentralized entities such as DAOs.","Abu Dhabi has unveiled a new regulatory framework for decentralized autonomous organizations (DAOs) and other entities built on distributed ledger technology (DLT), marking the first push toward such a framework by a Middle Eastern territory, the Registration Authority of Abu Dhabi Global Market (ADGM) said Thursday in a statement.","The framework, effectively immediately, enables DAOs, which have long operated within a legal grey area, to operate legally and issue tokens to their members.","Distributed ledger technology, which provides the basis for blockchain networks, is a system of recording and storing information on different ledgers within a network to ensure data accuracy and security.","The move forms part of a larger initiative to \"foster initiatives in the broader blockchain and digital asset realm\" in Abu Dhabi, the United Arab Emirates’ second-most populous territory after Dubai.","Abu Dhabi is vying to become a crypto hub alongside Dubai as the UAE embraces the digital assets sector and has a regulatory framework that can be valuable for firms looking for regulatory clarity, in contrast to elsewhere in the world.","\"The new regime serves as a driving force for positive change in the digital assets sector,\" ADGM Chairman Ahmed Jasim Al Zaabi said in a statement.","\"By transforming the blockchain and Web3 landscape, we are moving towards a future characterized by setting global benchmarks with enhanced transparency and efficiency,” he added.","Read more: Why Crypto Companies Are Warming to the United Arab Emirates"],"entity":[{"type":"Middle Eastern","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dubai","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Abu Dhabi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Registration Authority of Abu Dhabi Global Market","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Abu Dhabi","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Why Crypto Companies","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DLT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ahmed Jasim Al Zaabi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"United Arab Emirates","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UAE","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Abu Dhabi","UAE","DAO","Web3","dlt"],"authors":["Elizabeth Napolitano"]}