{"summary":"Former CEO Jamie Leverton is succeeded by president Asher Genoot.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/business\/2024\/02\/07\/bitcoin-miner-hut-8-shares-slide-as-ceo-departs-weeks-after-short-seller-report\/","publishDate":"2024-02-07T16:30:09","id":14991,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin Miner Hut 8 Shares Slide as CEO Departs Weeks After Short-Seller Report","category":["Finance"],"content":["The shares of bitcoin miner Hut 8 (HUT) fell as much as 8% on Wednesday, after CEO Jamie Leverton left the company just weeks after the firm was hit by a short-seller report.","The miner said Leverton, who served as CEO for three years, will be succeeded by the company's president, Asher Genoot, effective immediately. Genoot co-founded U.S. Bitcoin Corp. (USBTC) and became president and director of Hut 8 in November after a merger with USBTC.","“The merger of equals of Hut 8 and US Bitcoin Corp was a transformational moment for both companies,” Hut 8 Chairman Bill Tai said in a statement. “Hut 8 is now at a pivotal inflection point, and we believe that Asher is uniquely qualified to accelerate our path to market leadership.\"","The move comes after short seller JCapital Research released a report on Jan. 18 saying the merger was a \"pump and dump\" waiting to happen. The miner fired back a week later, saying the report was \"a deliberate attempt to spread misinformation about Hut 8, its operations, finances, management practices, and key executives.\"","Hut 8's stock has fallen more than 50% this year, while the Valkyrie Bitcoin Miners ETF (WGMI) – a fund that tracks miners' performance – lost about 39%, and bitcoin added about 2%.","Read more: Bitcoin Miner Selling Ahead of Halving Is Capping Prices: Bitfinex","Edited by Sheldon Reback.","\n","\n"],"entity":[{"type":"Sheldon Reback","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"8%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Jamie Leverton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"US Bitcoin Corp","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Asher","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bill Tai","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bitcoin Miner Selling Ahead","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"JCapital Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"50%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Asher Genoot","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Jan. 18","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Valkyrie Bitcoin Miners ETF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"39%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S. Bitcoin Corp.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Leverton","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["Hut 8","Bitcoin Mining","CEO","PEOPLE"],"authors":["Aoyon Ashraf"]}