{"summary":"The Mango Markets exploiter faces trial, raising questions about the legality of DeFi exploits and the \"code is law\" principle.","webName":"beincrypto.com","link":"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/mango-markets-exploiter-trial-begins\/","publishDate":"2024-04-09T06:30:00","id":15,"type":null,"title":"Mango Markets Mayhem: Avraham Eisenberg Faces Trial Over $100 Million Exploit","category":["Markets"],"content":["<strong>Avraham Eisenberg, accused of draining over $100 million from the Mango Markets decentralized exchange (DEX), will face his criminal trial this week.<\/strong>","A New York federal court jury was assembled on Monday, with members ranging from a financial professional to a Broadway performer.","The case stems from a controversial <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/mango-markets-loses-100m-defi-exploit-attacker-proposing-treasury-liquidation-vote\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener\">October 2022 hack of Mango Markets<\/a>. An investigation by journalist Chris Brunet <a href=\"https:\/\/www.karlstack.com\/p\/exclusive-the-man-who-may-have-milked\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener nofollow\">suggested<\/a> Eisenberg’s potential involvement. ","The Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/alleged-mango-markets-exploiter-placed-custody-puerto-rico\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener\">subsequently arrested Eisenberg<\/a> in Puerto Rico in December, charging him with market manipulation.","The case’s heart is whether Eisenberg’s actions were criminal or simply a clever exploit within the protocol. He used one account to drive up the collateral price, allowing him to borrow much larger sums from the platform with a separate account.","Eisenberg <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/mango-market-attacker-is-sorry-hes-not-sorry-for-actions\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener\">defended himself<\/a>, stating his actions were “legal open market actions, using the protocol as designed.” He argued that discrepancies between a protocol’s documentation and its code are common, and his actions exploited an unintended consequence.","<strong>Read more: <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/learn\/crypto-security\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener\">Top 5 Flaws in Crypto Security and How To Avoid Them<\/a><\/strong>","Despite his insistence on a “highly profitable trading strategy,” Eisenberg faced charges from multiple US regulators.","The Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/sec-charges-mango-market-attacker-for-stealing-116m\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener\">charged him on January 20, 2023<\/a>, for manipulating MNGO tokens. Before the SEC’s action, the Commodity <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/learn\/cryptocurrency-futures-where-to-trade-them\/\" target=\"_blank\" class=\"glossary-only-link\">Futures<\/a> Trading Commission (CFTC) had already <a href=\"https:\/\/www.cftc.gov\/PressRoom\/PressReleases\/8647-23\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener nofollow\">filed<\/a> charges against him on January 9, 2023, for violating commodities regulations.","The enforcement actions from both regulators indicated his strategies may not have been as profitable or legitimate as claimed.","The Mango Markets’ case has sparked <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/alleged-mango-markets-exploiter-denied-bail\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener\">intense debate in the crypto community<\/a>. Some defend Eisenberg, arguing the principle of “code is law” protects traders who exploit loopholes in blockchain platforms. However, prosecutors maintain that market manipulation and fraud remain illegal, even in decentralized finance (<a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/learn\/ethereum-decentralized-finance-revolution\/\" target=\"_blank\" class=\"glossary-only-link\">DeFi<\/a>).","Get guaranteed bonus up to $200 on Coinbase in 3 easy steps\n\n\t  ","“It touches on the big argument within crypto — is code law? Just because there is an opportunity to exploit it does not mean that it’s legal,” Chris Janczewski of TRM Labs <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2024-04-08\/crypto-scam-criminal-trial-tests-code-is-law-claim-by-trader\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener nofollow\">said<\/a>. ","<strong>Read more: <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/learn\/lending-protocols-risk\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener\">Identifying &amp; Exploring&nbsp;Risk on DeFi Lending Protocols<\/a><\/strong>","CFTC Chairman Rostin Behnam has previously emphasized transparency and engagement with the <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/learn\/decentralized-finance-and-use-cases\/\" target=\"_blank\" class=\"glossary-only-link\">DeFi<\/a> industry. However, he clarified a distinction between purely code-based protocols and platforms that market their services to US customers:","“… Who is either [the] individual or the group of individuals who set up that entity, that code, to offer those products?” Behnam <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2023-05-18\/transcript-cftc-chair-rostin-behnam-on-the-fight-to-regulate-crypto\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener nofollow\">emphasized<\/a>.","Eisenberg’s case isn’t the first time regulators have clashed with the DeFi world, but it’s by far the most high-profile. The outcome could influence development and investment in the DeFi space as investors seek clarity on whether the traditional financial rulebook applies to this sector.<span id=\"docs-internal-guid-5909a88d-7fff-0004-8ada-c2bb5627eef7\"><\/span>","Disclaimer","In adherence to the <a class=\"c-link\" href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/trust-project\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-stringify-link=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/trust-project\/\" data-sk=\"tooltip_parent\" aria-describedby=\"sk-tooltip-21920\">Trust Project<\/a> guidelines, BeInCrypto is committed to unbiased, transparent reporting. This news article aims to provide accurate, timely information. However, readers are advised to verify facts independently and consult with a professional before making any decisions based on this content. Please note that our&nbsp;<a class=\"c-link\" href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/terms-and-conditions\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-stringify-link=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/terms-and-conditions\/\" data-sk=\"tooltip_parent\">Terms and Conditions<\/a>,&nbsp;<a class=\"c-link\" href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/privacy-policy\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-stringify-link=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/privacy-policy\/\" data-sk=\"tooltip_parent\">Privacy Policy<\/a>, and&nbsp;<a class=\"c-link\" href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/disclaimer\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-stringify-link=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/disclaimer\/\" data-sk=\"tooltip_parent\">Disclaimers<\/a>&nbsp;have been updated."],"entity":[{"type":"January 20, 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"TRM Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Commodity <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/learn\/cryptocurrency-futures-where-to-trade-them\/\" target=\"_blank\" class=\"glossary-only-link\">Futures<\/a> Trading Commission (CFTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$100 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Rostin Behnam","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"December","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Crypto Security","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"October 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"DEX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Avraham Eisenberg","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Puerto Rico","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"January 9, 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Eisenberg","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"CFTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$200","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Trust Project","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chris Brunet","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Chris Janczewski","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Lynn Wang"]}