{"summary":"Two groups seeking to promote blockchain tech in the Asia-Pacific have officially merged to open up greater opportunities in the region.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/markets\/2019\/08\/01\/australias-two-leading-blockchain-advocate-groups-announce-merger\/","publishDate":"2019-08-01T04:15:26","id":15038,"type":null,"title":"Australia’s Two Leading Blockchain Advocate Groups Announce Merger","category":["Markets"],"content":["Two groups seeking to promote blockchain technology in the Asia-Pacific have officially merged.","Announced July 22, the Australian Digital Currency Association (ADCA) and Blockchain Australia (BA) signed documentation that will see the two groups formally combine efforts under the BA logo and brand.","ADCA is the industry's leading network for businesses seeking to implement blockchain solutions while BA is the industry body that represents domestic organizations participating in the crypto asset economy.","The announcement, as well as the unveiling of the group's new logo, took place at the Annual APAC Blockchain Conference in Sydney.","Further, the news was presented by the assistant minister for Superannuation, Financial Services and Financial Technology, the Hon. Senator Jane Hume, demonstrating government support for the merger and future developments from the Australian blockchain community.","\"I’m absolutely delighted to see that ADCA and BA have decided to merge, having a consistent and united voice advocating for the responsible adoption of blockchain technology,\" Hume told attendees. “We need to recognize the potential for Australian blockchain businesses to tap into the demand that’s deriving from Asia’s growing middle class.”","The official merger was hosted by the Sydney Stock Exchange (SSX) and witnessed by directors and members from both organizations.","Nick Giurietto, CEO and managing director of BA, told CoinDesk:","“The merger of our two organizations creates a stronger and more united voice,” added Adam Poulton, director on the newly formed organization's board.","Those involved in the new organization hope the merger will open pathways for greater opportunities and advancement in the APAC region.","Logo unveiling image via Annual APAC Blockchain Conference"],"entity":[{"type":"July 22","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Jane Hume","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"APAC Blockchain Conference","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sydney","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Financial Services and Financial Technology","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Blockchain Australia (BA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"APAC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Australian Digital Currency Association","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Pacific","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Hume","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Asia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Nick Giurietto","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Adam Poulton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sydney Stock Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BA","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["News","Blockchain Australia","ADCA","APAC Blockchain conference"],"authors":["Sebastian Sinclair"]}