{"summary":"Far from reassuring the markets, the Fed’s dramatic action over the weekend seems to have spooked them instead.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/markets\/2020\/03\/16\/the-feds-700b-bazooka-misfires-feat-coindesks-michael-casey-and-noelle-acheson\/","publishDate":"2020-03-16T19:00:00","id":15073,"type":null,"title":"The Fed's $700B Bazooka Misfires, Feat. CoinDesk's Michael Casey and Noelle Acheson","category":["Markets"],"content":["","Far from reassuring the markets, the Federal Reserve’s dramatic action over the weekend seems to have spooked them instead.","","","For more episodes and free early access before our regular 3 p.m. Eastern time releases, subscribe with Apple Podcasts, Spotify, Pocketcasts, Google Podcasts, Castbox, Stitcher, RadioPublica, IHeartRadio or RSS.","","","Over the weekend, the Fed decided it couldn’t wait for Wednesday’s planned meeting to act, cutting interest rates to nearly 0 percent. It also announced $700 billion of direct capital injection through the purchase of Treasury securities and mortgage-backed debt. ","","","The question is whether this action can actually calm markets. So far, it’s not looking great. Within minutes, emergency circuit breakers were triggered again. Markets are down more than 9 percent on the day. ","","","In this episode, @NLW chats with CoinDesk Chief Content Officer Michael Casey and Director of Research Noelle Acheson about:","","","For more episodes and free early access before our regular 3 p.m. Eastern time releases, subscribe with Apple Podcasts, Spotify, Pocketcasts, Google Podcasts, Castbox, Stitcher, RadioPublica, IHeartRadio or RSS.","","","","","","Watch: What Does The Fed's 0% Rate Cut Say About Bitcoin?",""],"entity":[{"type":"Federal Reserve","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$700 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Pocketcasts","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Fed","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Director of Research Noelle Acheson","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CoinDesk Chief Content","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Eastern","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"weekend","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"RadioPublica","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"9 percent","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Castbox","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Michael Casey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"0%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"0 percent","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"3 p.m.","content":"TIME"}],"hashtag":["Federal Reserve","Podcasts","The Breakdown","Coronavirus","noelle-acheson","Michael Casey"],"authors":["Nathaniel Whittemore"]}