{"summary":"The platform will feature deeper analytics and lower fees than the digital bank's app.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/business\/2024\/02\/16\/revolut-to-introduce-crypto-exchange-targeting-advanced-traders\/","publishDate":"2024-02-16T15:43:37","id":15122,"type":null,"title":"Revolut to Introduce Crypto Exchange Targeting 'Advanced Traders'","category":["Finance"],"content":["Digital bank Revolut is set to introduce a cryptocurrency exchange targeting \"advanced traders,\" according to a customer email seen by CoinDesk.","Revolut currently offers basic crypto services to many of its 30 million customers. The exchange will offer lower fees and enhanced market analytics.","\"We're launching a new crypto exchange, built with advanced traders in mind,\" the email, which asked the customer to test the new platform, read. \"You'll find deeper analytical tools and lower fees than the app.\"","Fees have been set between 0% and 0.09%, and functionality has been added to allow users to trade using limit and market orders. Limit orders are typically used when a trader wants to purchase or sell an asset at a specific price. Limit orders will incur no fees.","\"We always develop new products and functionalities, desired by our customers or asked by the market,\" a Revolut spokesperson told CoinDesk. \"The standalone cryptocurrency exchange is one of the future developments, but more information will be released only when the product will be available in-app. Currently this product is accessible by invite only, we will be rolling this out and inviting more customers to take part.\"","Revolut suspended crypto services for business customers in the U.K. in December, citing the Financial Conduct Authority's (FCA) new regulations covering crypto promotions. The email seen by CoinDesk was received by a U.K.-based customer.","Earlier this week, it emerged that Revolut plans to list Solana's biggest meme coin, BONK, in a \"learn and earn\" campaign that will see the distribution of BONK to some of its customers.","UPDATE (Feb. 19, 07:31 UTC): Adds comment from Revolut.","Edited by Sheldon Reback."],"entity":[{"type":"Sheldon Reback","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FCA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Financial Conduct Authority","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.K.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"CoinDesk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"December","content":"DATE"},{"type":"BONK","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"BONK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Feb. 19","content":"DATE"},{"type":"0%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"0.09%","content":"PERCENT"}],"hashtag":["Revolut","Crypto Exchange","banking"],"authors":["Oliver Knight"]}