{"summary":"Users will be able to buy and sell bitcoin, ether, USDT, EURT and XAUT.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/business\/2023\/06\/27\/bitfinex-launches-peer-to-peer-trading-platform-in-argentina-colombia-and-venezuela\/","publishDate":"2023-06-27T15:42:53","id":15167,"type":null,"title":"Bitfinex Launches Peer-to-Peer Trading Platform in Argentina, Colombia and Venezuela","category":["Finance"],"content":["Crypto exchange Bitfinex launched a peer-to-peer trading platform in Argentina, Colombia and Venezuela, the company announced on Tuesday.","According to Bitfinex, users are now able to buy and sell bitcoin (BTC), ether (ETH), tether tokens denominated in euros (EURT) and US dollars (USDT), and Tether gold (XAUT) pegged to the price of gold. Customers can use a payment method and domestic currency of choice, the company added.","In May, Bitfinex made an undisclosed investment in Chilean crypto exchange OrionX with the aim of expanding its footprint in Latin America, while Tether – the issuer of stablecoin USDT – invested in an energy production and sustainable bitcoin mining facility in Uruguay.","In May 2022, Tether had launched its MXNT token pegged to Mexico's peso, in what had been its first move into the Latin American market.","Edited by Rosie Perper."],"entity":[{"type":"Venezuela","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bitfinex","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"May 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Latin America","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mexico","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Argentina","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Colombia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Rosie Perper","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Uruguay","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["Bitfinex","South America","Tether","peer-to-peer"],"authors":["Andrés Engler"]}