{"summary":"Bitcoin has also given up some of its early Monday bounce, returning down to the $64,000 level.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/markets\/2024\/04\/15\/ether-altcoins-remain-under-pressure-following-volatile-weekend\/","publishDate":"2024-04-15T17:23:11","id":15189,"type":null,"title":"Ether, Altcoins Remain Under Pressure Following Volatile Weekend","category":["Markets"],"content":["Ether (ETH), the second largest cryptocurrency by market value, hovered just above the $3,100 mark in early afternoon U.S. hours on Monday, struggling to retain gains made since the crypto market's panicky selloff on Saturday.","While ahead 4% over the past 24 hours, ETH is lower by about 4% since rising to nearly $3,300 earlier Monday on word (as yet still unconfirmed) that multiple Hong Kong-based spot bitcoin and ether ETFs had been approved.","Downside pressure in bitcoin (BTC) has resumed as well, with that crypto now modestly lower over the past 24 hours to $64,200 after earlier Monday nearly reaching $67,000.","The broader CoinDesk 20 Index is ahead 0.68% over the past 24 hours.","Alongside, Solana's (SOL), gave up a large proportion of its overnight gains, dropping to around $140 from as high as $155 early Monday morning. That's also down from $175 reached on Friday.","Bitcoin, ether and the rest of crypto plunged on Saturday – with bitcoin dropping to the $61,000 area and ether below $3,000 – as Iran launched a bombing campaign on Israel, but the sector had regained some footing later in the weekend.","Singapore-based digital assets trading house QCP Capital said in a note to investors that historically, buying the dip on the outbreak of major geopolitical conflicts has been a profitable trade.","Ed Goh, head of trading at liquidity provider B2C2, said the firm has seen consistent buying in BTC, especially on the dip over the weekend. “57% of our flow has been to the buy side,” said Goh. He also added that altcoin activity remains high and they have seen a bias towards buying for alts.","Bitcoin’s halving event is fast approaching on April 19, which some traders are predicting could trigger a short-term “sell the news” reaction before and after the event.","Despite the setbacks, some altcoins continued with significant gains on Monday, with Ondo Finance (ONDO) up 15% over the past 24 hours while Render’s RNDR was aheadp 12% and The Graph (GRT) rose 9%.","Edited by Stephen Alpher."],"entity":[{"type":"$3,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$3,100","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$3,300","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"QCP Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"0.68%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"4%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"12%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$67,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$64,200","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Israel","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"57%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"15%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"earlier Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$140","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Saturday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Stephen Alpher","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"9%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Goh","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"April 19","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$61,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"morning","content":"TIME"},{"type":"$175","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$155","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Ondo Finance (ONDO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Iran","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["Ether","Bitcoin","Market Wrap"],"authors":["Lyllah Ledesma"]}