{"summary":"Digital currency exchange ShapeShift.io has raised $1.6m in new funding.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/markets\/2015\/09\/08\/altcoin-exchange-shapeshift-raises-16-million-in-new-funding\/","publishDate":"2015-09-08T17:00:40","id":15255,"type":null,"title":"Altcoin Exchange ShapeShift Raises $1.6 Million in New Funding","category":["Markets"],"content":["UPDATE (8th September 18:55 BST): This piece has been updated with comment from ShapeShift CEO Erik Voorhees.","","","Digital currency exchange ShapeShift.io has raised $1.6m in new funding.","As reported by TechCrunch, the round drew support from Digital Currency Group, bitcoin entrepreneur Roger Ver and Bitfinex, the Hong Kong-based bitcoin exchange","Bitcoin Foundation executive director Bruce Fenton, Transform PR founder and CEO Michael Terpin and Trevor Koverko, founder of education-oriented e-commerce platform eProf, also took part in the round as angel investors.","The announcement comes nearly six months after ShapeShift announced $525k in seed funding, an amount invested by both Ver and Digital Currency Group founder and CEO Barry Silbert.","ShapeShift later made headlines after it become one of the first of a growing number of digital currency businesses to stop serving New York customers following the development and launch of the BitLicense licensure framework in the state.","When reached for comment, ShapeShift CEO Erik Voorhees would be used to support ongoing development, provide liquidity to the exchange and enable further scalability.","He told CoinDesk:","\"Investors are starting to realize the enormity of the potential,\" he added.","Image via ShapeShift"],"entity":[{"type":"8th September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$1.6","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"BST","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Erik Voorhees","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bitcoin Foundation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Digital Currency Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$525k","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Barry Silbert","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bruce Fenton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"ShapeShift","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Michael Terpin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Trevor Koverko","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Roger Ver","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["Venture Capital","startups","Erik Voorhees","ShapeShift","Funding","News","Digital Currency Group","Companies"],"authors":["Stan Higgins"]}