{"summary":"South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol issued instructions to revise the bill to contain “practical measures to bolster national security,” the Korea JoongAng Daily reported.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/249108\/south-korea-looks-to-track-freeze-crypto-used-by-north-korea-in-new-bill-report","publishDate":"2023-09-05T00:19:13","id":1527,"type":null,"title":"South Korea looks to track, freeze crypto used by North Korea in new bill: report","category":["SECURITY"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">South Korea plans to submit a bill to track and freeze cryptocurrencies and other virtual assets used by North Korea, the Korea JoongAng Daily <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/koreajoongangdaily.joins.com\/news\/2023-09-04\/national\/northKorea\/South-seeks-to-track-and-freeze-Norths-crypto-assets\/1861813\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Monday.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The bill, aimed at cutting the funding of Pyongyang’s weapons programs, is the result of 10 months of consultations among various South Korean government agencies, the local media outlet reported, citing multiple government sources with knowledge of the matter.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Administration insiders said that President Yoon Suk Yeol issued instructions to revise the bill to contain “practical measures to bolster national security” before submission, adding that the bill is expected to add to South Korea’s existing sanctions against North Korea.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">One government official told the Daily that the South Korean President thought the country’s cybersecurity framework “urgently needs repair” and another administrator said the latest bill details measures to “track and neutralize virtual coins and other cryptocurrency assets stolen by the North through hacking.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">North Korea’s hackers illegally <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/245850\/north-korean-hackers-stole-over-180-million-in-crypto-during-h1-2023-report\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">amassed $180 million in cryptocurrency exploits<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in the first half of this year, <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">South Korea’s National Intelligence Service said last month, as <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.asiatoday.co.kr\/view.php?key=20230817010008575\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> by local media outlet Asia Today.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Korea JoongAng Daily reported that North Korea stole $1.28 billion worth of bitcoin and ether through hacks last year alone, citing South Korean intelligence.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Lazarus Group, the North Korean hacking organization, is among the most sought-after suspects in numerous crypto-related hacks. CoinsPaid, an entity linked to crypto payments processor Alphapo, disclosed that it <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/241607\/lazarus-group-suspected-by-coinspaid-of-37-million-hack\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">suffered a $37 million exploit in July<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/coinspaid.com\/tpost\/0zx28tmj51-coinspaid-is-back-to-processing-after-be\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">suspecting<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Lazarus Group as the culprit of the attack.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"South Korea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Yoon Suk Yeol","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"North Korea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Lazarus Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Korea JoongAng Daily","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"North","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"National Intelligence Service","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$37 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Asia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Pyongyang","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"the first half of this year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$180 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$1.28 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Alphapo","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["ASIAN PARLIAMENTS","ASIAN REGULATION","HACKS","SANCTIONS"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}