{"summary":"In November, the UAE-based company said its initial public offering (IPO) was 33-times oversubscribed.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/markets\/2023\/12\/05\/crypto-miner-phoenix-groups-shares-surge-35-in-abu-dhabi-stock-market-debut\/","publishDate":"2023-12-05T15:22:09","id":15290,"type":null,"title":"Crypto Miner Phoenix Group's Shares Surge 35% in Abu Dhabi Stock Market Debut","category":["Markets"],"content":["Shares of cryptocurrency miner Phoenix Group (PHX) rose 35% to 2.03 dirhams ($0.55) on Tuesday, their first day of trading on the Abu Dhabi Securities Exchange (ADX).","The shares, which sold for 1.50 dirhams in the UAE-based company's 1.36 billion-dirham ($368 million) initial public offering (IPO) in November, rose as much as 50% to touch 2.25 dirhams during the day. The share sale was 33-time oversubscribed, it said at the time.","Phoenix Group offers mining through hosting services and a cloud-based service whereby clients rent hashrate. The company also runs a cryptocurrency exchange called M2, powered by its native Ethereum-based token, MMX.","International Holding Company, which is chaired by Tahnoon bin Zayed Al Nahyan, brother of UAE president and Abu Dhabi ruler Mohamed bin Zayed Al Nahyan, acquired a 10% stake in Phoenix Group in early October.","Read More: M2 Crypto Exchange Launches in the UAE","Edited by Sheldon Reback."],"entity":[{"type":"Sheldon Reback","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Phoenix Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1.36 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"10%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Crypto Exchange Launches","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"50%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"35%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Abu Dhabi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$0.55","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Abu Dhabi Securities Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Zayed Al Nahyan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$368 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"October","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tahnoon","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"cryptocurrency miner Phoenix Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UAE","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Mining","Abu Dhabi","UAE","IPO","Public Listing"],"authors":["Jamie Crawley"]}