{"summary":"The latest price moves in crypto markets in context for August 3, 2023.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/markets\/2023\/08\/03\/first-mover-americas-justice-department-may-charge-binance-with-fraud-report\/","publishDate":"2023-08-03T12:31:47","id":15329,"type":null,"title":"First Mover Americas: Justice Department May Charge Binance With Fraud: Report","category":["Markets"],"content":["This article originally appeared in First Mover, CoinDesk’s daily newsletter putting the latest moves in crypto markets in context. Subscribe to get it in your inbox every day.","Crypto exchange Binance could face U.S. Department of Justice fraud charges, though prosecutors are weighing alternatives given the risk of an FTX-style bank run, news site Semafor reported, citing people familiar with the matter. U.S. officials are worried an indictment could imperil the broader cryptocurrency industry, according to Semafor, and so they are weighing alternatives such as \"fines and deferred or non-prosecution agreements,\" sources told the publication. Binance declined to comment. The Justice Department didn't immediately respond to CoinDesk's request for comment. It was already publicly known U.S. officials were scrutinizing Binance. Earlier this year, the Commodity Futures Trading Commission sued the company and founder and CEO Changpeng Zhao for \"willful evasion\" of U.S. laws.","Exchange-traded fund issuer Direxion filed for a bitcoin and ether futures product Wednesday, joining a whole raft of companies that are hoping to launch similar crypto-related trading products in the U.S. According to a filing with the Securities and Exchange Commission, the Direxion Bitcoin Ether Strategy ETF would invest in bitcoin and ether futures contracts. The fund may also include investments in other ETFs that have exposure to futures products. The move comes the same week six other companies filed to launch ether futures ETFs. They join a crowded field of crypto ETF hopefuls as the SEC is reviewing more than half a dozen applications to launch a spot bitcoin ETF.","A legion of Twitter bots pumped the price of crypto tokens traded by Sam Bankman-Fried's quant trading firm Alameda Research shortly after FTX listed the tokens, according to a report from the Network Contagion Research Institute. NCRI, an institution that studies cybersecurity and social-media threats, published a report on Wednesday that shows that \"inauthentic chatter\" on Twitter, now X, heavily influenced the prices of five FTX-listed tokens traded by Alameda insiders. The coins were BOBA, GALA, IMX, RNDR and SPELL. Fake tweets regarding the coins surged — by as much as 30% in some cases — after FTX officially listed them, with \"inauthentic\" comments eventually comprising roughly half of all Twitter posts about the tokens.","- Omkar Godbole","Edited by Mark Nacinovich."],"entity":[{"type":"First Mover","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NCRI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Justice Department","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Omkar Godbole","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Changpeng Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S. Department of Justice","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"30%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Commodity Futures Trading Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Direxion Bitcoin Ether Strategy ETF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Network Contagion Research Institute","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mark Nacinovich","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["First Mover","Markets","Binance","Justice department"],"authors":["Lyllah Ledesma","Omkar Godbole"]}