{"summary":"His Gemini crypto exchange and conglomerate Digital Currency Group are battling — in and out of court — over the failure of Gemini's Earn lending service.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/business\/2023\/08\/11\/good-luck-convincing-a-jury-cameron-winklevoss-rebuts-dcg-court-filing\/","publishDate":"2023-08-11T17:43:38","id":15361,"type":null,"title":"Cameron Winklevoss to DCG Amid Their Crypto Lending Fight: 'Good Luck' Convincing a Jury","category":["Finance"],"content":["The verbal battle between the Winklevoss twins’ Gemini crypto exchange and Digital Currency Group, the crypto conglomerate that had helped power a now-frozen Gemini lending service, continued Friday, a day after DCG sought to dismiss a fraud lawsuit.","On Thursday, DCG argued that Gemini’s fraud accusations over the Gemini Earn service should be tossed out, asserting that DCG had “virtually nothing to do with” the program. In a Friday post on X, the social-media service formerly known as Twitter, Cameron Winklevoss said, “This is a direct admission that they did in fact have something to do with the Gemini Earn program. Lol.”","Read more: Digital Currency Group Files to Dismiss Crypto Exchange Gemini’s Fraud Claims","A DCG unit, Genesis, held funds for Gemini Earn — which turned into a problem for Gemini when Genesis, following the failure of FTX in November, was forced to halt customer withdrawals at its lending arm. DCG also owns CoinDesk.","Winklevoss also cited a line from DCG's Thursday court filing that said DCG \"owed no duty to Gemini to correct the allegedly false misstatements of [Genesis],” its subsidiary.","\"You've got to be kidding me,\" Winklevoss wrote. \"When a company you own says you wrote a $1.1 billion dollar check that you know you didn’t write, yes, you have a duty to correct this. Sorry, but this doesn’t even pass the giggle test.\"","Winklevoss continued: \"Good luck making these arguments to a jury of your peers. See you in court.\"","Asked to comment, a DCG spokesperson said: \"DCG's motion speaks for itself.\"","Edited by Mark Nacinovich.","\n","\n"],"entity":[{"type":"DCG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gemini","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"CoinDesk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Winklevoss twins’ Gemini crypto","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Digital Currency Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$1.1 billion dollar","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Digital Currency Group Files to Dismiss Crypto Exchange Gemini","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cameron Winklevoss","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gemini Earn —","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Winklevoss","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Mark Nacinovich","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Genesis","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["DCG","Digital Currency Group","Gemini","Cameron Winklevoss","Lawsuit"],"authors":["Nick Baker"]}