{"summary":"The money is set to cover the costs associated with having meetings including travel expenses.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/policy\/2024\/02\/19\/virginia-proposes-a-mere-17192-a-year-for-new-blockchain-and-cryptocurrency-commission\/","publishDate":"2024-02-19T09:56:25","id":15390,"type":null,"title":"Virginia Proposes a Mere $17,192 a Year for New Blockchain and Cryptocurrency Commission","category":["Policy"],"content":["Virginia's Subcommittee on General Government proposed allocating a humble $17,192 a year to the Blockchain and Cryptocurrency Commission, according to its report on Sunday.","The U.S. states proposed funds will be allocated both in 2025 and 2026 and are slightly less than what is being set aside for the Artificial Intelligence Commission, which is getting $22,048 a year over the same period. However, the Virginia Autism Advisory Council will receive only $12,090 yearly over the two years.","Virginia recently established the Blockchain and Cryptocurrency Commission in the legislative branch of the state department, according to a 2024 session report. The commission will have 15 members who will study and make recommendations for the blockchain technology that runs cryptocurrencies and the digital assets themselves.","In the session report - the yearly expenditure was estimated to be $17,192, which is meant to cover the costs associated with having meetings, including travel expenses.","Edited by Omkar Godbole.","\n"],"entity":[{"type":"Sunday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2025","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2026","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Virginia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$22,048","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Omkar Godbole","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Blockchain","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Subcommittee on General Government","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Artificial Intelligence Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$17,192","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Virginia Autism Advisory Council","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$12,090","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Cryptocurrency Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Regulations","Virginia","US","Crypto","Blockchain"],"authors":["Camomile Shumba"]}