{"summary":"After registration, 6 cryptocurrencies will be available for deposits including bitcoin, ethereum, XRP, bitcoin cash, litecoin, and tether.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/markets\/2019\/09\/11\/binance-us-plans-to-begin-onboarding-customers-next-week\/","publishDate":"2019-09-11T19:10:04","id":15457,"type":null,"title":"Binance US Plans to Begin Onboarding Customers Next Week","category":["Markets"],"content":["The largest crypto exchange by volume is making its U.S. debut next week.","Binance.US said today that the platform will open registration and deposits on September 18. According to a company blog posting, the launch will initiate a rollout of multiple Binance products across the U.S.","After registration, six cryptocurrencies will be available for deposits including bitcoin, ethereum, XRP, bitcoin cash, litecoin, and tether.","Trading will commence later at an undisclosed date.","Based out of San Francisco, Binance.US was announced earlier this year. Residing officially in Malta, Binance has physical locations in Jersey, Singapore, Hong Kong, and Uganda.","Binance banned U.S. customers earlier this summer following regulatory uncertainty. A partnership with BAM Trading Services was announced just prior to the U.S. suspension.","The new U.S. exchange will not offer services in New York due to the ‘BitLicense’ regulatory requirement. As of August, Binance had not yet applied for the license.","Binance.US did not immediately respond to a request for comment.","Binance CEO Changpeng Zhao at Consensus via CoinDesk archives"],"entity":[{"type":"San Francisco","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"today","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Uganda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Changpeng Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Malta","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"BAM Trading Services","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"September 18","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Jersey","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"summer","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["News","Binance"],"authors":["William Foxley"]}