{"summary":"The house was reportedly bought by nonprofit &#x27;Guarding Against Pandemics&#x27; in April. Home linked to Sam Bankman-Fried goes up for sale for over $3.2 million.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/206831\/dream-home-near-us-capitol-linked-to-sam-bankman-fried-goes-up-for-sale","publishDate":"2023-01-30T14:57:00","id":1546,"type":null,"title":"`Dream home&#x27; near US Capitol linked to Sam Bankman-Fried goes up for sale","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A four-bedroom Victorian brownstone in Washington, D.C. linked to former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried is up for sale for $3.3 million.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The home was bought in April for the same amount by Guarding Against Pandemics, a nonprofit group founded by Bankman-Fried's brother, Gabe, according to news reports. &nbsp;<\/span>","The 2017 home is located at 420 3rd St. NE and described as “an entertainer’s dream home,” It <a href=\"https:\/\/www.zillow.com\/homes\/420-3rd-St-NE-Washington,-DC-20002_rb\/247163873_zpid\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">includes<\/a> four gas fireplaces, an elevator, a built-in wine fridge and a wet\/dry bar. The residence is about a 15-minute walk from the U.S. Capitol.&nbsp;","<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The crypto exchange FTX collapsed in November and filed for bankruptcy protection, with founder Sam Bankman-Fried facing criminal and civil charges involving wire fraud and campaign finance law violations. <\/span>Bankman-Fried has <a href=\"https:\/\/nypost.com\/2022\/11\/30\/sam-bankman-fried-claims-he-only-has-100000-left-in-his-bank-account\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a> he has less than $100,000 in the bank.","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">FTX sister trading firm Alameda Research donated more than $12 million to the pandemic prevention nonprofit, <a href=\"http:\/\/How former crypto king Sam Bankman-Fried and friends quietly donated to political groups and relatives\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">according<\/a> to CNBC. &nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Disclaimer: Beginning in 2021, Michael McCaffrey, the former CEO and majority owner of The Block, took a series of loans from founder and former FTX and Alameda CEO Sam Bankman-Fried. McCaffrey resigned from the company in December 2022 after failing to disclose those transactions.<\/i>&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$3.3 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$12 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Washington","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"CNBC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$100,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Gabe","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"December 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"3rd St. NE","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Michael McCaffrey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"D.C.","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}