{"summary":"Galaxy&#x27;s CEO Mike Novogratz thinks Sam Bankman-Fried is &#x27;delusional&#x27; and will spend time in jail.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/191360\/sbf-was-delusional-in-interview-says-galaxys-mike-novogratz","publishDate":"2022-12-01T10:37:29","id":1560,"type":null,"title":"SBF was &#x27;delusional&#x27; in interview, says Galaxy&#x27;s Mike Novogratz","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["Galaxy's CEO Mike Novogratz thinks Sam Bankman-Fried is \"delusional\" and will spend time in jail.","After watching the former FTX CEO's live <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/191180\/sam-bankman-frieds-bizarre-apology-tour-goes-prime-time\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">interview<\/a> with the New York Times on Wednesday, Novogratz alleged that Bankman-Fried is \"just spewing more lies.\"","\"It was delusional, let's be really clear,\" Novogratz <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/SquawkCNBC\/status\/1598306172792078337\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">told<\/a> Andrew Ross Sorkin on CNBC. \"Sam is delusional about what happened and his culpability in it.\"","Novogratz said that the ramifications of the FTX collapse would spread beyond crypto to all markets in general. He also said he didn't think that Bankman-Fried had acted alone.&nbsp; &nbsp;","\"You don't pull this off with one person,\" he said. \"I'm not saying he even planned this all like a criminal mastermind. What they did was criminal and they need to be prosecuted for it.\"","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"New York Times","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"CNBC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Novogratz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sam","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Mike Novogratz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Andrew Ross Sorkin","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Catarina Moura","The Block"]}