{"summary":"The transition is aimed at reducing barriers of entry for The Graph’s users by decreasing gas costs and speeding up transactions.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/tech\/2023\/06\/14\/the-graph-starts-migrating-its-settlement-layer-to-arbitrum-from-ethereum\/","publishDate":"2023-06-14T16:00:00","id":15703,"type":null,"title":"The Graph Migrates its Settlement Layer to Arbitrum from Ethereum","category":["Technology"],"content":["The Graph – a decentralized protocol for indexing and querying blockchain data – began on Wednesday the final phase of its migration from Ethereum to the layer 2 scaling solution Arbitrum.","With the migration, The Graph becomes one of the largest Ethereum apps to transition to a layer 2 rollup – a move that one of The Graph developers Edge & Node say will decrease barriers of entry for The Graph’s participants without compromising on security.","The Graph, through its web of “delegators” and “indexers,” allows web3 developers to view blockchain data without trusting centralized intermediaries for the data’s accuracy. Launched initially on Ethereum, its move to layer 2 platform Arbitrum is an effort to decrease gas costs and increase transaction speeds, according to Edge & Node CEO Tegan Kline.","Arbitrum, like other Ethereum layer 2 networks, operates as a separate blockchain that runs alongside Ethereum. To reduce fees for users without losing all of Ethereum’s security guarantees, Arbitrum bundles up large groups of transactions and then passes them back down to Ethereum for all-at-once settlement.","The Graph’s migration involves transferring its “settlement layer” from one network to another – rather than recording and settling activity directly on Ethereum, The Graph will now settle transactions on Arbitrum.","Every time a user performs a transaction on The Graph like delegating and indexing, there is a cost to it. “With this transfer to Artbitrum, those costs are lower. So we expect that there will likely be more indexers that spin up on the network [and] more delegators that get involved because that barrier to entry is lower, the cost isn’t so high,” Kline told CoinDesk.","GRT and ARB, the native tokens for The Graph and Arbitrum, have both remained stable in the past 24 hours amid The Graph’s transition to Arbitrum. GRT has ranged between as high as 9.9 cents and as low as 9.7 cents, while ARB has oscillated between 97 cents and $1.01, per CoinDesk data.","The Graph enables developers to query data from 40 networks and raised $50 million in a 2022 funding round, which saw participation from Tiger Global, Blockwall Digital, Fenbushi Capital, FinTech Collective and Reciprocal Ventures.","Edited by Sam Kessler.","CORRECTION (June 14, 2023, 18:23 UTC): Specifies in the piece's first sentence that the final stage of The Graph's migration started Wednesday. The original article stated that the migration itself started on Wednesday.","CORRECTION (June 15, 2023 15:32 UTC): Corrects the price for GRT on Wednesday."],"entity":[{"type":"June 14, 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Artbitrum","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"9.7 cents","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Tiger Global","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kline","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"June 15, 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"9.9 cents","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Reciprocal Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CoinDesk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"97 cents","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"The Graph developers Edge & Node","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FinTech Collective","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fenbushi Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1.01","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tegan Kline","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Blockwall Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Graph","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Edge & Node","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$50 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Sam Kessler","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["The Graph","Arbitrum","Settlement","Ethereum","Data"],"authors":["Sage D. Young"]}