{"summary":"Pudgy Penguins will use capital infusion to help expand brand reach and sell merchandise.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/229943\/pudgy-penguins-secures-9-million","publishDate":"2023-05-09T10:38:11","id":1571,"type":null,"title":"Pudgy Penguins secures $9 million months after CEO denied raising funds","category":["METAVERSE & NFT"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Roughly six months after Pudgy Penguins CEO denied the NFT collection was seeking to raise <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">up to $10 million, it has announced securing <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$9 million in the completion of its seed round.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The round was led by 1kx, “an early-stage investment firm that specializes in ecosystem growth,” the collection said in a statement.&nbsp; Big Brain Holdings, Kronos Research, the founders of LayerZero Labs, Old Fashion Research, and CRIT Ventures also participated, according to the statement.<\/span>","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/182494\/pudgy-penguins-seeks-10-million-seed-round\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Last November<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Pudgy Penguins CEO Luca Netz said The Block’s story that his collection sought to raise up to $10 million was “all wrong information,” and warned he would publicly brand any story on the subject “fake news.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The collection launched in 2021 and Netz acquired it the next year. Last week, it <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/pudgypenguins\/status\/1654569304145240065\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said Hollywood talent agency WME<\/a> will represent the collection as it pursues \"relationships in film, TV, and gaming.\"<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In its funding statement, Pudgy Penguins said it would use the fresh capital to help monetize its brand's intellectual property through, in part, merchandising.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Big Brain Holdings","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"LayerZero Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Luca Netz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$9 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Kronos Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CRIT Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Pudgy Penguins","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Pudgy Penguins CEO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Old Fashion Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$10 million","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}