{"summary":"The Paris-based firm is betting on the growth of staking services after Ethereum's Merge.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/business\/2022\/11\/28\/ethereum-staking-as-a-service-startup-kiln-raises-176m\/","publishDate":"2022-11-28T11:33:59","id":15777,"type":null,"title":"Ethereum Staking-as-a-Service Startup Kiln Raises $17.6M","category":["Finance"],"content":["Kiln, a startup that allows customers to receive rewards for helping secure the Ethereum blockchain, raised 17 million euros ($17.6 million) in a Series A funding round from a group of investors that included crypto incubator Consensys, investment firm GSR and crypto exchange Kraken's venture-capital arm.","The Paris-based company plans to use the funds to expand its staking-as-a-service offerings, according to a press release Monday.","Staking involves locking up a cryptocurrency for a period of time on a proof-of-stake blockchain such as Ethereum and receiving a share of the proceeds that come from verifying transactions. The world's second-largest cryptocurrency changed its consensus algorithm to proof-of-stake from proof-of-work in September, and staking services are expected to boom.","\"Staking is going to be one of the core fabrics of the entire crypto industry,\" Ciaran O'Leary, co-founder and general partner of BlueYard Capital, which invested in Kiln for the second time, said in the press release.","Staking-as-a-service products make it easy for custodians, exchanges, wallets and treasury managers to commit their digital assets to the blockchain. Kiln had $500 million of staked assets under management as of Nov. 23.","LeadblockPartners, Sparkle Ventures and XBTO also participated in the round, along with existing investors 3KVC, SV Angel and Alven.","Read more: Crypto Staking 101: What Is Staking?","CORRECTION (Nov. 28, 14:14 UTC): Corrects investor name to GSR in first paragraph. An earlier version of this story said the investor was GSR Ventures."],"entity":[{"type":"SV Angel","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nov. 28","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alven","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"GSR","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ciaran O'Leary","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Paris","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"UTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$17.6 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Kraken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$500 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"17 million euros","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sparkle Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"GSR Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nov. 23","content":"DATE"},{"type":"BlueYard Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Fundraising","Staking","Proof-of-Stake","Proof-of-Work"],"authors":["Eliza Gkritsi"]}