{"summary":"Anthony Grabiner alleged that some of COPA's fraud claims had no exact proof.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/policy\/2024\/03\/13\/craig-wrights-counsel-hits-back-at-copas-fraud-allegations-in-closing-argument\/","publishDate":"2024-03-13T17:16:51","id":15781,"type":null,"title":"Craig Wright's Counsel Hits Back at COPA's Fraud Allegations in Closing Argument","category":["Policy"],"content":["Craig Wright's team started its closing submissions on Wednesday by rebutting the Crypto Open Patent Alliance's fraud allegations against Wright in a trial that is set to find out whether or not Wright is Satoshi Nakamoto, the creator of Bitcoin.","Anthony Grabiner, Wright's attorney, hit back at COPA's argument that private signing sessions Wright hosted to prove he was the Bitcoin founder had been subverted, saying that no proof had been presented.","He also argued that COPA's witness Patrick Madden's evidence was inadmissible due to his ties with COPA. Madden had testified that many of Wright's reliance documents had been altered \"often with the apparent purpose of supporting his claims,\" a court document seen by CoinDesk showed.","Grabiner later added that in Wright's defense, he had not said that his reliance documents had never been edited.","COPA's counsel said in his closing statements on Tuesday that the evidence shared during the trial shows “beyond doubt” that Wright isn’t Satoshi. COPA's representatives also said they plan to ask U.K. prosecutors to consider if the computer scientist perjured himself during the trial.","The results of the case could have repercussions on other existing trials against crypto exchanges and developers.","Wright's counsel will continue giving their closing statement on Thursday.","Read more: COPA vs Wright: What's at Stake as the Trial to Determine Satoshi's Identity Wraps Up","Edited by Nikhilesh De."],"entity":[{"type":"Crypto Open Patent Alliance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Craig Wright","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Satoshi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Patrick Madden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.K.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Nikhilesh De","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Madden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Satoshi Nakamoto","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Wright","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Anthony Grabiner","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"COPA","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Regulations","Craig Wright","Bitcoin"],"authors":["Camomile Shumba"]}