{"summary":"Three U.S. senators have asked Fidelity Investments&#x27; CEO to reconsider allowing retirement plan holders to have bitcoin exposure.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/188869\/three-u-s-senators-ask-fidelity-to-reconsider-bitcoin-exposure-in-retirement-plans","publishDate":"2022-11-21T17:12:31","id":1578,"type":null,"title":"Three U.S. senators ask Fidelity to reconsider bitcoin exposure in retirement plans","category":["FINANCE FIRMS"],"content":["Three U.S. senators have again asked Fidelity Investments to reconsider a decision to allow retirement plan participants to invest in bitcoin, saying the industry has become increasingly \"volatile, tumultuous and chaotic.\"","Sens. Richard Durbin, D-Ill., Elizabeth Warren, D-Mass. and Tina Smith, D-Minn., sent the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.durbin.senate.gov\/imo\/media\/doc\/letter_to_fidelity_investments_ceo.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Nov. 21 letter<\/a> to Fidelity Investments CEO Abigail Johnson after first raising the issue in July. Durbin is the number-two Democrat in the Senate as Majority Whip, while Smith and Warren are on the Banking Committee.&nbsp;","\"Fidelity Investments has opted to expand beyond traditional finance and delve into the highly unstable and increasingly risky digital asset market,\" the senators wrote. \"The recent implosion of FTX, a cryptocurrency exchange, has made it abundantly clear the digital asset industry has serious problems. The industry is full of charismatic wunderkinds, opportunistic fraudsters and self-proclaimed investment advisers promoting financial products with little to no transparency.\"","Fidelity <a href=\"https:\/\/www.wsj.com\/articles\/fidelity-to-allow-retirement-savers-to-put-bitcoin-in-401-k-accounts-11650945661\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a> in April that it was readying a plan that would allow 401(k) plan holders to&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/143498\/fidelity-to-allow-clients-to-invest-in-bitcoin-through-their-401k-accounts\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">allocate<\/a> up to 20% of their retirement savings into bitcoin. In the July letter, the senators <a href=\"https:\/\/www.durbin.senate.gov\/imo\/media\/doc\/durbin_bitcoin_72622.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">argued<\/a> that the cap signaled that it was aware of the dangers of investing in the cryptocurrency.&nbsp;","Fidelity has been prioritizing growth of digital assets services across the company. Its Fidelity Digital Assets subsidiary recently added <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/178462\/fidelity-digital-assets-will-begin-offering-eth-to-institutions-later-this-month\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ether trading<\/a> for institutional customers and is planning to launch a new retail trading <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/182635\/fidelity-turns-its-attention-to-retail-investors-with-new-crypto-offering\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">platform<\/a> called Fidelity Crypto.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Mass.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Richard Durbin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Warren","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Banking Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Abigail Johnson","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Fidelity","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"20%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Fidelity Investments","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ill.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Smith","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fidelity Crypto","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tina Smith","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Minn.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Fidelity Digital Assets","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nov. 21","content":"DATE"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Elizabeth Warren","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Senate","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["ELIZABETH WARREN","SENATE BANKING COMMITTEE","SENATE FINANCE COMMITTEE","TRADFI BANKS"],"authors":["Kristin Majcher","The Block"]}