{"summary":"SWIFT payments and SEPA IBANs will be supported – allowing users to transact and transfer money globally.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/business\/2024\/03\/22\/floki-developers-plan-regulated-bank-accounts-in-next-value-capture-for-tokens\/","publishDate":"2024-03-22T13:13:54","id":15793,"type":null,"title":"Floki Developers Plan Regulated Bank Accounts in Next Value Capture for Tokens","category":["Finance"],"content":["Floki developers are planning to offer users a regulated digital banking account they can fund using (FLOKI) tokens that transact in dollars, euros and sterling, lead developer B told CoinDesk.","The development is part of a broader plan to release debit cards and staking services propelling the dog-themed meme coin to a serious project that offers users a crypto-based financial application.","“We will introduce Floki-powered Bank Accounts in partnership with a fintech company,” B wrote in a Telegram message. “These accounts will be facilitated through a key partner licensed in four key jurisdictions: Canada, Spain, Dominica, Australia, and the UAE.”","Users will be able to create digital bank accounts and generate debit cards linked to these accounts, B said. Payments over the SWIFT international banking network and SEPA IBANs will be supported – allowing users to transact and transfer money globally.","The debit card will be offered on both the VISA and Mastercard payment networks. The cards will be issued in partnership with a Switzerland-based company that is regulated under the Swiss Financial Market Supervisory Authority (FINMA), the country's top watchdog.","FLOKI tokens are down 6.7% in the past 24 hours, data shows, faster than the broader market drop. The CoinDesk 20 Index has dropped 3.5%.","Floki, fashioned after the popular Shiba Inu dog breed that has spurred popular tokens including dogecoin (DOGE) and shiba inu (SHIB) , started as a meme coin project and has tried to shift its image in the past years with a focus on projects spanning from gaming applications to artificial intelligence.","Edited by Sheldon Reback."],"entity":[{"type":"Sheldon Reback","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Canada","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"6.7%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Mastercard","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Switzerland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"3.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"CoinDesk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Australia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Spain","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Dominica","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Shiba Inu","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Floki","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Swiss Financial Market Supervisory Authority","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UAE","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Floki","meme","banking","TradFi","Exclusive"],"authors":["Shaurya Malwa"]}