{"summary":"The approval of spot bitcoin ETFs in the U.S. in January led to a pickup in interest from Goldman's existing clients, the report says.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/markets\/2024\/03\/25\/goldman-seeing-resurgence-of-interest-for-crypto-options-from-hedge-fund-clients-bloomberg\/","publishDate":"2024-03-25T15:23:02","id":15805,"type":null,"title":"Goldman Seeing 'Resurgence of Interest' for Crypto Options From Hedge Fund Clients: Bloomberg","category":["Markets"],"content":["Hedge fund clients of U.S. banking giant Goldman Sachs (GS) have become more active in crypto options trading this year, Bloomberg reported on Monday.","After a quieter 2023, the approval of spot bitcoin exchange-traded funds (ETFs) in the U.S. in January has triggered a \"resurgence of interest\" from Goldman clients, Max Minton, Asia Pacific head of digital assets, said in an interview with Bloomberg.","\"We’ve seen a pickup in interest from clients in onboarding, pipeline, and volume since the start of the year,” Minton said.","Demand is driven by existing clients, mainly hedge funds, but Goldman is expanding into asset managers, bank clients and certain digital asset firms, Minton added.","Goldman offers cash-settled bitcoin (BTC) and ether (ETH) option trading and CME-listed BTC and ETH futures.","Goldman Sachs did not immediately respond to CoinDesk's request for further comment.","Read More: Goldman Sachs, BNY Mellon and Others Test Enterprise Blockchain for Tokenized Assets","Edited by Aoyon Ashraf.","\n","\n","\n","\n"],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Goldman Sachs (GS","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Aoyon Ashraf","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Goldman","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Goldman Sachs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Minton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BNY Mellon and Others Test Enterprise Blockchain","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Max Minton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Asia Pacific","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["Goldman Sachs","Hedge Fund","Options","Futures"],"authors":["Jamie Crawley"]}