{"summary":"China’s announcement preceded choppy price moves around $34,000, which left traders with little sense of direction.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/markets\/2021\/07\/06\/market-wrap-bitcoin-consolidates-amid-china-crackdown\/","publishDate":"2021-07-06T20:39:48","id":15908,"type":null,"title":"Market Wrap: Bitcoin Consolidates Amid China Crackdown","category":["Markets"],"content":["","Bitcoin traded sideways on Tuesday as market participants digested the latest regulatory crackdown from China. On Monday, the People’s Bank of China (PBOC) reiterated its long-held anti-crypto stance, warning institutions against providing services to crypto-related companies. ","","","China’s announcement preceded choppy price moves around $34,000, which left traders with little sense of direction. Bitcoin trading remains in a tight range and the price is down about 6% over the past week.","","","Cryptocurrencies:","","","Traditional markets:","","","“Our strategists continue to expect a 6%-10% correction in U.S. equities this summer given that growth indicators are peaking, as well as a further sell-off in U.S. Treasurys that will see 10-year yields hit 2.25% by year end,” according to a Deutsche Bank report published on Tuesday.","","","For now, risky assets are still supported by accomodative monetary policy. For example, last week, European Central Bank (ECB) executive board member Isabel Schnabel pledged to do whatever it takes to support an economic recovery, according to a Bloomberg report. Schnabel also warned governments not to end fiscal stimulus too early. ","","","Read more: Leveraged Funds on CME Trim Bets Against Bitcoin","","","“Retail investors are increasingly confident in the potential of crypto assets, despite this quarter’s market correction, with new eToro data revealing increases in the numbers of crypto assets being held during the last quarter,” wrote eToro, a multi-asset investment platform, in an email to CoinDesk.","","","Bitcoin trading activity dropped significantly over the past week as the price remains stuck in a range between $30,000 and $40,000. The seven-day average of BTC daily price volume reached the lowest level since December 2020, according to a Tuesday report by Arcane Research.","","","“The 4th of July celebration could partly explain the slow weekend, but the appetite for trading bitcoin is certainly not very high in this range-bound environment,” Arcane wrote.","","","Slowing volume also reflects indecision between buyers and sellers. Bitcoin faces strong resistance from the intermediate-term downtrend since April. The current range can be difficult to navigate, placing some traders on the sidelines until a decisive breakout or breakdown is confirmed. ","","","“We expect intermediate-term oversold conditions to give way to a relief rally and would expect buyers to step in above the 50-day moving average around $36,000,” wrote Katie Stockton, managing director of Fairlead Strategies, in a newsletter published on Monday.","","","A breakout above the 50-day moving average would yield an upside target towards $44,000-$45,000 resistance, according to Stockton.  ","","","Digital-asset investment funds attracted net capital inflows in the week ending Friday, July 2, after four consecutive weeks of redemptions, according to CoinShares. Inflows totaled $63 million last week, of which nearly 62%, or $39 million, went into bitcoin-dedicated funds.","","","Active bitcoin miners may see their profitability doubled following the 28% downward difficulty adjustment in bitcoin mining on July 3, according to several mining sites.","","","Read more: 3 Crypto Chart Patterns to Help Make Sense of the Market","","","As more than 50% of miners went offline after China started cracking down on crypto mining, bitcoin’s hashrate dropped at one point to 84.3 EH\/s, the lowest since September 2019. In response to a prolonged time for miners to find a new block, bitcoin’s code was automatically adjusted, making it easier for miners to solve the computational puzzles.","","","“It's become both easier and more profitable to mine bitcoin,” said Nick Spanos, one of the earliest bitcoin exchange operators. “That’s a recipe for enticing more miners back in.”","","","Notable winners as of 21:00 UTC (4:00 p.m. ET): ","","","yearn finance (YFI) +14.41%","","","uniswap (UNI) +11.2%","","","aave (AAVE) +9.86%","","","Notable losers: ","","","the graph (GRT) -2.81%","","","cardano (ADA) -0.9%","","","litecoin (LTC) -0.84%",""],"entity":[{"type":"10%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"European Central Bank (ECB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"50%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Friday, July 2","content":"DATE"},{"type":"62%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"September 2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$34,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Fairlead Strategies","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Schnabel","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Stockton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"last quarter","content":"DATE"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Katie Stockton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$39 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Crypto Chart Patterns","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$30,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"CME Trim Bets Against Bitcoin","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Isabel Schnabel","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$45,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"-0.84%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$44,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"4:00 p.m.","content":"TIME"},{"type":"summer","content":"DATE"},{"type":"LTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"6%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"+14.41%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2.25%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"weekend","content":"DATE"},{"type":"-0.9%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"July 3","content":"DATE"},{"type":"People’s Bank of China (PBOC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Deutsche Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"+9.86%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"+11.2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$63 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Nick Spanos","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"UTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Arcane Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CoinDesk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"December 2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"28%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$36,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"-2.81%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"ADA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$40,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"China","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["Bitcoin Mining","European Central Bank","Bitcoin","Altcoins","Bitcoin Price","Technical Analysis","cryptocurrencies","Stablecoins","CoinShares","Digital Assets Data","Market Wrap","Pancakeswap","bitcoin volume"],"authors":["Damanick Dantes","Frances Yue"]}