{"summary":"A major defense spending bill passed by the US Senate yesterday calls for a blockchain study, public records show.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/markets\/2017\/09\/19\/700-billion-senate-defense-bill-calls-for-blockchain-cybersecurity-study\/","publishDate":"2017-09-19T19:00:21","id":15912,"type":null,"title":"$700 Billion Senate Defense Bill Calls for Blockchain Cybersecurity Study","category":["Markets"],"content":["A $700 billion defense bill passed by the US Senate includes a mandate for a blockchain study to be conducted by the Department of Defense.","Yesterday, the US Senate passed a massive defense spending package that provides hundreds of billions of dollars to the US military. Public records show that an amendment included in that bill, proposed by Senator Rob Portman of Ohio, would \"require a report on cyber applications of blockchain technology\" if signed into law.","According to the official Congressional website, the amendment was agreed to by unanimous consent ahead of the defense bill's final vote.","The research effort, according to the amendment's text is described as:","The study, additional materials indicate, is expected to be delivered six months after the defense bill is signed into law.","But more steps remain before the study's mandate becomes law, however. The House of Representatives – the lower chamber of the US Congress – passed a similar bill in July, and now the two bodies have to hammer out a reconciled version and pass it.","Image via Shutterstock"],"entity":[{"type":"House of Representatives","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$700 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"US Congress","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"hundreds of billions of dollars","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ohio","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"US Senate","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Shutterstock","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Department of Defense","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Rob Portman","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["Security","Congress","News","Legislation","Senate","Legal","us-canada"],"authors":["Stan Higgins"]}