{"summary":"The CoinDesk 20 index, which tracks major tokens minus stablecoins, slumped just over 4.5%.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/markets\/2024\/04\/02\/crypto-bulls-see-400m-liquidations-as-solana-dogecoin-lead-slide-in-majors\/","publishDate":"2024-04-02T07:27:29","id":16053,"type":null,"title":"Crypto Bulls See $400M Liquidations as Solana, Dogecoin Lead Slide in Majors","category":["Markets"],"content":["Major tokens slid as much as 8% in the past 24 hours as bitcoin (BTC) reversed last week’s gains amid selling pressure caused by a stronger dollar, leading to over $400 million bullish bets being liquidated.","Data shows that bitcoin fell 5%, with ether (ETH), Cardano’s ADA, and BNB Chain’s BNB showing similar losses. Solana’s SOL dropped 7% to trade at $185 after briefly touching $200 on Monday, while Dogecoin (DOGE) dropped more than 8%. Bitcoin Cash’s BCH fell 10% amid profit-taking after a 40% rally in the past week, buoyed by the expected halving event for the network on April 4.","The broad-based CoinDesk 20, a liquid index tracking major tokens minus stablecoins, slumped just over 5%.","Longs, or bets on higher prices, took on more than $400 million in liquidations, with shorts, or bets against, taking on a relatively smaller $85 million. A liquidation happens when a trader has insufficient funds to keep a leveraged trade open.","Analysts at crypto exchange Bitfinex told CoinDesk in an email that some long-term investors sold off holdings in the past week, adding they expect bitcoin to be range-bound in the coming weeks.","“We believe that bitcoin is likely to continue to consolidate within a range, as previously dormant supply, particularly among Long-Term Holders (LTHs), is being sold (although at a relatively smaller scale than previous bull market tops),” Bitfinex said.","“There is strategic profit-taking observed among the LTH cohort (holders of BTC of more than 155 days),” the analysts added.","Elsewhere, FxPro senior market analyst Alex Kuptsikevich said in a message that bitcoin faces resistance at the $71,000 level as broader markets show caution against riskier assets.","“Bitcoin's fourth attempt to consolidate above $71K this week was unsuccessful. The Nasdaq100 also showed some downward bias, indicating a cautious attitude towards risky assets, although the S&P500 closed at another high,” Kuptsikevich said. “Bitcoin has thus found strong resistance, and the $69.5K and $68.5K levels attract our increased attention.”","Edited by Parikshit Mishra."],"entity":[{"type":"BCH","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"8%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$71,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"10%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$85 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"40%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alex Kuptsikevich","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$400 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$71K","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$200","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$185","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"7%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Kuptsikevich","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Cardano’s ADA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April 4","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bitfinex","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"crypto exchange Bitfinex","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CoinDesk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Parikshit Mishra","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"S&P","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$69.5","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$68.5","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["Bitcoin","Trading","Markets"],"authors":["Shaurya Malwa"]}