{"summary":"The Square Crypto team announced three more developer hires on Thursday, pulling from major companies in the crypto space.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/tech\/2019\/09\/19\/square-crypto-hires-lightning-libra-developers-for-bitcoin-dream-team\/","publishDate":"2019-09-19T17:17:04","id":16188,"type":null,"title":"Square Crypto Hires Lightning, Libra Developers for 'Bitcoin Dream Team'","category":["Tech"],"content":["Square Crypto, the division of the publicly traded payments company that focuses exclusively on bitcoin, just announced three new hires to work on open source projects.","Among them is Facebook and BitGo alum Arik Sosman, most recently a member of the social media giant's Calibra subsidiary. He told CoinDesk:","The other two notable hires, Lightning Labs alum Valentine Wallace and Google alum Jeffrey Czyz, are joining to help “grow the FOSS [free and open software] developer base,” according to company tweets.","Square Crypto is still hiring as well, looking for a designer to join the team led by former Google product director Steve Lee.","“Software engineering is far from the only realm people can make contributions to open-source projects in,” Sosman said. “Steve himself being a product manager is but one example.”","According to another company tweet Thursday, Square Crypto is still “deciding what our first project will be,” adding:","Jack Dorsey image via CoinDesk archives"],"entity":[{"type":"Arik Sosman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sosman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Square Crypto","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Valentine Wallace","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Calibra","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jeffrey Czyz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Steve Lee","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Steve","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jack Dorsey","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["Google","startups","Facebook","Bitcoin","Lightning Labs","Square Crypto"],"authors":["Leigh Cuen"]}