{"summary":"Digital-asset investment products saw outflows totaling $9 million as trading volume fell to the second lowest this year.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/markets\/2022\/08\/22\/crypto-funds-see-minor-outflows-amid-trading-volume-dip-coinshares\/","publishDate":"2022-08-22T16:31:15","id":16259,"type":null,"title":"Crypto Funds See Minor Outflows Amid Trading Volume Dip: CoinShares","category":["Markets"],"content":["Crypto funds saw minor outflows totaling $9 million in the seven days up to Aug. 19, as trading volume dropped to $1 billion, the second lowest this year, according to a CoinShares report.","Bitcoin (BTC) investment products saw a third straight week of outflows totaling $15 million. The largest cryptocurrency by market capitalization plunged 10% on Aug. 19 after the U.S. Federal Reserve’s meeting minutes hinted at further interest rate hikes.","Ether (ETH) funds saw inflows totaling $2.9 million. Investor optimism strengthened as the network’s switch from proof-of-work to proof-of-stake, dubbed the Merge, draws closer.","Other altcoin funds saw mixed movement with outflows totaling $1.4 million for SOL and inflows totaled $500,000 for ADA and $300,000 for XRP.","Regionally, outflows were concentrated in the U.S., totaling $10 million. Minor outflows totaled $2.4 million for Germany and $2.1 million for Sweden. Inflows totaled $2.5 million for Brazil and $1.9 million for Switzerland."],"entity":[{"type":"$2.4 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sweden","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Switzerland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$1 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"SOL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$2.5 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"10%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Brazil","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$2.1 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$500,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$2.9 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$9 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$1.9 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$15 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Germany","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$300,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Aug. 19","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$1.4 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"ADA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$10 million","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["CoinShares","Reports","Fund flows","Investing"],"authors":["Jimmy He"]}