{"summary":"BTC could run towards $40,000-$45,000 after consolidating around current prices, Capriole Investments said.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/markets\/2023\/10\/25\/bitcoin-retreats-from-35k-miner-selling-pressure-may-cap-prices-crypto-hedge-fund-says\/","publishDate":"2023-10-25T17:42:16","id":16294,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin Retreats From $35K; Miner Selling Pressure May Cap Prices, Crypto Hedge Fund Says","category":["Markets"],"content":["Bitcoin (BTC) briefly topped $35,000 Wednesday for the second time this week, but prices quickly reversed as that level appeared to trigger numerous sell orders, perhaps from miners, suggested one hedge fund manager.","The $35,000 area represents a monthly resistance level for the price, and could mean that bitcoin will consolidate below for some time following the crypto’s big run higher, said Charles Edwards, founder of Bitcoin-focused hedge fund Capriole Investments.","\"Bitcoin miners are selling off more of their treasury than usual today; this can be a warning sign for consolidation,\" said Edwards. He noted an uptick in Capriole's Bitcoin Miner Sell Pressure, which indicates that BTC miners are selling a bigger part of their revenues than on average.","Read more: Bitcoin Mining Stocks Rally as BTC Holds Above $30K Despite Looming Halving Concerns","Despite the short-term consolidation, Edwards suggests bitcoin could target the $40,000-$45,000 range in the coming weeks as the sell pressure subsides.","\"While price may temporarily stall here at monthly resistance, the next significant trouble area is low- to mid-$40Ks,\" he said. \"We expect bitcoin will take us there in short order given the data on hand.\"","The largest crypto by market capitalization also topped at around $35,000 on Monday, hitting a 17-month high as anticipation for a spot bitcoin exchange-traded fund – coupled with some other catalysts – hit a fever pitch. Despite stories about imminent approval for a spot ETF turning out to be mistaken, bitcoin has retreated only modestly from that level.","While bitcoin pulled back nearly 2% following the run to $35,000, it remains higher by 1.6% over the past 24 hours. That’s a sizable outperformance over U.S. stocks, where the Nasdaq is lower by 2.4% and the S&P 500 by 1.4% early Wednesday afternoon.","The renewed tumble in stocks came alongside a sharp 13 basis point rise in the 10-year Treasury yield to 4.95%. Also on investor minds were poor Q3 earnings results from Google (down 9% today) and rising geopolitical worries.","Earlier Wednesday, Turkish President Tayyip Erdogan said Hamas was not a terrorist organization and canceled a planned trip to Israel. Shares in Istanbul closed 7% lower.","Edited by Stephen Alpher."],"entity":[{"type":"Charles Edwards","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Bitcoin Miner Sell Pressure","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1.6%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"1.4%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Hamas","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Capriole Investments","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Israel","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"4.95%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"afternoon","content":"TIME"},{"type":"7%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$35,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Stephen Alpher","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"9%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2.4%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Tayyip Erdogan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Edwards","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bitcoin Mining Stocks Rally as BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"S&P","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$45,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Capriole","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Istanbul","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$40,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$30K","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$40Ks","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Nasdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Markets","Bitcoin","btc price","Capriole Investments","Bitcoin Miners","Market Wrap"],"authors":["Krisztian Sandor"]}