{"summary":"The Block&#x27;s Frank Chaparro chatted crypto industry IPOs and the paths different companies could take with Voyager CEO Steve Ehrlich.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/73605\/voyager-crypto-ipos-podcast","publishDate":"2020-07-31T16:03:18","id":1666,"type":null,"title":"A retail brokerage veteran breaks down why crypto IPOs are good for bitcoin","category":["PODCASTS"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 30 of Season 2 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block’s Frank Chaparro and Voyager CEO Steve Ehrlich.<\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"3d4d52595e5c4e497d4955585f51525e565e4f444d4952135e5250\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode of The Scoop is brought to you by Bitstamp, the original global cryptocurrency exchange. Since 2011, Bitstamp has been a cornerstone of the industry, earning the trust of over four million individuals and top financial institutions looking for a reliable trading venue. <\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Whether you’re trading on our web platform, mobile app or industry-leading APIs, Bitstamp gives you the professional-grade tools you need to execute your strategy.&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/bitstamp.net\/app?r=pro%E2%80%93&amp;utm_source=Website&amp;utm_medium=podcast&amp;utm_campaign=theblock&amp;utm_content=ctaapp\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Download the Bitstamp app<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or visit&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.bitstamp.net\/pro\/?utm_source=Website&amp;utm_medium=podcast&amp;utm_campaign=theblock&amp;utm_content=ctaweb\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitstamp.net\/Pro<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;to learn more and start trading today!<\/i>","&nbsp;","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" scrolling=\"no\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK6539844957\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Voyager CEO Steve Ehrlich took his crypto brokerage firm public in February of last year in a somewhat unorthodox fashion. Now, Ehrlich says he's taking a lot of phone calls from crypto firms looking to do the same.","During this week's episode of The Scoop, Ehrlich broke down what he shares on those calls.&nbsp;Voyager conducted its initial public offering (IPO) through a reverse merger, listing on the Canadian Securities Exchange and trading in over-the-counter (OTC) markets. While an IPO calls for extensive regulatory filings and investment bank backing, a reverse merger sees private company investors acquire shares of a public but inactive corporation. In Voyager's case, it acquired the shell company UC Resources Ltd., which was publicly listed on the Canadian TSX Venture Exchange.","Voyager was an early addition to the IPO party, though Mike Novogratz's Galaxy Digital had already gone public on TSX in August 2018. Now, there's growing interest in crypto IPOs, with rumblings of Coinbase and BlockFi looking to take the plunge. While crypto touts transparency, IPOs put a firm's inner workings on display, opening the door for merger and acquisition activity, according to Ehrlich.","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/b><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"<\/em>You go public and it's right there in front of everybody: what you're worth, what your stock's worth, the financials of the company, the metrics of your company. It's there and it's a currency now to go make acquisitions,\" he said.","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/b>Ehrlich discussed the different approaches to crypto IPOs and which firms are right for which routes on This Week's episode. He also discussed:","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen to this week's episode on Apple, Spotify, Google Play, Stitcher or wherever you listen to podcasts.<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"IPO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Galaxy Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2011","content":"DATE"},{"type":"February of last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ehrlich","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UC Resources Ltd.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"TSX Venture Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitstamp","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Canadian Securities Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mike Novogratz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Steve Ehrlich","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"TSX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"August 2018","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Aislinn Keely","The Block"]}