{"summary":"A UN Security Council panel is investigating 17 crypto heists in 2023, for which North Korea may have been responsible, which were valued at more than $750 million","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/policy\/2024\/03\/21\/north-korean-crypto-hackers-have-stolen-3b-since-2017-says-un-security-council-report\/","publishDate":"2024-03-21T11:30:26","id":16699,"type":null,"title":"North Korean Crypto Hackers Have Stolen $3B Since 2017, Says UN Security Council: Report","category":["Policy"],"content":["North Korea-linked cryptocurrency hacks totaled $3 billion between 2017 and 2023, South Korean news agency Yonhap reported on Thursday, citing a United Nations (UN) Security Council study.","A UN Security Council panel is investigating 17 crypto heists in 2023, for which North Korea may have been responsible, which were valued at more than $750 million, the report added.","There were a total of 58 suspected cyberattacks on crypto-linked firms between 2017 and 2023, according to the report. The report said that North Korea derives around 50% of its foreign currency income from cyber attacks, which is used to fund its weapons programs.","North Korea has been targeting the crypto industry as a means of evading sanctions, the report said, branding the country “the world's most prolific cyber-thief.”","In December, cybersecurity firm Recorded Future also calculated that $3 billion in cryptocurrency had been stolen in the last six years by North Korea-linked hacker organization Lazarus Group.","Read More: EU Parliament Approves New Sanctions Laws That Also Apply to Crypto","Edited by Parikshit Mishra.","\n"],"entity":[{"type":"$3 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"EU Parliament","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"North Korea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Lazarus Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Yonhap","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"last six years","content":"DATE"},{"type":"50%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"December","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Parikshit Mishra","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"United Nations (UN) Security Council","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UN Security Council","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Recorded Future","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$750 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Crypto","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["North Korea","Hacks","Sanctions"],"authors":["Jamie Crawley"]}