{"summary":"Binance founder and CEO Changpeng Zhao said that a few former CIS team members may join or have joined CommEX.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253331\/binance-former-employees-commex-cz","publishDate":"2023-09-28T04:09:06","id":1674,"type":null,"title":"Former Binance employees may have joined Russia successor CommEX: CZ","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance, which announced Wednesday its <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253146\/binance-fully-exits-russia-amid-legal-risks-sells-business-to-commex\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Russia business sale to CommEX<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, said a few former Binance employees have joined the newly launched exchange. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Changpeng Zhao, founder and CEO of Binance, said in a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/cz_binance\/status\/1707293387001307551\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">post<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> today on X (formerly Twitter), that some former Binance cryptography and information security team members may join CommEX “or have already done so.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Zhao’s comment comes after the world’s largest crypto exchange said that it has decided to fully exit Russia and sell its business there to CommEX — a crypto exchange that only officially launched on Tuesday.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In response to questions and doubt that emerged in the crypto community concerning the similarities of the user interface between the two exchanges, Zhao said that Binance asked for it. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Their design, APIs, etc are similar to Binance. We asked for this to ensure a smooth user experience,” Zhao wrote in the post.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Zhao said that CommEX does not service users from the United States or the European Union. “They have IP and KYC blocks. This is a term we asked for in the deal,” he added.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Zhao also pointed out that he is not the ultimate beneficial owner of CommEX, and he does not own any shares in the new exchange.&nbsp;<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“The deal does not have any buy back options,” he continued. “A Google search seem to show some businesses like Mercedes, McDonalds, Nissan have buy back options in their Russia sell off deal. This is not the case here.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">During the transition period, Zhao explained that there will be crypto transfers between Binance and CommEX as users migrate with their funds. “There are also older transactions during the testing phase of the integrations. This is expected,” he said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/commex.zendesk.com\/hc\/en-us\/articles\/7986715160335-CommEX-Exchange-Official-Launch\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">statement<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> published Tuesday, CommEX said <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">it offers \"a wide range of product suites including Spot, Futures, Simple Futures and P2P service to engage with the world of cryptocurrency.\"<\/span>","There still remain many questions about CommEX. The exchange has no information about who owns it or who is running it. The only information it provides is an email (of which we received no response about its ownership) and a mention that any legal disputes would be held in Hong Kong. Binance also refused to answer questions about its ownership, but denied that the exchange uses the same underlying technology as Binance.","According to a&nbsp;<a class=\"c-link\" href=\"https:\/\/coinmarketcap.com\/exchanges\/commex\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-stringify-link=\"https:\/\/coinmarketcap.com\/exchanges\/commex\/\" data-sk=\"tooltip_parent\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">page<\/a>&nbsp;on Binance-owned CoinMarketCap, CommEX described itself as a \"rapidly expanding cryptocurrency exchange, backed by top-tier crypto VCs,\" but it does not name them.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"European Union","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Binance cryptography","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"KYC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Simple Futures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Russia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Nissan","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"McDonalds","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"United States","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE","CZ"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}