{"summary":"The iShares Ethereum Trust was registered as a corporate entity in the state of Delaware earlier Thursday.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/markets\/2023\/11\/09\/coinbase-ether-liquid-staking-tokens-lido-rocketpool-surge-on-blackrock-eth-etf-news\/","publishDate":"2023-11-09T16:41:25","id":16757,"type":null,"title":"Coinbase, Ether Liquid Staking Tokens Lido, RocketPool Surge on BlackRock ETH ETF News","category":["Markets"],"content":["Tokens of ether (ETH) liquid staking platforms as well as Coinbase shares surged Thursday on hope asset management giant BlackRock (BLK) may soon file to offer a spot ether exchange-traded fund (ETF).","The iShares Ethereum Trust was registered by BlackRock Advisors as a corporate entity in Delaware. News of the filing Thursday morning sent ether soaring to as high as $2,100 – its strongest level since April's Shanghai upgrade. It's since pulled back to $2,006, still ahead 6% for the session.","Crypto exchange Coinbase (COIN) – which also has a large market share as ETH depositors for staking – was higher by 8% at press time. Coinbase charges 25% commission on user rewards earned by staking.","Governance tokens of Lido Finance (LDO) and RocketPool (RPL) jumped 7% and 8%, respectively, over the past 24 hours, CoinDesk data show.","Edited by Stephen Alpher."],"entity":[{"type":"7%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"6%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Stephen Alpher","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BlackRock","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"8%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Delaware","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ethereum Trust","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"BlackRock Advisors","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lido Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$2,100","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"25%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"morning","content":"TIME"},{"type":"RocketPool (RPL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Shanghai","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$2,006","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["Ether","Liquid staking","Lido","BlackRock"],"authors":["Krisztian Sandor"]}