{"summary":"Multiple Ethereum NFT funds were also among the backers, marking their first investment in a Bitcoin-focused company","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/business\/2024\/03\/07\/bitcoin-ordinals-wallet-oyls-raises-3m-with-arthur-hayes-brc-20-creator-domo-among-investors\/","publishDate":"2024-03-07T18:00:00","id":16776,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin Ordinals Wallet Oyl Raises $3M With Arthur Hayes, BRC-20 Creator Domo Among Investors","category":["Finance"],"content":["Bitcoin Ordinals wallet Oyl has raised $3 million in pre-seed funding with backing from investors, including crypto entrepreneur Arthur Hayes and pseudonymous BRC-20 token standard creator Domo.","The round was led by Arca, a venture firm primarily focused on Ethereum non-fungible tokens (NFTs), according to an emailed announcement on Thursday.","Multiple other Ethereum NFT funds were also among the backers, marking their first investment in a Bitcoin-focused company. These investors included Kanosei and FlamingoDAO.","Oyl is set to roll out in the coming weeks and will be the first platform to offer \"in-wallet\" trading of Ordinals.","The Ordinals Protocol allows users to mint tokens that can be traded on the Bitcoin network by embedding data into small Bitcoin-based transactions. Ordinals has brought an equivalent of NFTs and other decentralized finance (DeFi) functions to the Bitcoin ecosystem.","Read More: Bitcoin NFT Project Taproot Wizards Sells Out First Collection, Raking in $13M","Edited by Aoyon Ashraf.","\n"],"entity":[{"type":"Ethereum NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ordinals Protocol","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"First Collection","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$3 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Arca","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"20","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Arthur Hayes","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Aoyon Ashraf","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BRC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitcoin NFT Project Taproot Wizards","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kanosei","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$13M","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["Bitcoin ordinals","Wallet","Funding Rounds","Arthur Hayes"],"authors":["Jamie Crawley"]}