{"summary":"Former Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey has donated to Nostr and promoted the open protocol that aspires to create a censorship-resistant global social network.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/tech\/2023\/02\/01\/decentralized-social-media-project-nostrs-damus-gets-listed-on-apple-app-store\/","publishDate":"2023-02-01T19:50:28","id":16907,"type":null,"title":"Decentralized Social Media Project Nostr's Damus Gets Listed on Apple App Store","category":["Tech"],"content":["Nostr, a startup decentralized social network, got its Twitter-like Damus application listed on Apple's App Store.","Nostr is an open protocol that aims to create a censorship-resistant global social network. Media commentators have described it as a possible alternative to Elon Musk's Twitter. According to an article in Protos, Nostr is popular with bitcoiners partly because most implementations of it support payments over Bitcoin's Lightning Network.","Former Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey, who last year donated roughly 14 BTC (worth $245,000 at the time) to fund Nostr's development, hailed the debut of Damus on Apple's App Store as a \"milestone for open protocols,\" in a tweet posted late Tuesday. As of press time, the tweet had been viewed 2.1 million times.","According to the Nostr website, Damus is one of several Nostr projects, including Anigma, a Telegram-like chat; Nostros, a mobile client; and Jester, a chess application."],"entity":[{"type":"Elon Musk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lightning Network","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$245,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nostr","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nostr website","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Damus","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Protos","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Jack Dorsey","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["Twitter","Jack Dorsey","Social Media","Funding","Bitcoin"],"authors":["Bradley Keoun"]}