{"summary":"Ethena's total value locked (TVL) breaks $2 billion, but experts warn of potential risks reminiscent of Terra (LUNA).","webName":"beincrypto.com","link":"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/ethena-tvl-2-billion-experts-skepticism\/","publishDate":"2024-04-05T04:32:53","id":17,"type":null,"title":"Ethena's TVL Surges to $2 Billion, Will Success Outweigh Sustainability Concerns?","category":["Markets"],"content":["<strong>Ethena Protocol (ENA), the project behind the synthetic dollar <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/learn\/what-is-stablecoin\/\" target=\"_blank\" class=\"glossary-only-link\">stablecoin<\/a> USDe, has catapulted its total value locked (TVL) beyond the $2 billion mark.<\/strong>","This significant growth spurt comes amidst a wave of skepticism from seasoned industry experts, echoing concerns reminiscent of the <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/learn\/what-is-luna\/\" target=\"_blank\" class=\"glossary-only-link\">Terra<\/a> (<a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/learn\/what-is-luna\/\" target=\"_blank\" class=\"glossary-only-link\">LUNA<\/a>) debacle.","Based on the data from DefiLlama, on April 1, Ethena’s TVL stood at $1.54 billion. In just four days, it has surged past the $2 billion mark, marking a growth of about 30%. This significant increase highlights the growing investor interest in what Ethena offers.","The protocol’s lucrative 27% annual percentage yield (<a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/learn\/apr-vs-apy-in-crypto\/\" target=\"_blank\" class=\"glossary-only-link\">APY<\/a>) and its recently launched <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/ethena-token-airdrop-stablecoin-usde\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener\">ENA token airdrop<\/a> undoubtedly attract investors. Ethena’s airdrop on April 2 rewarded eligible users with a generous 750 million tokens.","<strong>Read more: <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/learn\/ethena-protocol-explained\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener\">What Is Ethena Protocol and its USDe Synthetic Dollar?<\/a><\/strong>","This news follows another attention-grabbing decision from MakerDAO, which oversees the <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/learn\/dai-crypto\/\" target=\"_blank\" class=\"glossary-only-link\">DAI<\/a> stablecoin. MakerDAO is exploring a sizeable <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/makerdao-600-million-dai-usde\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener\">600 million DAI allocation toward USDe<\/a> through Morpho Labs.","Ethena’s surge is underpinned by substantial backing from prominent investors like Delphi Digital, Wintermute, and Galaxy Digital. This adds a layer of perceived credibility to the platform.","Yet, Ethena’s breakneck growth has come with warnings. <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/learn\/ethereum-decentralized-finance-revolution\/\" target=\"_blank\" class=\"glossary-only-link\">DeFi<\/a> luminary <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/andre-cronje-questions-ethena-usde\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener\">Andre Cronje voiced concerns about USDe<\/a> potentially facing a collapse mirroring the TerraUSD (UST) debacle. Cronje’s worries center on Ethena’s use of perpetual contracts and the reliance on yield-based collateral.","CryptoQuant founder Ki Young Ju echoed Cronje’s warning, focusing on Ethena’s <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/ethena_labs\/status\/1775944410011926931\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener nofollow\">announced<\/a> plans to integrate Bitcoin (BTC) as a USDe backing asset. He questions Ethena’s ability to maintain a delta-neutral BTC strategy during bear markets.","<strong>Read more: <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/learn\/how-to-ethena\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener\">How To Use Ethena Finance To Stake USDe<\/a><\/strong>","Get guaranteed bonus up to $200 on Coinbase in 3 easy steps\n\n\t  ","“I’m just concerned about a repeat of LUNA’s scenario: selling BTC to stabilize USDe’s peg if their algorithm fails during bear markets,” Ki Young Ju <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/ki_young_ju\/status\/1776076327969608060\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener nofollow\">emphasized<\/a>.","It’s worth noting that <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/learn\/anchor-protocol\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener\">Anchor Protocol<\/a> offered around 20% APY on UST. It means USDe’s APY is even higher than UST’s.","Despite <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/analysts-critical-flaw-ethena-listing\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener\">these critical voices<\/a>, USDe has become the fifth-largest stablecoin by capitalization. ENA, Ethena’s native token, has seen <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/why-3-altcoins-are-trending\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener\">a remarkable price increase<\/a> from $0.62 to $1.25 in less than two days following the successful airdrop. However, at the time of writing, ENA is trading at $0.99.","Disclaimer","In adherence to the <a class=\"c-link\" href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/trust-project\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-stringify-link=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/trust-project\/\" data-sk=\"tooltip_parent\" aria-describedby=\"sk-tooltip-21920\">Trust Project<\/a> guidelines, BeInCrypto is committed to unbiased, transparent reporting. This news article aims to provide accurate, timely information. However, readers are advised to verify facts independently and consult with a professional before making any decisions based on this content. Please note that our&nbsp;<a class=\"c-link\" href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/terms-and-conditions\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-stringify-link=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/terms-and-conditions\/\" data-sk=\"tooltip_parent\">Terms and Conditions<\/a>,&nbsp;<a class=\"c-link\" href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/privacy-policy\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-stringify-link=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/privacy-policy\/\" data-sk=\"tooltip_parent\">Privacy Policy<\/a>, and&nbsp;<a class=\"c-link\" href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/disclaimer\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-stringify-link=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/disclaimer\/\" data-sk=\"tooltip_parent\">Disclaimers<\/a>&nbsp;have been updated."],"entity":[{"type":"Wintermute","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Morpho Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Galaxy Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ethena","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"20%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$0.62","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"30%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Terra<\/a> (<a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/learn\/what-is-luna\/\" target=\"_blank\" class=\"glossary-only-link\">LUNA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1.25","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"27%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$0.99","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$200","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Trust Project","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Delphi Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ethena’s TVL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1.54 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Cronje","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"delta","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April 1","content":"DATE"},{"type":"April 2","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ki Young Ju","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Use Ethena Finance To Stake USDe","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$2 billion mark","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"ENA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Andre Cronje","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"UST","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ethena’s","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Lynn Wang"]}