{"summary":"Former CFTC Chair Christopher Giancarlo Joins Paxos Board of Directors","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/former-cftc-chair-christopher-giancarlo-joins-paxos-board-of-directors.htm","publishDate":"2024-05-14T21:44:10","id":17065,"type":null,"title":"Former CFTC Chair Christopher Giancarlo Joins Paxos Board of Directors","category":["Blockchain News "],"content":["Paxos, a leading regulated blockchain and tokenization infrastructure platform, appointed Christopher Giancarlo, the former Chairman of the United States Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC), to its board of directors on May 14.","Giancarlo, a respected figure in the financial services industry and a passionate advocate for blockchain technology brings decades of expertise to Paxos as the company continues to innovate in the digital asset space.","Paxos highlighted the move as part of the company’s strategy to expand in regulated crypto markets and advance innovation in stablecoins. ","We’re excited to announce that former @CFTC Chairman, J. Christopher Giancarlo, is joining our Board of Directors 🎉@giancarloMKTS brings invaluable expertise and understanding of complex market dynamics to Paxos as we continue to scale.","Welcome, Chris! https:\/\/t.co\/g8deOUGauC","— Paxos (@Paxos) May 14, 2024","","In response to his appointment, Giancarlo expressed his honor to join Paxos’s board and contribute to the crypto industry.","“Paxos’s commitment to compliance and dedication to building a more efficient and inclusive financial system resonates deeply with me,” said Giancarlo. “I look forward to leveraging my expertise to help guide Paxos as it continues to revolutionize traditional finance.”","Giancarlo’s career includes serving as the thirteenth Chairman of the U.S. Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC), where he oversaw the regulation of futures, options, and swaps derivatives markets from 2013 to 2017 and as chair from 2017 to 2019. ","He is widely regarded as one of the most influential figures in financial regulation and has contributed to the global discourse on cryptocurrencies and digital assets. ","He is also the founder of the Digital Dollar Project, an initiative to establish a U.S. central bank digital currency (CBDC). Currently, he serves on the Chamber of Digital Commerce’s advisory board.","Paxos, a registered trust company and issuer of regulated digital assets, including PayPal USD (PYUSD), Pax Dollar (USDP), and Pax Gold (PAXG), is one of the leaders of the industry, pushing for digital asset adoption.","However, Paxos has faced regulatory challenges in the past. Last year, the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) issued a Wells notice to Paxos, indicating potential enforcement action regarding issuing Binance USD (BUSD) as an unregistered security. ","Additionally, New York’s Department of Financial Services targeted the crypto firm over the stablecoin, leading Paxos to announce its decision to cease issuing Binance USD.","Giancarlo’s appointment to the board of Paxos follows his appointment as a Chevalier in the French National Order of Merit in March 2022, recognizing his expertise in financial markets and crypto finance potentials, according to French Ambassador Phillipe Etienne.","Giancarlo’s expertise spans the public and private sectors. He is recognized for his entrepreneurial success and advocacy for blockchain technology."],"entity":[{"type":"May 14, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"May 14","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Christopher Giancarlo","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Digital Dollar Project","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Chamber of Digital Commerce","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"United States Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2013","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Paxos","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"PayPal","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance USD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chris!","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S. Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"March 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Giancarlo","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"J. Christopher Giancarlo","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York’s Department of Financial Services","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Board of Directors","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chevalier","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"French National Order of Merit","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Phillipe Etienne","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["CFTC","Paxos"],"authors":["Hassan Shittu"]}