{"summary":"Web3 Luxury Fashion House 9dcc Set to Debut First NFT-Linked Collection During Paris Fashion Week","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/web3-luxury-fashion-house-9dcc-set-to-debut-first-nft-linked-collection-during-paris-fashion-week.htm","publishDate":"2024-02-20T19:47:13","id":17195,"type":null,"title":"Web3 Luxury Fashion House 9dcc Set to Debut First NFT-Linked Collection During Paris Fashion Week","category":["NFT News "],"content":["9dcc, a luxury Web3 fashion house, will unveil its first full collection linked to Ethereum NFTs in France this week at Paris Fashion Week and NFT Paris.","Created by crypto influencer, Gmoney, 9dcc merges high-quality apparel with blockchain technology to create both an immersive and wearable experience.","Each design from the fashion house’s latest collection features a near-field communication (NFC) chip linked to an Ethereum NFT to enhance interoperability with both 9dcc and other wearers of the brand. Gmoney’s vision for the collection extends beyond aesthetics.","“9dcc is thrilled to unveil its groundbreaking collection of fashion and lifestyle ‘Networked Products’ during NFT Paris and Paris Fashion Week, marking an exclusive debut that masterfully blends effortless luxury with digital innovation,” a statement from the company reads.“Conceived by the visionary mind of @gmoneyNFT, the first crypto-centric luxury brand presents a pioneering ‘full fashion collection on-chain,’ setting a historic milestone in the fusion of high fashion with blockchain technology.”","Designed for the “crypto mob,” the latest collection features luxury pieces including classic ball caps, plaid jackets, and trousers for the crypto community and beyond.","Ernest wears the 9dcc Signature Essential Structured Ball Cap, a 9dcc Luxe Glen Plaid Blazer, 9dcc White Poplin Tailored Shirt, and 9dcc Leather Cargo Trouser⁠\n⁠\n⁠\nFootwear courtesy of adidas⁠\nModel: Ernest Klimko⁠\nPhoto: Aldo Carrera pic.twitter.com\/ZI3SgwqnBy","— 9dcc (@9dccxyz) February 20, 2024","","In a February 20 interview on the Grateful Show, Gmoney discussed the importance of the collection subverting the criminal image given to crypto by bad actors such as FTX fraudster, Sam Bankman-Fried, by flipping it on its head through sophisticated pieces.","Taking style inspiration from classic American gangster style, the 9dcc founder highlighted the value of celebrating the positive attributes of those in the crypto space, including their capacity for risk-taking and innovation.","“Crypto isn’t SBF and Ponzis or whatever,” Gmoney stated. “There’s more to this.”","Launched in August 2022, 9dcc takes its name from “the last four digits of the Ethereum wallet of the house from which all product expressions of the brand will be born.”","In late 2023, the company launched its “Powered by 9dcc” platform to “support brands, creators, and artists to produce quality products with ‘networked products’ technology.”","Most recently, 9dcc took home “Phygital Brand of the Year” at the Phygicode Impact Awards at the 2023 World Economic Forum in Davos.","Currently, Gmoney is scheduled to speak on February 23 Morning at NFT Paris, with private appointments available throughout fashion week.","Interested consumers will be able to buy pieces from the collection in limited quantities this week in Paris as well as shop the full collection online starting this Friday."],"entity":[{"type":"Ethereum NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Davos","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ernest Klimko","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"February 20, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"France","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"August 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Paris","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Paris Fashion Week","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"February 23 Morning","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Luxe Glen Plaid Blazer","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Aldo Carrera","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gmoney","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Phygital Brand","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gmoney","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Phygicode Impact Awards","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"World Economic Forum","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"February 20","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gmoney","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["Ethereum","NFTs","Web3"],"authors":["Julia Smith"]}