{"summary":"The partnership with Mobile Streams augments Bitso&#x27;s product offerings for Latin American users.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/239454\/bitso-partners-with-data-firm-mobile-streams-to-offer-sports-nfts","publishDate":"2023-07-13T11:25:58","id":1720,"type":null,"title":"Bitso partners with data firm Mobile Streams to offer sports NFTs","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Crypto exchange Bitso has partnered with the data intelligence firm Mobile Streams to expand its sports NFTs offerings.&nbsp;","The move augments Bitso's products for Latin American users. Through the partnership, Bitso will help promote the digital assets of Heroes NFT Club, a web3 project in which users can buy, sell and trade NFTs of officially licensed athletes and athletic clubs.","\"This alliance with Mobile Streams represents our commitment to continue offering attractive products adapted to the needs of our community in Mexico,\" Bitso's Mexico CEO Bárbara González Briseño&nbsp; said in a statement.","Bitso, operating in Argentina, Brazil, Colombia and Mexico, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/178788\/bitso-says-it-doubled-its-latin-america-customer-base-in-the-past-year\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">doubled<\/a> its reach in Latin America at over <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/195543\/crypto-exchange-bitso-sees-growth-with-latin-america-facing-political-financial-chaos\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">1,500<\/a> institutional clients and over 6 million clients in 2022. As of July 2023, Bitso has over seven million users.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Bárbara González Briseño","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Argentina","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Colombia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Latin America","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Brazil","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Mexico","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Mobile Streams","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitso","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Heroes NFT Club","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July 2023","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}