{"summary":"New WWE Collection Hits the Shelves + More NFT News","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/new-wwe-collection-hits-the-shelves-more-nft-news.htm","publishDate":"2024-02-16T11:36:54","id":17268,"type":null,"title":"New WWE Collection Hits the Shelves + More NFT News","category":["NFT News "],"content":["Top NFT news today, February 16, 2024: Panini reveals its latest WWE digital trading card collection, Unique Network announces a grant with a $250,000 prize pot, and NFT art will be displayed at a Paris exhibition.","The non-fungible token (NFT) market is quite green today.","The sales volume is up 5% in 24 hours to $36,117,430, according to CryptoSlam.","At the same time, NFT buyers are up 10%, sellers 1%, and transactions 12%.","The novel ERC-404 token Pandora has kept the first space. Its sales have increased 26% to $5.4 million.","Among the top ten collections, Open Solmap has increased the most: 219% to $790,160.","Uncategorized Ordinals saw the largest drop among the top ten. It’s down 29% to $800,040. Pudgy Penguins is close with a 25% fall to $702,251.","As the biggest NFT news of the day, Panini, a major publisher of trading cards, stickers, comics, and children’s magazines, has revealed its latest digital trading card collection.","This one features globally known figures from the World Wrestling Entertainment (WWE).","The Donruss Elite collection comprises a hundred Superstars, as the wrestlers are called in WWE. It also features inserts, including Star Status, Spellbound, and Title Waves, said a press release.","The wrestlers include the “legendary and current” Superstars. One of the most famous names among the cards is John Cena.","Others include Chelsea Green, Chyna, Kiana James, Roman Reigns, Sika Anoa’I, The Undertaker. “Stone Cold” Steve Austin, Finn Bálor, Damian Priest, Rhea Ripley, and Lyra Valkyria.","Get ready for the WWE debut on #PaniniBlockchain!","Wednesday, Feb 14 at 10am CT, Panini #DonrussElite WWE packs will be available on Panini Blockchain and feature the debuts of more than 100 legendary and current Superstars!","More info: https:\/\/t.co\/x0AyqICbeX#WhoDoYouCollect pic.twitter.com\/EhnHSMTyAB","— Panini America (@PaniniAmerica) February 14, 2024","","Jason Howarth, Senior Vice President of Marketing and Athlete Relations, commented that for the last three years, “we’ve been focused on delivering a top-tier Blockchain product to our collectors, and adding a brand like WWE to the roster, with such a rabid audience, and deep history is in line with what our community has come to expect.”","Additional Blockchain WWE releases will follow with other brands, including Panini’s flagship brand Prizm.","NFT-focused blockchain platform Unique Network has announced the launch of its NFTs 2.0 CodeCraft Grant Fund for developers, designers, and enthusiasts worldwide.","According to the press release, the grant offers a prize pot of $250,000. It aims to empower participants to leverage NFT tech in creating novel applications using Unique Network’s advanced economies.","The participants get to “explore the vast potential of advanced NFTs by creating customizable, utility-driven solutions and pushing the envelope of innovation in the non-fungible token space.”","During the event, participants will learn about the Unique Network-supported NFTs. These include Customizable NFTs, Composable NFTs, Nested NFTs, Dynamic NFTs, Multi-asset NFTs, and Multi-resource NFTs.","All of these types can be deployed to create decentralized applications (dapps) and Micro dapps, said the team.","3\/","What does this entail? ✍️","We’re here to push the boundaries of #NFTs on Polkadot! We want to work with individuals and projects with inspiring ideas that leave an impact on communities for years to come ✨","All you’ve got to do is think of different ways and create…","— Unique Network (@Unique_NFTchain) February 15, 2024","","To start the program, the platform has awarded developer grants to DED GAMES and MusicMoon.","DED GAMES is working on developing its latest projects, utilizing Unique Network’s NFTs to enhance gaming experiences.","At the same time, MusicMoon – a Polkadot APAC Hackathon winner – uses blockchain and advanced NFTs to empower artists to retain control over their work and earnings.","Meanwhile, Unique Network said it would “consistently announce new winners from grant applicants.”","Also, it plans to open up challenges within the grant framework.","Soon after this announcement, the platform revealed that AWS Startups decided to contribute $100,000 in AWS Activate Credits to support grant participants.","📢 Exciting News! Following our incredible announcement of the NFTs 2.0 CodeCraft Grant Fund for developers, we’re thrilled to share that @AWSstartups is contributing $100k USD in #AWS Activate Credits to support grant participants! 🤯💥","We’re pleased to bring forward…","— Unique Network (@Unique_NFTchain) February 16, 2024","","In other NFT news, Palm Collective and PolyArts have announced that digital art will be displayed during Polygon Lab’s NFT Paris exhibition, nous nous sommes déjà rencontrés.","The collection is a part of the joint exhibition with The Sandbox Game and the Web3 fashion house SYKY.","Tweets by PalmDAOapp","Per the website, the three most-voted artists from the competition will see their work displayed during the 1-night-only exhibition party, along with other new and established artists. They will also win a $1,000 grant from the Palm Foundation.","Also, the artist with the most votes will receive the Open Call Winner Proof.","The top three artists will get invitations to attend with a +1. The tickets are transferable if the artist cannot make the event.","The exhibition will use projectors to showcase art and installations in THE RÉAUMUR SPACE, a vacant retail space, on February 23 during NFT Paris.","The submission end date is February 16.","Amazing!!! 🤩","Submissions ends this Friday, 16th. https:\/\/t.co\/MaBPacM6p2 https:\/\/t.co\/GMZinUlTIK","— Palm Collective 🪬 (@PalmDAOapp) February 13, 2024","",""],"entity":[{"type":"Composable NFTs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"February 16","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sika","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"219%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"10%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Blockchain WWE","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$790,160","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Panini Blockchain","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Panini America","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"February 15, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Chelsea Green","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Lyra Valkyria","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Donruss Elite","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"February 23","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Title Waves","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$100k","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$1,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Wednesday, Feb 14","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$100,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Palm Collective","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Palm Foundation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"26%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Panini","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Open Call Winner Proof","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$800,040","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Paris","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"12%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$5.4 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Finn Bálor","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"WWE","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"February 16, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"USD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jason Howarth","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Damian Priest","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"29%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Senior Vice President of Marketing","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"25%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"February 13, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$702,251","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"AWS","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$250,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$36,117,430","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Kiana James","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Unique Network","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chyna","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"PalmDAOapp","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"February 14, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"John Cena","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Rhea Ripley","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"1%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Steve Austin","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["Art","NFT","Sport"],"authors":["Sead Fadilpašić"]}