{"summary":"Germany’s Biggest Bank Talked the Talk, Now it Walks the Crypto Walk","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/germany-s-biggest-bank-talked-the-talk-now-it-walks-the-cryp-9226.htm","publishDate":"2021-02-15T08:47:00","id":17266,"type":null,"title":"Germany’s Biggest Bank Talked the Talk, Now it Walks the Crypto Walk","category":["Bitcoin News "],"content":["Deutsche Bank has gone low-key with its crypto intentions, but after months of crypto-positalk, the bank – Germany’s biggest with assets of almost USD 1.8 trillion – has taken the plunge into crypto custody.","It’s not a surprising move as the bank’s analysts have been making bullish remarks on bitcoin (BTC) in recent months, and have called fiat a monetary “fad.” Back in 2019, the bank warned that fiat was wobbling, and called crypto’s rise “inevitable.”","And while Deutsche Bank refrained from making a big public announcement, it appears to have come good on its talk as early as last year – although few have noticed until media reports this weekend picked up on a World Economic Forum originally published in December 2020. Named Crypto, What Is it Good for?: An Overview of Cryptocurrency Use Cases, the report featured a section called Deutsche Bank Digital Asset Custody.","The authors wrote that the bank envisages creating a “secure connected bridge between digital assets and a customer’s traditional banking services,” and allow customers to access their “digital assets and fiat holdings in one easy-to-use platform.”","And like many other international banks of late, the report noted that the bank is hoping to “offer an institutional-grade” hot and cold wallet “storage solution” featuring “insurance-grade protection.”","The authors added that initial technical work on the project was already done, and added that an international test was now in the pipelines – with a rollout possible as early as this year.","They concluded,","“The bank has completed its proof of concept and is aiming for a minimum viable product in 2021 while exploring global client interest for a pilot initiative.”","___\nLearn more:\n– Cash Still a Top Hedge Pick, but Digital Winning Payments War – Bank Strategist\n– Deutsche Bank Strategist Bullish on Bitcoin, But JPMorgan Boss Still Unmoved\n– Fiat Will Be a Passing Fad In the History of Money – Deutsche Bank Strategist\n– Deutsche Bank: Fiat Money is Fragile, Crypto – Inevitable\n– America’s Oldest Bank, BNY Mellon, Goes Bitcoin"],"entity":[{"type":"Deutsche Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Digital Winning Payments War – Bank Strategist\n– Deutsche Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Goes Bitcoin","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"weekend","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Deutsche Bank Digital Asset Custody","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fiat Money","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"BNY Mellon","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"December 2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Cryptocurrency Use Cases","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"History of Money – Deutsche Bank Strategist\n– Deutsche Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Crypto – Inevitable\n– America’s Oldest Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Germany","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Fiat","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Adoption","Banking","Bitcoin","Cryptocurrency","Custody"],"authors":["Tim Alper"]}