{"summary":"Listen to The NFT Scoop, the place for in-depth conversations about NFTs hosted by MK Manoylov, NFTs and metaverse reporter for The Block.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/158952\/nft-scoop-with-mk-manoylov-a-brief-history-of-nfts","publishDate":"2022-07-25T14:18:45","id":1735,"type":null,"title":"NFT Scoop with MK Manoylov: A Brief History of NFTs","category":["NFTS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">68<\/strong><\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 4 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block's MK Manoylov and The Block Research's Thomas Bialek.<\/i><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"97e7f8f3f4f6e4e3d7e3fff2f5fbf8f4fcf4e5eee7e3f8b9f4f8fa\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK2045085076\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/i><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Non-fungible tokens (NFTs), the blockchain-based method to verify and transfer ownership of a digital asset, exploded in popularity in 2021.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Though some collections such as NBA Top Shot and CryptoPunks had existed before last year’s climb in popularity, NFTs largely did not enter mainstream consciousness until the arrival of Bored Ape Yacht Club, a collection of 10,000 algorithmically assembled images of languid monkeys.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The success of Bored Ape Yacht Club in the spring of 2021 sparked an influx of large-scale NFT collections such as Mutant Ape Yacht Club, Meebits, Doodles, Cool Cats and Azuki. What followed was the scramble in the crypto community to buy in early to the next popular project — and the rush for non-crypto natives to understand what these types of tokens even are.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Around the same time as so-called profile-picture projects emerged, NFTs also expanded into the blockchain-based gaming sector through play-to-earn (P2E) mechanics. The P2E game Axie Infinity particularly emerged as a giant in the blockchain-based gaming space in the late summer and early fall of last year before losing traction.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In all, NFTs surpassed <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/128676\/nft-trading-volume-surpassed-13-billion-in-2021\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$13 billion<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in trading volume in 2021. NFT trading volume cooled in concert with the broader crypto bear market in 2022. With high-profile parties like Coinbase and GameStop entering the space, this technology doesn’t seem to be going away. With it, so too are pertinent questions around copyright and ownership.<\/span>","In this debut episode of The Block's NFT Scoop, reporter MK Manoylov speaks with The Block Research's <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockresearch.com\/author\/thomas-bialek\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Thomas Bialek<\/span><\/a> about the history of NFTs, where they came from and what lead to their explosion in popularity in 2021.","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In this episode, Manoylov and Bialek also discuss<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">:&nbsp;<\/span><\/em>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors <em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.chainalysis.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Chainalysis<\/a>&nbsp;&amp;<\/em>&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.iwc.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC Schaffhausen<\/a><\/em><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/b>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Chainalysis<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nChainalysis is the leading blockchain data platform. We provide data, software, services, and research to government agencies, exchanges, financial institutions, and insurance and cybersecurity companies in over 60 countries. Backed by Accel, Addition, Benchmark, Coatue, Paradigm, Ribbit, and other leading firms in venture capital, Chainalysis builds trust in blockchains to promote more financial freedom with less risk. For more information, visit <a href=\"https:\/\/www.chainalysis.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">www.chainalysis.com<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About IWC Schaffhausen<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC Schaffhausen is a Swiss luxury watch manufacturer based in Schaffhausen, Switzerland. Known for its unique engineering approach to watchmaking, IWC combines the best of human craftsmanship and creativity with cutting-edge technology and processes. With collections like the Portugieser and the Pilot’s Watches, the brand covers the whole spectrum from elegant timepieces to sports watches. For more information, visit <a href=\"https:\/\/www.iwc.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC.com<\/a><\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Switzerland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bored Ape Yacht Club","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coatue","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chainalysis<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nChainalysis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Benchmark","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"IWC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"spring of 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Schaffhausen","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"IWC Schaffhausen<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC Schaffhausen","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"GameStop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NBA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Thomas Bialek","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cool Cats","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Paradigm","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Manoylov","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Mutant Ape Yacht Club","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Accel","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ribbit","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bialek","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Infinity","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"summer","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Chainalysis<\/a>&nbsp;&amp;<\/em>&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.iwc.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC Schaffhausen","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$13 billion","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["CRYPTOPUNKS","YUGA LABS"],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}