{"summary":"Franklin Templeton Lists Ethereum ETF Under Ticker ‘EZET’ on DTCC","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/franklin-templeton-lists-ethereum-etf-under-ticker-ezet-on-dtcc.htm","publishDate":"2024-04-29T03:57:55","id":17372,"type":null,"title":"Franklin Templeton Lists Ethereum ETF Under Ticker ‘EZET’ on DTCC","category":["Ethereum News "],"content":["Asset management firm Franklin Templeton has listed its Ethereum exchange-traded fund (ETF) under the ticker EZET on the Depository Trust and Clearing Corporation (DTCC) website.","The “Franklin Templeton Ethereum TR Ethereum ETF” is listed in the create or redeem column on the DTCC website. The product has yet to be approved by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC).","","On February 12, Franklin Templeton was the latest asset manager to file a spot Ethereum ETF application with the SEC — joining ​​a long list of asset managers such as BlackRock, Fidelity, Grayscale, VanEck, Invesco and Galaxy, as well as Cathy Wood’s Ark Invests and 21Shares, all of which have submitted applications for a spot Ethereum ETF.","Last week, the SEC announced a delay in its decision regarding Franklin Templeton’s proposed spot Ethereum ETF, extending the deadline to June 11. This news comes from a filing made public, leaving the future of this financial product uncertain for the time being.","The proposed ETF seeks to track the price of ether and would utilize Coinbase Custody Trust Company and the Bank of New York Mellon as custodians.","In March, the SEC delayed a decision to approve the BlackRock spot Ethereum ETF. The SEC now has until May 23 to approve or reject VanEck’s ETF application for an Ethereum ETF tracking the world’s second-largest cryptocurrency.","Bloomberg Intelligence analyst James Seyffart has expressed scepticism, suggesting the current round of Ether ETF applications might ultimately be denied.","Earlier today, Tron CEO and founder Justin Sun said it is unlikely an Ethereum ETF will be approved in May with the cryptocurrency in need of “long-term education with regulators.”  ","The status of Ethereum is in limbo – currently, ETH is not considered a security by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) — but this could all change very quickly. It has been widely reported that several U.S.-based companies have received subpoenas attempting to label ETH as a security.","Ethereum is viewed as a decentralized cryptocurrency, rather than a security. However, regulatory agencies like the SEC continue to monitor the cryptocurrency space and may provide further guidance and sudden changes or new rulings in the future. It’s essential to stay updated on regulatory developments.","On Thursday, it emerged, that Ethereum developer firm Consensys, managed by Joe Lubin, filed a lawsuit on April 25 against the SEC over its “overzealous regulation” around the Ethereum blockchain.","In an announcement on social media platform X, Lubin said Consensys has taken an important step towards “preserving access to ether and, by extension, the Ethereum blockchain in the U.S. We are suing the SEC and fighting back against its overzealous regulatory overreach.”","In a blog post, Consensys said the SEC’s reckless approach is causing chaos to developers, market participants, institutions, and nations that are building or already managing critical systems running on Ethereum, the world’s largest platform for decentralized applications."],"entity":[{"type":"Cathy Wood","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Coinbase Custody Trust Company","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"February 12","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bank of New York Mellon","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lubin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Consensys","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"April 25","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Joe Lubin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Franklin Templeton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Franklin Templeton Ethereum","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ethereum ETF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"May 23","content":"DATE"},{"type":"James Seyffart","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BlackRock","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Grayscale","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Justin Sun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"DTCC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fidelity","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Depository Trust","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"VanEck","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bloomberg Intelligence","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Invesco","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"June 11","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["Ethereum ETF","Franklin Templeton"],"authors":["Tanzeel Akhtar"]}