{"summary":"B2C2 said the acquisition of the French market maker grants it access to a license in France.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/247150\/crypto-market-maker-b2c2-acquires-woorton-in-european-expansion-drive","publishDate":"2023-08-24T03:04:41","id":1738,"type":null,"title":"Crypto market maker B2C2 acquires Woorton in European expansion drive","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto market maker B2C2 acquired Woorton, a France-based rival, to expand its European presence.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.b2c2.com\/newspost\/b2c2-boosts-european-presence-with-woorton-acquisition\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">statement<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> released today, B2C2 said the acquisition grants it access to Woorton’s PSAN license regulated by the AMF, the financial market regulator in France.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The move gives B2C2 the opportunity to serve clients in the European Union in line with the incoming Markets in Crypto Assets Regulation (MiCA) regulations, the company said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“This acquisition is an important milestone in the ongoing journey of B2C2's growth and evolution,” Nicola White, chief executive officer of B2C2, said in the statement. “We welcome joining forces with Woorton’s expert team who, with their collective experience, have built a first rate digital assets market making firm supported by a robust client base and strong regulatory standing.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Woorton currently has nearly 250 clients trading 96 coins, according to the statement.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Founded in 2015, B2C2 is majority-owned by Japanese financial group SBI and is headquartered in the UK, with a presence in the U.S., Cayman Islands and Japan.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Thomas Restout, B2C2’s head of EMEA, said Woorton's team combines traditional financial experience with a focus on crypto and digital assets. “Together we are a combination of highly complementary businesses that deliver multi asset breadth and depth to clients in the EU market,” he added.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Cayman Islands","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2015","content":"DATE"},{"type":"European Union","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"France","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"EMEA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"today","content":"DATE"},{"type":"EU","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Japan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Woorton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Woorton","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"UK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thomas Restout","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nicola White","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"AMF","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["EUROZONE REGULATION","PRIVATE COMPANY M&AMP;A"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}