{"summary":"Clumsy Cardano Co-Founder’s Tweet Sparks Outrage","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/clumsy-cardano-co-founder-s-tweet-sparks-outrage-2338.htm","publishDate":"2018-07-27T10:14:00","id":17410,"type":null,"title":"Clumsy Cardano Co-Founder’s Tweet Sparks Outrage","category":["Altcoin News "],"content":["One of the side-effects of being successful in the crypto world is that people would go out of their way to help you with a problem. Also, you’re generally considered an immortal superstar who doesn’t need to go down the same path us mortals do, to get something done.\nAt least that is what one may think, after seeing this (clumsy) tweet:","To put things into more perspective, Charles Hoskinson, co-founder of Cardano, a public blockchain and cryptocurrency project, co-founder and ex-CEO of the Ethereum platform, as well as CEO of Input Output Hong Kong (IOHK), a tech company, reached out to MetaMask app via Twitter, asking about the recent Chrome app store delisting at a time when the latter was trying to figure out why they got delisted in the first place.","As you might expect, Twitter and Reddit all but crucified the man, pointing out how his ego grew larger than him. However, Hoskinson was quick to emphasize that it has nothing to do with ego, but rather with efficiency because, as he says, Microsoft would never tell the CEO of Ford to contact them through customer support.","“I was making a point to a project I like and respect. Don’t blow off CEOs when they take the time to reach out to you. It’s just stupid regardless of whether you like them or not.”","He even drew parallels with Elon Musk and the way he communicates through Twitter. Suffice it to say, the community wasn’t impressed by his shenanigans.","“LOL what a response. Muhhh research muhhh CEO muhhh Elon,” was one we found particularly funny.","“Get called out for elite\/impolite\/rude behavior – defends self by pointing to ruder person. Like a person on trial pointing to someone else “Hey, I only killed one person, that guy over there killed five”. It doesn’t excuse the fact your behavior wasn’t socially appropriate.”","However another user of Reddit, runny6play, points out: “Yeah, I mean the way he worded it sounds bad, but honestly an active CEO in the same space should have more pull than having to email support. Then again if he’s CEO of a less than 10 man company and it is a shitcoin with no standing, then really maybe not.”","For example, market capitalization of ADA (Cardano cryptocurrency) currently stands at USD 4.2bn."],"entity":[{"type":"Elon Musk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hoskinson","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ford","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Reddit","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Cardano","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Microsoft","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"muhhh Elon","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"ADA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"USD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Charles Hoskinson","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["Cardano","Community","MetaMask"],"authors":["Sead Fadilpašić"]}