{"summary":"Japan’s SBI Group Plans to Issue NFTs Built on XRP Ledger for World Expo 2025 in Osaka","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/japans-sbi-group-plans-to-issue-nfts-built-on-xrp-ledger-for-world-expo-2025-in-osaka.htm","publishDate":"2024-04-19T09:41:44","id":17522,"type":null,"title":"Japan’s SBI Group Plans to Issue NFTs Built on XRP Ledger for World Expo 2025 in Osaka","category":["News "],"content":["Japan’s SBI Group is planning on issuing non-fungible tokens (NFTs) built on XRP Ledger during the World Expo 2025 to be held in Osaka, Japan.","According to marketing material released before the event, those attending the upcoming Expo will receive exclusive NFTs of “MYAKU-MYAKU” which is the official character of the EXPO. The non-fungible tokens will be given away at the event starting from April 13, 2025.","At the World Expo 2025 in Osaka 🇯🇵 (Apr – Oct 2025), official NFTs (\"MYUAKU-N\") minted on the XRP Ledger will be distributed to millions of visitors!\n✅ you can get NFTs by visiting the Expo and completing missions.\n✅ you can get additional NFTs by using the Expo mobile payments… pic.twitter.com\/a7jblbV48U","— Emi Yoshikawa {X} (@emy_wng) April 18, 2024","","The “MYAKU-MYAKU” NFTs will have no cash value and cannot be bought or sold, although there will be proof of authenticity. No fees will be charged to create a “wallet” (a virtual “box” on the Internet to manage crypto assets) and to mint them on the blockchain.  ID will be required for registration for the app “EXPO2025 DIGITAL WALLET.”","As Japan’s SBI steps up its efforts to drop NFTs during a 2025 event several American firms have been removing NFT purchase protection as trading declines.","Earlier this week it emerged the payments giant PayPal plans to remove non-fungible token (NFT) purchases from its purchase protection program from May 20. In an online announcement, PayPal said amendments to its protection program will exclude NFTs and any payments that you initiated via a third-party platform using the PayPal Balance.","In January, GameStop revealed it had shut down its NFT marketplace, signalling its withdrawal from the cryptocurrency space. The announcement was made via a statement on the platform with the firm stating “the continuing regulatory uncertainty of the crypto space” as the primary reason behind this decision.","Trading of NFTs has been in decline for over a year. Data compiled by Statista shows the number of active wallets involved in NFT trading has declined.","The World Expo 2025 will be held in Osaka, Japan, In 2023, it emerged Osaka Digital Exchange Co. is set to revolutionize Japan’s financial landscape by introducing the country’s first-ever digital securities trading.","Osaka Digital Exchange (ODX)  launched Japan’s first-ever digital securities trading. The platform will feature security tokens issued by real estate firms Ichigo Inc. and Kenedix Inc., with the inaugural trading focusing on securities backed by property investments from Ichigo."],"entity":[{"type":"2025","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Osaka Digital Exchange Co.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Kenedix Inc.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"PayPal","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Japan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"PayPal Balance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April 18, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SBI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SBI Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Osaka","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ichigo Inc.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Oct 2025","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Emi Yoshikawa","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"May 20","content":"DATE"},{"type":"April 13, 2025","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ichigo","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Osaka Digital Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"GameStop","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["NFTs","SBI Group","XRP LED"],"authors":["Tanzeel Akhtar"]}