{"summary":"New York State to Ban Carbon-Powered Bitcoin, Altcoin Mining, While Kenya Fosters Green BTC","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/new-york-state-to-ban-carbon-powered-bitcoin-altcoin-mining-while-kenya-fosters-green-btc.htm","publishDate":"2022-06-03T10:14:00","id":17611,"type":null,"title":"New York State to Ban Carbon-Powered Bitcoin, Altcoin Mining, While Kenya Fosters Green BTC","category":["Bitcoin News "],"content":[" ","As regulators across the world work to adopt varying stances on crypto mining, the US state of New York and the East African country of Kenya offer two examples of how legislators can thwart or foster crypto innovation through their initiatives.","Citing the need to curb the state’s energy use, the New York Senate has passed a bill that introduces a moratorium on certain crypto mining operations with the use of proof-of-work (PoW) authentication methods to validate blockchain transactions. The two-year moratorium concerns any new PoW mining projects operated with the use of carbon-based fuel, including bitcoin (BTC) and other cryptoassets. ","After it was passed by the Senate and the New York State Assembly, the lower chamber of the state’s legislature, the bill was delivered to New York’s governor. Unless the incumbent governor, Democrat Kathy Hochul, vetoes the bill, its provisions will go into force.","The bill states that the “continued and expanded operation of cryptocurrency mining operations running proof-of-work authentication methods to validate blockchain transactions will greatly increase the amount of energy usage in the state of New York, and impact compliance with the Climate Leadership and Community Protection Act.” ","End\/ We still haven’t heard an answer.\n\nOur focus now turns to @GovKathyHochul who should veto this misguided bill. We encourage all pro-tech NYers to make their voices heard and ask the governor to veto.","Meanwhile, Greenidge Generation Holdings, a vertically integrated crypto data center and power generation company, said that “should the legislation be signed into law, our fully permitted power generation and cryptocurrency data center in Dresden, NY will continue to operate without interruption.”","On the other hand, Kenya’s energy production company KenGen has adopted a different approach to crypto, declaring its plans to offer BTC mining companies the KenGen’s surplus geothermal power. This is designed to help industry players meet their energy needs, Quartz reports.","The energy business says that, by offering clean energy, it will contribute to cutting crypto mining’s carbon emissions triggered by bitcoin mining. ","As Africa’s leading geothermal energy producer, Kenya has an installed capacity of 863 MW, the majority of which is ensured by KenGen. The state has an estimated geothermal potential of some 10,000 MW located along the Rift Valley circuit which could be used to foster green crypto mining by local industry players.","____","Learn more: \n– Another Bitcoin Mining Scrutiny\n– Bitcoin Mining Can be a Force for Good or Bad, Banning it Doesn’t Solve Anything – FTX.US President\n\n– Kenyan Crypto Entrepreneurs Urge CMA to Create Regulatory Framework, Not Demons\n– Bitcoin in Kenya w\/ Roselyne Wanjiru\n\n– Crypto’s Need for Sustainability Standard-Setting Starts Here\n– Bitcoin Mining Efficiency Up 63% in Year, ‘Sustainable Electricity Mix’ Jumped 59% – Bitcoin Mining Council\n\n– After Mozilla Abandoned PoW Cryptos Citing Energy Concerns, Wikipedia May Follow\n– The Compromises and Benefits of Ethereum Switching to a Proof-of-Stake Network\n__\n(Updated at 13:09 UTC with a statement by the Blockchain Association. Updated at 13:39 UTC with a comment from Greenidge Generation Holdings.)"],"entity":[{"type":"Kathy Hochul","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Blockchain Association","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kenya","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Roselyne Wanjiru","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"UTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dresden","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"63%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Kenyan Crypto Entrepreneurs Urge CMA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Greenidge Generation Holdings","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"59%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"New York Senate","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitcoin Mining Council\n\n– After Mozilla Abandoned PoW Cryptos Citing Energy Concerns","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Climate Leadership and Community","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Africa","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Rift Valley","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York State Assembly","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"KenGen","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Senate","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Create Regulatory Framework","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Africa","Bitcoin","Ecology","Mining","Proof-of-work","Regulation","USA"],"authors":["Jaroslaw Adamowski"]}