{"summary":"&quot;Business in the Metaverse Economy,&quot; as it&#x27;s called, is one of the first business courses about the metaverse in an Ivy League school.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/159723\/wharton-school-launches-metaverse-focused-business-course","publishDate":"2022-07-26T14:43:32","id":1766,"type":null,"title":"Wharton School launches metaverse-focused business course","category":["METAVERSE & NFT"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Wharton School, a high-profile business school out of the University of Pennsylvania, announced the launch of a new course regarding business in the metaverse.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The online course is titled “Business in the Metaverse Economy” and educates students about metaverse business practices, giving participants first-hand interactive experiences in virtual spaces.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The intent of the course is to provide business professionals a better understanding of opportunities in the budding metaverse economy and better tools to address issues in it, said the program’s academic director Kevin Werbach in a <a href=\"https:\/\/news.wharton.upenn.edu\/press-releases\/2022\/07\/wharton-launches-business-in-the-metaverse-economy-executive-education-online-certificate-program-becoming-first-ivy-league-business-school-to-launch-a-program-on-the-emerging-techn\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">release<\/a>.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Other high-profile universities in the United States have incorporated web3 tech as learning tools, such as classes at Duke University and Stanford University providing course completion certificates as non-fungible tokens (NFTs). However, Wharton’s new program marks one of the first instances that the metaverse as an economic opportunity enters higher education.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Wharton developed the metaverse business course with the economic consulting firm Prysm Group. The six-week program is asynchronous and contains over 50 lecture videos, with guest speakers from Adobe, Animoca Brands, Second Life, Unity and more. <\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Kevin Werbach","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Wharton","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Adobe","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Wharton School","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Stanford University","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Animoca Brands","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"the University of Pennsylvania","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Duke University","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Unity","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"United States","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Prysm Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Second Life","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}