{"summary":"Super Bowl Champion Gronk Set to Auction His Own NFT Collection","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/super-bowl-champion-gronk-set-to-auction-his-own-nft-collect-9480.htm","publishDate":"2021-03-09T15:00:00","id":17669,"type":null,"title":"Super Bowl Champion Gronk Set to Auction His Own NFT Collection","category":["News "],"content":["And the non-fungible token (NFT) craze continues, gaining more steam with each passing day. Today, US Super Bowl champion Rob Gronkowski, aka Gronk, announced the launch of his own NFT collection commemorating his four Super Bowl wins.","The American football tight end for the Tampa Bay Buccaneers of the National Football League (NFL) is a four-time Super Bowl champion. Following the latest Super Bowl victory, Gronk announced his Championship Series NFT Collection minted on the Ethereum (ETH) blockchain.","For this purpose, he partnered with a digital marketplace for crypto collectibles, OpenSea.","“With the rapid success of NFT’s across platforms like NBA Topshop and Opensea, I wanted to take the business into my own hands and be the first professional athlete to launch my own NFT collection,” said Gronkowski in an emailed press release. He added that the fans will now be able to get “a piece of the action and share these iconic Super Bowl moments” with him in digital format.","OpenSea Chief Technology Officer Alex Atallah said that Gronk’s offering is the first of its kind on this platform, and that the sale will be part of OpenSea Drops, which is a new initiative meant to highlight “exceptional content in the growing NFT space.”","The press release stated that the cards were created by visual arts studio Black Madre, the website of which lists a number of major companies as clients, such as Samsung, Netflix, Nike, Nestlé, Coca Cola, and others.","Five different trading cards will be available in the collection. Each card in the series is “certified by Gronk and generated on the Ethereum blockchain, so there is provable scarcity,” said the release, adding that “extremely unique to the NFT market, every card is digitally hand-signed by Gronk and individually numbered.”","The five cards are composed of hand-drawn original art and are limited to 87 editions of each, except for the fifth, which is limited to 1 edition. They commemorate:","","The highest bidder of the 1-of-1 Career Highlight Refractor Card NFT will also receive the opportunity to meet Gronk in person and attend a game as his guest, said the press release.","Gronk’s NFTs will be available for auction for 48 hours on GRONKNFT.com, from March 11 until March 13. The auction accepts only payment in ETH, and will not accept credit cards. It also requires that users set up an OpenSea account and a MetaMask wallet.\n___","Learn more:\n– Justin Sun, Sina Estavi & Co Race to Buy NFT of Jack Dorsey’s First Tweet\n– Consider These Legal Questions Before Spending Millions on NFTs\n– NFT Overtakes Litecoin, Bitcoin Cash, and XRP on Google\n– Grimes and Paris Hilton Go Full NFT – But Some Warn of Trouble Ahead\n– Check These 4 Make-Your-Own-NFT Platforms\n– Non-Fungible 2021: Prepare Your NFTs For DeFi, Staking, and Sharing\n– ‘Traditional’ Art vs. Crypto Art: How to Value It\n– NFT: Can Burning A Banksy Make It More Valuable?"],"entity":[{"type":"Paris","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NBA Topshop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Netflix","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"OpenSea Drops","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Grimes","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nike","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coca Cola","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Gronk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"National Football League (NFL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"First Tweet\n– Consider These Legal Questions Before Spending Millions","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Justin Sun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alex Atallah","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sina Estavi & Co Race to Buy NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"March 13","content":"DATE"},{"type":"March 11","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Jack Dorsey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Rob Gronkowski","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Samsung","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1 Career Highlight Refractor Card NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Gronkowski","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nestlé","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Opensea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Tampa Bay Buccaneers","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Black Madre","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["Ethereum","NFT","Non-fungible tokens","Sport"],"authors":["Sead Fadilpašić"]}