{"summary":"Hans Zimmer Composes Anthem for TRON Founder Justin Sun","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/hans-zimmer-composes-anthem-for-tron-founder-justin-sun.htm","publishDate":"2024-04-16T09:28:48","id":17674,"type":null,"title":"Hans Zimmer Composes Anthem for TRON Founder Justin Sun","category":["Altcoin News "],"content":["Academy award-winning music composer and producer Hans Zimmer has composed an anthem for the controversial entrepreneur and TRON founder Justin Sun.","Zimmer is one of the most celebrated film composers and is the musical mastermind behind Gladiator, The Last Samurai, the Pirates of the Caribbean series, The Dark Knight trilogy, Inception, Man of Steel, Interstellar, Dunkirk, and No Time to Die …and now Justin Sun’s TRON Anthem.","Sun is widely known to be brash and outspoken, and as the founder of TRON, he remains one of the most influential names in the cryptocurrency space — although his status as a villain or hero remains a bit murky.","The theme TRON anthem released by Zimmer is a winner with absolutely incredible scores. Dubbed the song for the “Web3 Generation” the TRON theme tune captures the epic struggles Sun has experienced over the years.","Most recently Sun is being sued by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission on allegations of fraud, market manipulation and airdropping unregistered securities.","The future of music is NOW! 🚀\nI’m thrilled to partner with the legendary @HansZimmer to create the #TRONAnthem.  This is a groundbreaking fusion of music and blockchain.Get ready to experience the sound of tomorrow. 👇https:\/\/t.co\/UYlRqTGSMf pic.twitter.com\/9dlK9yajpC","— H.E. Justin Sun 孙宇晨 (@justinsuntron) April 16, 2024","","The entity behind the layer-1 blockchain Tron requested the dismissal of a lawsuit filed by the SEC  against it, arguing that the regulator’s focus on “predominantly foreign conduct” goes beyond its jurisdiction. ","In a dismissal motion filed on March 28 in a New York federal court, the Tron Foundation stated that the SEC’s attempt to apply U.S. security laws to predominantly foreign activities exceeds the regulator’s authority as it is not a global regulatory body.","The SEC’s lawsuit, filed in March of last year, targeted Sun, who is also behind BitTorrent Foundation, and Rainberry Inc., the San Francisco-based parent company of BitTorrent, which Tron acquired in 2018. ","The Tron Foundation, based in Singapore, argued in its motion that the tokens were sold exclusively overseas, with measures taken to avoid the U.S. market, and that the SEC did not claim they were initially offered or sold to U.S. residents.","Tron further argued that even if the SEC had jurisdiction, the tokens would not meet the criteria of investment contracts under the U.S. securities classification, as defined by the Howey test. ","As the Sun versus SEC saga continues — Zimmer has created THE perfect theme tune for the epic battle…and on that note, I bid you adieu!",""],"entity":[{"type":"San Francisco","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"BitTorrent","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Zimmer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"March 28","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Hans Zimmer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Justin Sun’s TRON Anthem","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Caribbean","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"1","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tron Foundation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"H.E. Justin Sun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Justin Sun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BitTorrent Foundation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April 16, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Dunkirk","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"March of last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Rainberry Inc.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"TRON","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Interstellar","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Howey","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["Hans Zimmer","Justin Sun","Tron"],"authors":["Tanzeel Akhtar"]}