{"summary":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: April 22, 2024","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/crypto-exchange-listing-and-delisting-announcements-april-22-2024.htm","publishDate":"2024-04-22T20:56:16","id":17729,"type":null,"title":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: April 22, 2024","category":["Altcoin News "],"content":[""," ","Here is our weekly collection of digital asset listing and delisting, trading pair-related announcements by crypto exchanges that we found last week and today.","Have we missed something? Do you have information about new listings and\/or delistings? Let us know here.","_________________________________________","MEXC\nListings:\nGROK X (GROKXAI)\nSpectraChain (SPCT)\nSidus Heroes (SENATE)\nSedra Coin (SDR)\nLuluOasis (LULU)\nGobli (GOBLI)\ndogwifsaudihat (WIFSA)\nStreamlining AI (SMAI)\nColle AI (COLLE)\nKinka Gold (XNK)\nSharky (SHARK)\nGentle Titan (GENTLETITA)\nMars Battle (SHOOT)\nCeDeFiAi (CDFI)\nTradeleaf (TLF)\nGaming Stars (GAMES)\nKAARIGAR Connect (KARCON)\nEagle Network (EGON)\nNuklai (NAI)\nWorld Bank (WORLD)\nAirbot (AIBOT)\nOrdinalsBot (TRIO)\nHULVIN (HULVIN)\nNeko (NEKO)\nMeow Gangs (MEOWG)\nSmileK to the Bank (SMILEK)\nNeuroWeb AI (NEURO)\nSuper Raccoon (SROC)\nMerlin Chain (MERL)\nPEPES Token (PEPES)\nOORT (OORT)\nPopcat (POPCAT)\nSuper AI (SUPERAI)\nGuufy (GUUFY)\nAIT Protocol (AITPROTOCOL)\nInqubeta (QUBE)\nRug World Assets (RWA)\nAI Pepe King (AIPEPE)\nCall of Memes (COME)\nHumanode (HMND)\nNeptuneX (NPTX)\nSuperWalk (WALK)\nCatvax (CATVAX)\nPortuma (PORTUMA)\nWIFHAT (WIFHAT)\nSnapmuse.io (SMX)\nShinobi Ninja (SHINOBI)\nUPTOS (UPTOS)\nFather Of Meme (FOMO)\nLightning AI (LNGAI)\nMeow Coin (MEOW1)\nEND OF DARKNESS (AINVDIA)\nMeowifhat (MEOWIF)\nDecentralized ETF (DETF)\nBunny Box (BNY)\nGold Cat (GOLDCAT)"," ","KuCoin\nListings:\nParcl (PRCL)\nMerlin Chain (MERL)\nDegen (DEGEN)\nKarrat Coin (KARRAT)\nDefispot (SPOT)\nVita Inu (VINU)"," ","Bitrue\nListings:\nParcl (PRCL)\nAffi Network (AFFI)\nOmni Network (OMNI)"," ","OKX\nListings:\nParcl (PRCL)\nMerlin Chain (MERL)\n"," ","Poloniex\nListings:\nVerifiable Oracle Protocol (OLM)\n1intro (INTRO)\nWzrd (WZRD)\nTEH EPIK DUCK (EPIK)\nRailgun (RAIL)\nSpeedy (SPEEDY)\nTooker Kurlson (TOOKER)\nRunesBridge (RB)\nFather Of Meme (BASEFOMO)\nAltered State Machine (ASTO)\nCoinye West (COINYE)\nKomputai (KAI)\nMerlin Chain (MERL)"," ","CoinEx\nListings:\nParcl (PRCL)\nSharky (SHARK)\nOmni Network (OMNI)\nMerlinStarter (MSTAR)\nMerlin Chain (MERL)\nDefactor (FACTR)\nBoop (BOOP)\nBitcoin Wizard (WZRD)"," ","Gate.io\nListings:\nParcl (PRCL)\nMerlin Chain (MERL)\nSatoshi Nakamoto (SATOSHI)\nMeme Economics (MEMERUNE)\nWanko Manko (WANKO)"," ","BitMart\nListings:\nRailgun (RAIL)\nBrainers (BRAINERS)\nParcl (PRCL)\nGreen Grey MetaGame (GGMT)\nCetCoin (CET)\nBoo Boo Bear (BOOBOO)\ncrow with knife (CAW)\nMerlin Chain (MERL)\nElon Cat Finance (ECAT)\nGreyStack (GREYSTACK)\nCatWif (CATWIF)\nMouse in a cats world (MOW)\nAndy (ANDY)\nPikamoon (PIKA)\nMeow Coin (MEOW)\nKibhocoin (KBC)\nScorpion Casino (SCORP)"," ","LBank\nListings:\nMouse in a cats world (MOW)\nScorpion Casino (SCORP)\nOmni Network (OMNI)\nMinds Entering Other Worlds (MEOW)\nCOHI Flana (COHI)\nSpongebob Squarepants (SPONGEBOB)\nShiba Protocol (SPO)\nFather Of Meme (FOMOBASE)\nArmonia Meta Chain (AMAX)\nWhiteSwap (WSD)\nMickey Of Meme (MICKEYOFMEME)\nGolden MagFi (GMFI)\nWebMind Network (WMN)"," ","P2B Crypto Exchange\nListings:\nSnipcoins (SNIPS)\nMuzikoin (MZK)\nWood Dragon Token (WDC)\nIMB Coin (IMB)\nPROC (PROC)"," ","AscendEX\nListings:\nOmni Network (OMNI)\nJustAnEgg (EGG)\nMerlin Chain (MERL)\nDingocoin (DINGO)"," ","BigONE\nListings:\nWorldwide USD (WUSD)"," ","CEX.io\nListings:\nCelestia (TIA)\nZetaChain (ZETA)\nAssemble Protocol (ASM)","  ","ChangeNOW\nListings:\nCat in a dogs world (MEW)","  ","Crypto.com\nListings:\nParcl (PRCL)\nOmni Network (OMNI)\nZebec Network (ZBCN)"," ","DigiFinex\nListings:\nBrett (BRETT)\nJoltify (JOLT)\nMerlin Chain (MERL)\nOmni Network (OMNI)\nFather Of Meme Origin (FOMO)\nEvadore (EVADORE)\nBlackCardCoin (BCCOIN)","    ","HTX\nListings:\nParcl (PRCL)\nOmni Network (OMNI)\nMerlin Chain (MERL)\nReady To Fight (RTF)","         ","ProBit\nListings:\nUnify Platform Token (UPT)\nDelistings:\nEtherLite (ETL)\nAdEx (ADX)\nAeternity (AE)\nAlchemy Pay (ACH)\nDobuy (DBY)\nGCAlliance (CALL)\niCrowdCoin (ICC)\nMarshall Inu (MRI)\nSafeGame Cash (SGC)\nSkaflic (FLIC)\n","  ","VinDax\nListings:\nVerum Coin (VERUM)\nIntellique (KARA)"," ","WazirX\nListings:\nPlayDapp (PDA)\nOmni Network (OMNI)\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nPOLYX\/INR\nREI\/INR\nOP\/INR"," ","XT\nListings:\nRailgun (RAIL)\nEesee (ESE)\nDexOrdi (XODI)\niMe Smart Platform (LIME)\nKaty Perry Fans (KATYCAT)\nOmni Network (OMNI)\nSnakePepe (SPEPE)\nBlackCardCoin (BCCOIN)\nDynex (DNX)"],"entity":[{"type":"ICC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Merlin Chain (MERL)\nDegen (DEGEN","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"EPIK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bank (SMILEK)\nNeuroWeb","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Boop (BOOP","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Satoshi Nakamoto","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Pepe King","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Andy (ANDY)\nPikamoon","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"SPO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BASEFOMO)\nAltered State Machine (ASTO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Verifiable Oracle","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ASM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sidus","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CDFI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"AMAX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tooker Kurlson (TOOKER","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"RTF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DNX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"WebMind","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NAI)\nWorld Bank (","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Marshall Inu","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CAW","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Katy Perry","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Wanko Manko","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Dynex","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Crypto Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Brett (BRETT)\nJoltify","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["Altcoins","Exchange","Trading"],"authors":["Mao Orillana"]}