{"summary":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: February 26, 2024","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/crypto-exchange-listing-and-delisting-announcements-february-26-2024.htm","publishDate":"2024-02-26T19:00:19","id":17744,"type":null,"title":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: February 26, 2024","category":["Altcoin News "],"content":[""," ","Here is our weekly collection of digital asset listing and delisting, trading pair-related announcements by crypto exchanges that we found last week and today.","Have we missed something? Do you have information about new listings and\/or delistings? Let us know here.","_________________________________________","MEXC\nListings:\nBen The Dog (BENDOG)\nCobra King (COB)\nReality Metaverse (RMV)\nDeChat (DECHAT)\nStrike (SK)\nAI Analysis Token (AIAT)\nStarknet (STRK)\nDoge Payment (DOGEPAY)\nBozo Collective (BOZO)\nMetaverser DAO (MTVT)\nTriathon (GROW)\nDragon (DRAGONS)\nOctavia (VIA)\nZkGap (ZKGAP)\nSX Network (SX)\nPigcoin (PIGCOIN)\nNexusMind (NMD)\nCUDOS (CUDOS)\nZenith DEX (ZENX)\nGenesisForge (GSF)\nInscribe (INSCRIBE)\nEVDC Network (EVDC)\nNelore Coin (NLC)\nPaysenger (EGO)\nPepe the pepe (PEPEE)\nSmart Layer Network (SLN)\nOcean Finance (OF)\nSpider (SPIDER)\nQuantFlow (QAI)\nAndromeda (ANDR)\nART (AXDT)\nDark Brandon (BRANDON)\nFortuna Finance (FTNA)\n404Aliens (404A)\nCapital Rock (CRK)\nStitch (STITCH)\nDolphin (DOLPHIN)\nForgotten Playland (FP)\nLanceGree (LGR)\nVestate (VES)\nCavada (CAVADA)\nIcrypex Token (ICPX)\nXPay (WALLET)\nGold Dragon Coin (GDCB)\nLpotic (LPC)\nCyberDoge (CDOGE)\nPaLM AI (PALMAI)\nBlockchain Advanced AI (BAA)\nDelistings:\nATPAY (ATPAY)"," ","Binance\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nSTRK\/BTC\nSTRK\/USDT\nSTRK\/FDUSD\nSTRK\/TRY"," ","Bitrue\nListings:\nGames for a Living (GFAL)\nMaverick Protocol (MAV)\nSmart Layer Network (SLN)\nSX Network (SX)"," ","OKX\nListings:\nSmart Layer Network (SLN)\nRemoved Trading Pairs:\nYFII\/USDC\nYFII\/USDT"," ","Poloniex\nListings:\nSora AI Community (SORA)\nJivara (JIVA)\nStarkNet (STRK)\nPixels (PIXEL)\nxPet.Tech (XPET)\nPepeFork (PORK)\nNada Protocol (NADA)\nBeoble (BEOBLE)\nBen The Dog (BENDOG)\nSORA (SORABTC)\nMintlayer (ML)\nDeChat (CHAT)"," ","CoinEx\nListings:\nPixels (PIXEL)\nPonke (PONKE)\nSora AI Community (SORA)\nVector Reserve (VEC)\nToshi (TOSHI)\nStarkNet (STRK)\nLimeWire (LMWR)\nCommune.ai (COMAI)\nAutonolas (OLAS)\nDexCheck (DCK)\nMagic Square (SQR)\nFloor Protocol (FLC)\nenqAI (ENQAI)\nSmart Layer Network (SLN)"," ","Gate.io\nListings:\nStarkNet (STRK)\nHelium Mobile (MOBILE)"," ","BitMart\nListings:\nZbyte (DPLAT)\nPortal (PORTAL)\nAvacus (SWK)\nQuantum Uni (QUBIC)\nTektias (TEKTIAS)\nStarkNet (STRK)\nAlita (ALITA)\nShade Protocol (SHD)\nAtPay (ATPAY)\nSmart Layer Network (SLN)\nBlack Enjoy The Future (BLACK)"," ","LBank\nListings:\nThe Quantum Resistant Ledger (QRL)\nMetaMUI Token (MMUI)\nPapo Coin (PAPO)\nStarkNet (STRK)\nAlita (ALITA)\nCockroach Coin (ROACHCOIN)\nSmartset Token (SST)\nSheboshis (SHEB)\nMickey Meme (MICKEY)\nSafeMars (SAFEMARS)\nAZ Banc Services (ABS)\nBeoble (BBL)\nHTX Token (HTK)"," ","AscendEX\nListings:\nStarkNet (STRK)\nSmart Layer Network (SLN)\nMetacraft Token (MCTP)\nSora AI Community (SORA)"," ","Changelly\nListings:\nTrustSwap (SWAP)\nDogwifhat (WIF)\nClearpool (CPOOL)\nMathWallet (MATH)"," ","Crypto.com\nListings:\nStarkNet (STRK)\nbitsCrunch (BCUT)\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nPIXEL\/RONIN"," ","Crypto.com Institutional\nListings:\nbitsCrunch (BCUT)\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nPIXEL\/USDT\nAGIX\/USDT"," ","DigiFinex\nListings:\nADAMAT Messenger (ADM)\nStarkNet (STRK)\nFantastic Theme Park Coin (FTPC)"," ","FINEXBOX\nListings:\nFirst Digital USD (FDUSD)"," ","HitBTC\nListings:\nArtyfact (ARTY)\nMATH (MATH)"," ","HTX\nListings:\nSora AI Community (SORA)\nBeoble (BBL)\nDeChat (CHAT)"," ","Kraken\nListings:\nStarkNet (STRK)"," ","ProBit\nDelistings:\nEdge Coin (EDGT)\nHupayX (HPX)\n"," ","VinDax\nListings:\nEYE Network (EYE)\nBonkcon (BONKCON)\nAmaterasu Omikami (OMIKAMI)\nXfish (XFISH)"," "," ","WazirX\nListings:\nHTX DAO (HTX)\nPixels (PIXEL)"," ","XT\nListings:\nL7 (LSD)\nOrange (ORNJ)\nbitsCrunch (BCUT)\nPrometeus Network (PROM)\nSpell (SPELL)\nQuark (QUARK)"],"entity":[{"type":"USDT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"COB)\nReality Metaverse (RMV","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BAA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MAV","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nada Protocol (NADA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fortuna Finance (FTNA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Smart Layer Network (SLN","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"JIVA","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"NMD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NLC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Zenith DEX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"AZ Banc Services","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ADM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sora AI Community (SORA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Amaterasu Omikami (OMIKAMI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Brandon (BRANDON","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"First Digital USD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"LimeWire","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"SLN)\nOcean Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SLN","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Vector Reserve (VEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CRK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"GSF","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Altcoins","Exchange","Trading"],"authors":["Mao Orillana"]}