{"summary":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: March 18, 2024","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/crypto-exchange-listing-and-delisting-announcements-march-18-2024.htm","publishDate":"2024-03-19T03:02:04","id":17800,"type":null,"title":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: March 18, 2024","category":["Altcoin News "],"content":[""," ","Here is our weekly collection of digital asset listing and delisting, trading pair-related announcements by crypto exchanges that we found last week and today.","Have we missed something? Do you have information about new listings and\/or delistings? Let us know here.","_________________________________________","MEXC\nListings:\nMyDogSOL (MYDOGSOL)\nPepe Son (PEPESON)\nNibiru Chain (NIBI)\nPEPEYE 2.0 (PEPEYE2)\nEXGOLAND (EXGO)\nAros (AROS)\nPatex (PATEX)\nBaby Musk (BABYMUSK)\nASN AI (ASN)\nCrown By Third Time (CROWN2)\nZAIBOT (ZAI)\nGONE (GONE)\nStank Memes (STONKS)\nEntangle (MNGL)\nPyramidAI (PYRAMIDAI)\nSuperAI (SA)\nAlvara Protocol (ALVA)\nmyDid (SYL)\nDoge Baby (DOGEBABY)\nBanano (BAN)\nRowan Energy (RWN)\nAntara Token (ANTT)\nAITAO (AITAO)\nInferix (INFERIX)\nSolama (SOLAMA)\nGui Inu (GUI)\nSpacePi (SPACEPI)\nBABY FLOKI (BABYFLOKI)\nGrand Base (GRAND)\nWolf Wif Ballz (BALLZ)\nBOOK OF MEME (BOME)\nNexum (NEXM)\nChonky (CHONKY)\nMega Universe (MEGAUNI)\nGamer Arena (GAU)\nOneFinity (ONEFINITY)\nCornucopias (COPI)\nCipherFuse Wallet (CFW)\nDoland Tremp (TREMP)\nTonUP (TONUP)\nDUKO (DUKO)\nInteractive AI (IT)\nGAPNexus (GAP)\nHUHU Connect (HUHU)\nMain AI (MAINAI)\nBonk 2.0 (BONK2SOL)\nCrazy Bunny (CRAZY BUNNY)\nJUICE (JUICE)\nCYBONK (CYBONK)\nSorry (SORRY)\nShredn Dog (SHREDN)\nMagicLampPePe (MLPEPE)\nGarfield (GFCAT)\nSNAP (NAP)\nMinBig (MBG)\nMetaAi (MAI)\nPizza (PIZZA)\nChainSwap (CSWAP)\nMumu The Bull (MUMU)\nDoge KOng (DOGEKONG)\nPelfort (PELF)\nDoraemon Coin (DRAM)\nTRUMP PEPE (TRUMPEPE)\nNextGen (NEXTGEN)\nTrump404 (TRUMP404)\nLittle Dragon (10N8)\nNostalgia (NOSTALGIA)\nSlerf (SLERF)\nLionheart Robotics Design (LRDS)\nIQ50 (IQ50)\nTitan Trading Platform (TES)\nEther.Fi Foundation (ETHFI)\nWrapped eETH (WEETH)\nAISagaCoin (SAGA)\nCheckDot (CDT)\nPolimec (PLMC)\nPEPI (PEPI)\nGecko Inu (GECKOAVAX)\nStarHeroes (STAR)"," ","Binance\nListings:\nMetis (METIS)\nBOOK OF MEME (BOME)"," ","KuCoin\nListings:\nNibiru Chain (NIBI)\nzkLend (ZEND)\nPatex (PATEX)\nRoot Protocol (ISME)\nEntangle (kNGL)\nAEVO (AEVO)\nHTX DAO (HTX)\nUTXO (UTXO)\nSolidus Ai Tech (AITECH)\nBOOK OF MEME (BOME)\nether.fi (ETHFI)\nPolyhedra (ZK)\nPartisia Blockchain (MPC)"," ","Bitrue\nListings:\nAEVO (AEVO)\ncatwifhat (CWIF)\nNewLand (NEW)\nCornucopias (COPI)\nBOOK OF MEME (BOME)\nether.fi (ETHFI)\nSlerf (SLERF)\nVIP (VIP)\nPartisia (MPC)"," ","OKX\nListings:\nAEVO (AEVO)\nether.fi (ETHFI)"," ","Poloniex\nListings:\nBitcoinVM (BVM)\nDepinDAO (DEPD)\nMozaic Finance (MOZ)\nNodeAI (GPU)\nCloud AI (CLD)\nWorld TAO (WTAO)\n0xFair (FAIR)\nPrisma Finance (PRISMA)\nOrigin Ether (OETH)\nMumu The Bull (MUMU)\nOrca (ORCA)\nAEVO (AEVO)\nBOOK OF MEME (BOME)\nAndy on Solana (ANDYSOL)\nPORTNOY (PORTNOY)\nMOROS NET (MOROS)\nAcria.AI (ACRIA)\nBillion Dollar Inu (BINU)\nProof Of Great AI (POGAISOL)\nSlerf (SLERF)\nether.fi (ETHFI)\nSafemoon (SAFEMOON)\nWrapped eETH (WEETH)\nI Don’t Know (IDK)"," ","CoinEx\nListings:\nNibiru Chain (NIBI)\n0x0 (0X0)\nDoland Tremp (TREMP)\nBlack Dragon (BLACKDRAGON)\nBlendr Network (BLENDR)\nAEVO (AEVO)\nEntangle (ENTANGLE)\nAITECH (AITECH)\nAsMatch (ASM)\nPicasso (PICA)\nSolama (SOLAMA)\nPENG on Solana (PENG)\nBOOK OF MEME (BOME)\nzkLend (ZEND)\nWolf Wif Ballz (BALLS)\nLANDWOLF (WOLF)\nStan Cup Coin (STAN)\nIm Boden (BODEN)\nIQ50 (IQ50)\nSNAP (NAP)\nether.fi (ETHFI)\nSlerf (SLERF)"," ","Gate.io\nListings:\nPopcat (POPCAT)\nBOOK OF MEME (BOME)\nWrapped eETH (WEETH)\nSNAP (NAP)\nDigiByte (DGB)\nSlerf (SLERF)\nAEVO (AEVO)\nEntangle (GNGL)"," ","BitMart\nListings:\nSolChat (CHAT)\nSEIYAN (SEIYAN)\nSpacePi (SPACEPI)\nPLUMPY DRAGONS (LOONG)\nBitcoin Virtual Machine (BVM)\nBABYDOGWIFHAT (BABYWIF)\nMAGA VP (MVP)\nArgocoin (AGC)\nWREC (WREC)\nAEVO (AEVO)\nBlast Pepe (BEPE)\nLuna Inu (LINU)\nJust The Tip (TIPS)\nRich Rabbit (RABBIT)\nSuper Trump Coin (STRUMP)\nJUICE (JUICE)\nAlkimi (ADS)\nSolana Baby (SOLANABABY)\nCortex (CTXC)\nGorilla In A Coupe (GIAC)\nBOOK OF MEME (BOME)\nBFIC Gold (BFICGOLD)\nFuture (FUTURE)\nNAVI Protocol (NAVX)\nether.fi (ETHFI)\nNot Jim Cramer (CRAMER)\nPopcat (POPCAT)\nSatoshi Panda (SAP)\nOggy Inu (OGGYETH)\nBlendr Network (BLENDR)\nHugeWin (HUGE)\nGoing To The Moon (GTTM)\nNirvana (VANA)\nPropbase (PROPS)\nDollarMoon (DMOON)\nBounty Temple (TYT)\nAlita (ANGEL)\nLittle Dragon (10N8)\nSolamb (SOLAMB)\nProof of Great AI (POGAI)\nIQ50 (IQ50)\nOSIS (OSIS)\nSNAP (NAP)\nTRUMP PEPE (TRUMPEPE)\nNostalgia (NOS)\nBurek Obema (OBEMA)\nSlerf (SLERF)\nROBOT AI (BOTAI)\nIPMB (IPMB)"," ","LBank\nListings:\nPENG on Solana (PENG)\nAevo (AEVO)\nReality Metaverse (RMV)\nPlanktos (PLANK)\nSolar Swap (SOLARSWAP)\nCZOLANA (CZOL)\nBooby (BOOBY)\nEpep (EPEP)\nMorse (MORSE)\nMixin Kernel (XIN)\nMarpto (MRPT)\nBOOK OF MEME (BOME)\nEnergi (NRG)\nSolamb (SOLAMB)\nVIGO (VIGO)\nCatboy (CATBOY)\nAndy (ANDY)\nKPOP CUSTOMIZING COIN (KCC)\nDecubate Token (DCB)\nIQ50 (IQ50)\nOrange (ORNJ)\nDexCheck (DCK)\nSNAP (NAP)\nLevana (LVN)\nSlerf (SLERF)\nOctet (OCT)\nSimong Coin (SMC)\nAGII (AGII)\nHeHe (HEHE)\nether.fi (ETHFI)\n"," ","P2B Crypto Exchange\nListings:\nBALKAN IMPERIUM ART (BIA)\nTOTO (TOTO)\nSALVATRON (SLV)\nBFIC Gold (BFICGOLD)\nThriends (TT)\nNelore Coin (NLC)"," ","AscendEX\nListings:\nAevo (AEVO)\nArkham (ARKM)\nDBIT (DBIT)\nBOOK OF MEME (BOME)\nSNAP (NAP)\nether.fi (ETHFI)\nBrett (BRETT)\nSlerf (SLERF)"," ","BigONE\nListings:\nADANANT (ADM)","     ","Changelly\nListings:\nNeon (NEON)"," ","Crypto.com\nListings:\nAevo (AEVO)\nMOG Coin (MOG)\nBOOK OF MEME (BOME)\nShrapnel (SHRAP)\nether.fi (ETHFI)"," ","Crypto.com Institutional\nListings:\nMOG Coin (MOG)\nAevo (AEVO)\nShrapnel (SHRAP)\nBOOK OF MEME (BOME)\nSubQuery Network (SQT)\nether.fi (ETHFI)\n"," ","DigiFinex\nListings:\nPortal (PORTAL)\nSyncus DAO (SYNC)\nAevo (AEVO)\nLucky Inu (LUCKY)\nBOOK OF MEME (BOME)\nSlerf (SLERF)\nAI PictoMusic H5X Token (H5X)"," ","FINEXBOX\nListings:\nSimples (SP)\nBitvincy (BTY)","  ","HTX\nListings:\nPandora (PANDORA)\nMVL (MVL)\nBOOK OF MEME (BOME)\nMOG Coin (MOG)\nether.fi (ETHFI)\nSlerf (SLERF)\nWrapped eETH (WEETH)","    ","ProBit\nListings:\nByat (BYAT)\nDelisting:\nAscendEX token (ASD)\nBitstars (BSTS)\nFuzeX (FXT)\nKlaySwap (KSP)\nPaxos Gold (PAXG)\nLego Coin (LEGO)","  ","VinDax\nListings:\nSexy Meme AI (SEXY)\nDeranged (DERANGED)\nBITOX ECLAT LIQUIDITY TOKEN (BELT)\nECLAT (ECLAT)\nVICOM (VICOM)\nVirium DAO (VDAO)"," "," ","WazirX\nListings:\nMetis (METIS)\nBOOK OF MEME (BOME)\nSei (SEI)\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nKAS\/INR\nWIF\/INR\nBOME\/INR"," ","XT\nListings:\nPolimec (PLMC)\nRexx Ecosystem (REXX)\nether.fi (ETHFI)\nCoconut Chicken (CCC)\nSnap (NAP)\nAI Dragon (ChatGPT)\nzkLend (ZEND)\nJC Coin (JCC)\nSnoopy (SNOOPY)\nShuffle (SHFL)\nAfriq Arbitrage System Token (AAST)\nEntangle (NGL)\nNibiru Chain (NIBI)\nWorld Friendship Cash (WFCA)\nBinaryX (BNX)\nSyscoin (SYS)\nEchelon Prime (PRIME)\nSpacePi (SPACEPI)"],"entity":[{"type":"Pandora (PANDORA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wolf Wif Ballz","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"VICOM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ISME","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"AEVO)\nReality Metaverse (RMV","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Stan Cup Coin (STAN)\nIm Boden (BODEN","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Mozaic Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"KCC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"JCC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gecko Inu","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Prisma Finance (PRISMA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DGB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nibiru Chain (NIBI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ASM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BIA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wolf Wif Ballz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Satoshi Panda","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Partisia Blockchain (MPC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SAP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NLC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Third Time (","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"GPU","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jim Cramer (CRAMER","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Morse (MORSE)\nMixin Kernel","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ADM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Brett (BRETT","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"VANA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Andy (","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Crypto Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MPC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NewLand","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Doland Tremp (TREMP)\nBlack Dragon","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Altcoins","Exchange","Trading"],"authors":["Mao Orillana"]}