{"summary":"Animoca Brands Japan and Quidd to Release ‘FAIRY TAIL’ Digital Collectibles","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/animoca-brands-japan-to-release-fairy-tail-digital-collectibles.htm","publishDate":"2024-05-14T08:46:51","id":17823,"type":null,"title":"Animoca Brands Japan and Quidd to Release ‘FAIRY TAIL’ Digital Collectibles","category":["NFT News "],"content":["Animoca Brands Japan and Quidd will launch digital collectibles of the popular manga “FAIRY TAIL.”","According to a press release shared with Cryptonews.com, the Japanese subsidiary of Animoca Brands’ new collectibles will feature 29 characters from the series, including Natsu, Lucy, and Happy. The collection will be available on Quidd, starting from 5 p.m. EST on May 24, 2024.","Key scenes from the series have been chosen and turned into art cards under the guidance of FAIRY TAIL author Hiro Mashima, and are available in various rarities.","Founded in 2021, Animoca Brands Japan aimed to support the global web3 strategies of Japanese intellectual property and content holders, including publishers, brands, educational institutions, sports teams, athletes, artists, and gaming companies.","Quidd is also a subsidiary of Animoca Brands. It offers a digital collectible and NFT marketplace and features collaborations with brands like Disney and the NBA. Quidd supports both off-chain and on-chain digital collecting to multiple blockchains.","The company previously posted plans to launch a new non-fungible token (NFT) platform designed to bridge web3 projects in Japan with the global market, with an official introduction set for this summer to support creators and projects in selling their NFTs.","The launchpad has since been inviting applicants to submit their web3 projects. Once selected into the program, the platform will also provide “multifaceted support for sales strategies and marketing.”","The targeted content producers and holders include publishers, brands, educational institutions, sports teams, athletes, artists, and game companies.","On April 30, Animoca Brands announced their plans to “come to Bitcoin,” aiming to develop a diverse ecosystem of gaming, entertainment, DeFi, education, and culture on Bitcoin.","Animoca Brands is coming to #Bitcoin!","Bitcoin is ready for Web3. OPAL Protocol (@OpalBTC), powered by $BLIF and initiated by @darewise & @animocabrands, is slated to become the largest #Web3 ecosystem of #gaming, entertainment, #Defi, education, and culture, built on Bitcoin.\nA… pic.twitter.com\/WcJ65vMHfB","— Animoca Brands (@animocabrands) April 30, 2024","","The initiative, led by Animoca and the metaverse technology platform Darewise, will use the Opal Protocol and the BLIF token, along with the Opal Protocol Runes token, as the foundation for this ecosystem."],"entity":[{"type":"May 24, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"NBA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Animoca","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Animoca Brands Japan","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hiro Mashima","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Japan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Opal Protocol","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April 30","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Quidd","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$BLIF","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Animoca Brands","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lucy","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Animoca Brands Japan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"April 30, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"5 p.m. EST","content":"TIME"},{"type":"Opal Protocol Runes","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Natsu","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"summer","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Disney","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["Japan","NFT"],"authors":["Hongji Feng"]}