{"summary":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: April 8, 2024","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/crypto-exchange-listing-and-delisting-announcements-april-8-2024.htm","publishDate":"2024-04-10T06:07:04","id":17837,"type":null,"title":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: April 8, 2024","category":["Altcoin News "],"content":[""," ","Here is our weekly collection of digital asset listing and delisting, trading pair-related announcements by crypto exchanges that we found last week and today.","Have we missed something? Do you have information about new listings and\/or delistings? Let us know here.","_________________________________________","MEXC\nListings:\nShiboo (SHIBOO)\nGrok Cat (GROKCAT)\nIndex Coop (INDEX)\nDecentralised Cloud Infrastructure (DCI)\nAxo (AXO)\nTensor (TNSR)\nPixel Island (PIXL)\nDoge Mob (DOGEMOB)\nGaga (GAGA)\nAIChainMatrix (AICM)\nEnergy Web (EWT)\nBOMX (BOMX)\nR Games (RGAME)\nUnibit (UIBT)\nSolSpend (SPEND)\nHanChain (HAN)\nCatCoin (CATCOIN)\nTensorSpace (TPU)\nHODL (HODL)\nMetaDOS (SECOND)\nMusk Dao (MUSK)\nSword of Zeus (ZEUS1)\nGatsby (GATSBY)\nAI Dragon (CHATGPT)\nFash Protocol (FLASH)\nMoon Inu (MOONINU)\nDopamine (DOPE)\nPerpy (PRY)\nMonkey Empire (MKC)\nAnsems Cat (HOBBES)\nOrigin Protocol (OETH)\nRing AI (RINGAI)\ncat in a dogs world (MEW)\nMeowthWifHat (MEOWTH)\nGradient Token (GDT)\nHoneyland (HXD)\nSmog (SMOG)\nAI Exclusive (AIET)\nSatoshiSync (SSNC)\nAITA (AITA)\nxExchange (MEX)\nOrchai.io (OCH)\nANote Music (NOTES)\nNordic AI (NRDC)\nZeus Network (ZEUS)\nECOMI (ECOMI)\nBig Red (TD)\nCarnomaly (CARR)\nFIFO THE CAT (FIFO)\nBeaconDog (BDOG)\nYour AI (YOURAI)\nOsne (ONEAI)\nLandshare (LANDSHARE)\nSuper Trump Coin (STRUMP)\nSolNav (SOLNAV)\nWebMind Network (WMN)\nShadow Node (SVPN)\ndogwifhood (WIFT)\nGoNFTY (GNFTY)\nFace Token (FACE)\nGenAI (GENAI)\nMAGA ClownPepe (MCPE)\nBitcoin Cat (BTCAT)\nSodi Protocol (SODI)\nSynth AI Meme (SAMAI)\nApu Apustaja (APU)\nAIPay (AIPAY)\nCats of Sol (COS)\nSolMail (MAIL)\nBlackFort (BXN)\nHund on Sol (HUND)\nButane Token (BTN)\nSugar Kindom (SKO)\nSolSpend (SPEND)\nMCN Coin (MCN)\nRUBIKAI (RUBIKAI)\nSensay (SNSY)\nAI Varius (AVR)\nPullix (PLX)\nVersus-X (VSX)"," ","Binance\nListings:\nWormhole (W)\nTensor (TNSR)"," ","KuCoin\nListings:\nGAM3S.GG (G3)\nTensor (TNSR)\nEthena USDe (USDe)\nWorkhole (W)\nCat in a dogs world (MEW)\nZeus Network (ZEUS)\nAerodrome Finance (AERO)\nTruflation (TRUF)"," ","Bitrue\nListings:\nEthena (ENA)\nWormhole (W)\nZeus Network (ZEUS)\nTensor (TNSR)"," ","OKX\nListings:\nWormhole (W)\nZeus Network (ZEUS)\nTensor (TNSR)\nRemoved Trading Pairs:\nXETA\/USDT\nKAR\/USDT\nHC\/USDT\nVSYS\/USDT\n"," ","Poloniex\nListings:\nCatino (CATINO)\nStratos (STOS)\nMfer (MFER)\nEthena (ENA)\nBased Shiba Inu (BSHIB)\nAnsem’s Cat (HOBBES)\nLyte Finance (LYTE)\nBase God (TYBG)\nHigher (HIGHER)\nBUBCAT (BUB)\nHashAI (HASHAI)\nBlerf (BLERF)\nYai (YAI)\nSpectra Chain (SPCT)\nFren Pet (FRENPET)\nX314 (X314)\nTensor (TNSR)"," ","CoinEx\nListings:\nEthena (ENA)\nXend Finance (RWA)\nPundu (PUNDU)\nAnsem’s Cat (HOBBES)\nWormhole (W)\nZeus Network (ZEUS)\nTensor (TNSR)"," ","Gate.io\nListings:\nZeus Network (ZEUS)\nTensor (TNSR)"," ","BitMart\nListings:\nPanda Swap (PANDA)\nWormhole (W)\nMineral Token (MXTK)\nDogs in cats world (BARK)\nVibingCatToken (VCT)\nEthena USDe (USDe)\nCatino (CATINO)\nAnsem’s Cat (HOBBES)\nHoneyland (HXD)\nOkratech (ORT)\nGreen Shiba Inu (GINUX)\nTeq Network (TEQ)\nCAT KING (CATKING)\nBook of Meow (BOMEOW)\nDogwifsaudihat (WIFSA)\nZeus Network (ZEUS)\nChainge (XCHNG)\nRoseWifHat (ROSE)\nBase Peach (PEACH)\nG8 Coin (G8C)\nBitcoin Cat (BTCAT)\nCodeGenie (CODEG)\nEvernode (EVR)\nCat Hero (CATHERO)\nSkydrome (SKY)\nViridis Network (VRD)\nSolgoat (SOLGOAT)\nTensor (TNSR)"," ","LBank\nListings:\nCatscoin (CATSS)\nAnsem’s Cat (HOBBES)\nWormhole (W)\nGiveth (GIV)\nExotrust (EXOT)\nMeta Funz (FUNZ)\nBOBER (BOBER)\nMeowCat (MCAT)\nEthereum Power Inscription (ETHPI)\nBased Peaches (PEACH)\nBook Of Bonk (BOBONK)\nSonicWifHat (SONICWIF)\nKendu Inu (KENDU)\nZeus Network (ZEUS)\nTonk Inu (TONK)\nTubes (TUBES)\nIMARO (IMARO)\nMinu (MINU)\nMegalink Token (MG8)\nTensor (TNSR)\nGenesys Network (GSYS)\nLynex (LYNX)\n"," ","P2B Crypto Exchange\nListings:\nGamia (GIA)\nAlpha Omega Coin (AOC)\nGolden Paws (GPAWS)"," ","AscendEX\nListings:\nCat in dogs world (MEW)\nEthena (ENA)\nWormhole (W)\nBackstage Pass (NOTES)\nCrazy Frog (FROG)\nArtrade (ATR)\nZeus Network (ZEUS)\nMetis (METIS)\nTensor (TNSR)\nPups (PUPS)","  ","CEX.io\nListings:\nNervos.bit (CKB)\nPixels (PIXEL)"," ","Changelly\nListings:\nMagic Square (SQR)\nAevo (AEVO)\nSyntropy (NOIA)","  ","Crypto.com\nListings:\nWormhole (W)\nEthena (ENA)\nStratis (STRAX)\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nW\/USDT\nENA\/USDT"," ","Crypto.com Institutional\nListings:\nEthena (ENA)"," ","DigiFinex\nListings:\nPolyhedra Network (ZK)\nWormhole (W)\nEthena (ENA)\nCat in a dogs world (MEW)"," ","FINEXBOX\nListings:\nTechno Token (TCN)\nBitcoinPoW (BTCW)\nBlack Phoenix (BPX)","     ","HTX\nListings:\nWormhole (W)\nCat in a dogs world (MEW)\nEthena (ENA)\nJuice (JUICE)\nAltered State Machine (ASTO)"," ","Kraken\nListings:\nWormhole (W)","    ","Nexo\nListings:\nEthena (ENA)\nSei (SEI)\nWormhole (W)\nOndo (ONDO)"," ","ProBit\nListings:\nFriend3 (F3)\nHEALTHMEDI (HMD)\nDelistings:\nSODA Coin (SOC)\nSmartRentalTerminal (SRT)\nSting (STN)\nSwapcone (SWAPP)\nWishChain (WISH)\n","  ","VinDax\nListings:\nLiza Coin (LIZA)"," ","WazirX\nListings:\nWormhole (W)\nQRDO (QRDO)\nJupiter (JUP)\nStarknet (STRK)\nEthena (ENA)\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nNAKA\/INR\nQRDO\/INR"," ","XT\nListings:\nJetTon Games (JETTON)\nZeus Network (ZEUS)\nAPF Digital Agrifund (APFC)\nX314 (X314)\nUnderworld (UDW)\nKorean Chicken Protocol (KFC)\nMagicRing (MRING)\n"],"entity":[{"type":"JetTon","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Pixel Island","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Monkey Empire","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NRDC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FIFO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MCAT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jupiter","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DCI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ethena (ENA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ORT)\nGreen Shiba Inu","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hund","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Lyte Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tensor","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ondo","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"GIA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Juice (JUICE)\nAltered State Machine (ASTO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Catino (CATINO","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"KFC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDT\nENA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Xend Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MAGA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDT\nKAR\/USDT\nHC\/USDT\nVSYS\/USDT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"WebMind","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"G3","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alpha Omega Coin (AOC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"VCT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MCN","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ENA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"APF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"JETTON","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"XETA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Crypto Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"AERO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ATR","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Aerodrome Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Altcoins","Exchange","Trading"],"authors":["Mao Orillana"]}