{"summary":"Robinhood Set to List Spot Bitcoin ETFs ‘As Soon As Possible’","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/robinhood-set-to-list-spot-bitcoin-etfs-as-soon-as-possible.htm","publishDate":"2024-01-11T09:00:56","id":17870,"type":null,"title":"Robinhood Set to List Spot Bitcoin ETFs ‘As Soon As Possible’","category":["Bitcoin News "],"content":["To better integrate cryptocurrencies into traditional finance, Robinhood CEO Vlad Tenev announced that the platform will list the newly approved spot Bitcoin exchange-traded funds (ETFs) swiftly.","According to Tenev’s recent social media post, Robinhood is excited about the Securities and Exchange Commission’s final decision approving the first Bitcoin ETFs. Robinhood as a platform has long integrated crypto trading into its service and now plans to include buying and selling Bitcoin ETFs, too.","“As a pioneer in offering spot crypto trading, Robinhood is thrilled about the SEC’s decision to approve spot Bitcoin ETFs,” said Tenev. “We’ve been ahead of the curve in crypto access, and we plan to list these ETFs on Robinhood as soon as possible.”","Exciting update from Washington today! As a pioneer in offering spot crypto trading, Robinhood is thrilled about the @SECGov's decision to approve spot Bitcoin ETFs. We've been ahead of the curve in crypto access, and we plan to list these ETFs on @Robinhoodapp as soon as…","— Vlad Tenev (@vladtenev) January 10, 2024","","The listing of Bitcoin ETFs on major U.S. exchanges signifies the option and opportunity for the investors to diversify their investments by purchasing regulated exchange-traded crypto products.","While established finance institutions became Bitcoin ETF issuers, the traditional finance industry coincides and gradually embraces the crypto world.","“This milestone enhances the integration of cryptocurrencies with traditional finance,” said Tenev. “It not only offers clarity but also opens avenues for sophisticated risk management tools that benefit our customers in managing their digital asset investments.”","Other crypto leaders and executives have also expressed their perspectives following the historical regulatory step.","“The significance of this moment cannot be overstated,” said Ripple CEO Brad Garlinghouse. “Congrats to all who have worked to get Bitcoin spot ETFs approved!”","Coinbase’s executives credited Grayscale for their endeavors pushing the regulatory landscape forward. “Grayscale deserves a huge amount of credit for today, pushing this through the courts,” said Coinbase CEO Brian Armstrong.","We should all be grateful to @Grayscale for pushing back against the SEC’s arbitrary and capricious behavior, and clearing the way to get these spot BTC ETFs over the finish line. And of course to the DC Circuit, for affirming that the rule of law must prevail over politics. 2\/3","— paulgrewal.eth (@iampaulgrewal) January 10, 2024","","“We should all be grateful to Grayscale for pushing back against the SEC’s arbitrary and capricious behavior, and clearing the way to get these spot BTC ETFs over the finish line,” said Paul Grewal, Coinbase Chief Legal Officer.","“And of course to the DC Circuit, for affirming that the rule of law must prevail over politics,” said Grewal."],"entity":[{"type":"Vlad Tenev","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"January 10, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Washington","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Robinhood","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Grewal","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tenev","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Brad Garlinghouse","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Brian Armstrong","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"DC Circuit","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Paul Grewal","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Coinbase Chief Legal Officer","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Bitcoin","Bitcoin ETF","Robinhood"],"authors":["Hongji Feng"]}