{"summary":"Worldcoin Executives Meet Malaysian Leaders Amid Privacy Concerns","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/worldcoin-executives-meet-malaysian-leaders-amid-privacy-concerns.htm","publishDate":"2024-04-24T06:50:57","id":17968,"type":null,"title":"Worldcoin Executives Meet Malaysian Leaders Amid Privacy Concerns","category":["Blockchain News "],"content":["Worldcoin executives have met with top Malaysian officials amid ongoing privacy concerns and regulatory challenges.","According to a recent social media post by the Malaysia Digital Economy Corporation, the engagement highlighted the key role of MDEC’s programs, demonstrating potential collaboration opportunities including strategic expansion into Malaysia.","The Deputy General Secretary of the Ministry of Digital, Malaysia Digital Economy Corporation CEO Ts. Mahadhir Aziz, and Director General of the Department of Personal Data Protection Mohd Nazri bin Kama attended the meeting.","Exciting discussions today as we met with Nordstar and its impressive lineup of portfolio companies including Nothing, Airwallex, and Worldcoin.","The meeting was attended by YB Tuan Gobind Singh Deo, Minister of Digital; YBrs. Tuan Ma Sivanesan, pic.twitter.com\/GOpn6L6qmR","— Malaysia Digital Economy Corporation (@mymdec) April 23, 2024","","“Exciting discussions today as we met with Nordstar and its impressive lineup of portfolio companies including Nothing, Airwallex, and Worldcoin,” the post reads. “The meeting was attended by YB Tuan Gobind Singh Deo, Minister of Digital; YBrs. Tuan Ma Sivanesan.”","The post included images of Alex Blania, the lead developer of Worldcoin and the co-founder and CEO of Tools of Humanity, having conversations with the Malaysian leaders.","“The session explored MDEC’s impactful programmes, its pivotal role in nurturing the venture capital and start-up landscape, and avenues for collaboration, including strategic expansion plans into Malaysia,” the post reads.","Previously, Blania and OpenAI CEO Sam Altman had a 30-minute virtual discussion via video conference with the Malaysian government, touching on several matters related to the rapid development of technology.","During the meeting, Altman and Blania elaborated on the development of the Worldcoin project focuses on creating a global and inclusive financial network, prioritizing confidentiality and the protection of private information in its latest identity initiative.","Ethereum co-founder Vitalik Buterin recently acknowledged Worldcoin’s efforts to secure user data privacy, recognizing their improvements.","Buterin specifically noted that Worldcoin, co-founded by OpenAI’s Sam Altman, has performed “quite a good job” in implementing cryptographic measures to ensure the confidentiality of user data.","“IMO [In my opinion] they actually have been doing quite a good job of taking the privacy critiques seriously and designing their system to be more and more data-minimal,” said Buterin."],"entity":[{"type":"Alex Blania","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Blania","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Mahadhir Aziz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ma Sivanesan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Malaysia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Department of Personal Data Protection Mohd Nazri","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Airwallex","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Vitalik Buterin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Worldcoin","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Altman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Worldcoin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"IMO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Buterin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Altman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"April 23, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ministry of Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nordstar","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tuan Ma Sivanesan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tuan Gobind Singh Deo","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Malaysia Digital Economy Corporation","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Malaysia","OpenAI","Worldcoin"],"authors":["Hongji Feng"]}