{"summary":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: April 29, 2024","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/crypto-exchange-listing-and-delisting-announcements-april-29-2024.htm","publishDate":"2024-04-29T19:00:41","id":17987,"type":null,"title":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: April 29, 2024","category":["Altcoin News "],"content":[""," ","Here is our weekly collection of digital asset listing and delisting, trading pair-related announcements by crypto exchanges that we found last week and today.","Have we missed something? Do you have information about new listings and\/or delistings? Let us know here.","_________________________________________","MEXC\nListings:\nNyan Cat (NCAT)\nVitruvian Nexus (VNPT)\nBitMin Wallet (BMN)\nBowled (BWLD)\nEvercraft (ECET)\nKittenWifHat (KITTENWIF)\nBreach Bitsat (AIBIT)\nGODZ DAO (GODZ)\nGaimin (GMRX)\nDefispot (SPOT)\nPlaybux (PBUX)\nBRC-20 DEX (BD20)\nY8U.AI (Y8U)\nBlackCardCoin (BCCOIN)\nHemule (HEMULE)\nReady to Fight (RTF)\nExverse (EXVG)\nSpeedy (SPEEDY)\nGummy (GUMMY)\nPanda Swap (PANDA)\nTrumpCat (TRUMPCAT)\nSafe (SAFE)\nPlanet Mojo (MOJO)\nDrive3 (DRV3)\nManeki (MANEKI)\nSlerf NFT (SLERFNFT)\nCosmic Network (COSMIC)\nRieDog (RIE)\nStoryFire (BLAZE)\nLetit Trade (LETIT)\nPointPay (PXP)\nStake Vault Network (SVN)\nEarlyFans (EARLY)\nWorldwide Stablecoin Payment Network (WSPN)\nAcornBits (ACORNBITS)\nAce Dog (AOG)\nDigital Sat (SATXAI)\nStar Fate (SFE)\nRadiant (RXD)\nMeson Network (MSN)\nThe Dork Lord (DLORD)\nShimmer (SMR)\nDurov (DUROV)\nCampusAI (CMAI)\nGarfield Cat (GCAT)\nWLDT Chain (WLDT)\nRenzo (REZ)\nFluffys (FLUFF)\nSNORT (SNORT)\nGame of Memes (GOME)"," ","KuCoin\nListings:\nPlaybux (PBUX)\nLightLink (LL)\nSafe (SAFE)\nGameta (HIP)\nMeson Network (MSN)\nRealio Network (RIO)"," ","Bitrue\nListings:\nSafe (SAFE)\nPulsara (SARA)\nSatoshi Nakamoto (SATOSHI)\nDog Go to the Moon (DOG)\nRunecoin (RUNE)\nManeki (MANEKI)"," ","OKX\nListings:\nSafe (SAFE)\nMeson Network (MSN)"," ","Poloniex\nListings:\nManeki (MANEKI)\nSafe (SAFE)\nArtrade (ATR)\nSki Mask Dog (SKI)\nNoggles (NOGS)\nVulcan Forged (LAVA)\nDucke (DUCKE)\nElon (ELONETH)\nMeson Network (MSN)\nYes But (YESBUT)\nCatGPT (CATGPT)\nFluffys (FLUFF)\nBased Bunny (BUNNY)\nCoolman (COOL)\nMichi (MICHI)"," ","CoinEx\nListings:\nSafe (SAFE)\nManeki (MANEKI)\nApeiron (APRS)\nPyrin Network (PYI)\nFjord Foundry (FJO)\nPacmoon (PAC)\nOre (ORE)\nFren Pet (FP)\nDog Go to the Moon (DOG)\nKarrat (KARRAT)\nPlaybux (PBUX)\nKeyboard Cat (KEYCAT)\n"," ","Gate.io\nListings:\nSafe (SAFE)\nDog Go to the Moon (DOG)\nMeson Network (MSN)"," ","BitMart\nListings:\nCatGPT (CATGPT)\nSeal (SEAL)\nLayer One X (L1X)\nGarfield Cat (GARFIELD)\nGTA Token (GTA)\nBritt (BRITT)\nOrbitt (ORBT)\nPlaybux (PBUX)\nTrumpCat (TRUMPCAT)\nBeaVer (BVR)\nDogita (DOGITA)\nManeki (MANEKI)\nSafe (SAFE)\nKittenWifHat (KITTENWIF)\nBaby Slerf (BABYSLERF)\nSpeedy (SPEEDY)\nFjord Foundry (FJO)\nDoland Tremp (TREMP)\nSOLBULL (SOLBULL)\nScorpion (SCORP)\nQuby AI (QYAI)\nElon (ELON)\nBasenji (BENJI)\nBitbama (BAMA)\nPandacoin Inu (PANDAS)\nDOG•GO•TO•THE•MOON (DOG)\nMeson Network (MSN)\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nAKTIO\/USDC\n"," ","LBank\nListings:\nHedera Hashgraph (HBAR)\nTheta Token (THETA)\nMerlin Chain (MERL)\nCatGPT (CATGPT)\nMeson Network (MSN)\nIZE Fintech Blockchain (IZE)\nRenzo (REZ)\nGolden MagFi (GMFI)\nWebMind Network (WMN)\nBitcoin EDen Rich (BITBEDR)\nColumbus (COBS)\nSafe Token (SAFE1)\nManeki (MANEKI)\nRipplereum (RPRM)\nMO (MO)\nBitMinerX (BMX)\nGolden MagFi (GMFI)\nRenewable Energy Token (RETTOKEN)\nPepe Neko (PEKO)\nBitcoin 2 (BII)\nGodefi Swap (GO20)\nElectric Vehicle Direct Currency (EVDC)\nSpacePi (SPACEPI)"," ","P2B Crypto Exchange\nListings:\nCerticos (CERT)\nBlack Card Coin (BCCOIN)\nElon Cat Finance (ECAT)\nSolbull (SOLBULL)\nWorldwide USD (WUSD)\nAITTCOIN (AITT)"," ","AscendEX\nListings:\nGummy (GUMMY)\nManeki (MANEKI)\nDOTA (DOTA)\nNub Cat (NUB)\nFather Of Meme Origin (FOMO)\nKeyboard Cat (KEYCAT)\nNoggles (NOGS)\nFluffys (FLUFF)\nUBIX Network (UBX)\nMeson Network (MSN)\nRoboAI (RBAI)","    ","CEX.io\nListings:\nThe Open Network (TON)\nDogwifcoin (WIF)"," ","Crypto.com\nListings:\nKarrat (KARRAT)\nSafe (SAFE)\nManeki (MANEKI)\nCrow with knife (CAR)"," ","Crypto.com Institutional\nListings:\nKarrat (KARRAT)\nCrow with knife (CAW)"," ","DigiFinex\nListings:\nReal Carbon Zero Integration (RZI)"," ","FINEXBOX\nListings:\nArbitrum (ARB)\nDiamond Token (DIMT)","    ","ProBit\nListings:\nUnify Platform Token (UPT)\nDelistings:\nAskobar Network (ASKO)\nAtari (ATRI)\nEsports Players League (ARENA)\nShipItPro (SHPP)\nTopcoin (TCT)\nU-Pick (UPK)\n","  ","VinDax\nListings:\nPuppy Coin (PUP)\nSD Coin (SDC)\nWorldwide USD (WUSD)"," ","WazirX\nListings:\nCat in a dogs world (MEW)\n ","XT\nListings:\nNolus Protocol (NLS)\nFlare Fox Inu (FLX)\nSpace Floki (SPACEFLOKI)\nQuBy AI (QYAI)\nProperty System Platform (PS)"],"entity":[{"type":"Maneki (MANEKI","content":"PERSON"},{"type":")\nElectric Vehicle Direct Currency (EVDC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coolman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Vulcan","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MSN","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"VNPT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Renewable Energy Token (RETTOKEN)\nPepe Neko (PEKO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Atari (ATRI)\nEsports Players League","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fjord Foundry (FJO)\nDoland Tremp","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SARA)\nSatoshi Nakamoto","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Columbus","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Nolus Protocol (NLS)\nFlare Fox Inu","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Maneki","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Michi (MICHI)","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"RTF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"WebMind","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CAW","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ASKO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DEX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BRC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Crypto Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Slerf NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ATR","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BVR","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Altcoins","Exchange","Trading"],"authors":["Mao Orillana"]}