{"summary":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: March 11, 2024","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/crypto-exchange-listing-and-delisting-announcements-march-11-2024.htm","publishDate":"2024-03-12T02:12:06","id":18031,"type":null,"title":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: March 11, 2024","category":["Altcoin News "],"content":["","Here is our weekly collection of digital asset listing and delisting, trading pair-related announcements by crypto exchanges that we found last week and today.","Have we missed something? Do you have information about new listings and\/or delistings? Let us know here.","_________________________________________","MEXC\nListings:\nHeadStarter (HST)\nChimpzee (CHMPZ)\nyPredict (YPRED)\nFandomdao (FAND)\nMegaHero (MEGAHERO)\nUPDOG (UPDOG)\nZEBU (ZEBU)\nEtherKEY (ETK)\nCatboy (CATBOY)\nMAGA (MAGA)\nAimemes (AIMEMES)\nBounty Temple (TYT)\nGameluk (GAME)\nSTFX (STFX)\nBonkwifhat (BIF)\nSolanaCEO (SOLANACEO)\nEdu3Labs (NFE)\nBULLSHI (BULLSHI)\nZatin Coin (ZTN)\nDOLZ.io (DOLZ)\nNibiru Chain (NIBI)\nGPU AI (GPUAI)\nPepe On SOL (PEPESOL)\nBaby Sora (BABYSORA)\nPaPrika (PPAI)\nLink AI (LKI)\nScallop (SCA)\nBRCStarter (BRCST)\nETHEREUM AI (ETHEREUMAI)\nDonald Trump 2.0 (DT2024)\nEvadore (EVADORE)\nLuma (LUA)\nCatBit (CB)\nGinux (GINUX)\nConscious Network (CVN)\nMetars GO (MRS)\nGrin (GRIN)\nRAMADAM (RAMADAM)\nPeng (PENG)\nBID Protocol (BIDP)\nNIRVANA ( VANA)\nAevo (AEVO)\nOrdibank (ORBK)\nTatsu (TATSU)\nWAGMI Games (WAGMIGAMES)\nAITK (AITK)\nivendPay (IVPAY)\nTupan Community Token (TCT)\nUltrix (ULR)\nDecentraCard (DCARD)\nTiFi Token (TIFI)"," ","Binance\nListings:\nMetis (METIS)\nDogwifcoin (WIF)"," ","KuCoin\nListings:\nNibiru Chain (NIBI)\nzkLend (ZEND)\nRoot Protocol (ISME)\nPatex (PATEX)"," ","Bitrue\nListings:\nWAM (WAM)\nDexCheck (DCK)\nSolama (SOLAMA)\neSync Network (ECS)"," ","Poloniex\nListings:\nSolChat (SOLCHAT)\nChildrens Aid Foundation (CAF)\nBounty Temple (TYT)\nHemule (HEMULE)\nAlvara (ALVA)\nPortal (PORTAL)\nUPDOG (UPDOG)\nOpsec (OPSEC)\nPeng (PENG)\nBrett (BRETT)\nScallop (SCA)\nClosedAI (CLOSEDAI)\nSyncus DAO (SYNC)"," ","CoinEx\nListings:\nNetMind.AI (NMT)\nSolChat (CHAT)\nShib (LEASH)\nMerlin Chain (VOYA)\nNOCHILL (NOCHILL)\nGT Protocol (GTAI)\nNINJA (NINJA)\nMetaDAO (META)\nBrett (BRETT)\nZynCoin (ZYN)\nHuhu Chat (HUHU)\nShutter (SHU)\nBeoble (BBL)"," ","Gate.io\nListings:\nAether Games (AEG)\nCoq Inu (COQ)\nPatex (PATEX)"," ","BitMart\nListings:\nDUKO (DUKO)\nNetMind Token (NMT)\nJLT (JLT)\nPullix (PLX)\nThe EYE (THEYE)\nTanpin (TANPIN)\nKermit (KERMIT)\nPepe Son (PEPESON)\nMNet (NUUM)\nMaxxChain (PWR)\nBitcoin Future (BTCF)\nNot Financial Advice (NFAI)\nBaby Trump (BABYTRUMP)\nClip Token (CLIP)\nInvestive (IN)\nNeversol (NEVER)\nTo The Moon (TTM)\nBased Brett (BRETT)\nSpacePi (SPACEPI)\nPlumpy Dragons (LOONG)\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nBTC\/WUSD\n"," ","LBank\nListings:\nDoge Killer (LEASH)\nJLT Token (JLT)\nNode AI (GPU)\nYES (YES)\nZIPI (ZIPI)\nBrett (BRETT)\nScarcity (SCARCITY)\nPopcat (POPCAT)\nBonk 2.0 (BONK2)\nJeo Boden (BODEN)\nMNet Continuum (NUUM)\nCatwifhat (CWIF)\nVOYA (VOYA)\nSuper Trump (STRUMP)\nBaby Musk (BABYMUSK)\nScallop (SCA)\nInvest Club Global (ICG)\nWAGMI Games (WAGMIGAMES)\nSyncus DAO (SYNC)\nChinu (CHINU)\nHugeWin (HUGE)\nBaby (BABY)\nArtcoin (AC)"," ","P2B Crypto Exchange\nListings:\nBotopia (BTOP)\nGT Protocol (GTAI)\nJLT Token (JLT)\nScarcity (SCARCITY)"," ","AscendEX\nListings:\nGT Protocol (GTAI)\nNetMind Token (NMT)\nMia (MIA)\nSyncus DAO (SYNC)","  ","BigONE\nListings:\nScarcity (SCARCITY)","         ","Changelly\nListings:\nEnjin (ENJ)\nStarknet (STRK)\nDelysium (AGI)\nPixels (PIXEL)","  ","Crypto.com\nListings:\nMyro (MYRO)\nCoq Inu (COQ)"," ","Crypto.com Institutional\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nAXL\/USDT\nLADYS\/USDT\nHNT\/USDT\nMOBILE\/USDT\nSTRK\/USDT\n"," ","DigiFinex\nListings:\nScarcity (SCARCITY)\nMotorcoin (MTRC)","   ","HitBTC\nListings:\nGrapeCoin (GRAPE)\nDelysium (AGI)\n","  ","HTX\nListings:\nPortal (PORTAL)\nScallop (SCA)\nAEVO (AEVO)","      ","ProBit\nListings:\nSTANDUP (STDU)\nMineable (MNB)\nMojaik (FEE)\nFANTARA (FTR)\nEmpty (EMT)","  ","VinDax\nListings:\nAutism (ASD)"," ","WazirX\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nTON\/USDT\nWIF\/USDT\nSUI\/USDT\nPYTH\/USDT"," ","XT\nListings:\nUnix Gaming (UNIX)\nEthpi (ETHPI)\nCoconut Chicken (CCC)\nClash of Lilliput (COL)\nDoichain (DOI)\nScarcity (SCARCITY)\nDexCheck (DCK)\nNervos Network (CKB)\nHugeWin (HUGE)\nNosana (NOS)\nSynesis One (SNS)\nRun Tu Coin (RTC7)\nSyncus DAO (SYNC)\nTonUP (TONUP)"],"entity":[{"type":"Brett (BRETT)\nZynCoin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"AEG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SCA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ISME","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SCA)\nInvest Club","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ICG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kermit (KERMIT)\nPepe","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tupan Community Token","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Aether","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BIF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nibiru Chain (NIBI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"HeadStarter (HST","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jeo Boden (BODEN","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"GPU","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Brett (BRETT","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"VANA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Donald Trump","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"AXL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Opsec (OPSEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MaxxChain (PWR","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Crypto Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MAGA (MAGA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"RAMADAM","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Childrens Aid Foundation (CAF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MTRC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDT\nSUI\/USDT\nPYTH\/USDT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lilliput","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["Altcoins","Exchange","Trading"],"authors":["Mao Orillana"]}