{"summary":"Colombia’s Bancolombia Launches Crypto Exchange Wenia and Stablecoin COPW","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/colombias-bancolombia-launches-crypto-exchange-wenia-and-stablecoin-copw.htm","publishDate":"2024-05-07T19:24:14","id":18067,"type":null,"title":"Colombia’s Bancolombia Launches Crypto Exchange Wenia and Stablecoin COPW","category":["Blockchain News "],"content":["Bancolombia Group, Colombia’s largest bank, launched the cryptocurrency exchange Wenia on May 3, marking a major step in the country’s crypto evolution.","According to the announcement, the development follows nearly a decade of research and signifies the bank’s dedication to Colombia’s crypto market.","Wenia, alongside the newly introduced Colombian peso stablecoin COPW, which has a 1:1 parity to the Colombian peso, seeks to attract 60,000 users in its first year. The platform’s goal is to compete with major crypto exchanges like Binance and Coinbase, offering trading in Bitcoin, USD Coin, Polygon, Ether, and, of course, the COPW stablecoin.","By catering to both experienced and novice traders, Wenia seeks to solidify Colombia’s position as a leader in crypto adoption within Latin America.","Access to the exchange requires Colombian residency, aligning with the nation’s rising prominence in the global crypto market. Colombia currently holds third place in the 2023 Global Crypto Adoption Index among Latin American countries, demonstrating considerable interest in crypto assets within the region.","","Juan Carlos Mora, president of Bancolombia Group, highlighted the bank’s decade-long journey to develop a platform that facilitates the adoption of digital assets and blockchain technology. This move underscores Bancolombia’s commitment to innovation within the Colombia crypto sphere.","While this development presents exciting opportunities, Bancolombia emphasized the importance of understanding the risks associated with digital assets. These assets lack deposit insurance and carry inherent risks like volatility and potential loss. Additionally, no entity within the Bancolombia Group participates directly in digital asset transactions. The bank also cautioned traders about the absence of government backing or guaranteed safe storage methods for these assets.","Additionally, a lawyer posted on LinkedIn about Wenia’s independent status as an entity registered in Bermuda. Any legal claims or disputes would fall under the jurisdiction of Bermuda courts, involving Wenia directly, not Bancolombia."],"entity":[{"type":"May 3","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Polygon","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Latin America","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bermuda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Juan Carlos Mora","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Colombia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Wenia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bancolombia","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USD Coin","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bancolombia Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["CEXs","Colombia","Stablecoin"],"authors":["Thomas Musgrave"]}