{"summary":"Solana’s Meme Coin ‘Bonk’ Spikes 15% On Revolut Listing Report","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/solanas-meme-coin-bonk-spikes-15-on-revolut-listing-report.htm","publishDate":"2024-02-15T05:02:05","id":18088,"type":null,"title":"Solana’s Meme Coin ‘Bonk’ Spikes 15% On Revolut Listing Report","category":["Altcoin News "],"content":["Financial technology startup and neobank, Revolut plans to list Solana-based meme coin “Bonk” on its trading platform, according to a CoinDesk report, citing a person familiar with the matter.","Following the news Bonk could be listed on Revolut, the meme coin spiked and is trading up 15% in the last 24 hours, according to data from Coingecko.","Bonk will run a $1.2 million campaign to incentivize its users to learn about the cryptocurrency. The “learn” campaign will distribute up to 93 billion Bonk tokens to users, according to the report.","During the time of publication, a spokesperson from Revolut was unavailable to comment on speculation the Bonk meme coin will be listed on its trading platform.","On December 14, Bonk gained more than 45% in 24 hours following the announcement of its listing on the prominent exchange Coinbase. The move positioned Bonk as the third-largest meme coin, trailing only Dogecoin and Shiba Inu, to be offered on the platform.","The decentralized autonomous organization (DAO) behind Bonk has a proposal to launch the token on a trading platform. The proposal aims to onboard 500,000 new BONK users through a Learn and Earn campaign, as reported by The Defiant.","“Bonk will be launching on one of the biggest European fintechs with more than 38m users, operating under a banking license and live in more than 50 countries. The focus of the campaign will be to onboard 500,000 new BONK Users, significantly increasing the active holder base through a Learn and Earn Campaign.” — BonkDAO proposal.","It is unclear at this stage if the Meme coin will be listed on the European fintech platform Revolut.","Bonk is the first Solana dog coin for the people, by the people with 50% of the total supply airdropped to the Solana community. The tokens can be traded on centralized crypto exchanges. The most popular exchange to buy and trade Bonk is MEXC, where the most active trading pair BONK\/USDT has a trading volume of $1,773,775 in the last 24 hours. Other popular options include Binance and Coinbase Exchange. The market capitalization of Bonk is $862,173,747 and is ranked at 95 on CoinGecko today.","On Wednesday, Joel Frank from Cryptonews reported, that as Bonk fails to keep pace with the broader cryptocurrency market’s rally, many Bonk holders are migrating to a new meme coin called Meme Kombat (MK) to hunt potential 100x returns.","On Thursday, Bitcoin soared past the $52,000 mark, propelling its market cap beyond the $1 trillion milestone. This leap occurred in the wake of spot Bitcoin ETF approvals and in anticipation of the expected halving event in April."],"entity":[{"type":"last 24 hours","content":"DATE"},{"type":"93 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$1,773,775","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Coinbase Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1.2 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"50%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Bonk","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Joel Frank","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"15%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"December 14","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Shiba Inu","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"BONK\/USDT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1 trillion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$862,173,747","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Coingecko","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dogecoin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"today","content":"DATE"},{"type":"45%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Bonk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$52,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"BONK Users","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["BONK Coin","Meme Coins","Solana"],"authors":["Tanzeel Akhtar"]}