{"summary":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: April 1, 2024","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/crypto-exchange-listing-and-delisting-announcements-april-1-2024.htm","publishDate":"2024-04-02T04:10:23","id":18113,"type":null,"title":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: April 1, 2024","category":["Altcoin News "],"content":[""," ","Here is our weekly collection of digital asset listing and delisting, trading pair-related announcements by crypto exchanges that we found last week and today.","Have we missed something? Do you have information about new listings and\/or delistings? Let us know here.","_________________________________________","MEXC\nListings:\nWormhole (W)\nLampapuy (LPP)\nTesla Meme (TSLA)\nDucky City (DCM)\nNubcat (NUB)\nRex (REX)\nGram (GRAM)\nMfercoin (MFER)\nMTMS Netw0rk (MTMS)\nAquarius Loan (ARS)\nOraichain (ORAI)\nAny Inu (AINU)\nDiCaprio (CHEERZ)\nNettensor (NAO)\nEmerald (EMRLD)\nBella Doge (BOG)\nSariel (SARIEL)\nMeow Of Meme (MEOWMEME)\nBoba Cat (PSPS)\nzkSwap Finance (ZF)\nTrippy Labs (SHROOM)\nDor Technologies (DOR)\nRobot AI (BOTAI)\nLOOPY (LOOPY)\nBoge (BOGE)\nCtomorrow Platform (CTP)\nEthena Labs (ENA)\nKetta (KETTA)\nStrikeX (STRX)\nLinqAI (LNQ)\nSpaceCatch (CATCH)\nBitBrawl (BRAWL)\nKoala AI (KOKO)\nJizzLord (JIZZLORD)\nWinnie The Moon (WINNE)\nCommune AI (COMAI)\nCOSS Chain (COSS)\nCoq Inu (COQ)\nSolamb (SOLAMB)\nCryptiClown (CRYPTICLOWN)\nLegends of Elysium (LOE)\nOPEN Ecosystem Token (OPN1)\nDEV (DEV)\nUplink Finance (UPFI)\nARTINO STUDIO AI (ARTINO)\nBitcoin Flash (BITCOINFLASH)\nMixin (XIN)\nFRGX Finance (FRGX)\nStronghold (SHX)\nStobox (STBU)\nCastle of Blackwater (COBE)\nSonic Goat (SGOAT)\nHomer Simpson (HOME)\nCatWifHat (CATWIF)\nROD.AI (RODAI)\nGTA AI (GA)\nSyntax AI (XSYNTX)\nBlendr Network (BLENDR)\nMussel.so (MUSSEL)\nDegen (DEGENBASE)\nBAO LFG (BAOLFG)\nClouds (CDS)\nBig Pump (BIGPUMP)\nAlienForm (A4M)\nZorro (ZORRO)\nOrangeDX (O4DX)\nAlgentX (AIGENTX)\nPundu (PUNDU)\nHover (HOV)\nSpartaDex (SPARTA)\nScotty AI (SCOTTYAI)\nDingocoin (DINGO)\nGreen Grey MetaGame (GGMT)\nRoost (ROOST)\nRTC DAO (RTC)\nNumberGoUpTech (TECH)\nBULLRUN (BULLRUN)\nZypto (ZYPTO)\nTitanium22 (TI)\nBlood Crystal (BC)\nSoldoge (SOLDOGE)\nUSD Mapped Token (USDM)\nIndexAI (IAI)\nDelistings:\nHachiAI (MEMEHA)\nFunft (FFT)\nLENDEX (LEND)\ndHealth (DHP)\n"," ","Binance\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nBONK\/USDC\nFLOKI\/USDC\nFTM\/USDC\nMKR\/TRY\nRAY\/TRY\nRNDR\/BRL\nETHFI\/USDT\n"," ","KuCoin\nListings:\nBitBrawl (BRAWL)\nSmolecoin (SMOLE)\nVenom Blockchain (VENOM)\nEthena (ENA)\nJohnny Coin (JOHNNY)\nEthena USDe (USDe)\n ","Bitrue\nListings:\nSmurf Cat (SMURF)\nAVAX Has No Chill (NOCHILL)\nAlephium (ALPH)\nRoost (ROOST)\nCrypto Hunters (CRH)\nMfercoin (MFER)\nPoopcoin (POOP)"," ","OKX\nListings:\nWormhole (W)"," ","Poloniex\nListings:\nBig Pump (PUMP)\nJoe Boden (BODEN)\nBasedAI (BASEDAI)\nRex (REX)\niMe Lab (LIME)\nCat in a dogs world (MEW)\nDoginme (DOGINME)\nFomo (FOMO)\nBased Fink (FINK)\nSolmail (MAIL)\nScalia (SCALE)\nSORA (SORABTC)\nAltura (ALU)\nDawkoins (DAW)\nRoost Coin (ROOST)\nGrumpy Cat (GRUMPY)\nArchitex (ARCX)\nChainSwap (CSWAP)\nTensorSpace (TPU)\nSom Bonkmon Fraud (SBFSOL)\nIX Swap (IXS)\nShiva Inu (SHIV)\nSholana (SHOL)\nThe Doge NFT (DOG)\nMOGGO (MOGGO)"," ","CoinEx\nListings:\nGaimin (GMRX)\nBig Pump (PUMP)\nCat in dogs world (MEW)\nNormie (NORMIE)\nDoginme (DOGINME)\nIX Swap (IXS)\nMantra (OM)\nCreditcoin (CTC)\nMerlinSwap (MP)\nClearpool (CPOOL)\nEpep (EPEP)\nLonk (LONK)\nStarHeroes (STAR)\nZeek The ZK Cat (MEOW)"," ","Gate.io\nListings:\nJuice Finance (JUICE)\nAerodrome (AERO)\nShadow Token (SHDW)\nMfercoin (MFER)\nEthena (ENA)\nDegen (DEGEN)\nWormhole (W)"," ","BitMart\nListings:\nChimera (CULT)\nPartisia Blockchain (MPC)\nAerodrome (AERO)\nNubcat (NUB)\nBig Pump (PUMP)\nAlphaScan AI (ASCN)\nSolordi (SOLO)\nPundu (PUNDU)\nPepe Sora AI (PEPESORA)\nAxo (AXO)\nSpaceCatch (CATCH)\nAirbloc (ABL)\nMussel.so (MUSSEL)\nBeFi Labs (BEFI)\nSoccermania (SOCCERMANIA)\nSOLANAX (SOLANAX)\nBHO Network (BHO)\nCat Coin (CAT)\nAI Dragon (CHATGPT)\nCrazyPepe (CRAZYPEPE)\nCat Pepe (CATPEPE)\nBlue Floki (BLUEFLOKI)\nKena AI (KENA)\nRex (REX)\nGRIMACE (GRIMACE)\nOrangeDX (O4DX)\nXend Finance(RWA)\nRoost Coin (ROOST)\nKORRA (KORRA)\nDogemob (DOGEMOB)\nChainSwap (CSWAP)\nNibiru Chain (NIBI)\nEthena Labs (ENA)\nHomer of Meme (HOME)\nCrypto Hunters Coin (CRH)\nK9 Finance DAO (FNINE)\nFools (FOOLS)\nTholos (THOL)\nShibasso (SHIBASSO)\nQCAT Coin (QCAT)\nCat in dogs world (MEW)\nCirque Du Sol (CIRCUS)\nPanda Swap (PANDA)"," ","LBank\nListings:\nDegen (DEGEN)\nCat in dogs world (MEW)\nCatwifbag (BAG)\n300FIT Network (FIT)\nBitCo2 (BITCO2)\nPundu (PUNDU)\nRoost Coin (ROOST)\nBits (BITS)\nBDPlayground (BDP)\nBianco (BIANCO)\nRex (REX)\nTitan Token (TITAN)\nGyreToken (GYR)\nMAGA VP (MVP)\nBasenji (BENJI)\nAIgentX (AIX)\nJizzlord (JIZZLORD)\nICRYPEX Global (ICPX)\nBlackFort Exchange Network (BXN)\nFireChatToken (FCT)\nShark Cat (SC)\nJake The Dog (JAKE)\nLOOPY (LOOPY)\nNubcat (NUB)\nMAGA Memecoin (TRUMP)\nEthena (ENA)"," ","P2B Crypto Exchange\nListings:\nSoComfy (COMFY)\nMetaground Coin (MG)\nAvax Lama (LAMA)\nTaubium (TAUB)\nDark Universe (DMV)\nSave Elon Coin (SEC)\nTitan Token (TITAN)\nCathena Gold (CGO)"," ","AscendEX\nListings:\nChimera (CULT)\nRoost (ROOST)\nOndo (ONDO)\nZynCoin (ZYN)\nHigher (HIGHER)\nBase God (TYBG)\nToshi Base (TOSHI)\nPizzaVerse (PIZZA)\nNormie (NORMIE)\nCODING DINO (DINOBASE)\nMfercoin (MFER)\nCatWifHat (CATWIF)\nPoopcoin (POOP)\nMerlinSwap (MP)\nRayn (AKTIO)","  ","Bitfinex\nListings:\nCoq Inu (COQ)","     ","CEX.io\nListings:\nLivepeer (LPT)\nTHORChain (RUNE)\nBlur (BLUR)\nMantle (MNT)\nXAI (XAI)"," ","Changelly\nListings:\nSleepless AI (AI)\nNosana (NOS)\nArcBlock (ABT)","  ","Crypto.com\nListings:\nSubQuery Network (SQT)\nWen (WEN)\nShadow Token (SHDW)\nAerodrome Finance (AERO)\nMfercoin (MFER)\nDegen (DEGEN)"," ","DigiFinex\nListings:\nDimitra (DMTR)\nDigital Standard (DSB)\nRadiant Blockchain (RXD)\nRayn (AKTIO)\nWormhole (W)"," ","FINEXBOX\nListings:\nGold Cart Victorias (GCV)"," ","HTX\nListings:\nMfercoin (MFER)\nBig Pump (PUMP)\nPundu (PUNDU)","   ","Nexo\nListings:\nOndo (ONDO)","   ","ProBit\nListings:\nHODLpad (HODL)\nDelistings:\nLisk (LSK)\nYocoin (YOC)\nXTRM (XTRM)\nCreamPYE (PYE)\n","  ","VinDax\nListings:\nNAPKON (NAP)\nWesp (WESP)\nRSG Token (RSG)\nWhite Yorkshire (WSH)"," ","WazirX\nListings:\nNakamoto Games (NAKA)\nbitsCrunch (BCUT)"," ","XT\nListings:\nTK Coin (TKC)\nSpaceCatch (CATCH)\nZero1 Token (DEAI)\nSwiss Cheese (SWCH)\nPundu (PUNDU)\nQuantum Resistant Ledger (QRL)\nKnightsbridge Digital Asset (KDA)\nTitan Token (TITAN)\nSwirl Social (SWIRL)\nJake The Dog (JAKE)\nArtificial Intelligent Platform Coin (AIPC)\nRoost (ROOST)\nSlerf Cat (SLERFCAT)\nJoltify (JOLT)\nRayn (AKTIO)\nDojo (DOJO)"],"entity":[{"type":"TAUB)\nDark Universe (DMV","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"IAI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coq Inu","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDC\nMKR","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Juice Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ondo","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Boge (BOGE","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Castle of Blackwater","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ondo (ONDO","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bianco (BIANCO","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Xend Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ARS","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"COBE","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BDP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Shiva Inu","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ABL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"AVAX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nakamoto Games (NAKA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CRH","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ENA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FCT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ethena Labs (ENA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mantle","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Cirque Du Sol","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"RTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dimitra (DMTR)\nDigital Standard (DSB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nibiru Chain (NIBI)\nEthena Labs (ENA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"AIPC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDC\nFTM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"WSH","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Uplink Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Joe Boden (BODEN","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Degen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Fink (FINK","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"MAGA Memecoin (TRUMP)\nEthena (ENA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Degen (DEGEN","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Pepe Sora","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"AIX","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Partisia Blockchain (MPC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Avax Lama (LAMA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Elon Coin (SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Knightsbridge Digital Asset (KDA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Crypto Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CTP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"AERO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kena AI (KENA)\nRex (","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Aerodrome Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Altcoins","Exchange","Trading"],"authors":["Mao Orillana"]}