{"summary":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: February 19, 2024","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/crypto-exchange-listing-and-delisting-announcements-february-19-2024.htm","publishDate":"2024-02-19T19:00:03","id":18137,"type":null,"title":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: February 19, 2024","category":["Altcoin News "],"content":[""," ","Here is our weekly collection of digital asset listing and delisting, trading pair-related announcements by crypto exchanges that we found last week and today.","Have we missed something? Do you have information about new listings and\/or delistings? Let us know here.","_________________________________________","MEXC\nListings:\nFACT0RN (FACT)\nTrestle (TRESTLE)\nRain Coin (RAINCOIN)\nApeDoge (APEDOGE)\nMeme AI (MEMEAI)\nUnigraph (GRPH)\nXPAYMENT (PAY)\nSEIYAN (SEIYAN)\nLoong (LOONG)\nStarknet (STRK)\nBambooBounty (PAN)\nForward Protocol (FORWARD)\nEldarune (ELDA)\nLynex (LYNX)\nTanpin.io (TANPIN)\nTerivto Protocol (TRV)\nMeMusic (MMT)\nCrystal Diamond (CLD)\nMOG Coin (MOG)\nMAGA (MAGA)\nPixels (PIXEL)\nSoundProtocol (SOP)\nSora AI (SORA)\nKey Stake (KTK)\nNuson Chain (NSC)\nDragon (DRAGON404)\nPerfBloc (PBL)\nDevvE (DEVVE)\nDoge AI (DOGEAI)\nRemoved Trading Pairs:\nPAXG\/USDC"," ","Binance\nListings:\nPixels (PIXEL)"," ","KuCoin\nListings:\nbitsCrunch (BCUT)\nPixels (PIXEL)\nStarknet (STRK)\nTa-da (TADA)\nDeChat (DECHAT)\nSmart Layer Network (SLN)\nPandora (PANDORA)\nSatoshiVM (SAVM)"," ","Bitrue\nListings:\nGT Protocol (GTAI)\nRonin (RONIN)\nPixels (PIXEL)\nbitsCrunch (BCUT)\nStarknet (STRK)"," ","OKX\nListings:\nStarknet (STRK)"," ","Poloniex\nListings:\nSpyro (SPYRO)\nHeroes of Mavia (MAVIA)"," ","CoinEx\nListings:\nAIT Protocol (AIT)\nMOG Coin (MOG)"," ","Gate.io\nListings:\nHMX (HMX)\nStarknet (STRK)\nPixels (PIXEL)"," ","BitMart\nListings:\nThe CZ Battle (THECZBATTLE)\nSX Network (SX)\nBlockchainSpace (GUILD)\nAkita Inu (AKT)\nShibwifhatcoin (SHIBWIF)\nOperation Phoenix (OPHX)\nVirtual X (VRL)\nOrion Protocol (ORN)\nBot Mascot AI (MASCOT)\nPixels (PIXEL)\nGigaChadGPT (GIGA)\nAvacus Sowaka (SWK)\nSora (SORA)"," ","LBank\nListings:\nAsterix (ASTX)\nBeefi Social (BEEFI)\nXFILE (XFILE)\nPixels (PIXEL)"," ","P2B Crypto Exchange\nListings:\nUniports Online Shopping Token (UOST)"," ","AscendEX\nListings:\nDeFrogs (DEFROGS)\nRic Flair (WOOOOO)\nPandora (PANDORA)\nForward Protocol (FORWARD)"," ","Changelly\nListings:\nPlanet ReFi (PLANET)\nOoki Protocol (OOKI)\nAleph.im (ALEPH)"," ","ChangeNOW\nListings:\nPandora (PANDORA)"," ","Crypto.com\nListings:\nLUKSO (LYX)\nHelium Mobile (MOBILE)\nPixels (PIXEL)\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nAR\/SOL\nDOGE\/SOL\nSHIB\/SOL\nATOM\/SOL\nMOBILE\/HNT"," ","Crypto.com Institutional\nListings:\nHelium Mobile (MOBILE)\nPixels (PIXEL)"," ","HitBTC\nListings:\nClearpool (CPOOL)"," ","HTX\nListings:\nStatter Network (STT)\nPixels (PIXEL)\nStarknet (STRK)"," ","Nexo\nListings:\nCelestia (TIA)"," ","ProBit\nListings:\nGT Protocol (GTAI)"," ","VinDax\nListings:\nNEXNEX Coin (NXNX)\nGolf Cart Victorias (GCV)"," ","XT\nListings:\nXscription (XSCI)\nStarknet (STRK)\nGT Protocol (GTAI)\nAPI3 (API3)\nGrok Project (GROK)\nArtCoin (AC)\nZKF (ZKF)\nSora (SORA)\nLivepeer (LPT)\nMOG Coin (MOG)\nHTX (HTX)"],"entity":[{"type":"Orion Protocol (ORN)\nBot Mascot","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Pandora (PANDORA)","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nuson Chain (NSC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"TADA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Statter Network (STT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"KTK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mavia","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ric Flair","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"PBL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Akita Inu","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Crypto Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MAVIA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MAGA (MAGA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SLN","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Altcoins","Exchange","Trading"],"authors":["Mao Orillana"]}