{"summary":"Crypto Drama: Remilia Founder Claims Hacking Amid Ether and NFT Transfers","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/crypto-drama-remilia-founder-claims-hacking-amid-ether-and-nft-transfers.htm","publishDate":"2024-03-18T11:15:53","id":18139,"type":null,"title":"Crypto Drama: Remilia Founder Claims Hacking Amid Ether and NFT Transfers","category":["Altcoin News "],"content":["In a new wave of crypto drama, Remilia’s founder has ostensibly fallen victim to a hacking incident involving the unauthorized transfer of substantial amounts of Ether and non-fungible tokens (NFTs).","The incident came to light when Dumpster DAO on X shared a screenshot of Krishna Okhandiar, also known as Charlotte Fang, stating, “I got drained,” accompanied by a link to an address that received assets from wallets associated with Remilia.","Remilia is a decentralized autonomous organization (DAO) responsible for the Milady Maker NFT collection. ","Blockchain records reveal that the hacker in question has sold multiple Milady-linked NFTs, including those staked on NFTx. ","The hack has also resulted in $1 million worth of Ether transferred to another address, currently holding nearly $1 million in Ether and various other tokens at the time of reporting.","The exact method of the alleged hack remains unclear.","“Still assessing, technical post-mortem will follow, but primary damage was the Fumo LP and the NFTs we held staked in NFTX, however NFT contract ownerships remain secure on hardware wallets,” Fang said in a post on X. ","My system was hacked and it compromised all imported wallets. If you receive an odd message from any of my accounts, treat with caution. Still assessing, technical post-mortem will follow, but primary damage was the Fumo LP and the NFTs we held staked in NFTX, however NFT… https:\/\/t.co\/K6w1CBTdFb","— ♡ Charlotte Fang 🐉 Crown Prince ❀ LOVE HEALS 💞 (@CharlotteFang77) March 16, 2024","","Meanwhile, adding fuel to the crypto drama fire, blockchain security firm PeckShield revealed that there was a prior transaction from the Remilia treasury wallet to the address implicated in the draining.","In September 2023, Fang made an announcement on the X social platform, revealing that a developer within the Milady ecosystem had diverted approximately $1 million in fees from Remilia Corporation. ","Fang claimed that the attacker had gained control over three X accounts, including Miladymaker and Remilionaire, while Remiliacorp was locked out.","Milady, launched in 2021, is a collection of 10,000 anime profile picture NFTs designed by Fang. ","The collection received public endorsement from Tesla CEO Elon Musk in May 2023 when he shared a meme featuring imagery from the Milady NFT collection. ","This endorsement caused a rapid surge in the floor price of Milady NFTs, which jumped from 3.8 ETH to 7.8 ETH.","Hacks and exploits have become a mounting concern in the crypto industry, particularly within the realm of decentralized finance (DeFi) applications. ","According to a report by Immunefi, a total of $1.8 billion was lost to crypto hacks and scams in 2023, with 17% of the losses attributed to the North Korean Lazarus Group. ","In individual incidents, hacking accounted for over $65 million (97.54%) of the stolen funds in February 2024.","Last month, the token for the layer-1 blockchain Shido plunged 85% after the project’s Ethereum-based staking contract fell victim to an exploit.","The exploit targeting Shido came just one day after Serenity Shield project, a multi-chain data storage startup, fell victim to a theft that compromised its MetaMask wallet.","As reported, bad actors have stolen $38.9 million from various Web3 projects in the first month of 2024.","One of the first major crypto hacks of the year occurred when Radiant Capital experienced a $4.5 million loss due to an empty market exploit.","Gamma Strategies, another affected platform, fell victim to a flash loan attack on January 4, shortly after the Radiant Capital incident."],"entity":[{"type":"Fumo LP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"February 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"March 16, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"NFTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1.8 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"17%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"PeckShield","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"North Korean Lazarus Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"97.54%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Elon Musk","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Milady Maker NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Radiant Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$65 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Krishna Okhandiar","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"May 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tesla","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Milady NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$38.9 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"January 4","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$4.5 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Immunefi","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"85%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"the first month of 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Remilia Corporation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Charlotte","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$1 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Shido","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"September 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Fang","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Charlotte Fang","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["Ethereum","Hack","NFTs"],"authors":["Ruholamin Haqshanas"]}