{"summary":"The demand for crypto risk management solutions grows in 2021, as the crypto market continues to see notable price action. Join The Block&#x27;s Director of News Frank Chaparro along side CME Group and industry experts from Tradestation, and Ninja Trading, for a live webinar and Q&amp;A session.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/105041\/the-block-presents-the-rise-of-crypto-derivatives-brought-to-you-by-cme-group","publishDate":"2021-05-17T17:39:54","id":1819,"type":null,"title":"The Block Presents: The Rise of Crypto Derivatives - Brought to you by CME Group","category":["SPONSORED"],"content":["The demand for crypto risk management solutions grows in 2021, as the crypto market continues to see notable price action. Join The Block’s Director of News Frank Chaparro along side CME Group and industry experts from Tradestation, and Ninja Trading, for a live webinar and Q&amp;A session discussing recent trends in the crypto derivatives marketplace and what’s to come in the second half of 2021.","You can register for the event and learn more about our panelists below:&nbsp;","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" frameborder=\"0\" height=\"360\" src=\"https:\/\/app.livestorm.co\/p\/c5a7f329-1400-482b-b38d-a31ea8b76944\/form\" title=\"The rise of crypto derivatives | The Block\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><u data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Featuring:<\/u><\/strong>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Tim McCourt<\/strong> – Managing Director and Global Head of Equity Products and Alternative Investments, CME Group","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Peter Korotkiy – <\/b>Chief Brokerage Officer, Tradestation","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Martin Franchi<\/strong> – CEO, NinjaTrader","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Brooks Dudley –<\/strong> Global Head of Digital Assets, ED&amp;F Man","————————————————————————————————————————-","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This event is brought to you by CME Group.<\/strong>","As the world’s leading and most diverse derivatives marketplace, CME Group is where the world comes to manage risk. Comprised of four exchanges – CME, CBOT, NYMEX and COMEX – CME Group offers the widest range of global benchmark products across all major asset classes, helping businesses everywhere mitigate the myriad of risks they face in today’s uncertain global economy.","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.cmegroup.com\/markets\/cryptocurrencies.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">https:\/\/www.cmegroup.com\/markets\/cryptocurrencies.html<\/a>"],"entity":[{"type":"Global Head of Equity Products and Alternative Investments","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ninja Trading","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"CBOT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CME Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Brooks Dudley –<\/strong> Global Head of Digital Assets","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"the second half of 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tradestation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Martin Franchi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Peter Korotkiy","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NinjaTrader","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tim McCourt","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sponsored","The Block"]}