{"summary":"Why One Crypto Artist Won’t Call Biden Victory until Fat Lady Sings","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/why-one-crypto-artist-won-t-call-biden-victory-until-fat-lad-8259.htm","publishDate":"2020-11-10T21:00:00","id":18221,"type":null,"title":"Why One Crypto Artist Won’t Call Biden Victory until Fat Lady Sings","category":["Blockchain News "],"content":["World leaders may have been racing to congratulate United States President-elect Joe Biden on his still officially unconfirmed win over President Donald Trump – but like the incumbent commander-in-chief, one crypto artist said he will wait for conclusive proof of Biden’s election triumph before declaring a victor.","That is because the artist in question, who goes by the name of Beeple, has created a non-fungible token (NFT) piece of blockchain-powered art that features the dueling candidates in a standoff limbo.","And once the result is finally called, the NFT will change forever – depicting Trump in one of two very different scenarios.","The piece is named Crossroad and was sold prior to the election on the Nifty platform. Although Biden has already begun putting together his political team ahead of taking power in January next year, Trump is thought to be looking for ways to mount a legal challenge into the ballot-counting process.","That means that Beeple is still reluctant to pull the trigger. Once a winner is finally declared, a chain function will be enacted, changing the artwork forever.","The most likely result – a confirmed Biden win – will see them artwork switch to a depiction of Trump’s apparently lifeless, bloated corpse lying face down in a public park, covered in disparaging graffiti as a blue bird lands on his back and tweets a clown emoji.","But should Trump pull off a remarkable turnaround, a very different outcome is in the cards: Enter a muscle-bound, mean-looking Trump, naked but for a crown – and striding purposefully through a blazing inferno.","A user named Pablo bought the artwork back in October – and now wants a cool USD 66,666 for it.","Meanwhile, as reported, after a number of complaints, crypto derivatives exchange FTX will allow those who bet on Donald Trump to win the 2020 US presidential election to hold onto their bets for free until February 1, 2021. “If, by then, Trump has been unambiguously reelected to the presidency, they will pay out [USD] 1,” said the announcement. The exchange added that they have “given in to the trolls,” that they “regret deeply doing this,” and that they will not make further concessions.\n___\nLearn more:\nThe US Election: Pullback Possible, But Neither Trump Nor Biden Won’t Stop Bitcoin\nKnife-edge Biden-Trump Showdown Has Crypto Backers on Both Sides"],"entity":[{"type":"Trump","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Beeple","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Beeple","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Trump Showdown Has Crypto Backers","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"February 1, 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"USD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Donald Trump","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Trump","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Joe Biden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Biden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"October","content":"DATE"},{"type":"United States","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Biden","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Art","Blockchain","Non-fungible tokens"],"authors":["Tim Alper"]}