{"summary":"FBI Investigates Bitcoin Developer Event Linked to Luke Dashjr’s Hack","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/fbi-investigates-bitcoin-developer-event-linked-to-dashjr-hack.htm","publishDate":"2024-04-12T05:50:43","id":18234,"type":null,"title":"FBI Investigates Bitcoin Developer Event Linked to Luke Dashjr’s Hack","category":["Blockchain News "],"content":["In response to a subpoena, Mike Schmidt provided details of participants at a Bitcoin developer event linked to the investigation of Luke Dashjr’s Bitcoin theft.","As revealed in a social media post by Schmidt, the co-founder of Brink received the subpoena from the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) that required him to submit personal information of attendees from the October 2022 CoreDev Atlanta event.","According to Schmidt, the FBI sent him the subpoena to seek his cooperation a year ago. Since there was a non-disclosure order, Schmidt could only post about the investigation once the order expired.","“Some of you were invited to the event and attended all of the days, and some of you stopped by for some period of time as guests,” said Schmidt.","Mike Schmidt complied with an FBI subpoena to provide information on attendees at a developer event, as part of the investigation into the theft of Luke Dashjr’s Bitcoins.","“The original subpoena requested much information,” explained Schmidt, “but after pushback, the FBI agent agreed to the following subset of information about you.”","In addition to the full names of the event attendees, Schmidt also provided their GitHub usernames and email addresses “as a part of the investigation into Luke Dashjr’s announced theft of his bitcoins.”","“I do not have any details about the investigation or whether the subpoena was due to a targeted suspect or general information gathering as part of the investigation,” said Schmidt.","The guy who wants to tell you how to use Bitcoin couldn’t even secure his own Bitcoin and, as a consequence, got everyone at a conference he attended doxxed by the FBI. 😱","Good job, Luke! 👍 pic.twitter.com\/QQGdJ7AnaT","— Mike In Space (@mikeinspace) April 10, 2024","","With the screenshot of the email sent included in the post, Schmidt also pinpointed the irony of this incident, saying, “The guy who wants to tell you how to use Bitcoin couldn’t even secure his own Bitcoin and, as a consequence, got everyone at a conference he attended doxxed by the FBI.”","“Good job, Luke!” he said.","In 2023, the Core Bitcoin developer Luke Dashjr revealed that he lost almost all his Bitcoin holdings after his Pretty Good Privacy (PGP) key was compromised.","Dashjr stated that his PGP key was compromised by the hackers on Dec. 31, 2022, leading to the theft of over 200 BTC. The total value of the Bitcoins stolen would exceed $14.2 million today with the current Bitcoin price of $71,000."],"entity":[{"type":"April 10, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$71,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Luke!","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$14.2 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"FBI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Schmidt","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"October 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Luke","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Mike Schmidt","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Luke Dashjr’s Bitcoin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Dec. 31, 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Luke Dashjr’s Bitcoins","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Atlanta","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Luke Dashjr","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Mike","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"PGP","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Bitcoin","FBI","Hack"],"authors":["Hongji Feng"]}