{"summary":"Work is still underway to get House Democrats on board for two bills to regulate crypto and stablecoins, said Rep. Wiley Nickel, D-N.C.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/262075\/work-is-still-underway-to-get-bipartisan-support-for-house-stablecoin-crypto-bills-democratic-congressman-says","publishDate":"2023-11-07T17:34:25","id":1823,"type":null,"title":"Work is still underway to get bipartisan support for House stablecoin, crypto bills, Democratic congressman says","category":["STABLECOINS"],"content":["<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Work is still underway get House Democrats on board for a bill that would regulate stablecoins and another that takes a more comprehensive approach to writing rules for crypto, said Rep. Wiley Nickel, D-N.C.<\/span>","<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The two bills passed out of the Republican-led House Financial Services Committee over the summer, but still need to be voted on in the full House before it moves over to the Senate. <\/span><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Rep. Maxine Waters, D-Calif, who used to chair the committee, had concerns over a provision that would allow state regulators to approve stablecoin issuance without Federal Reserve input. Waters also said the larger digital asset market structure bill would create more <a href=\"https:\/\/democrats-financialservices.house.gov\/news\/documentsingle.aspx?DocumentID=410718\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">confusion<\/span><\/a> and will have fewer protections for consumers.&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Nickel shed some optimism about those two bills on Tuesday during DC Fintech week and said<\/span><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> lawmakers were not very far apart when it comes to state regulators' connection to federal regulators. There will be changes made to garner support, even from Waters, Nickel said.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">For the stablecoin bill, there will be \"some finessing of what a strong federal floor means,\" the freshman Democrat said on Tuesday. For the larger market structure bill, there is a willingness to work across the aisle, he added.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"You will see changes in the House and then if we can get it through the Senate, you will see changes there,\" Nickel said.<\/span>","<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">One place to trade interests would be for the Senate's Secure and Fair Enforcement Regulation Banking Act, which would allow financial institutions to provide services to the marijuana industry, Nickel suggested.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Those are places where I see some deals being made,\" Nickel said.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s5\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sen. Elizabeth Warren, D-Mass., reintroduced<\/span><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.warren.senate.gov\/newsroom\/press-releases\/warren-marshall-manchin-graham-renew-push-for-bipartisan-legislation-to-crack-down-on-cryptos-use-in-money-laundering-drug-trafficking-and-financing-of-terrorism-and-rogue-nations\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s6\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">bill<\/span><\/a> in July that would crack down on the use of crypto for money laundering and sanctions evasion as well as extend Bank Secrecy Act requirements to digital asset wallet providers, miners, among other participants. The bill has been criticized by some in the crypto industry, who say rules around anti-money laundering are already in place.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Nickel said everyone can agree crypto shouldn't be used by terrorist groups.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"So much of this is colored by FTX and that I think just has been a real challenge because any time you say crypto that's kind of where a lot of my colleagues' minds go,\" Nickel said.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The digital asset market structure bill passed out of the House committee would prevent another FTX, Nickel added.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Nickel's comments almost a week after former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried's criminal trial came to an end after he was found <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/261240\/sam-bankman-fried-convicted-on-all-counts-report\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">guilty<\/span><\/a> on all counts for defrauding investors.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Federal Reserve","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"\" Nickel","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mass.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"DC Fintech","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Maxine Waters","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Calif","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Wiley Nickel","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"House","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"House Financial Services Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"summer","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Elizabeth Warren","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Senate","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nickel","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["HOUSE AGRICULTURE COMMITTEE","HOUSE FINANCIAL SERVICES COMMITTEE"],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}