{"summary":"The crypto custody service provider said that Peter Marton will help develop programmable blockchain-based compliance products.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/259119\/fireblocks-taps-former-new-york-regulator-to-step-up-compliance","publishDate":"2023-10-24T09:01:05","id":1828,"type":null,"title":"Fireblocks taps former New York regulator to step up compliance","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto custody firm Fireblocks hired a former New York financial regulator to help develop blockchain-based compliance products.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Fireblocks said today in a statement shared with The Block that it has appointed Peter Marton, a former deputy superintendent of virtual currency at the New York State Department of Financial Services, as the company’s director of digital identity. Marton will report directly to Jason Allegrante, chief legal and compliance officer of Fireblocks.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Meanwhile, Chaitanya Reddy Konda, an expert cryptographer who built Nightfall — <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">a Layer 2 rollup blockchain that EY co-developed with Polygon —<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;has also joined Fireblocks as senior technical product manager for digital identity and privacy, according to the statement.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Peter’s exceptional experience developing regulatory frameworks at one the world’s preeminent virtual currency units should prove invaluable as we undertake the development of on-chain identity and programmable compliance solutions that will transform the digital and financial markets and help set the standards for safety, soundness, and consumer protection,” Allegrante said in the statement.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The latest appointments come after Fireblocks last month announced its <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253576\/fireblocks-acquires-blockfold-to-expand-tokenization-capabilities\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$10 million acquisition<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> of BlockFold<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">a smart contract development and consulting firm.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Fireblocks said that its platform has evolved to provide its clients with total control over the full life cycle of their digital assets with major focuses on tokenization, secure storage and payment workflows.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"today","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Peter Marton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Peter","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jason Allegrante","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Polygon —","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Marton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Allegrante","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Fireblocks","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York State Department of Financial Services","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chaitanya Reddy Konda","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$10 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"BlockFold","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["SECURITY FIRMS","WALLETS"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}