{"summary":"Samsung Adds Bitcoin Focused Exchange Gemini To Its Flagships","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/samsung-adds-bitcoin-focused-exchange-gemini-to-its-flagship-6674.htm","publishDate":"2020-05-28T13:15:00","id":18347,"type":null,"title":"Samsung Adds Bitcoin Focused Exchange Gemini To Its Flagships","category":["Bitcoin News "],"content":["The world’s largest smartphone maker, Samsung, has integrated the Gemini exchange into its Blockchain Wallet on Galaxy smartphones in the US and Canada. (Updated at 13:36 UTC: a quote by Jeanine Hightower-Sellitto has been added).","By connecting their Samsung Blockchain Wallet to the Gemini mobile app, users can buy and sell crypto, view their Gemini account balances, and also transfer their crypto into cold storage with Gemini Custody, the exchange said. They’re the first US crypto exchange and custodian to partner with South Korean giant, according to the announcement.","The Samsung Blockchain Wallet and the Gemini Mobile App are available in the Samsung Galaxy Store for these devices: Galaxy S20 Series, Galaxy Z Flip, Galaxy Note 10 Series, Galaxy Fold, Galaxy S10 series (Verizon excluded).","“It’s a full integration between the two apps that’s very transparent and very easy to use,” Jeanine Hightower-Sellitto, Managing Director of Operations at Gemini, told Bloomberg. “It’s all integrated.” Terms of the deal were not disclosed.","24-hour trading volume (13:03 UTC) on Gemini stands at USD 20.6 million, while bitcoin (BTC) is responsible for 86% of it, ethereum (ETH) – 11%.","As reported, recession, a more favorable regulatory view, a better understanding of the technology, and traditional investors turning to crypto – are all aspects that are bringing adoption to crypto, Julian Sawyer, Gemini’s Managing Director for Europe, recently told Cryptonews.com. Also as reported, major investment bank JPMorgan Chase recently welcomed Gemini and Coinbase as their first crypto clients.","Meanwhile, THETA.tv, the esports video platform powered by Theta (THETA) blockchain, recently said that might be featured as one of the content providers available in the Samsung Daily platform, pre-installed in every flagship Galaxy S20 phone shipped in the US."],"entity":[{"type":"Samsung Blockchain Wallet","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Canada","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Verizon","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sellitto","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gemini","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"86%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"UTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gemini Custody","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"11%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"USD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gemini Mobile App","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Samsung","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jeanine Hightower","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Samsung Galaxy Store","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Julian Sawyer","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["Adoption","Bitcoin","Exchange","Gemini","Samsung"],"authors":["Linas Kmieliauskas"]}