{"summary":"Defeated Donald Trump-themed NFT Sells for USD 6.6 Million","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/defeated-donald-trump-themed-nft-sells-for-usd-6-6-million-9338.htm","publishDate":"2021-02-25T09:55:00","id":18355,"type":null,"title":"Defeated Donald Trump-themed NFT Sells for USD 6.6 Million","category":["News "],"content":["The non-fungible tokens (NFTs) market is showing signs of hotting up to unprecedented levels – with a Donald Trump-themed piece of digital art fetching a staggering USD 6.6m in a resale deal.","The artwork was created by popular digital artist Beeple, who has had an outstanding start to 2021. Earlier this month, arguably the most famous auction house on the planet – the UK’s Christie’s – agreed to put his “EVERYDAYS: THE FIRST 5000 DAYS” NFT under the hammer. The auction is slated for today.","But it looks like NFT art is now hot property, with the Nifty Gateway trading platform announcing that the Trump-themed work named “Crossroad” had “just resold on the secondary market for USD 6.6 million.”","Nifty Gateway added,","“History has just been made.”","Beeple replied that he was “he was absolutely f***ing speechless” to hear the news.","The deal saw the previous owner Pablo, a collector with over 100 digital artworks in their portfolio, make a huge profit on the work, purchasing it for a few thousand dollars in October. Back in December last year, Pablo was asking just USD 66,666 for the work. But per Nifty data, a new user named Baby Beluga has now snapped it up for the six-figure fee.","As previously reported, Beeple created the work ahead of the 2020 Presidential Election in the United States – raising eyebrows with a token that would either go on to show a naked, absurdly buff Trump stomping through the fires of Hell for eternity…or his bloated corpse lying lifeless and graffiti-covered in a public park.","Prior to the election, the NFT portrayed the unclothed Trump and victor President Joe Biden squaring up to one another in a gravity-free embryonic stasis.\n___\nLearn more:\n– Non-Fungible 2021: Prepare Your NFTs For DeFi, Staking, and Sharing\n– ‘Traditional’ Art vs. Crypto Art: How to Value It\n– Mark Cuban Says Crypto Is a Store of Value & Redditors Right to ‘Kick Wall St. Ass’\n– Check These 4 Make-Your-Own-NFT Platforms"],"entity":[{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"December last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Beeple","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nifty","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UK’s Christie","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Pablo","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Donald Trump","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Baby Beluga","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nifty Gateway","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Trump","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Joe Biden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Store of Value & Redditors Right to ‘Kick Wall St. Ass","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"October","content":"DATE"},{"type":"United States","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["Art","Non-fungible tokens"],"authors":["Tim Alper"]}