{"summary":"Trump Calls CBDCs a “Very Dangerous Thing,” Criticizes Artificial Intelligence","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/trump-calls-cbdc-a-very-dangerous-thing-criticizes-artificial-intelligence.htm","publishDate":"2024-02-05T22:25:42","id":18403,"type":null,"title":"Trump Calls CBDCs a “Very Dangerous Thing,” Criticizes Artificial Intelligence","category":["Blockchain News "],"content":["Former President and leading Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump called the prospect of a central bank digital currency (CBDC) a “very dangerous thing” during a February 2 interview on Fox Business.","Fielding questions from Maria Bartiromo, Trump once again doubled down on his anti-CBDC stance, calling it “a very dangerous thing.”","He also took the time to criticize the rise of artificial intelligence, alleging “it may be the most dangerous thing out there” as it has “no real solution.”","“I saw somebody ripping me off the other day where they had me making a speech about their product,” Trump said. “I said I’ll never endorse that product. You can’t even tell the difference—it looks like I’m actually endorsing it.”","“You can get into wars and other things,” he continued. “Something has to be done about this, and it has to be done fast.”","Trump’s latest comments echo those he made during a New Hampshire rally last month, where he promised to “never allow the creation of a central bank digital currency.”","The ex-president gave credit to former Republican rival, Vivek Ramaswamy, for informing him of the dangers of CBDC.","“I didn’t like him when he was running, but I like him now,” Trump said of Ramaswamy during last month’s rally. “It’s amazing how you can like somebody when you win.”","I respect Trump & give him full credit for being a strong leader who is willing to listen to the right ideas. 🇺🇸 https:\/\/t.co\/xcGdp8W7S2","— Vivek Ramaswamy (@VivekGRamaswamy) January 23, 2024","","In addition to Ramaswamy, Trump has gained the support of his former opponent, Florida Governor Ron DeSantis, following the suspension of his presidential campaign.","“I signed a pledge to support the Republican nominee and I will honor that pledge,” DeSantis said in a video posted to X.","Trump’s views on cryptocurrency have shifted in previous years, with the former president having previously called digital assets “highly volatile,” “not money,” and “based on thin air.”","I am not a fan of Bitcoin and other Cryptocurrencies, which are not money, and whose value is highly volatile and based on thin air. Unregulated Crypto Assets can facilitate unlawful behavior, including drug trade and other illegal activity….","— Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump) July 12, 2019","","Speaking to Fox Business in 2021, Trump alleged cryptocurrencies “may be fake.”","“Who knows what they are, but they certainly know something that people don’t know very much about,” he said.","“We have only one real currency in the USA, and it is stronger than ever, both dependable and reliable,” Trump wrote in a 2019 X post. “It is by far the most dominant currency anywhere in the World, and it will always stay that way. It is called the United States Dollar!”"],"entity":[{"type":"Trump &","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ron DeSantis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Trump","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Vivek Ramaswamy","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Florida","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"DeSantis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"USA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"” Trump","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"New Hampshire","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Fox Business","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Maria Bartiromo","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"January 23, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Donald Trump","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Trump","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"July 12, 2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ramaswamy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Donald J. Trump","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"United States","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["CBDC","Donald Trump","Trump"],"authors":["Julia Smith"]}