{"summary":"Japanese Release Pig-Themed Ethereum Blockchain Game","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/japanese-release-pig-themed-ethereum-blockchain-game-1676.htm","publishDate":"2018-04-30T05:10:00","id":18481,"type":null,"title":"Japanese Release Pig-Themed Ethereum Blockchain Game","category":["Ethereum News "],"content":["Following on from CryptoKitties, China’s blockchain dogs and Russian Ethereum-powered unicorns, Japanese developers have unveiled a virtual blockchain-powered pig trading platform – imaginatively titled Crypt-Oink.","Per a press release from its developers, Crypt-Oink is a smartphone game that allows traders to buy, sell and breed multi-colored pigs on an Ethereum blockchain platform, using ETH as a trading currency.","The game has been co-developed by Ceres, a subsidiary of rewards point operator Mercury. The company earlier this year applied to become an officially licensed cryptocurrency exchange platform. Ceres teamed up with Japanese game developer Good Luck 3 for the new pig-themed game.","The companies say they have launched Android and iOS versions, and will look to develop foreign language versions of Crypt-Oink should the game’s popularity catch on.","Meanwhile, a software developer in the United States has unveiled a children’s book about blockchain technology and cryptocurrency, entitled A Place in the Blockchain. The illustrated book tells the tale of a cute character named Blocky and his struggle for blockchain acceptance."],"entity":[{"type":"Blockchain","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Oink","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Mercury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ceres","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Crypt","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Oink","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"United States","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"China","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["Entertainment","Ethereum","Game","Japan"],"authors":["Tim Alper"]}