{"summary":"Former First Lady Melania Trump Selling Mother’s Day Necklace With NFT On The Solana Blockchain","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/donald-trumps-wife-melania-trump-selling-necklace-and-nft-on-solana-blockchain.htm","publishDate":"2024-04-24T20:14:20","id":18562,"type":null,"title":"Former First Lady Melania Trump Selling Mother’s Day Necklace With NFT On The Solana Blockchain","category":["NFT News "],"content":["Melania Trump, the wife of former President Donald Trump, launched a Mother’s Day necklace on Sunday that comes with a free matching NFT on the Solana blockchain.","Entitled the “Her Live and Gratitude” necklace, Trump’s latest design “can be engraved with names, initials, or significant dates to create a one-of-a-kind piece of jewelry.”","Selling for $245, buyers will also receive a “limited edition digital collectible” minted on the Solana blockchain alongside the gold vermeil pendant.","“Being a mother is one of the most important roles in life,” Trump said in a statement Sunday. “For this Mother’s Day, I have designed the “Her Love and Gratitude” necklace to express immense gratitude and honor all mothers.”","Let’s honor and celebrate all mothers with love and gratitude. https:\/\/t.co\/ESihnAQ8kg pic.twitter.com\/Nj3IKfwzG1","— MELANIA TRUMP (@MELANIATRUMP) April 21, 2024","","The customizable necklace and corresponding NFT mark the latest venture for the polarizing political figure, having first cashed in on the craze by selling a digital token called “Melania’s Vision” in December 2021.","Trump, whose own mother passed away earlier this year, has largely kept out of the spotlight amid Donald Trump’s campaign ahead of the 2024 U.S. presidential election.","In April 2023, the former Republican president released the second edition of his controversial Trump Digital Trading Cards for $99, prompting the value of the first batch of NFTs originally released in December 2022 to drop significantly.","Data from OpenSea reveals that Trump’s NFT brand may be dying, however, with the last documented sale of the tokens occurring over three weeks ago.","Despite disparaging cryptocurrencies in the past, Donald Trump has been fairly active in crypto, telling CNBC that he likes to “make money” and “do little things for fun with it” earlier last month.","Recent data from digital asset venture capital firm Paradigm revealed that Trump was largely favored over incumbent President Joe Biden by the crypto community at large, receiving 48% of digital asset users’ votes compared to Biden’s 3%.","A number of Trump-themed meme coins have soared in the lead-up to the general election, with MAGA Coin (TRUMP) surging in price in recent months.","In addition to the “Her Love and Gratitude” necklace, Trump is currently selling two other NFTs commemorating Women’s History Month and National Foster Care Month, each retailing at $150.","According to the U.S. political site, The Hill, the former First Lady is set to make her first official public appearance in recent memory at a fundraiser this Saturday at the Trump estate in Mar-a-lago."],"entity":[{"type":"April 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$245","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Trump","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MAGA","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Melania Trump","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$99","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"MELANIA TRUMP","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Trump’s NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Joe Biden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"History Month and National Foster Care Month","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Saturday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sunday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"3%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"April 21, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Trump Digital Trading Cards","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"December 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Donald Trump","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Trump","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"December 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"OpenSea","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"48%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Trump","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Biden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$150","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["Donald Trump","NFT","Solana"],"authors":["Julia Smith"]}