{"summary":"Web3 music startup Arpeggi Labs is seeking to raise $11 million and has secured $9.1 million from 21 investors.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/208437\/a16z-backed-arpeggi-labs-is-looking-to-raise-11-million","publishDate":"2023-02-03T08:07:14","id":1859,"type":null,"title":"A16z-backed Arpeggi Labs is looking to raise $11 million","category":["DEALS"],"content":["Web3 music startup <a href=\"https:\/\/www.arpeggi.io\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Arpeggi Labs<\/a> is seeking to raise $11 million.","A U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) <a href=\"https:\/\/www.sec.gov\/Archives\/edgar\/data\/1963552\/000156761923001648\/xslFormDX01\/primary_doc.xml\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filing<\/a> shows the startup has already secured $9.1 million from 21 investors.","The company did not immediately respond to a request for comment on the raise.","Arpeggi Labs is a startup that is focused on using blockchain technology to make music creation more collaborative. It <a href=\"https:\/\/techcrunch.com\/2022\/09\/14\/arpeggi-labs-banks-a16z-funding-to-build-web3-music-creation-software\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">raised<\/a> $5.1 million from investors in September. Its backers include Andreessen Horowitz (a16z), Electric Feel Ventures, the Audius Foundation, 1Confirmation as well as several artists including Steve Aoki and Wyclef Jean, according to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.crunchbase.com\/organization\/arpeggi-711e\/company_financials\/investors\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">data<\/a> from Crunchbase.","When the startup raised its seed round, co-founders Evan Dhillon, Kyle Dhillon and James Pastan <a href=\"https:\/\/techcrunch.com\/2022\/09\/14\/arpeggi-labs-banks-a16z-funding-to-build-web3-music-creation-software\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">told<\/a> TechCrunch that Arpeggi Labs' setup would encourage a new type of “remix culture” to permeate the music industry.","The startup <a href=\"https:\/\/www.arpeggi.io\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">offers<\/a> a free in-browser digital audio workstation that enables individuals to create music and mint it as an NFT. It also allows artists to share their music with others for reuse while guaranteeing attribution when the sound is used.&nbsp;","Arpeggi's platform is built on top of a decentralized sound library called the \"Audio Relationship Protocol, \"according to the company <a href=\"https:\/\/www.arpeggi.io\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">website<\/a>.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$5.1 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Electric Feel Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wyclef Jean","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$11 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"James Pastan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Arpeggi Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Evan Dhillon","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kyle Dhillon","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Audius Foundation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$9.1 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Andreessen Horowitz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Steve Aoki","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Kari McMahon","The Block"]}