{"summary":"Worldcoin Operator Announces Mexico Expansion – Despite Potential Probe","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/worldcoin-operator-announces-mexico-expansion-despite-potential-probe.htm","publishDate":"2024-04-30T23:30:36","id":18688,"type":null,"title":"Worldcoin Operator Announces Mexico Expansion – Despite Potential Probe","category":["Altcoin News "],"content":["The Worldcoin operator Tools for Humanity is expanding its services in Mexico, the firm announced, in spite of lawmakers’ calls for a government probe into its iris-scanning drive.","Per the media outlet Criptonoticias, the company said it had opened iris-scanning centers in the capital Mexico City, as well as Guadalajara and Monterrey."," ","Worldcoin has nine regional centers in Mexico where staffers can collect citizens’ biometric data, making it the third-largest base for the project in the Latin America region.","The project has also enjoyed great success in Argentina. This same nation’s data protection agency announced the launch of an investigation into Worldcoin in January this year.","The company also operates 21 data collection centers in Chile.","Worldcoin, the eyeball-scanning crypto project co-founded by Sam Altman, is looking to team up with major names in tech—including OpenAI https:\/\/t.co\/FtiAfIahGy","— Bloomberg Crypto (@crypto) April 29, 2024","","However, Mexican lawmakers have expressed concern. Earlier this month, María Eugenia Hernández, an MP for the ruling Morena party, called on the National Institute of Transparency, Access to Information and Protection of Personal Data (INAI) to act. Hernández said:","“We cannot allow our citizens’ data to fall into the hands of individuals without establishing clear rules for this data’s use and possible exploitation. It is very important to raise our concerns. We need to find out what this company is really doing, and what the risks involved could be.”","The lawmaker asked INAI to verify that it “would be safe” for Mexicans to “continue to hand over their biometric data in exchange for a few cryptocurrency tokens.”","Tools for Humanity has been operating in Mexico since July 2023. The firm has been working “under the pretext” of “creating a financial and identity network,” Hernández said.","The lawmaker also pointed to the example of Spain. The European nation cited “privacy concerns” and the “protection of biometric data” as reasons for temporarily banning Worldcoin iris scanning, she added.","Despite its LATAM popularity, Worldcoin has faced more regional pushback. In the Buenos Aires region, officials have warned of “possible” recriminations, including “million-dollar fines.”","Chilean government agents have inspected three centers. They have also asked the firm to submit “additional information” to “ensure that Worldcoin complies with national regulations.”","Increased access to World ID's verified proof of humanness is coming to Mexico. pic.twitter.com\/5Fj6ixvIXf","— Worldcoin (@worldcoin) April 29, 2024","","Worldcoin-related investigations are ongoing in countries all over the world, including South Korea and Hong Kong.","The firm has also had to suspend its orb verification service in nations such as India, Brazil, and France.","In Spain, a High Court ruling upheld a temporary ban on Worldcoin iris-scanning in March. The court voiced several data and privacy-related concerns."],"entity":[{"type":"South Korea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"France","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Worldcoin","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Worldcoin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Argentina","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Spain","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"María Eugenia Hernández","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Buenos Aires","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Hernández","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bloomberg Crypto","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"National Institute of Transparency, Access to Information and Protection of Personal Data (INAI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Monterrey","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Morena","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Mexico City","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Latin America","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"April 29, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Brazil","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Mexico","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Altman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"January this year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Chile","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"India","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Guadalajara","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"July 2023","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["Mexico","Worldcoin"],"authors":["Tim Alper"]}