{"summary":"Polygon wants to grow its headcount by 200 before year-end.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/168588\/polygon-will-continue-hiring-despite-market-downturn-bloomberg","publishDate":"2022-09-08T09:45:23","id":187,"type":null,"title":"Polygon will continue hiring despite market downturn: Bloomberg","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Ethereum scaling solution Polygon plans to continue hiring despite the bear market and choppy macro conditions, it said this week.&nbsp;","This will include plans to increase its overall headcount by over 40%, according to an <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2022-09-08\/as-crypto-reels-one-company-deploys-cash-hoard-in-hiring-binge\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">interview<\/a> published by Bloomberg.","Bhumika Srivastava, the firm's head of human resources, said the company hopes to capitalize on the misfortune of other companies in the space.&nbsp;","Srivastava added that the firm will use the bear market as an opportunity to hire, although the hiring landscape is difficult to navigate at present she admitted.","\"It is difficult to hire the quality talent you want, especially as web3 skills is something that’s still getting built,” she said.&nbsp;","Polygon is well placed to hire at present having <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/133269\/polygon-raises-450-million-matic-token-sale\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">raised<\/a> $450 million in a private token sale in February, led by Sequoia Capital India. The sale included more than 40 other investors, with SoftBank Vision Fund 2, Tiger Global, Alan Howard, Kevin O’Leary, Galaxy Digital, Sino Global Capital, Alameda Research, Digital Currency Group, Accel, Union Square Ventures and Dragonfly Capital all involved.&nbsp;","Polygon said at the time that it planned to allocate $100 million to its ecosystem fund and about $10 million each per year to its various scaling products, including Hermez, Miden, Zero and Nightfall.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Kevin O’Leary","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$450 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Galaxy Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tiger Global","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hermez","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$100 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bhumika Srivastava","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"SoftBank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"February","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Union Square Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sino Global Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Digital Currency Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"40%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sequoia Capital India","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Accel","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Miden","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Alan Howard","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nightfall","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dragonfly Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$10 million","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["HIRING","POLYGON"],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}