{"summary":"Armed with $24 million in total funding, MetaStreet aims to build liquidity, debt and collateralization infrastructure for the NFT industry. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/176984\/dragonfly-and-opensea-back-10-million-raise-for-nft-financing-firm-metastreet","publishDate":"2022-10-13T11:47:10","id":1875,"type":null,"title":"NFT financing firm MetaStreet raises a total of $24 million in funding","category":["METAVERSE & NFT"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The NFT debt provider MetaStreet has raised $10 million in fresh funding.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Investors in the round include DragonFly Capital, Nascent and Ethereal Ventures, who funded MetaStreet before. New investors participated as well, such as Fintech Collective, DCG, TheLAO, Focus Labs, Mirana Ventures, Metaversal, OpenSea Ventures, Ledgerprime, Meta4 and Flying Falcon.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Combined with $14 million total in seed funding acquired in February, MetaStreet’s total financing is now $24 million, according to a release shared with The Block.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The firm will use the funding to create trust, credit and ownership products to facilitate debt and build out the NFT industry’s debt infrastructure.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">MetaStreet was founded in 2021 and provides liquidity and scaling infrastructure for NFT collateralization platforms. The firm aims to augment the NFT industry debt system by providing automated underwriting, mitigation waterfalls and other tools.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">While not as hot as in 2021, this year’s NFT trading industry sees consistent interest, especially in the gaming sector. Weekly trade volumes exceeded $30 million in sales in the first week of October, The Block’s data shows.<\/span>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/nft-non-fungible-tokens\/nft-overview\/weekly-trade-volume-of-nfts\/embed\" title=\"Weekly Trade Volume of NFTs by Category\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"DCG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DragonFly Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"the first week of October","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"February","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$14 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"OpenSea Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fintech Collective","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$30 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Ledgerprime","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Focus Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mirana Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$24 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$10 million","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}