{"summary":"SEC Hints What Crypto Assets Might be Securities (UPDATED 3)","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/sec-hints-what-crypto-assets-might-be-securities-3637.htm","publishDate":"2019-04-03T15:45:00","id":18863,"type":null,"title":"SEC Hints What Crypto Assets Might be Securities (UPDATED 3)","category":["Altcoin News "],"content":["On Wednesday, in a long-awaited move, a division at the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) released a framework for analyzing whether a digital asset is offered and sold as an investment contract, and, therefore, is a security.\n","(Updated on April 3, 17:04 UTC: two new sections – “Nothing new here” and “A no-action request” – have been added.\nUpdated on April 3, 18:26 UTC: two new paragraphs in the beginning of the “Nothing new here” section have been added.\nUpdated on April 4, 03:39 UTC: a new video with comments by a lawyer has been added to the “Nothing new here” section)","However, in an announcement, Bill Hinman, Director of Division of Corporation Finance at SEC, and Valerie Szczepanik, Senior Advisor for Digital Assets and Innovation at SEC, stressed that the framework is not intended to be an exhaustive overview of the law, but rather, “an analytical tool to help market participants assess whether the federal securities laws apply to the offer, sale, or resale of a particular digital asset.”","“This framework represents Staff views and is not a rule, regulation, or statement of the Commission. The Commission has neither approved nor disapproved its content,” they added.","According to them, the information contained in this framework may apply to entities conducting the following activities related to digital assets:","The framework focuses on the Howey test that helps to determine whether an asset, including digital assets, is an “investment contract.”","“Usually, the main issue in analyzing a digital asset under the Howey test is whether a purchaser has a reasonable expectation of profits (or other financial returns) derived from the efforts of others,” according to the framework.","It goes further to explain:","","“A purchaser may expect to realize a return through participating in distributions or through other methods of realizing appreciation on the asset, such as selling at a gain in a secondary market.\nWhen a promoter, sponsor, or other third party (or affiliated group of third parties) (each, an “Active Participant” or “AP”) provides essential managerial efforts that affect the success of the enterprise, and investors reasonably expect to derive profit from those efforts, then this prong of the test is met.\nRelevant to this inquiry is the “economic reality” of the transaction and “what character the instrument is given in commerce by the terms of the offer, the plan of distribution, and the economic inducements held out to the prospect.” The inquiry, therefore, is an objective one, focused on the transaction itself and the manner in which the digital asset is offered and sold.”","The framework also listed the following characteristics that are important in evaluating a digital asset – “the stronger their presence, the less likely the Howey test is met”:","However, the document added that even in cases where a digital asset can be used to purchase goods or services on a network, where that network’s or digital asset’s functionality is being developed or improved, there may be securities transactions.","According to the framework, in this case, among other factors, the following is present:\n– the digital asset is offered or sold to purchasers at a discount to the value of the goods or services;\n– the digital asset is offered or sold to purchasers in quantities that exceed reasonable use;\n– and\/or there are limited or no restrictions on reselling those digital assets, particularly where an AP is continuing in its efforts to increase the value of the digital assets or has facilitated a secondary market.\n____","“This guidance not only confirms that cryptocurrencies like Bitcoin and Ethereum are not securities, it also goes a long way in helping entrepreneurs and technologists who have done the right thing know that they have done the right thing, and it should help those who want to build new networks know how the securities laws will be applied,” Peter Van Valkenburgh, director of research at the Coin Center, a Washington based crypto-focused research and advocacy center, wrote in commentary on the framework.","According to him, the bottom line is that it is possible to fundraise by selling tokens in compliance with the securities laws and then have those tokens be clearly not securities when the promoter is no longer essential to the continued viability of the project.","Meanwhile, lawyer, blockchain enthusiast Preston Byrne tweeted that “there’s really nothing new here.”","“Any lawyer looking realistically at token sales will have given advice along these lines for years,” he said.","According to Philip Liu, co-founder and chief legal officer of Arca, a Los Angeles-based crypto investment management firm, “the SEC just says if you issue tokens based on blockchain for use as a mere exchange mechanism for existing goods and services, the tokens are not a security.”","Andrew “Drew” Hinkes, co-founder and the General Counsel of investment firm Athena Blockchain, concluded that “it’ll be another way for lawyers to analyze offerings and make arguments, but this doesn’t create the checklist that so many have begged for- which makes sense.”","“The SEC wants you to talk to get lawyers and to communicate with the SEC on Finhub,” he said in a tweet.","In March, SEC Chairman Jay Clayton also clarified his position on crypto, however, not everyone was convinced back then.\n____","Stephen Palley, a partner at U.S.-based corporate law firm Anderson Kill, discusses what the framework means for ICOs","____","Also, the Division of Corporation Finance issued a no-action request regarding TurnKey Jet (TKJ), a private aviation firm, concluding that tokens issued by the company are not securities.","According to the Division, these are the reasons why it will not recommend enforcement action to the Commission:","Blockchain and finance deal lawyer Joshua Ashley Klayman commented:",""],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Athena Blockchain","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jay Clayton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coin Center","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"AP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bill Hinman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Director of Division of Corporation Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Finhub","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Stephen Palley","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April 3","content":"DATE"},{"type":"April 4","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Andrew “Drew” Hinkes","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Washington","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Preston Byrne","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Anderson Kill","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Joshua Ashley Klayman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Los Angeles","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"UTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Arca","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"the Division of Corporation Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ICOs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Howey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Valerie Szczepanik","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Peter Van Valkenburgh","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Philip Liu","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"General Counsel","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Regulation","SEC"],"authors":["Linas Kmieliauskas"]}