{"summary":"Worldcoin Pauses Orb Verification Services in India, Brazil and France","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/worldcoin-discontinues-its-orb-verification-services-in-india-brazil-and-france.htm","publishDate":"2023-12-21T07:54:19","id":18883,"type":null,"title":"Worldcoin Pauses Orb Verification Services in India, Brazil and France","category":["News "],"content":["Worldcoin, the controversial startup led by Sam Altman, has temporarily paused its Orb-verification service in India, Brazil, and France.","The decision follows just months after the company’s expansion of its helmet-shaped eyeball-scanning verification device, known as the Orb, into these markets.","The Tools for Humanity foundation, overseeing Worldcoin’s development, clarified that the Orb’s introduction in these regions was part of a “limited time access” initiative. Despite the withdrawal, the foundation reiterated its global commitment to collaborating with partners to ensure compliance with regulatory standards and to maintain a secure, transparent, and safe service for verified individuals, MoneyControl reported.","Worldcoin’s eyeball verification process received a lot of scrutiny from governments as well as within the web3 industry who advocate for digital privacy rights.","The Orb, a distinctive five-pound chromatic sphere, scans individuals’ eyeballs to verify their identities. The Orb’s multi-city tour commenced in Tokyo in April 2023 and spanned North America, Europe, the Middle East, and Asia this year. The tour concluded in late summer, accompanied by Orb previews in various cities and the launch of the protocol.","Worldcoin, backed by approximately $250 million in funding from prominent investors such as Andreessen Horowitz, Khosla Ventures, and Reid Hoffman, initiated its global services rollout in July. The startup’s mission is to develop a reliable solution for distinguishing humans from AI online, facilitating global democratic processes, and enhancing economic opportunities.","Worldcoin’s World app recently crossed 5 million users and is now being used by 1 million users per week, Tools for Humanity Head of Product, Engineering & Design Tiago Sada revealed in a post on X."],"entity":[{"type":"Middle East","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"April 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tokyo","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"France","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Khosla Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"North America","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$250 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Brazil","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sam Altman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Asia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"MoneyControl","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Humanity Head of Product, Engineering & Design Tiago Sada","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"India","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Andreessen Horowitz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Reid Hoffman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"summer","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["Brazil","France","India"],"authors":["Jai Pratap"]}