{"summary":"Crypto Listing and Delisting Announcements: Week 30","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/crypto-listing-delisting-announcements-week-30.htm","publishDate":"2022-07-25T20:00:00","id":18908,"type":null,"title":"Crypto Listing and Delisting Announcements: Week 30","category":["Altcoin News "],"content":[" ","Here is our weekly collection of digital asset listing and delisting, trading pair-related announcements by crypto exchanges that we found last week and today.","Have we missed something? Do you have information about new listings and\/or delistings? Let us know here.","_________________________________________","Bibox\nListings: \nWateenswap (WTN)\n\n\n ","BigONE\nListings: \nHelium (HNT)\n\n\n ","BitMart\nListings: \nArtèQ (ARTEQ)\nLand of Conquest (SLG)\nbeFITTER (FIU)\nHappyFans ($HAPPY)\nFIX00 LTD (FIX00)\nXANA (XETA)\nBitcicoin (BITCI)\nGnosis (GNO)\nAmazy (AZY)\nCaduceus Metaverse Protocol (CMP)\nLITE (LITE)\n\n\n ","Bitrue\nListings: \nBOLT (BOLT)\nSmart MFG (MFG)\nEuro Tether (EURT)\nSTIMA (STIMA)\nKarura (KAR)\nCeek (CEEK)\nOrigin Dollar Governance (OGV)\nGenopets KI (KI)\nHOPR (HOPR)\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nKAVA\/XRP\nTFUEL\/XRP\nLRC\/XRP\nFTM\/XRP\nGRT\/XRP\nALICE\/XRP\nENS\/XRP\nOMG\/XRP\nDUSK\/XRP\nCRV\/XRP\nRNDR\/XRP\nGMT\/XRP\nQNT\/XRP\n\n\n ","Bittrex\nListings: \nAlchemy Pay (ACH)\n\n\n ","CEX.io\nListings: \nAlgorand (ALGO)\n\n\n ","Changelly\nListings: \nImmutable (IMX)\nOcean Protocol (OCEAN)\nSuperRare (RARE)\nSia Foundation (SC)\n\n\n ","ChangeNOW\nListings: \nSpell Token (SPELL)\nVelas (VLX)\nSafePal (SFP)\nCurve Finance (CRV)\nTenshi (TENSHI)\n\n\n ","CoinBetter\nListings: \nOpenBlox (OBX)\nBarnBridgΞ (BOND)\nAmazy (AZY)\nXANA (XETA)\n\n\n ","CoinEx\nListings: \nEuler Finance (EUL)\n\n\n ","Crex 24\nDelistings: \nCardano (ADA)\nAvalanche (AVAX)\nBitcoin Cash (BCH)\nPolkadot (DOT)\nEos (EOS)\nStellar (XLM)\nXRP (XRP)\n\n\n ","Crypto.com\nListings: \nMarlin Protocol (POND)\n\n\n ","DigiFinex\nListings: \nBees Coin (EBS)\nPancakeSwap (CAKE)\nPax Gold (PAXG)\nWrapped Bitcoin (WBTC)\nWadzPay (WTK)\nHolo (HOT)\nConvex Finance (CVX)\nHDBTC Foundation (HDBTC)\nAngry Polar Bears (AICE)"," "," ","FINEXBOX\nListings: \nModden (MDDN)\nScholarship Coin (SCHO)\n "," ","Gate.io\nListings: \nbeFITTER (FIU)\nSeele (SEELE)\nLand of Conquest (SLG)\nRound X (RNDX)\nMoneySwap (MSWAP)\nLABEL Foundation (LBL)\nAmazingTeamDAO (ATEAM)\n\n\n ","HitBTC\nListings: \nBanano (BAN)\n\n\n ","Hotbit\nListings: \nEVE Media World (EVET)\nSimzo Coin (SZC)\nHold on for Dear Life Token (HODL)\n\n\n ","Huobi\nListings: \nAleph Zero (AZERO)\nXANA (XETA)\nSologenic (SOLO)\nKlever (KLV)\nSTEPN (GSTERC)\nANIVERSE (ANV)\nTOMTOM Coin (TOMS)\nDeFiChain (DFI)\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nSWFTC\/USDC\nMTL\/USDT\n\n\n ","LBank\nListings: \nCryptokki Coin (TOKKI)\nTezos (XTZ)\nCasting Network (CSTN)\nInternet Computer (ICP)\nShowTime Protocol (STP)\nFidlecoin (FIDLE)\nTRCAIR (TRCAIR)\nTemplate value sharing token (TVS)\nNipperture (NPR)\nEnergy Empire (E2COIN)\nCryptostone (CPS)\n\n\n ","MEXC Global\nListings: \nAmazy (AZY)\nProton Blockchain (XPR)\nCaduceus (CMP)\n\n\n ","Okcoin\nListings: \nChain (XCN)\n\n\n ","OKX\nListings:\nXANA (XETA)\nAmazy (AZY)\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nYGG\/USDC\nCELT\/USDC\nGARI\/USDC\nVRA\/USDC\nXEM\/USDC\nAGLD\/USDC\nSWFTC\/USDC\nKLAY\/USDC\nMXC\/USDC\nMKR\/USDC\nAR\/USDC\nANT\/USDC\nPERP\/USDC\nSLP\/USDC\nCSPR\/USDC\nBICO\/USDC\nDelistings:\nWaltonchain (WTC)\nDMM: Governance (DMG)\nXensor (XSR)\nBOX Token (BOX)\nAchain (ACT)\nNDN Link (NDN)\nBLOC.MONEY (BLOC)\nXpool (XPO)\nAllive (ALV)\nEn-Tan-Mo (ETM)\nAeternity (AE)\n\n\n ","ProBit\nListings: \nZappay (ZAPC)\n\n\n ","P2PB2B\nListings: \nEarhart (EHT)\nHyperChain (SNC)\nXRSwan (XRSWAN)\nGoldRush Token (GRUSH)\n\n\n ","VinDax\nListings: \nMetaboardX Token (MTBX)\nCharity Token (CHAT)\n\n\n ","XT\nListings:\nEvmos (EVMOS)\nBBCOIN (BBC)\nRocket Pool (RPL)"],"entity":[{"type":"BCH","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NPR)\nEnergy Empire","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CMP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"TOMTOM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Proton Blockchain (XPR","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Convex Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"AICE","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDC\nKLAY\/USDC\nMXC\/USDC\nMKR\/USDC\nAR\/USDC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Caduceus","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Curve Finance (CRV","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Klever","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"XRP\nCRV","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$HAPPY","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"USDC\nGARI\/USDC\nVRA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DMG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Seele (SEELE","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Euler Finance (EUL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cardano (ADA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NDN","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ICP","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"XRP\nLRC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Marlin Protocol (POND","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DFI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CPS","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gnosis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"WTK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"RPL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BBC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDC\nSLP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"AVAX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SZC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDC\nCSPR\/USDC\nBICO\/USDC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"XETA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sia Foundation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDC\nMTL\/USDT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"AZY)\nCaduceus Metaverse Protocol (CMP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"TOKKI","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"ETM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ShowTime Protocol (STP","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Altcoins","Exchange","Trading"],"authors":["Sumejja Muratagić-Tadić"]}