{"summary":"South Korean Banks Bet Big on Blockchain","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/south-korean-banks-bet-big-on-blockchain-3793.htm","publishDate":"2019-05-03T03:24:29","id":18939,"type":null,"title":"South Korean Banks Bet Big on Blockchain","category":["Blockchain News "],"content":["Some of South Korea’s largest commercial banks are stepping up their blockchain activities in what is proving to be a year of massive investment in fintech for the country.","IBK Bank has teamed up with Terra, a public blockchain provider that operates a blockchain-based payment system. Terra was founded by the creator of one of the country’s biggest e-commerce platforms, TMON – and last year struck a business deal with the Kakako Group’s Ground X blockchain affiliate.","ZDNet Korea quotes Terra’s CEO Shin Hyun-seung as stating that the IBK-Terra partnership will see the companies develop “payment services that consumers can actually experience.” Shin also says the companies will co-create “a wide range of financial products and services.”","IBK has processed more money from South Korean cryptocurrency exchange platforms than any of its rivals.","There was also a blockchain breakthrough for IBK competitor Woori Bank. Woori was given the green light on a blockchain-powered initiative that will allow its customers to exchange foreign and domestic currency or make cash withdrawals of up to USD 850 at airport drive-through restaurants, fast food outlets, stores and parking lots. The initiative will begin in October this year.","Woori’s project is part of a regulatory sandbox program operated by the Financial Services Commission (FSC) – one of the country’s top regulators.","Per ET News, the FSC has also given its approval to a blockchain-powered real estate platform to be co-developed by two more banks – KEB Hana and KB.","Readers may recall that KB is also working with LG on a range of blockchain projects, including a possible LG Coin – a digital token or cryptocurrency currently being tested behind closed doors.","KEB Hana, meanwhile, has previously filed no less than 46 blockchain technology-related patents, and has joined the international R3 CEV, Hyperledger and Enterprise Ethereum Alliance blockchain consortiums.","Earlier this week, a range of South Korea’s largest conglomerates also unveiled the scope of their blockchain ambitions – with plans to commercialize the technology before the year is out."],"entity":[{"type":"Kakako Group’s Ground","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"South Korea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"October this year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Hana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Korea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"fintech","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Woori Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ET News","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Shin Hyun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FSC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Enterprise Ethereum Alliance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"IBK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"KEB Hana","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Terra","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hyperledger","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"IBK Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Financial Services Commission (FSC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"LG","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Adoption","Banking","Blockchain","South Korea"],"authors":["Tim Alper"]}