{"summary":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: March 4, 2024","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/crypto-exchange-listing-and-delisting-announcements-march-4-2024.htm","publishDate":"2024-03-04T19:16:36","id":18994,"type":null,"title":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: March 4, 2024","category":["Altcoin News "],"content":["","Here is our weekly collection of digital asset listing and delisting, trading pair-related announcements by crypto exchanges that we found last week and today.","Have we missed something? Do you have information about new listings and\/or delistings? Let us know here.","_________________________________________","MEXC\nListings:\nGreever (GVL)\nMARS AI (MARS)\nPortal (PORTAL)\nONSWEB3.0 (ONS)\nWork on Bitcoin (WOB)\nCycleFi Protocol (CYF)\nMetahorse Unity (MUNITY)\nDeFrogs (DEFROGS)\nBlock Ape Scissors (BANANA)\nBonk Baby (BOBY)\nLeo (LEO)\nThe Terminal (TTTU)\nBaby Trump (BABYTRUMP)\nMars Coin (MARSCOIN)\nTholana (THOLANA)\nScarQuest (SCAR)\nChainX (IDX)\nArtrade (ATR)\nBeoble (BBL)\nIce Network (ICE)\nCrypto Hunters (CRH)\nDOVU (DOVU)\nChief Troll Grok (CTG)\nWINR Protocol (WINR)\nDreams Quest (DREAMS)\nQORPO (QORPO)\nAfricarare (UBU)\nMetaFighter (MF)\nPets Crush (PETS)\nDogeTF (DOGETF)\nAcria.AI (ACRIA)\nMinu (MINU)\nHomer Simpson (SIMPSONSOL)\nSeamans Project (SEAT)\nKoava (KOAVA)\nAny Dog (AD)\nETCMC (ETCPOW)\nSolanaDoge (SOLANADOGE)\nBillionAir (AIRB)\nProject Hive (HGT)\nDeepFakeAI (FAKEAI)\nChildrens Aid Foundation (CAF)\nGolden Inu (GOLDEN)\nFelix (FEL)\nNavist (NAVIST)\nAIWORLD (AIWLD)\nMars Coin (MARSCOIN)\nInfinityMesh (IFM)\nGold Cow Coin (GCOW)\nAASToken (AAST)\nMAGASOL (MAGASOL)\nStaikaFi (STAIKA)\nMerlin Inu (MERLININU)\nSyncus DAO (SYNC)\nRabi (RABI)\nWeave6 (WX)\nVersity (SITY)\nLittle Kitten Pinky (LKP)"," ","Binance\nListings:\nAxelar Network (AXL)"," ","KuCoin\nListings:\nSatoshiVM (SAVM)\nBeoble (BBL)\nIce Network (ICE)\nPortal (PORTAL)\nQORPO World (QORPO)\nHourglass Protocol (HGP)\nOpenStamp (STAMP)"," ","Bitrue\nListings:\nAkash Network (AKT)\nDelysium (AGI)\nPortal (PORTAL)\nOrange (ORNJ)\nQnA3.AI (GPT)\nBPINKY (BPINKY)\nCircularity Finance (CIFI)"," ","OKX\nListings:\nQnA3.AI (GPT)"," ","Poloniex\nListings:\nKlimaDAO (KLIMA)\nPopcat (POPCAT)\nIndependence Token (RFKJ)\nFlokiFork (FORK)\nMOBY (MOBY)\nIce Network (ICE)\nTao Bank (TBANK)\nShutter (SHU)\nBonkwifhat (BIF)\nDoland tremp (TREMP)\nDizzy Havoc (DZHV)\nArtCoin (AC)\nNeversol (NEVER)"," ","CoinEx\nListings:\nOpSec (OPSEC)\nGraphLinq Chain (GLQ)\nMixMob (MXM)\nVictoria VR (VR)\nSyntropy (NOIA)\nQnA3.AI (GPT)\nAINN (AINN)\nbitsCrunch (BCUT)\nPortal (PORTAL)\nDeChat (DECHAT)\nLTO Network (LTO)\nPandora (PANDORA)\nSynesis One (SNS)\nXRGB (XRGB)"," ","Gate.io\nListings:\nQnA3.AI (GPT)\nPortal (PORTAL)"," ","BitMart\nListings:\nBaby Troll (BABYTROLL)\nRonin (RONIN)\nMXC Foundation (MXC)\nChonky (CHONKY)\nIce Network (ICE)\nBeoble (BBL)\nIX Swap (IXS)\nOpen Games Builders (OGB)\nQnA3.AI (GPT)\nDOVU (DOVU)\nHypra (HYP)\nAvalox (AVALOX)\nyPredict (YPRED)\nSempsun AI 2.0 (SMAI2.0)\nONINO (ONI)\nAASToken (AAST)\nMia (MIA)\nMAGASOL (MAGASOL)\nCatwifhat (CWIF)"," ","LBank\nListings:\nThe Love Care Coin (TLCC)\nThe Quantum Resistant Ledger (QRL)\nPortal (PORTAL)\nLifeBank Chain (LBC)\nTamkin (TSLT)\nCyberDoge (CDOGE)\nBidz Coin (BIDZ)\nVulcan Forged (LAVA)"," ","P2B Crypto Exchange\nListings:\nEpeiron (EPN)\nMoonboi589 (MB589)"," ","AscendEX\nListings:\nAlkimi Exchange (ADS)"," ","BigONE\nListings:\nNoah (NOAH)"," ","Changelly\nListings:\nNFPrompt (NFP)\nThe Grapes (GRAPE)"," ","ChangeNOW\nListings:\nArkham (ARKM)\nRain Coin (RAIN)"," ","Crypto.com\nListings:\nLiquid CRO (LCRO)"," ","Crypto.com Institutional\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nWIF\/USDT"," ","DigiFinex\nListings:\nAvalox (AVALOX)\nAxelar (AXL)"," ","FINEXBOX\nListings:\nJoin, Learn & Thrive (JLT)\nBuddy AI (BUDDY)\nUSEU (USEU)\nEUUS (EUUS)\nDIBCOIN (DIBC)"," ","HitBTC\nListings:\nAnaloS (ANALOS)"," ","HTX\nListings:\nThe Root Network (ROOT)\nBifrost (BFC)"," ","ProBit\nListings:\nFANTARA (FTR)\nKneenano (KNA)"," ","VinDax\nListings:\nBook My Asset (BMA)\nLittle Kitten Pinky (LKP)\nAL-Virland (AVL)\nAPG COINT (APGC)"," ","WazirX\nListings:\nHTX DAO (HTX)\nDelistings:\nDFI.Money (YFII)\nWaltonchain (WTC)"," ","XT\nListings:\nAkash Network (AKT)\nFAYA (FAYA)\nEpik Protocol (AIEPK)\nBullBear AI (AIBB)\nShentu (CTK)\nAlfacoin.io (ALFA)"],"entity":[{"type":"HGP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"OPSEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Vulcan","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Circularity Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"APGC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Doland","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alkimi Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BMA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ONS","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BIF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"IDX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ONI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tamkin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"ALFA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"LTO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"EPN","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"IFM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Merlin Inu","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Epik","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"GPT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CRH","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Learn & Thrive (JLT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"AVL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CTG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Leo (LEO)","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"AXL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Crypto Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ATR","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BFC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"KNA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Childrens Aid Foundation (CAF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Noah (NOAH)","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["Altcoins","Exchange","Trading"],"authors":["Mao Orillana"]}