{"summary":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: May 6, 2024","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/crypto-exchange-listing-and-delisting-announcements-may-6-2024.htm","publishDate":"2024-05-07T10:06:05","id":19061,"type":null,"title":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: May 6, 2024","category":["Altcoin News "],"content":[""," ","Here is our weekly collection of digital asset listing and delisting, trading pair-related announcements by crypto exchanges that we found last week and today.","Have we missed something? Do you have information about new listings and\/or delistings? Let us know here.","_________________________________________","MEXC\nListings:\nPixel Prowler (PPROWLER)\nNinja (NINJA)\nZynecoin (ZYN)\nCrypto GPT (CRGPT)\nErgo (ERG)\nTuna Chain (TUNA)\nRoboHero (ROBO)\nGolazo (GOL)\nTrinity Of The Fabled (ABYS)\nQuantum XAI (QXA)\nSolgoat (SOLGOAT)\nKamino Finance (KMNO)\nThs Binary Hoddings (BNRY)\nLunarStorm (LUST)\nZIGAP (ZIGAP)\nGather (GAT)\nTUX Project (TUXC)\nScrap Guilds (SUIAI)\nGPTVerse (GPTV)\nBet45 (B45)\nAllStreetBets (BETS)\nSTYLE Protocol (STYLE)\nMyst AI (MYSTAI)\nOrditt (Token (ORDITT)\nLuxury Travel Token (LTT)\nLove Power Coin (LOVE)\nAxiome (AXM)\nPOG coin (POGS)\nUndeads Games (UDS)\nReplay (RPLAY)\nPepe Bomb (PEPEBOMB)\nBase Inu (BASEINU)\nCATS (CATS)\nBTC20X (BRCX)\nFOMO Network (FOMONET)\nShockwaves (NEUROS)\nChallenge (CT)\nNodewaves (NWS)\nBonk Wif Glass (BONG)\nPig Coin Hero (PCH)\nMasternoded (NODED)\nBOMEAI (BOMEAI)\nBumper (BUMP)\nSmudge Cat (SMUDGE)\nAgo DeFi (AGO)\nEarthlings.land (STEAM)\nTrump Cat (TRUMPCAT1)\nXuruAI (XUA)\nPin3 (PIN)\nFriend tech (FRIEND)\nInternet Protocol  Coin (IPC)\nChainPL (CPL)\nDogecoin20 (DOGE20)\nBook of Base (BOOKOFBASE)\nAroon Exchange (ARO)\nZeroLand (ZERO)\nTori the Cat (TORI)\nSilomon AI (SLM)\nVOOX AI (VOOXAI)\nXSwap (XSWAP)\nBlockDropCoin (BDROP)\nMode (MODE)"," ","KuCoin\nListings:\nManeki (MANEKI)\nZeroLend (ZERO)\nRenzo (REZ)\nKamino (KMNO)"," ","Bitrue\nListings:\nAI Pepe King (GPTV)"," ","OKX\nListings:\nRunecoin (RUNECOIN)\nZeroLend (ZERO)"," ","Poloniex\nListings:\nPika (PIKA)\nAreon Network (AREA)\nMonke (MONKE)\nTim Does Not (TIM)\nPink Elements (PINK)\nATOR Protocol (ATOR)\nBoomer (BOOMER)\nZeroLend (ZERO)\nAmerican Coin (USA)\nArky (ARKY)\nSad Hamster (HAMMY)"," ","CoinEx\nListings:\nMeson Network (MSN)\nNoggles (NOGS)\nOra Protocol (ORA)\nGlobal Earth Observation Decentralized Network (GEOD)\nFungi (FUNGI)\nRenzo (REZ)\nRunecoin (RUNECOIN)\nKamino (KMNO)\nZeroLend (ZERO)"," ","Gate.io\nListings:\nRunecoin (RUNECOIN)\nKamino (KMNO)\nRenzo (REZ)\nUncommon Goods (UNCOMMONGOODS)"," ","BitMart\nListings:\nRenzo (REZ)\nWelsh Corgi Coin (WELSH)\nRunecoin (RUNECOIN)\nApu Apustaja (APU)\nFriend3.AI (F3)\nBlackCardCoin (BCCOIN)\nAIBlock (AIBCOIN)\nSnort (SNORT)\nNervos Network (CKB)\nShepi Coin (SHEPI)\nCet.sol (CET)\nBITCOIN PAY (BPAY)\nSeahorses (SEAH)\nZeroLend (ZERO)\nFriend.tech (FRIEND)\nBook of Billionaires (BOBE)\nSynthetiX (STX)\nFX Stock Token (FXST)\nUSD MAPPED TOKEN (USDM)\nList Hippo Wallet (HPO)\nPEPE CHAPLIN WIF HAT (PEPEWIFHAT)\nList Swarm (BZZ)\nLandwolf (LANDWOLF)\n"," ","LBank\nListings:\nFluffys (FLUFF)\nRomCoin (ROM)\nFoxPool (FOX2)\nMebe World (MEBE)\nMatar AI (MATAR)\nCrodie (CRODIE)\nMichi (MICHI)"," ","P2B Crypto Exchange\nListings:\nBankcoin Cash (BKCC)\nDog Wif Crocs (DWC)"," ","AscendEX\nListings:\nRenzo (REZ)\nToncoin (TON)\nFriend.tech (FRIEND)\nRublex (RBL)\nTon Fish Memecoin (FISH)\nMahabibi Bin Solman (MBS)","   ","Bitfinex\nListings:\nMode (MODE)"," ","CEX.io\nListings:\nDog Wif Coin (WIF)"," ","Crypto.com\nListings:\nSenor Dip (DIP)\nOpen Custody Protocol (OPEN)\nSpectral (SPEC)"," ","Crypto.com Institutional\nListings:\nSenor Dip (DIP)\nOpen Custody Protocol (OPEN)\nSpectral (SPEC)\n"," ","DigiFinex\nListings:\nCulture trading adventure (CUTAC)"," ","FINEXBOX\nListings:\nBitRo Coin (BTRC)","  ","HTX\nListings:\nMeson Network (MSN)\nRonin (RONIN)\nRenzo (REZ)\nFlux (FLUX)\nNIM Network (NIM)\nZeroLend (ZERO)  "," ","ProBit\nDelistings:\nAleph.Im (ALEPH)\nAloha (ALOHA)\nAnswerly (ANSR)\nCostCoinPlus (AKM)\n","  ","VinDax\nListings:\nRhodium (RHO)\nHard Rock (ROCK)"," ","WazirX\nListings:\nOpen Custody Protocol (OPEN)\nRenzo (REZ)"," ","XT\nListings:\nQuby AI (QYAI)\nUSD Mapped Token (USDM)\nTori the Cat (TORI)\nRenzo (REZ)\nXOOCITY (XOO)\nKamino (KMNO)\nScorpion (SCORP)\nEigenLayer (EIGEN)\nParallel Universe Coin (PUC)\nNetCoinCapital (NCC)\nRoaring Groundhog (AHHH)\nFriend.tech (FRIEND)\nZeroLend (ZERO)\nLynex (LYNX)\nBurnedFi (BURN)\nSpectral (SPEC)"],"entity":[{"type":"NWS","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Maneki (MANEKI","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Crocs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Senor Dip (DIP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"EIGEN)\nParallel Universe Coin (PUC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MSN","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"PIKA)\nAreon Network (AREA)\nMonke (MONKE)\nTim Does Not (TIM)\nPink Elements","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"RBL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Senor Dip","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Crypto GPT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ergo","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"PEPE CHAPLIN","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Pepe King","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Crypto Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CPL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SLM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"PCH","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Matar","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kamino Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Michi (MICHI)","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["Altcoins","Exchange","Trading"],"authors":["Mao Orillana"]}