{"summary":"Elon Musk Sees ‘Broad Acceptance’ For Bitcoin","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/elon-musk-sees-broad-acceptance-for-bitcoin-9079.htm","publishDate":"2021-02-01T07:23:00","id":19077,"type":null,"title":"Elon Musk Sees ‘Broad Acceptance’ For Bitcoin","category":["Bitcoin News "],"content":["Bitcoin (BTC) is on the verge of getting a broad acceptance by the “conventional finance people,” the world’s richest person, Tesla’s Elon Musk said during an interview on Clubhouse, an invitation-only audio-chat social networking app, today.","Musk said he must be careful when talking about cryptocurrencies because his words could move the market. He also added that he doesn’t have “strong opinions on other cryptocurrencies.”","At pixel time (07:22 UTC), BTC trades at USD 33,561 and is unchanged in a day.","As reported, this past Friday, Musk added “#Bitcoin” to his profile on Twitter, later commenting: “In retrospect, it was inevitable”. Following the news, BTC rallied to more than USD 38,400, before it corrected below USD 33,000 again.","Learn more:\nElon Musk Just Asked Robinhood CEO These Questions – Here Are His Answers\nElon Musk Deconstructs Money, Prompting Bitcoiners to Ponder the Meaning\nBTC Drops Below USD 23K While Investors Watch Elon Musk, New Stimulus, and Crackdown\nElon Musk Says There’s No Bitcoin ATM at Gigafactory, But There is A But\nElon Musk, ‘Ethereum’ and ‘jk’. What Could Possibly Go Wrong?\nElon Musk Praises Bitcoin, Says “Paper Money is Going Away”\nBridgewater’s Ray Dalio Sends Stronger Bitcoin Signal\nBitcoin Snowball Is Expected To Hit More Institutions in 2021"],"entity":[{"type":"Tesla’s Elon Musk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Meaning\nBTC Drops Below USD 23K While Investors Watch Elon Musk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Elon Musk Just Asked Robinhood","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Twitter","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Musk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gigafactory","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Clubhouse","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Elon Musk","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ray Dalio","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bridgewater","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["Bitcoin","Elon Musk"],"authors":["Linas Kmieliauskas"]}