{"summary":"‘Trump’ Token Soars on Base, with Traders Eyeing Next Dog-Themed Coin for 100x Jump","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/trump-token-soars-on-base-with-traders-eyeing-next-dog-themed-coin-for-100x-jump.htm","publishDate":"2024-05-08T17:50:40","id":19106,"type":null,"title":"‘Trump’ Token Soars on Base, with Traders Eyeing Next Dog-Themed Coin for 100x Jump","category":["Industry Talk "],"content":["In the latest Base meme coin pump, new Trump MAGA Base token has skyrocketed ahead of the US Presidential Election.","This article will provide an analysis of TRUMP’s current price trends and look to see whether an innovative new meme coin, Dogeverse, represents a more promising investment opportunity at this time.","$Trump on base 0x2024 LFG pic.twitter.com\/mKP4gj8TUb","— 🍊🐉CRYPTO TITAN 💎👑🐉T$UKA (@CRYPTO_TITAN21) May 7, 2024","","The PoliFi meme coin appears to have gained major traction on BASE after striking a chord with MAGA-minded retail investors enjoying the dip on Base meme coins (amid declining trading volumes).","","As TRUMP continues to push up in an emerging second-rally leg move, Trump MAGA Base is currently trading at a market price of $0.00399 (representing a 24-hour change of +23,246%).","This comes after a sensational launch saw TRUMP token gain immediate traction following its launch at 2:40 AM (UTC) on May 8.","Substantial trading volume surged into the project around 5:30AM, triggering an exceptionally impressive +3,394% climb to hit an all-time high at $0.0069.","","However, the impressive gains triggered a quickfire sell-off, which saw TRUMP price tumble -85%.","Yet, a strong display of double-bottomed support at $0.001 set the stage for a resurgent second rally move, which has so far seen the price climb an initial +300% before stalling beneath upside resistance at $0.0042.","Now with a market cap of just over $1m, the current technical structure offers an alluring entry that could lead to 10x gains in the coming hours.","But while Trump’s MAGA Base is popping off again, another viral crypto presale is making waves in the Base chain community.","","DOGEVERSE is continuing to snowball with viral traction on the BASE chain, as the fastest-growing meme coin presale surges past $13m raised – here’s what’s going on.","The answer is simple: the unification of DOGE across all major blockchains.","You heard that right – whilst the original Dogecoin has inspired a huge family of spin-off tokens – no DOGE-linked meme coin has ever delivered multi-chain trading.","DOGEVERSE is here to fill that huge void in the year of Omnichain cryptocurrency.","🐶 📣:\n\"A bit higher, guys\" pic.twitter.com\/OHV19ENomD","— DogeVerse (@The_DogeVerse) May 6, 2024","","DOGEVERSE will operate on Ethereum, Polygon, BNB Chain, Solana, Avalanche, and Base, a multichain feature that supporters will drive prices in 2024.","Moreover, holders cite DOGEVERSE’s capped supply of 200 million combined with staking as attractive attributes.","These features will likely create a supply squeeze, progressively lifting prices over time.","Buy DOGEVERSE Here",""],"entity":[{"type":"2:40","content":"TIME"},{"type":"$1m","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"MAGA","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Polygon","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Base","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"-85%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$0.0042","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$0.0069","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Dogeverse","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Trump’s MAGA Base","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$Trump","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"+23,246%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"May 6, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"US Presidential Election","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$0.00399","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"+300%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Dogecoin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"UTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"LFG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Trump MAGA Base","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"+3,394%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"May 8","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$0.001","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"May 7, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$13m","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["Base meme coin","Trump","TRUMP token"],"authors":["Sam Cooling"]}