{"summary":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: January 2, 2024","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/crypto-exchange-listing-and-delisting-announcements-january-2-2024.htm","publishDate":"2024-01-02T13:49:20","id":19114,"type":null,"title":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: January 2, 2024","category":["Altcoin News "],"content":["","Here is our weekly collection of digital asset listing and delisting, trading pair-related announcements by crypto exchanges that we found last week and today.","Have we missed something? Do you have information about new listings and\/or delistings? Let us know here.","_________________________________________","AscendEX\nListings:\nAvascriptions (ASCT)\nAVAV (AVAV)\nDINO (DINO)\nAtomicals Protocol (ATOM)\nNostr Assets Protocol (NOSTR)\nSilly Dragon (SILLY)\nanaloS (ANALOS)"," ","Binance\nListings:\nNFP (NFP)\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nADA\/USDC\nARB\/USDC\nAVAX\/USDC\nDOT\/USDC\nINJ\/USDC\nMATIC\/USDC\nOP\/USDC\nORDI\/USDC\nSOL\/USDC\nXRP\/USDC\nRemoved Trading Pairs:\nAPE\/BNB\nAPE\/EUR\nARPA\/ETH\nBETA\/ETH\nCVX\/BTC\nENS\/BNB\nEOS\/EUR\nETC\/EUR\nKAVA\/BNB\nPAXG\/BNB"," ","BitMart\nListings:\nPonke (PONKE)\nKAP Games (KAP)\nBabyBonk (BABYBONK)\nATOM (ATOMARC)\nBDID (BDID)\nASCT (ASCT)\nAVAV (AVAV)\nDino (DINO)\nNostr Assets Protocol (NOSTR)\nAnalysoor (ZERO)\nNFPrompt (NFP)\nOrdiswap (ORDS)\nxPET (XPET)\nTRICK (TRICK)\nTREAT (TREAT)\nNFT Strike (NFTS)\nMAGA (TRUMP)\nUnix Gaming (UNIX)\nSnek (SNEK)\nVERGE ERC20 (XVGETH)\nEthereal (ETRL)\nHappy New Year (HPNY)\nMUA DAO (BMBI)"," ","CoinEx\nListings:\nHivemapper (HONEY)\nMICE (MICE)\nanaloS (ANALOS)\n!knoB (KNOB)\nArtyfact (ARTY)\nAnalysoor (ZERO)\nAnalysoor (WHEN)\nGhostly Ghosts (BOOTOKEN)\nDEGO (DEGO)\nNFP (NFP)\nChihuahua (HUAHUA)\nNEAT (NEAT)\nBitcoin Name Service System (BNSX)\nResearchHub (RSC)\nGuacamole (GUAC)"," ","Crypto.com\nListings:\nCorgiAI (CORGIAI)\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nOCEAN\/ETH\nORDI\/ETH\nOSMO\/ETH\nPAXG\/ETH\nILV\/ETH\nLUNA2\/ETH\nLUNC\/ETH\nMASK\/ETH\nPRIME\/ETH\nPUSH\/ETH\nSTRAX\/ETH\nSUPER\/ETH"," ","Crypto.com Institutional\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nBONK\/USDT\nCORGIAI\/USDT\n"," ","DigiFinex\nListings:\nNelore Coin (NLC)\nNFP (NFP)\nSleepless AI (AI)\nAI Register Key (ARK)\nARMY Coin (AMC)"," ","FINEXBOX\nListings:\nSealink Network (SLK)"," ","Gate.io\nListings:\nNEAT (NEAT)\nATOM (ATOMARC)\nNFPrompt (NFP)"," ","HitBTC\nListings:\nOpulous (OPUL)\nPyth Network (PYTH)"," ","HTX\nListings:\nNFP (NFP)\nBTC20.COM (COM)\nPonke (PONKE)\nCoupon Assets (CA)\nxPET (XPET)"," ","KuCoin\nListings:\nanaloS (ANALOS)\nMyro (MYRO)\nSilly Dragon (SILLY)\nHelium Mobile (MOBILE)\nRoup (ROUP)\nOrdinal Open Financial Protocol (OOFP)"," ","LBank\nListings:\n1IOSK (1IOSK)\nHappy New Year (HPNY)\nAits (AITS)\nTongtongCoin (TTC)\nLessFnGas (LFG)\nOrdinal Open Finance Protocol (OOFP)\nPonke (PONKE)\nAnalysoor (Zero)\nMice (MICE)\nxPET (XPET)\nNFPrompt (NFP)\nPlxyer (PLXY)\nMetisDAO (METIS)\nDego Finance (DEGO)\nBlue Kirby (KIRBY)\nSearch AI (SOSO)"," ","MEXC\nListings:\nPiin (PIINS)\nAnalysoor (ZERO)\nWHEN (WHEN)\nInscriptionDAO (ICDA)\nMeme Alliance (MMA)\nJinDAO (JIN)\nSuperpepe (SUPERPEPE)\nZano (ZANO)\nzkGROK (ZKGROK)\nSwiftCloud (SC2)\nAlphaGuard (AGD)\nAlephium (ALPH)\nBrillion (DUA)\nYou Only Live Once (YOLO)\nxPET (XPET)\nDova Protocol (DOVA)\nGP4U (GP4U)\nCook Simpson (COOK)\nRootDex (REX)\nThe Goat (GOAT)\nEcoChain (ECC)\nReach (REACH)\nSol Trading Bot (STBOT)\nGoon (GOON)\nParty Cats (PCT)\nOrders.Exchange (RDEX)\nGeminiAI (GEMINIAI)\nDisCas (DISC)\nWelshcorgicoin (WELSH)\nLessFnGas (LFG)\nGrok Inu (GROKINU)\nHeartAI (HEARTAI)\nJax.Network (WJXN)\nRealWorldX (RWX)\nOpenAI (OPAI)\nDomon (DOC)\nSOLAV (SOLAV)\nGecko Coin (GECKO)\nDesert Wars NFT (DESWAR)\nBank BTC (BANKBTC)\nDoge Moon (DOGEMOON)\nOracle Mesh (OM3)\nDigiNetGuard (DNG)\nFROGMoon (FROG)\nMarkmarkGo (MMG)\niGames (IGS)\nNOTHING (NOTHING)\nBoo Token (BOO1)\nOpenfabric AI (OFN)\nNeurashi (NEI)\nFunft (FFT)\nOmniCat (OMNICAT)\nJoltify (JOLT)\nKAP Games (KAP)\nSleepless AI (AI)\nOrdiswap (ORDS)\nPixel Panic (PIXEL)"," ","OKX\nRemoved Trading Pairs:\nKSM\/USDC\nFLOW\/USDC\nJST\/USDC\nKNC\/USDC\nANT\/USDC\nFSN\/USDT\nZKS\/USDT\nCAPO\/USDT\nCVP\/USDT\nXMR\/BTC\nXMR\/ETH\nXMR\/USDT\nXMR\/USDC\nDASH\/BTC\nDASH\/USDT\nZEC\/BTC\nZEC\/USDT\nZEC\/USDC\nZEN\/BTC\nZEN\/USDT\n"," ","Poloniex\nListings:\nanaloS (ANALOS)\n!knoB (KNOB)\nGh0stly Gh0st (BOO)\nXeggeX (XPE)"," ","P2B Crypto Exchange\nListings:\nRevepe (REV)\nAiMalls (AIT)\nDinarTether (DINT)\nLarge Hadron (LHC)\nNFT Strike (NFTS)"," ","VinDax\nListings:\nBily Coin (BLYCOIN)\nFire Classic Token (FCLT)\nMonte (MONTE)"," ","WazirX\nListings:\nJito (JTO)\nBonk! (BONK)"," ","XT\nListings:\nPyrin (PYI)\nMIMIC COIN (MIMIC)\nTHORChain (RUNE)\nAVAV (AVAV)\nWHEN (WHEN)\nGh0stly Gh0st (BOO)\nFlow (FLOW)\nASCT (ASCT)\nAlfa Coin (ALFA)\nTHE Valkyrie (VKYE)\nEggdog (EGG)\nAlienB Token (ALIENB)\nArweave Ecosystem (AR)\nHanuman Universe Token (HUT)\nPLAYA3ULL GAMES (3ULL)\nFrax Share (FXS)\nPIVX (PIVX)\nSobit Token (SOBB)\nCarbcoin (CARB)\nOrdiswap (ORDS)\nDozy (DOZY)\nSolDegen (DEGEN)\nNFPrompt (NFP)\nTellor (TRB)\nSatoshi Nakamoto (SNMT)"," "],"entity":[{"type":"Domon","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"ECC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"EUR\nETC\/EUR\nKAVA\/BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cook Simpson","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Desert Wars NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDC\nSOL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bank BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Satoshi Nakamoto","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Chihuahua","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Oracle","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MMA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDT\nCAPO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDC\nFSN","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDC\nAVAX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MUA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDC\nDOT\/USDC\nINJ\/USDC\nMATIC\/USDC\nOP\/USDC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDT\nCVP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"LHC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDT\nZEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitcoin Name Service","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"EUR\nARPA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NLC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"LFG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"KSM","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Dego Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kirby (KIRBY","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Dino (DINO","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BTC\nZEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"IGS","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alfa Coin (ALFA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NEI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Crypto Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ADA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Brillion (DUA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ICDA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDC\nJST\/USDC\nKNC","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Altcoins","Exchange","Trading"],"authors":["Mao Orillana"]}