{"summary":"Eliminating Fees, Killing Features, Reducing Payouts and 20 Crypto Jokes","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/eliminating-fees-killing-features-reducing-payouts-and-20-crypto-jokes.htm","publishDate":"2023-12-16T10:00:15","id":19145,"type":null,"title":"Eliminating Fees, Killing Features, Reducing Payouts and 20 Crypto Jokes","category":["Altcoin News "],"content":["","This is your weekly digest of top crypto news from Cryptonews.com, followed by a collection of 20 hand-picked crypto jokes.","__________","This week in crypto: we looked into bitcoin price predictions as BTC surpassed $42,000 amidst dovish Fed signals, as well as ethereum price predictions as JPMorgan said ETH would outperform BTC in 2024, while Mike Novogratz admitted that he was wrong about XRP and altcoins.","Then, FIFA announced an NFT collection in its first collaboration with tech firm Modex, Sotheby’s first Bitcoin inscription auction raised $451,000, Pudgy Penguins revealed its zkSync Era-based Web3 game Pudgy World, and Immutable eliminated fees in its zkEVM gaming solution,","Speaking of games, Immortal Game decided to kill off its NFT and P2E features due to widespread cheating, the Rhysida hacker group attacked Insomniac Games and asked for 50 BTC in ransom, multiple popular dapps were compromised following a hack against a popular Web3 connector, OKX DEX was exploited with some wallets losing around $400,000, and while HTX saw $248 million in net outflow since resuming operations, Justin Sun said customer deposits at HTX and Poloniex are “100% safe” despite multiple recent hacks.","Meanwhile, the Brazilian neobanking unicorn Nubank will begin allowing its customers to make crypto withdrawals, messaging app LINE secured $140 million for expansion of its NFT platform, Nasdaq will leverage the technology developed for its crypto venture to expand into emerging markets, and Deutsche Bank’s DWS Group teamed up with Galaxy Digital to issue a euro stablecoin.","That’s not all. BankSocial said it would launch a credit union that would let people buy and sell digital currencies, a former Credit Suisse executive launched a crypto trading platform for financial institutions, and Worldcoin unveiled integrations with Minecraft, Reddit, Telegram, Shopify, and Mercado Libre.","In Russia, the government claimed that all citizens will be able to use the CBDC in 2024, but the Central Bank insisted that the coin will not be ready for nationwide use before 2025. While major Turkish banking institutions were making moves to secure their positions in the digital asset space, and South Korean financial regulators said NFTs were not subject to the same rules as cryptoassets, the US SEC Chair Gary Gensler evaded questions regarding the status of spot bitcoin ETF application.","Meanwhile, new details emerged surrounding Binance’s compliance requirements in the wake of its plea deal with the US government, Gemini Earn creditors could face up to a 70% reduction in their promised crypto payouts as part of a proposed reorganization plan, and the Hong Kong High Court ruled against Huobi in a trademark infringement case. Also, Sam Bankman-Frieds’s lawyer said his client “may be at the very top of the list as the worst person I’ve ever seen do a cross-examination.”","As that was happening, Cardano introduced a new digital Identity Wallet, Coinbase announced the launch of spot trading for non-US investors on its international exchange, BNB Chain published its tech roadmap for the decentralized storage network BNB Greenfield, and we learned a North American Bitcoin mining infrastructure boom is coming.","And now: the jokes!","__________","Good morning, all!","GM to all the dip survivors pic.twitter.com\/yI8wrZgWpo","— Devchart 👨🏻‍💻 (@devchart) December 13, 2023","","__","Disbelief.","my underwear watching me buy the dip: pic.twitter.com\/k2jxkSwnMx","— LilMoonLambo (@LilMoonLambo) December 13, 2023","","__","“Can’t buy it now, look at it! It dropped.”","__","No more kidneys.","__","Fair enough.","When people ask me about my $BTC + Crypto portfolio pic.twitter.com\/QDYjV5T4O6","— Altcoin Sherpa (@AltcoinSherpa) December 13, 2023","","__","Colourful and bling-bling.","When I show them my portfolio pic.twitter.com\/A3qAJxJXIf","— Gordon (@AltcoinGordon) December 13, 2023","","__","“…if it weren’t for those meddling ETFs!”","__","Investooor.","__","Be honest.","__","Satoshithanksgiving Day.","14+ years and counting since Satoshi made this lifestyle possible and profitable.","Embrace the bottles of piss and sleepless nights. They're coming… pic.twitter.com\/AXlNQu0uMT","— The Crypto Monk (@thecryptomonk) December 12, 2023","","__","Dammit, Janet Yellen!","__","Spreading love, pity, and condescension?","How I treat nocoiners pic.twitter.com\/WTUyMV9M5G","— The Crypto Dog 📈 (@TheCryptoDog) December 12, 2023","","__","Zen.","When you think you bought a 100x shitcoin you are confident about and it rugs the next day. pic.twitter.com\/a1JgXPRSj5","— Blackbeard (@blackbeardXBT) December 11, 2023","","__","Literally, the only reason.","__","…. Can’t even….","Sidelined people, who sold during FTX collapse, making fun of buyers throughout 2023 pic.twitter.com\/HrtvzTm3SL","— The Crypto Monk (@thecryptomonk) December 10, 2023","","__","He’s got (more) complaints.","__","Or you’re married to it, and it just won’t let you escape it.","When you're married to your shit coin bag but you can't let go pic.twitter.com\/xrOT9RlKD7","— Altcoin Sherpa (@AltcoinSherpa) December 11, 2023","","__","Practically rich.","__","Get ready, y’all!","me and the boys when bitcoin goes to $50,000pic.twitter.com\/OwOR2cFeI3","— LilMoonLambo (@LilMoonLambo) December 11, 2023","","__","And lastly, a documentary with actual, found, live footage.","ayo, BTFD. pic.twitter.com\/ar2JaQnDrw","— panamax (@xamanap) December 11, 2023","",""],"entity":[{"type":"Sotheby’s","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"70%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Galaxy Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Janet Yellen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"December 12, 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$50,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$42,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$248 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Mike Novogratz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FIFA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Deutsche Bank’s DWS Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2025","content":"DATE"},{"type":"December 11, 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Central Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cardano","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Satoshi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gemini Earn","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"HTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"3SL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"unicorn Nubank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Pudgy Penguins","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nasdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Reddit","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"GM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fed","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$400,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"100%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Gary Gensler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$140 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"BNB Greenfield","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Telegram","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Russia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$451,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"US SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hong Kong High Court","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$BTC","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Credit Suisse","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"North American Bitcoin","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Justin Sun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"December 13, 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"DEX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Shopify","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"December 10, 2023","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["Community","Humor"],"authors":["Sead Fadilpašić"]}