{"summary":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: January 22, 2024","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/crypto-exchange-listing-and-delisting-announcements-january-22-2024.htm","publishDate":"2024-01-22T11:54:49","id":19193,"type":null,"title":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: January 22, 2024","category":["Altcoin News "],"content":["","Here is our weekly collection of digital asset listing and delisting, trading pair-related announcements by crypto exchanges that we found last week and today.","Have we missed something? Do you have information about new listings and\/or delistings? Let us know here.","_________________________________________","MEXC\nListings:\nLiquid Crypto (LQDX)\nSatoshiVM (SAVM)\nMetatime Coin (MTC)\nKirby Inu (KIRBYINU)\nPepeBonk (PEPEBONK)\nMetaSurvival (ARKT)\nSociaPol (SPOL)\nEcoGreen (ESC)\nSimu (SIM)\nBNB Wolf (BWOLF)\nShell Trade (SS20)\nSmileStack AI (SST)\nmockJUP (MOCKJUP)\nMemerats (MEMERATS)\nGrok CEO (GROKCEO)\nSeed.Photo (SEED)\nDate Booms (DTBOM)\nAltLayer (ALTLAYER)\nGas Labs (BURN)\nQuantumVertics (QTV)\nSatino (STN)\nPikaboss (PIKA)\nCVIP (CVIP)\nBeamswap (GLINT)\nDrago (GRAGO)\nAins Domains (AINS)\nUPYY (UPY)\nBool Ran (BOOL)\nCanxium (CAU)\nStorageChain (WSTOR)\nTrollFace (TROLL)\nSMILEY (SMILEY)\nAnita Max Wynn (WYNN)\nSoBit (SOBB)\nScklingmice (KMICE)\nZELWIN (ZLW)\nRake.com (RAKE)\nELON 2024 (ELON2024)\nSolana Baby (SOLANABABY)\nX Rise (XRISE)\nZuzalu Inu (ZUZALU)\nCapshort (CAPS)\nOneStop (OST)\nOndo (ONDO)\nGold Coin Cat (GCC)\nCatecoin (CATE)\nBonk Grok (BONKGROK)\nBub Ai (BBAI)\nAI Kirby (AIKIRBY)\nMmsscat (MMSSCAT)\nTurtleFly (TF)"," ","Binance\nListings:\nManta Network (MANTA)\nAdded Trading Pairs\nENS\/FDUSD\nETC\/FDUSD\nSUI\/USDC\nTIA\/USDC"," ","KuCoin\nListings:\nISSP.io (ISSP)\nBID Protocol (BIDP)\nSoul Society (HON)\nETGM (ETGM)\nOndo (ONDO)\nDogwifhat (WIF)\nSaros (SAROS)\nGT Protocol (GTAI)\nAmulet (AMU)"," ","Bitrue\nListings:\nSMILEY (SMILEY)\nTectum (TET)\nIce (ICE1)\nManta Network (MANTA)\nOndo (ONDO)\nmockJUP (MOCKJUP)"," ","OKX\nListings:\nIce (ICE)"," ","Poloniex\nListings:\nEggdog (EGG)\nd\/acc (DACC)\nZuzalu Inu (ZUZALU)\nMyra (MYRA)\nMuskX (MUSKX)\nFerret AI (FERRET)\nAnita Max Wynn (WYNN)\nSaga Genesis (GENESIS)\ne\/acc (EACC)\nmockJUP (MOCKJUP)\nOndo (ONDO)\nCroc Cat (CROCCAT)\nSatoshiVM (SAVM)"," ","CoinEx\nListings:\nGameGPT (DUEL)\nRocky (ROCKY)\nAnita Max Wynn (WYNN)\nPop Cat (POPCAT)\nFud (FUD)\nSuiswap (SSWP)\nPhoto Finish LIVE (CROWN)\nZuzalu Inu (ZUZALU)\nSMILEY (SMILEY)\nAI Power Grid (AIPG)\nInspect (INSP)\nWelsh Corgi (WELSH)\nOndo (ONDO)"," ","Gate.io\nListings:\nTrollFace (TROLL)\nIce (ICE)\nGT-Protocol (GTAI)"," ","BitMart\nListings:\nRake Coin (RAKE)\nDevelocity (DEVE)\nVirtual Coin (GVC)\nSMILEY (SMILEY)\nLigo (LIGO)\nManta Network (MANTA)\nDeCats (DECATS)\nZuzalu Inu (ZUZALU)\nFuture Ai (PRT)\nAllianceBlock Nexera (NXRA)\nWUSD (WUSD)\nXOX Labs (XOX)\nNebula Revelation (NBL)\nPunk Sat (PSAT)\nOndo (ONDO)\nEggdog (EGG)\nAnita Max Wynn (WYNN)\nBlocksquare (BST)\nSatoshiVM (SAVM)\nFerret AI (FERRET)\nDigiverse (DIGI)\nArtificial Intelligence Super Chain (AISC)"," ","LBank\nListings:\nPrometheum Prodigy (PMPY)\nPanther Protocol (ZKP)"," ","P2B Crypto Exchange\nListings:\nGreelance (GRL)\nMinu (MINU)"," ","AscendEX\nListings:\nZuzalu Inu (ZUZALU)\nLigo (LIGO)\nManta Network (MANTA)"," ","BigONE\nListings:\nManta Network (MANTA)"," ","Changelly\nListings:\nClover (CLV)\nExit Shopping (EXIT)\npNetwork (PNT)"," ","Crypto.com\nListings:\nOndo (ONDO)\nOraichain (ORAI)\nPocket Network (POKT)\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nWIF\/SOL"," ","Crypto.com Institutional\nListings:\nMiL.K (MLK)\nStreamr (DATA)\nLUKSO (LYX)"," ","DigiFinex\nListings:\nTrollFace (TROLL)\nSolFarm (SFARM)\nSMILEY (SMILEY)\nManta Network (MANTA)\nEntertainment Coin (ETMC)"," ","FINEXBOX\nListings:\nKing Bonk (KINGBONK)"," ","HTX\nListings:\nLevana (LVN)\nZuzalu Inu (ZUZALU)\nManta Network (MANTA)\nOndo (ONDO)\nSaros (SAROS)\nViction (VIC)\nTHORChain (RUNE)\nSMILEY (SMILEY)"," ","VinDax\nListings:\nSushiSwap (SUSHI)\nMission20 V2 (M20V2)\nMemereum (MEME)\nNuson Chain (NSC)\nBull Token (BULL)"," ","WazirX\nListings:\nConflux (CFX)\nFind Satoshi Lab (GMT)\nJito (JTO)\nLiverpeer (LPT)"," ","XT\nListings:\nMetaworld (MWCC)\nRam Sena (RAMSENA)\nManta Network (MANTA)\nSMILEY (SMILEY)\nUBi (UBN)\nSmooth Network Solutions Token (SNST)"," "],"entity":[{"type":"GCC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"AllianceBlock Nexera (NXRA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BST","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nuson Chain (NSC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MANTA","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bonk","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"CFX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ondo","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"UBN","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDC\nTIA\/USDC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DIGI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ondo (ONDO","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Nebula Revelation (NBL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Drago","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Satoshi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Zuzalu Inu","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"King Bonk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Manta","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"GVC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ONDO","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"XOX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Crypto Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kirby","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Anita Max Wynn (WYNN","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["Altcoins","Exchange","Trading"],"authors":["Mao Orillana"]}