{"summary":"Binance Executive Sues Nigerian Authorities for Alleged Rights Violations","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/binance-exec-sues-nigerian-authorities-alleged-rights-violations.htm","publishDate":"2024-03-29T05:24:48","id":19209,"type":null,"title":"Binance Executive Sues Nigerian Authorities for Alleged Rights Violations","category":["News "],"content":["Detained Binance executive Tigran Gambaryan has sued two Nigerian agencies, accusing them of infringing his basic human rights.","Local media outlet Premium Times reported Thursday that the suit was filed against the Natural Security Adviser (NSA) and the Economic Financial Crimes Commission (EFCC) on March 18.","Meanwhile, Nadeem Anjarwalla, Binance’s regional manager for Africa, has also lodged an individual lawsuit for rights enforcement with Justice Ekwo. Anjarwalla, who eluded lawful detention on March 22, is pursuing the same legal remedies as Gambaryan.","Binance didn’t return Cryptonews’ request for comment by press time.","The lawsuits follow the detention of both executives and the confiscation of their passports in February as part of a wider crypto exchange crackdown in Nigeria. Nigerian authorities alleged that Binance violated local tax regulations by failing to provide proper documentation (VAT invoices) and hindering tax collection from its users.","This crackdown was related to Nigerian Naira experiencing frequent depreciation compared to the US dollar.","According to Premium Times, Gambaryan (a US citizen) argued that his detention and passport confiscation violated his right to personal liberty enshrined in Articles 35(1) and (4) of the Nigerian Constitution. He petitioned for his immediate release and the return of his passport.","He further requested a permanent court order barring the authorities from detaining him in connection with any future investigation or demands related to Binance. Additionally, he sought a public apology from the authorities and compensation for all legal expenses incurred.","In a supporting affidavit, Gambaryan clarified that he visited Nigeria on Feb. 26 solely as a Binance representative, attending a meeting requested by the authorities to discuss relevant issues.","He further asserted that he neither committed any offense during the meeting, nor received prior written notification of any alleged wrongdoing in Nigeria.","During the hearing on Thursday, a senior Nigerian lawyer, TJ Krukrubo, appeared on behalf of both executives, but clarified they lacked official legal representation. He notified the court of a previously submitted withdrawal notice filed for Anjarwalla on March 26.","In light of the missing representation, Justice Echo postponed the case until April 8. This adjournment allows the applicants to secure legal counsel and provides the respondents with additional preparation time."],"entity":[{"type":"Natural Security Adviser (NSA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Economic Financial Crimes Commission (EFCC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nigerian Naira","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"March 18","content":"DATE"},{"type":"February","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Feb. 26","content":"DATE"},{"type":"March 26","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Justice Echo","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"TJ Krukrubo","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"March 22","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Nadeem Anjarwalla","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Justice Ekwo","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tigran Gambaryan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Nigeria","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Premium Times","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April 8","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Africa","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["Binance","Nigeria"],"authors":["Shalini Nagarajan"]}