{"summary":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: January 8, 2024","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/crypto-exchange-listing-and-delisting-announcements-january-8-2024.htm","publishDate":"2024-01-09T02:37:00","id":19228,"type":null,"title":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: January 8, 2024","category":["Altcoin News "],"content":["","Here is our weekly collection of digital asset listing and delisting, trading pair-related announcements by crypto exchanges that we found last week and today.","Have we missed something? Do you have information about new listings and\/or delistings? Let us know here.","_________________________________________","AscendEX\nListings:\nDogihub (HUB)\nQuark (QUARK)\nOrdinals OS (ODOS)\nRestake Finance (RSTK)\nZKFair (ZKF)"," ","Binance\nListings:\nSleepless AI (AI)\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nICP\/FDUSD\nLDO\/FDUSD\nMOVR\/TRY\nRemoved Trading Pairs:\nANT\/BNB\nDAR\/EUR\nHIGH\/BNB\nHOOK\/BNB\nLOKA\/BNB\nRPL\/BTC\nXTZ\/TRY\n"," ","BitMart\nListings:\nLess Fess & Gas (LFG)\nBRC App (BRCT)\n2024 (2024)\nSleepless AI (AI)\nOrdinals OS (ODOS)\nAIGC (AIGC)\nETF (ETF)\nPax Unitas (PAXU)\nJTC Network (JTC)\nContract Dev AI (0xDEV)\nTitan Finance (TTT)\nVerge (XVG)\nMaidSafe (EMAID)\nPort3 Network (PORT3)\nXai (XAI)"," ","Bitrue\nListings:\nSleepless AI (AI)\nMedifakt (FAKT)\nZKFair (ZKF)\nPort3 Network (PORT3)\nXai (XAI)"," ","Changelly\nListings:\nChainflip Labs (FLIP)\nPARSIQ (PRQ)\n","   ","CoinEx\nListings:\na gently used 2001 honda civic (USEDCAR)\nLess Fess & Gas (LFG)\nAccess Protocol (ACS)\nSoBit (SOBB)\nOrdiswap (ORDS)\nKryptonite – Sei Liqui (SEILOR)\nSatoxcoin (SATOX)\nSEIYAN on SEI (SEIYAN)\nBork (BORK)\nSleepless AI (AI)\nMAP Protocol (MAP)\nFact0rn (FACT)\nVirtual Versions (VV)\nPort3 Network (PORT3)"," ","Crypto.com\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nHNT\/SOL\nORCA\/SOL\nJTO\/SOL\nMNDE\/SOL\nPYTH\/SOL\nDOGE\/CORGIAI\nSHIB\/CORGIAI\n"," ","Crypto.com Institutional\nListings:\nElastos (ELA)\nPolygon Ecosystem Token (POL)\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nSEI\/USDT\nNEON\/USDT\n"," ","DigiFinex\nListings:\nAnalysoor (ZERO)\nKalamos (KAL)\nFlappy Moonbird (FMB)"," ","Gate.io\nListings:\nSleepless AI (AI)\nGetReach (REACH)\nEthscriptions (ETHS)"," ","HitBTC\nListings:\nBeam (BEAMX)\nVoxie Tactics (VOXEL)\nCurioDAO (CGT)\nIspolink (ISP)\n"," ","HTX\nListings:\nanaloS (ANALOS)\nSleepless AI (AI)\nOrdiswap (ORDS)\nZKFair (ZKF)"," ","KuCoin\nListings:\nBitCoin Cats (1CAT)\nRaydium (RAY)\nALEX Lab (ALEX)\nZKFair (ZKF)\nPort3 Network (PORT3)\nXai (XAI)"," ","LBank\nListings:\nSleepless AI (AI)\nMysterious Point (MSP)\nBork (BORK)\nBaby Grok (BABYGROK)\nDynasty Coin (DNY)\nIslamic Coin (ISLM)\nMETAFROMCO (FROMCO)"," ","MEXC\nListings:\nBaby Bonk (BABYBONK)\nBrcAutoBot (BAB)\nLedgix (LDX)\nMartian (MARTIAN)\nBRC App (BRCT)\nRocket (ROCKET)\nVaporWallet (VPR)\nSacabam (SCB)\nLeviatanbonk (LEVIATANBONK)\nGrok Bank (GROKBANK)\nSolDragon (DRAGON)\nknoB! (KNOB)\nDataChain (DCP)\nNFTD (NTD)\nPayslink (PAYS)\nAiRight (AIRI)\nPropy (PRO)\nBrcExchange (BEX)\nZKFair (ZKF)\nMopher (MPR)\nXai (XAI)\nCracle (CRAC)\nSilly Coin (SILYCOIN)\n2024 (2024)\nManta Hero (MHERO)\nIron Man Fi (IRONHERO)\nPort3 Network (PORT3)\nMainnetZ (NETZ)\nVirtual Coin (VRC)\nBitland (BLLB)\nSolana Shiba (SSHIB)\nHeFi (HEFI)","  ","OKX\nListings:\nJito (JTO)\nBonk! (BONK)\nRemoved Trading Pairs:\nDOME\/USDT\nFAME\/USDT\n"," ","Poloniex\nListings: "," ","ProBit\nListings:\nSeeU (SEEU)\nDovi_L2 (DOVI)\nBFI Coin (BFIC)\nNFPrompt (NFP)\nSleepless AI (AI)\nMultiBit (MUBI)\nTurtSat (TURT)\nOrdiswap (ORDS)\nBitStable (BSSB)\nGuacamole (GUAC)\nA gently Used 2001 Honda Civic (USEDCAR)\nCoq Inu (COQ)\nZKFair (ZKF)\nShdwDrive (SHDW1)"," ","P2B Crypto Exchange\nListings:\nBitcoin Vault (BTCV)"," ","VinDax\nListings:\nElonPepe (ELONPEPE)"," ","WazirX\nListings:\nImmutable (IMX)\nWoo Network (WOO)\nAdventure Gold DAO (AGLD)\nDelistings:\nBUSD (BUSD)"," ","XT\nListings:\nAutonolas (OLAS)\nOften (OFTN)\nRabbit DAO (RABBIT)\nXSaiyan (SAIX)\nCoinNavigator (CNG)\nMainnetZ (NETZ)\nChainGPT (CGPT)\nLords (LORDS)\nPikaboss (PIKA)\nEthereum Name Service (ENS)"," "],"entity":[{"type":"MSP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ACS","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CGT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"PIKA)\nEthereum Name Service","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USEDCAR)\nLess Fess & Gas (LFG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Titan Finance (TTT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Restake Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BNB\nRPL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FMB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ICP","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"USDT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"VOXEL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BFI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bork (BORK","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2001","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"USDT\nNEON\/USDT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MPR","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"LFG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"VRC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"JTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BEX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Manta","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"BRC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BNB\nDAR\/EUR\nHIGH\/BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SCB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Crypto Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DataChain (DCP","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Altcoins","Exchange","Trading"],"authors":["Mao Orillana"]}