{"summary":"Binance.US Officially Adds Binance Coin to Their Markets","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/binance-s-riddle-what-is-bnb-doing-on-binance-us-4677.htm","publishDate":"2019-09-18T10:29:00","id":19251,"type":null,"title":"Binance.US Officially Adds Binance Coin to Their Markets","category":["Altcoin News "],"content":["Binance.US, the American branch of major crypto exchange Binance, confirmed today that Binance coin (BNB) has been added to the Phase 1 digital asset offerings. (Updated at 11:36 UTC: the first paragraph has been updated and a recent tweet by Binance.US has been added)","Even before the official confirmation, the news were already circulating on social media and BNB was already featured on the Binance.US website.","___","Earlier today, Changpeng Zhao, the CEO of Binance, retweeted a screenshot with BNB in it, only adding “Utility token $BNB.”","“Although the new U.S. exchange will be a subsidiary company the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission is unlikely to be impressed by the business model of Binance. The BNB token is both a security and a utility token and as such passes the Howey test for being a security irrespective of its utility properties,” cryptocurrency analyst Gary McFarlane recently told Cryptonews.com. Other experts also agree that BNB would certainly pass the Howey test, and that the token is likely to become problematic for Binance as it establishes itself in America.","We’ve contacted Binance.US for comment and will update the article should they reply.","Yesterday, Binance.US said that at launch new users will be able to registered in most U.S. states, except Alabama, Alaska, Connecticut, Florida, Georgia, Hawaii, Idaho, Louisiana, New York, North Carolina, Texas, Vermont, and Washington.","Binance stopped their service to the U.S. customers on September 12, while Binance.US will take its place. At the time, Binance coin (BNB), was not on the initial list despite it being mentioned among 30 crypto assets that Binance.US is considering to list. The initial Binance.US registration phase opens today.","At pixel time (11:32 UTC), BNB trades at c. USD 22.8 and is up by 10% in the past 24 hours and by almost 5% in the past week."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$BNB","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Hawaii","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Louisiana","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"10%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Idaho","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Changpeng Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Gary McFarlane","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Connecticut","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Florida","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Washington","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"UTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Georgia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"America","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Texas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"North Carolina","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Vermont","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"September 12","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alabama","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Howey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alaska","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["Binance","Binance Coin"],"authors":["Sead Fadilpašić"]}