{"summary":"De.Fi 2.0: Revolutionizing SocialFi & Antivirus, Secures $5 Million in Funding","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/de-fi-2-0-revolutionizing-socialfi-antivirus-secures-5-million-in-funding.htm","publishDate":"2023-11-21T13:48:57","id":19255,"type":null,"title":"De.Fi 2.0: Revolutionizing SocialFi & Antivirus, Secures $5 Million in Funding","category":["DeFi News "],"content":["De.Fi, a platform that describes itself as a “SocialFi & Antivirus SuperApp,” has achieved a major milestone with the introduction of decentralized finance (DeFi) platform De.Fi 2.0, along with an ongoing public sale of its DEFI token.","So far, the project has successfully raised $5 million, with the sale still open for users eager to join the 2.0 ecosystem.","Investments can be made either with crypto using BNB, USDT or USDC, or directly with a credit card.","Originating during the so-called “DeFi Summer” of 2020 as a community of yield farmers, De.Fi has now evolved, resolving multiple industry challenges and expanding its user base over 100 times in the past three years, according to Michael Rosmer, the project’s co-founder.","De.Fi’s contributions include defusing over 540,000 risk tokens, potentially saving a staggering $27 billion by identifying scams based on smart code, sometimes before a scam project even goes live.","The project has been supported by HOF Capital, one of the early investors instrumental in the success of Tesla and SpaceX, Rosmer said about his project’s backers in a video on the De.Fi website.","Other notable investors in the project include the venture arms of the crypto exchanges OKX, Huobi, and MEXC, as well as former directors from the top-tier exchanges Binance and Coinbase."],"entity":[{"type":"SpaceX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"HOF Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tesla","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Michael Rosmer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$27 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Rosmer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Huobi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$5 million","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["DeFi"],"authors":["Fredrik Vold"]}