{"summary":"Fifty Shades of Blockchain Is Dogecoin Creator’s New Venture","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/fifty-shades-of-blockchain-is-dogecoin-creator-s-new-venture-2194.htm","publishDate":"2018-07-09T10:06:00","id":19284,"type":null,"title":"Fifty Shades of Blockchain Is Dogecoin Creator’s New Venture","category":["Blockchain News "],"content":["Dogecoin, arguably the internet’s favorite coin and the living embodiment of a meme, sees its team members working on other, equally hilarious projects. This time, its creator Jackson Palmer has launched a bot that tweets lines from the erotic novel Fifty Shades of Grey, mashed with jargon-filled lines from industry whitepapers.","Fifty Shades of Blockchain is a new Twitter account that Palmer says he’ll keep developing so nobody misses out on the juicy life of the crypto Mr. Grey, according to thenextweb.com. The original novel was filled to bursting with groan-worthy phrases such as “my inner goddess” (that keeps jumping up and down all the time…) and “desire pools dark and deadly in my groin,” and this is not the first parody of the infamous book. But it definitely is in the cryptoverse.","Highlights of the lovely works of art that the bot comes up with include:","And this is not even the first time that the Dogecoin community came up with something equally hilarious and astounding. Back in 2014, they crowdfunded USD 30,000 worth of cryptocurrency in a bid to send Jamaica’s bobsled team to the Winter Olympics in Sochi, Russia."],"entity":[{"type":"Fifty Shades of Blockchain","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2014","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Palmer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jamaica","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sochi","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Grey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Winter Olympics","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Russia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Fifty Shades of Grey","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jackson Palmer","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["Community","Dogecoin","Humor"],"authors":["Sead Fadilpašić"]}