{"summary":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: December 18, 2023","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/crypto-exchange-listing-and-delisting-announcements-december-18-2023.htm","publishDate":"2023-12-18T21:47:07","id":19282,"type":null,"title":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: December 18, 2023","category":["Altcoin News "],"content":["","Here is our weekly collection of digital asset listing and delisting, trading pair-related announcements by crypto exchanges that we found last week and today.","Have we missed something? Do you have information about new listings and\/or delistings? Let us know here.","_________________________________________","AscendEX\nListings:\nTurtSat (TURT)\nSolscription (SOLS)\nBTCs (BTCS)\nKong (KONG)\nNxHub (NHUB)\nBNSx (BNSX)","  ","BigONE\nListings:\nBonk (BONK)\nSolscription (SOLS)"," ","Binance\nListings:\nBonk (BONK)\nFusionist (ACE)"," ","Bitfinex\nListings:\nGoMining (GOMINING)","  ","BitMart\nListings:\nFluxbot (FLUXB)\nZKP Panther (ZKP)\nVanguard (VANGUARD)\nEno Token (ENO)\nSeamless (SEAM)\nArtCoin ($AC)\nzkPEPE (ZKPEPE)\nCrazy Rabbit (CRC)\nFinschia (FNSA)\nSolscription (SOLS)\nBreederDAO (BREED)\nHelium Mobile (MOBILE)\nKongscription (KONG)\nLandwolf (WOLF)\nFinance AI (F.AI)\nUnielon (UNIX)\nDexCheck (DCK)\nBTCs (BTCS)\nBNSx (BNSX)\nMICE (MICE)\nFusionist (ACE)\nStablecomp (SCOMP)\nNIKO (NKO)\n"," ","Bitrue\nListings:\nNEWM (NEWM)\nOggy Inu (OGGY)\nFusionist (ACE)\nCoq Inu (COQ)\nSolscription (SOLS)\nSolidus Ai Tech (AITECH)","  ","Changelly\nListings:\nDrep (DREP)\nInjective (INJ)\nCLV by Clover (CLV)\nQredo (QRDO)"," ","ChangeNOW\nListings:\nEnjin (ENJ)","  ","CoinEx\nListings:\nGood Games Guild (GGG)\nRealms.World (LORDS)\nDIMO (DIMO)\nZephyr Protocol (ZEPH)\nEmpyreal (EMP)\nVitaDAO (VITA)\nThe Root Network (ROOT)\nFusionit (ACE)"," ","Crypto.com\nListings:\nBonk (BONK)"," ","DigiFinex\nListings:\nOrdinals (DOVI)\nKeep Finance (KEEP8)\nFusionist (ACE)"," ","Gate.io\nListings:\nSolscription (SOLS)\nDogi (DOGI)\nFusionist (ACE)\nBTCs (BTCS)\nMICE (MICE)\nBNSx (BNSX)","  ","HitBTC\nListings:\nBonk (BONK)\nShrapnel (SHRAP) "," ","HTX\nListings:\nJito (JTO)\nMyro (MYRO)\nMultiBit (MUBI)\nTurtSat (TURT)\nBitStable (BSSB)\nCoq Inu (COQ)\nFusionist (ACE)"," ","KuCoin\nListings:\nDovi (DOVI)\nSeamless (SEAM)\nFinceptor (FINC)\nGame Tournament Trophy (GTT)\nMarinade (MNDE)\nCoq Inu (COQ)\nRebase GG (IRL)"," ","LBank\nListings:\nFinschia (FNSA)\nCapverse (CAP)\nWEB3MET (W3M)\nVanar Chain (VANRY)\nMAP Protocol (MAPO)\nBTCs (BTCS)\nFusionist (ACE)\nGrok Girl (GROKGIRL)"," ","MEXC Global\nListings:\nMcCheese (MCCHEESE)\nTokenize Emblem (TKX)\nZeroX (ZEROX)\nDeFi Mall (DFM)\nLevana (LVN)\nSerenity Shield (SERSH)\nBandZai (BZAI)\nSats (SATS)\nHelium Mobile (MOBILE)\nEnergi (NRG)\nMEME Coin (MEME3)\nWater (WATER)\nAstrobits (ASTRB)\nEthereal (ETRL)\nCapverse (CAP)\nRonald McDonald (RONALD)\nSuper Trade (SPX)\nNovaDEX (NCX)\nRice (RCE)\nVoluMint (VMINT)\nBonk 2.0 (BONK2)\nGM (GMBRC)\nRabbit Games (RAIT)\nSportuniverse (SUV)\nBRC20.COM (COM)\nZbyte (DPLAT)\nPanda (PANDA)\nHomer Simpson (HOMER)\nDoracle (DRC)\nLandX Finance (LNDX)\nLandwolf (WOLF)\nSatsMax (SATS2)\nGalaxy Wallet (GAX)\nXDC Network (XDC)\nShiro (SHIRO)\nToffeenut (TOFFEE)\nStarship (STARSHIP)\nSappchat (SEC)\nXRPBABY (XRPBABY)\nORDI (ORDI)\nAIHub (AIH)\nGPTPlus (GPTPLUS)\nSOLS (SOLS1)\nGrok X (GROKX)\nMagator (MGC)\nROOS (ROOS)\nOrdi Plus (TRBS)\nTeslai (TESLAI)\nThe Lumina (TLT)\nDecubate (DCB)\nApeBond (ABOND)\nOrdinals Inscribe (ORDII)\nSeamless (SEAM)\nXAIGROK (XAIGROK)\nHonorswap (HONOR)\nPepeultimate (PEPE8)\nCalm Finance (CALM)\nFusionist (ACE)\nTunnel (TNL)\nX-Metapol (XMP)\nCovasart (CO)\nThe Root Network (ROOT)\nCyberTruck (CYBERTRUCK)\nGOOD (GOOD)","   ","OKX\nListings:\nFusionist (ACE)\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nSATS\/USDT"," ","Poloniex\nListings:\nGeometric Energy Corporation (GEC)\nWEB (WEB)\nChainflip Labs (FLIP)\nMind (MIND)\nByte (BYTE)"," ","ProBit\nListings:\nDogelon Mars (ELON)\nLimoverse (LIMO)\nPomerium Ecosystem Token (PMG)\nLove.io (LOVE)"," ","P2B Crypto Exchange\nListings:\nStatescoin (SSC)\nDawg Coin (DAWG)\nSolidus AITECH (AITECH)\nColour (CDM)\nPomerium Ecosystem Token (PMG)\nAidi Finance Token (AIDI)\nINTDESTCOIN (INTD)\n"," ","VinDax\nListings:\nSnow Leopard (IRBIS)\nINTDESTCOIN (INTD)\nSafeBLAST (SAFEBLAST)\nMETA BSG (MBSG)"," ","WazirX\nListings:\nWAX (WAXP)\nSelfKey (KEY)\nFUN Token (FUN)\nBounce Brand (AUCTION)"," ","XT\nListings:\nCheelee (CHEEL)\nRiso Finance (RISO)\nMaximus Vegas (MAXIMUS)\nZero (ZERO)\nDIMO (DIMO)\nFusionist (ACE)\nFact0rn (FACT)\nLiquidLayer (LILA)"],"entity":[{"type":"MGC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"EMP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dovi (DOVI","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Pomerium","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"GM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$AC","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Riso Finance (RISO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ronald McDonald (RONALD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"VANGUARD)\nEno Token (ENO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DFM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Colour (CDM)\nPomerium Ecosystem Token (PMG)\nAidi Finance Token","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Geometric Energy Corporation (GEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Shiro (SHIRO","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BSG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DRC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CRC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bonk (BONK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"TNL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Crypto Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"WOLF)\nFinance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Vanguard","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Altcoins","Exchange","Trading"],"authors":["Mao Orillana"]}