{"summary":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: March 25, 2024","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/crypto-exchange-listing-and-delisting-announcements-march-25-2024.htm","publishDate":"2024-03-26T04:50:37","id":19287,"type":null,"title":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: March 25, 2024","category":["Altcoin News "],"content":[""," ","Here is our weekly collection of digital asset listing and delisting, trading pair-related announcements by crypto exchanges that we found last week and today.","Have we missed something? Do you have information about new listings and\/or delistings? Let us know here.","_________________________________________","MEXC\nListings:\nDemonWar (DAT)\nDaVinciGraph (DAVINCI)\ni don’t know (IDK)\nSylo (SYLO)\nBeFi Labs (BEFI)\nSealwifhat (SI)\nAIPandora (AIPANDORA)\nVenom (VENOM)\nLegendary Meme (LME)\nMulti AI (MULTIAI)\nAzure Wallet (AZURE)\nNon-Playable Coin (NPC)\nWag the dog (WTD)\nBitLex (BL)\nZeroVirtual (ZVI)\nMOMO 2.0 (MOMO)\nGAMER (GMR)\nScamfari (SCM)\nKermit (KERMIT)\ndogewifhat (DIF)\niMe Lab (LIME)\nARBUZ (ARBUZ)\nCreaTiveAISwap (CTAS)\nToadie Meme Coin (TOAD)\nOcher (OCHER)\nDimitra (DMTR)\nKitchen Haimer (KHAI)\nSquadSwap (SQUAD)\nNEXUS (NEX)\nArkadiko (DIKO)\nsmole (SMOLE)\nColana (COL)\nAndy (ANDY)\nBVM Network (BVM)\nMarpto (MRPT)\nChatni (CHATNI)\nDeepBrain Chain (DBC)\nAtlas Navi (NAVI)\nPandora GPT (PANDORAGPT)\nEsCoin (ELG)\nEACC (EACC)\nNodeFreedToken (NF)\nTyrel Derpden (TYREL)\nFrogonsol (FROGONSOL)\nGIB (GIB)\nMILLI (MILLI)\nPikamoon (PIKA)\nSovryn (SOV)\nTrollVerse (TV)\nDRUNK Token (DRUNK)\nCircuitry (CIRCRUITY)\nBrainers (BRAINERS)\nShaunt Gaming (SUT)\nWCD (WCD)\nAventis AI (AVENTISAI)\nKalichain (KALIS)\nLFG2024 (LFG2024)\nXLV (XA)\nTokHit (TH)\nQuantum PAWS (PAWS)\nTAO Inu (TAONU)\nTOPAI (TOPAI)\nSheertopia (AMBO)\nAutoAir AI (AAI)\nK9 Finance DAO (KNINE)\nPolyhedra Network (ZK)\nUWON (UWON)\nMEGE (TREMP1)\nEcoterra (ECOTERRA)\nVariation Pepe (VT)\nDooDoo (DOODOO)\nGRE Labs (GRE)\nSuper Best Friends (SUBF)\nOracle AI (ORACLE)\nDanol Tremp (TRWP)\nSORAI (SORAI)\nGorilla In A Coupe (GIAC)\nPunkAI (PUNKAI)\nBABYDOGWIFHAT (BABYWIF)\nLICKGOAT (LICK)\nSam Altman Project (SAM)\nSource Code AI (SCAI)\nMinerGate (MGT)"," ","Binance\nDelistings:\nDREP (DREP)\nMobilecoin (MOB)\npNetwork (PNT)"," ","KuCoin\nListings:\nGaimin (GMRX)\nBeFi Labs (BEFI)"," ","Bitrue\nListings:\nPolyhedra (ZK)\nDiamond Standard Co. (CARAT)\nSmole (SMOLE)\nGrimace (GRIMACE)\nDegen (DEGEN)\nBrett (BRETT)\nDelistings:\nAdax (ADAX)\nAergo (AERGO)\nArivaSwap (ARVS)\nBitcoin (BITCOIN)\nBlockWorkz (BLKZ)\nCelsius (CEL)\nCelestial (CELT)\nChorusX (CX1)\nDuck DAO (DUCK)\nCoinerr (ERR)\nStrategy Engine (FSE)\nGifthands (GHD)\nGreyhound (GREYHOUND)\nHXAcoin (HXA)\nJD Coin (JD)\nOpen Exchange (OX)\nLyra (LYRA)\nMilk Token (MILK)\nMone Coin (MONE)\nMotionWreck (MWG)\nEnvelop (NIFTSY)\n0xDAO (OXD)\nPepeCoin (PEPECOIN)\nPepe 2.0 (PEPE2)\nShiba Predator (QOM)\nSea Token (SEA)\nStrong Inu (SINU)\nSmartLOX (SMARTLOX)\nSmartNFT (SMARTNFT)\nTERA (TERA)\nTornado Cash (TORN)\nZKBase (ZKS)\nShapeShift (FOX)\nMetagalaxy (MEGALAND)\nPLC Ultima (PLCU)\nPLC Ultima Classic (PLCUC)\n"," ","OKX\nListings:\nPolyhedra (ZK)\nVenom Network (VENOM)"," ","Poloniex\nListings:\nSNAP (NAP)\nDupe (DUPE)\nKermit (KERMIT)\nAVAX Has No Chill (NOCHILL)\nSmole (SMOLE)\nGrimace Coin (GRIMACE)\nBriun Armstrung (BRIUN)\nDegen (DEGEN)\nNormie (NORMIE)\nEchelon Prime (PRIME)\nPnut (PNUT)\nEntangle (NGL)\nMatr1x Fire (FIRE)\nLOOM (LOOMSOL)\nTrippy Labs (SHROOM)\nCommunity of Meme (COME)\nMoonlandMeta (MTK)\nVenom (VENOM)\nPIPI (PIPI)\nPanda Swap (PANDA)\nCatwifhat (CWIF)\nDogWifCat (DWIFC)\nBasenji (BENJI)"," ","CoinEx\nListings:\nPolyhedra (ZK)\nMumu The Bull (MUMU)\nDUKO (DUKO)\nSmole (SMOLE)\nMOCHI on BASE (MOCHI)\nDooDoo (DOODOO)\nGecko Inu (GEC)\nFluence DAO (FLT)\nZero1 Labs (DEAI)\nVenom (VENOM)\nBeFi Labs (BEFI)\nRealio (RIO)"," ","Gate.io\nListings:\nIQ.wiki (IQ)\nSmole (SMOLE)"," ","BitMart\nListings:\nBillion Dollar Inu (BINU)\nPolyhedra Network (ZK)\nKmonCoin (KMON)\nWAGMI (WAGMI)\ni dont know (IDK)\nGenius Crypto Token (GNUS)\nHUND (HUND)\nJC Coin (JCC)\nTrump Inu (TRUMPINU)\nKermit (KERMIT)\nMeme 2.0 (BOME2)\nRunTuCoin (RTC)\nLAVA (LAVA)\nDegen (DEGEN)\nApeWifHat (APEWIFHAT)\nCamel Tec (CAMELTEC)\nShibaAi Club (SHIBAAI)\nLoom (LOOM)\nSmole (SMOLE)\nParifi (PRF)\nBABA (BABA)\nMiss Flokita (FLOKITA)\nNormie (NORMIE)\nBased Shiba Inu (BSHIB)\ndoginme (DOGINME)\nLynex (LYNX)\nPublic Meme Token (PMT)\nTrumpJr (TRUMPJR)\nZero1 Token (DEAI)\nShina Inu (SHI)\nLumerin (LMR)\nQuerio (QRO)\nObi Real Estate (OBICOIN)\ncatwifbag (CATWIFBAG)\nSonic Goat (sGOAT)\nTimpi (NTMPI)\n"," ","LBank\nListings:\nLithosphere (LITHO)\nMumu The Bull (MUMU)\nDimitra (DMTR)\nNormie (NORMIE)\nTrump Inu (TRUMPINU)\nBook of Meme 2.0 (BOME2)\nGrimace (GRIMACE)\nWalk Up Token (WUT)\n300FIT Network (FIT)\nAI Dragon (CHATGPT)\nLadyf (LADYF)\nPDT (PDT)\nBig Pump (PUMP)"," ","P2B Crypto Exchange\nListings:\nClimacoin (CLICO)\nZbyte (DPLAT)\nMAGA VP (MVP)\nMetamui (MMUI)\nLondon Coin Gold (LDXG)\nHugeWin (WIN)"," ","AscendEX\nListings:\nPolyhedra (ZK)\nSolidus Ai Tech (AITECH)\nLoom on Solana (LOOM)\nStash Inu (STASH)\nDegen (DEGEN)\ndoginme (DOGINME)\nPIPI (PIPI)\nDamex (DAMEX)\nVoltage Finance (VOLT)","   ","Bitfinex\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nLYM\/USDT","  ","catEx\nListings:\nBFIC Gold (BFICGOLD)"," ","CEX.io\nListings:\nThe Render Network (RNDR)\nORDI (ORDI)\nether.fi (ETHFI)\nBook Of Meme (BOME)\nPolyhedra (ZK)\nWorldcoin (WLD)\nMask Network (MASK)\nQtum (QTUM)\nens.eth (ENS)\nSui (SUI)\neCash (XEC)"," ","Changelly\nListings:\nCheelee (CHEEL)\nAltLayer (ALT)\nOndo Finance (ONDO)\nSymbiosis (SIS) ","  ","Crypto.com\nListings:\nPolyhedra (ZK)\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nORAI\/CDCETH\nORAI\/ETH\n"," ","Crypto.com Institutional\nListings:\nPolyhedra (ZK)\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nMOG\/USDT\nMYRO\/USDT\nSOL\/ETH"," ","DigiFinex\nListings:\nether.fi (ETHFI)\nSNAP (NAP)\nMAGA VP (MVP)\nEntreep Token (ENTT)\nMAGA Trump (MAGATRUMP)\nMoney Gold Coin (MOGC)\nOndo (ONDO)","   ","HTX\nListings:\nIce Network (ICE)\nSmole (SMOLE)\nNormie (NORMIE)","     ","Nexo\nListings:\nSei (SEI)\nSui (SUI)","    ","ProBit\nListings:\nXensei (XSEI)\nTechno (TCN)\nDelistings:\nMoeda (MDA)\nMedium Token (MDM)\nMONK (MONK)\nMS Token (MST)\nPLANET (PLA)\nQuiztok (QTCON)\n"," ","VinDax\nListings:\nDNApet Infinity (PET)\nGemini Coin (GEMINI)"," ","WazirX\nListings:\nether.fi (ETHFI)\nPixels (PIXEL)\nPyth Network (PYTH)\nSui (SUI)\nDelistings:\npNetwork (PNT)\n"," ","XT\nListings:\nMixin (XIN)\nmilestoneBased (MILE)\nLunar Storm (LUST)\nCobak Token (CBK)\nMAGA VP (MVP)\nSomdej Coin (SOMDEJ)\nST Protocol (ST)\nJake (JAKE)\nEgochain (ESTA)"],"entity":[{"type":"AAI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mone","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"GMR","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"JCC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Trippy Labs (SHROOM)\nCommunity of Meme (COME)\nMoonlandMeta (MTK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FSE","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FOX)\nMetagalaxy (MEGALAND)\nPLC Ultima (PLCU)\nPLC Ultima Classic","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Camel Tec (CAMELTEC)\nShibaAi Club","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ondo","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"USDT\nSOL\/ETH","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"GIB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DIKO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Aventis","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gecko Inu (GEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"PLA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CBK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Shina Inu","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"AVAX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CLICO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Brett (BRETT","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Lyra","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Normie (NORMIE)\nTrump","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Andy (","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NPC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"RTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"GRE","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ST Protocol (ST","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Voltage Finance (VOLT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Normie (NORMIE)\nBased Shiba Inu","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"LMR","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Degen (DEGEN)\nNormie (NORMIE)\nEchelon","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"LYRA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MAGA Trump","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Oracle","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"London","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Trump Inu","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CARAT)\nSmole (SMOLE","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Degen (DEGEN","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Diamond Standard Co.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DBC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Atlas Navi (NAVI)\nPandora GPT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ORACLE","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tyrel Derpden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sam Altman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jake (","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"MDA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"TERA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SCM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Infinity","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Smole (SMOLE)\nNormie (NORMIE)","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Crypto Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ondo Finance (ONDO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"PMT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"AMBO","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["Altcoins","Exchange","Trading"],"authors":["Mao Orillana"]}