{"summary":"Rep. Tom Emmer’s maneuver to move up the ranks in House leadership could bode well for cryptocurrency legislation, sources say.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/255317\/tom-emmers-maneuver-to-move-up-in-us-house-leadership-could-be-good-for-crypto","publishDate":"2023-10-06T15:49:09","id":1930,"type":null,"title":"Tom Emmer&#x27;s maneuver to move up in US House leadership could be good for crypto","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Rep. Tom Emmer's maneuver to move up the ranks in House leadership amid a vacant House Speaker spot could bode well for cryptocurrency legislation.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Minnesota Republican and Majority Whip is reportedly vying for House Majority Leader or to the top position as Speaker, after the dramatic <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/254816\/us-crypto-legislation-could-stall-amid-republican-leadership-drama\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ousting<\/a> of former Speaker Kevin McCarthy, R-Calif., earlier in the week. That could be good for crypto as more seniority could mean a push to get crypto legislation across the finish line.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"We are always excited to see any champion of the digital asset space advance and we look forward to seeing what this means for the future of our industry,” said Perianne Boring, CEO and founder of the Chamber of Digital Commerce. “Rep. Emmer has been a key collaborator for us, and we appreciate his hard work to foster innovation for digital assets and blockchain technologies.\"<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Emmer has introduced legislation in the past few years, including the Securities Clarity Act, which would create a new definition for tokens that exist in the in-between of commodity and security. Emmer has also been staunchly against central bank digital currencies and introduced a bill last month to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/252093\/maxine-waters-criticizes-anti-innovation-stance-of-republicans-over-anti-cbdc-bill\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">prohibit<\/span><\/a> the Federal Reserve from issuing a CBDC directly to individuals.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Emmer has also been critical Securities and Exchange Commission Chair Gary Gensler<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253305\/gensler-takes-heat-from-lawmakers-over-his-approach-to-regulating-crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,<\/span><\/a> calling him <\/span><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">an “impartial regulator” and taking a “regulation by harassment approach” toward digital assets during a hearing <span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253305\/gensler-takes-heat-from-lawmakers-over-his-approach-to-regulating-crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">last week<\/span><\/a><\/span>. <\/span><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Emmer <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253093\/lawmakers-urge-sec-chair-gensler-to-allow-spot-bitcoin-etfs-immediately\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">criticized<\/span><\/a> the agency recently as well for not yet allowing the listing of a spot bitcoin exchange-traded fund.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Emmer is also supportive of a <\/span><span class=\"s5\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">bill that takes a comprehensive approach at creating a regulatory framework for crypto<\/span><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> and could be another voice behind Rep. Patrick T. McHenry, R-N.C., to push it to be considered. That bill, along with a separate bill to regulate stablecoins, was advanced out of the House Financial Services Committee in July. Notably, Emmer is a member of that committee, and McHenry leads it.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Those two have a good relationship,” <\/span><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said Ron Hammond, director of government relations at the Blockchain Association. So if McHenry asks for work on his crypto bills, Emmer will take that very seriously, Hammond added.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">McHenry <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/254816\/us-crypto-legislation-could-stall-amid-republican-leadership-drama\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">took over<\/span><\/a> the position of Speaker of the House temporarily on Tuesday — a spot he is not necessarily keen on as he has been focused on getting those two crypto bills out on the floor for a full House vote. <\/span><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">They would still need to garner support in the Senate, which could prove to be tough.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">McHenry’s shift to House Speaker could waste precious time needed to move those bills closer to the finish line, as lawmakers ascertain who the next speaker could be. <\/span><span class=\"s6\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A closed door call or conversation with the Republican party is expected to happen on Oct. 10, with a possible general floor vote the next day.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“If there is anyone who holds the most power right now, for the House when it comes to crypto legislation’s future, it still rests with Patrick McHenry,” Hammond said.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Federal Reserve","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Blockchain Association","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Emmer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kevin McCarthy","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Minnesota","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"House Speaker","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hammond","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gary Gensler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ron Hammond","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"last month","content":"DATE"},{"type":"House Financial Services Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"McHenry","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tom Emmer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Chamber of Digital Commerce","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Patrick McHenry","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"House","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Perianne Boring","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Patrick T. McHenry","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Calif.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Oct. 10","content":"DATE"},{"type":"McHenry","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Senate","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["HOUSE AGRICULTURE COMMITTEE","HOUSE FINANCIAL SERVICES COMMITTEE"],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}