{"summary":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: January 16, 2024","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/crypto-exchange-listing-and-delisting-announcements-january-16-2024.htm","publishDate":"2024-01-15T21:22:03","id":19337,"type":null,"title":"Crypto Exchange Listing and Delisting Announcements: January 16, 2024","category":["Altcoin News "],"content":["Here is our weekly collection of digital asset listing and delisting, trading pair-related announcements by crypto exchanges that we found last week and today.Have we missed something? Do you have information about new listings and\/or delistings? Let us know here."," ","_________________________________________"," ","Binance\nListings:\nXai (XAI)"," ","BitMart\nListings: \nRoth Token (ROTH)\nMeme Mint (MEMEMINT)\nPig9 (PIG9)\nAnimal Army (ANIMAL)\nFayda (FAYD)\nChartAI (CX)\nReadON (REON)\nRabi (RABI)\nELON DRAGON (ELONDRAGON)\nThe Age of Apes (APES)\nBonkBaby (BOBY)\nBoba Finance (BFI)\nA Gently Used 2001 Honda Civic (USEDCAR)\nMoon App (APP)\nNelore Coin (NLC)\nFacet (FACET)\nDuel (DUEL)\nRocky the Dog (ROCKY)\nArcane DEX (ARC)\nVirtual Versions (VV)\nNeurashi (NEI)\nTonka Finance (TOKA)\nSolFarm (SFARM)"," ","Bitrue\nListings:\nTroll (TROLL)\nBozo Collective (BOZO)\nMyro (MYRO)"," ","catEx\nListings:\nBFIC Gold (BGOLD)"," ","Changelly\nListings:\nWhiteBIT (WBT)\nCoq Inu (COQ)\nExit Shopping Token (EXIT)\nVela Exchange (VELA)"," ","CoinEx\nListings:\nXai (XAI)\nPrisma Finance (PRISMA)\nDecimated (DIO)\nTurbos Finance (TURBOS)\nBRC20roup (ROUP)\nTrias (TRIAS)\nxPET (XPET)\nRestake Finance (RSTK)\nMoon App (APP)\nSpeero (SPEERO)\nTroll (TROLL)\n"," ","Crypto.com\nListings: \nKryptonite (SEILOR)\nALEX Lab (ALEX)\nDecentralized Social (DESO)\nXai (XAI)\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nJUNO\/ETH\nNMR\/ETH\nNTRN\/ETH\nRNDR\/ETH\nAKT\/ETH\nAURORA\/ETH\nCUDOS\/ETH\nIOTX\/ETH\nSC\/ETH\nPYTH\/ETH\nARCH\/ETH\nDATA\/ETH\nNEON\/ETH\nTIA\/ATOM\nINJ\/ATOM\nOSMO\/ATOM\n"," ","Crypto.com Institutional\nListings: \nVanar Chain (VANRY)\nXai (XAI)\nAdded Trading Pairs:\nAKT\/USDT\nLMWR\/USDT\n"," ","DigiFinex\nListings:\nXai (XAI)\nArtificial Intelligent OR (AIOR)"," ","FINEXBOX\nListings: \nBaby Myro (BABYMYRO)"," ","Gate.io\nListings:\nXai (XAI)\nMoon App (APP)\nManta Network (MANTA)"," ","HitBTC\nListings:\nHello Labs (HELLO)\nWrapped NXM (WNXM)"," ","HTX\nListings: \nDogwifcoin (WIF)\nCyberConnect (CYBER)\nCyberCrowdChain (CCROWD)\nTrollFace (TROLL)"," ","KuCoin\nListings: \nNFPrompt (NFP)\nManta Network (MANTA)\nOrca (ORCA)\nFusionist (kACE)\nMoon App (APP)\nNeon EVM (NEON)"," ","LBank\nListings: \nXai (XAI)\nMetacoin (MTC)\nZebec (ZBC)\nStarus Coin (STUC)\nAvascriptions (AVAV)\nGame Meteor Coin (GMTO)\nGameGPT (DUEL)\n"," ","MEXC\nListings: \nHubot (HBT)\nBaby Dragon (BABYDRAGON)\nGhost (Ghost)\nTombplus (TOMBPLUS)\nAnimal Army (ANIMAL)\nXYM Finance (XYMF)\nMochiCat (MOCHICAT)\nSolFarm (SFARM)\nCamly Coin (CAMLY)\nPepe Mining Company (PPMC)\nAIGPT (AIGPT)\nKoinon (KOINON)\nBama AI (BAMA)\nFud the Pug (FUD)\nGreelance (GRL)\nGenesis Spark Coin (GSC)\nGameGPT (DUEL)\nMoon App (APP)\nMeme Mint (MEMEMINT)\nGameSwift (GSWIFT)\nMar3 AI (MAR3)\nPeercoin (PPC)\nTomorrowLend (TMT)\nFool Bull (FOOLBULL)\nJetron Game (JETTON)\nManta Network (MANTA)\nBonkBest (BONKBEST)\nSolBroe (SOLBROE)\nDragonEra (DRAGONERA)\nIYU Finance (IYU)\nPassiveSphere (PPX)\nETFSOL2024 (ETFSOL2024)\nPirate Chain (ARRR)\nCrazyDave (CRAZYDAVE)\nBaby Elon (BABYELON)\nEthereum2 (ETHEREUM2)\nApeX Protocol (APEX)\nWeb3Games.com (WGT)\nDePIN DAO (DEPINDAO)\nDinosaur (DINOS)"," ","OKX\nListings:\nIce (ICE)"," ","Poloniex\nListings: \nLong (LONG1)\nMMSS (MMSS)\nDotSwap (DSWP)\nComsats (CSAS)\nOrders.Exchange (RDEX)\nRaydium (RAY)\nBRC20.com (.COM)\nSpeero (SPEERO)\nDogwifhat (WIF)\nBRC20roup (ROUP)\nTrollFace (TROLL)\nRSTK (RSTK)\nFentanyl Dragon (FENTANYL)\nTrac (TRAC)\nSolFarm (SFARM)\nBozo Collective (BOZO)"," ","P2B Crypto Exchange\nListings: \nProjectX’s LOW CAP GEM (PXC)\nBoba Finance (BFI)\nCHIMPZEE (CHMPZ)\nBIZTOKEN (BIZT)\nNitroken (NITO)"," ","VinDax\nListings: \nDarkMeta (DMT)\nElectronic Lira (SLI)\nDIFOGG (DFOG)\nROYAL CLUB WIN (1RCW)"," ","XT\nListings:\nATOPLUS (ATOPLUS)\nXai (XAI)\nThreshold Network (T)\nTrollFace (TROLL)\nLENX Finance (XD)\nCakepie (CKP)\nGameluk (GAME)\nDogwifhat (WIF)\nSolkek (SOLS)\nPika (PIKA)\nPeapods (PEAS)\nZuzalu Inu (ZUZALU)"],"entity":[{"type":"Boba Finance (BFI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2001","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tonka Finance (TOKA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Roth Token (ROTH","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"PPC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NLC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MANTA","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"ATOM\nOSMO\/ATOM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Pepe Mining Company (PPMC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"WBT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Vela Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ZBC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DEX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"GSC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"JETTON","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Manta","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"last week","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Prisma Finance (PRISMA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"AURORA","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"USDT\nLMWR\/USDT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NEI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Crypto Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Restake Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NITO","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Altcoins","Exchange","Trading"],"authors":["Mao Orillana"]}