{"summary":"A federal court denied a motion in favor of Yuga Labs in its lawsuit against artist Ryder Ripps and Jeremy Cahen.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/195945\/bored-ape-yuga-lab-lawsuit-ryder-ripps","publishDate":"2022-12-17T09:40:36","id":1938,"type":null,"title":"Yuga Labs advances in lawsuit accusing artist of copying Bored Ape NFTs","category":["LEGAL"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">An ongoing legal tiff between NFT developers Yuga Labs and an artist and his NFT business partner continues as a U.S. federal court denied a motion to dismiss opposition from the Bored Ape Yacht Club creators, according to a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/storage.courtlistener.com\/recap\/gov.uscourts.cacd.855658\/gov.uscourts.cacd.855658.62.0.pdf\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filing<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;on Friday.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Yuga Labs first <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/154206\/yuga-labs-sues-artist-in-bored-ape-yacht-club-nft-case\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filed<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> the lawsuit in June against California-based artist Ryder Ripps and the founder of NFT marketplace Not Larva Labs, Jeremy Cahen, accusing them of copying and selling NFT collections and devaluing the original Bored Ape products.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Defendants Ripps and Cahen filed a motion to dismiss opposition from Yuga Labs in October, together with an anti-strategic lawsuit against public participation (SLAPP) motion. The District Court of Central California has now denied these motions.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Our lawsuit to hold Ripps and Cahen accountable for their obvious and blatant theft of Yuga Labs’ trademarks rightfully moves forward with this ruling,” a Yuga Labs spokesperson wrote in a statement sent to The Block, accusing the pair of profiting off of Yuga’s intellectual property.&nbsp;<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We will continue to prove these facts as the case progresses,\" the spokesperson wrote.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ripps <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">has portrayed the lawsuit as an attack on his freedom of speech, and previously<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/157281\/ryder-ripps-instructs-lawyers-ahead-of-yuga-labs-court-case-will-only-settle-for-100-billion\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that he would only agree to settle the case for a payout of at least $100 billion.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The court granted the defendants the possibility to re-file a motion in the future against Yuga Lab's claim that the duo was benefiting at Yuga's expense.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Editor's note: This story has been updated to include a quote from Ryder Ripps.<\/em><\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"District Court of Central California","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ryder Ripps","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Yuga","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cahen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Yuga Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bored Ape Yacht Club","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ryder Ripps","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"California","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"June","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Jeremy Cahen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$100 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Ripps","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"October","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["LAWSUITS","YUGA LABS"],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}