{"summary":"Jack Dorsey’s Decentralized Social Media Bluesky Removes Invite-Only Restrictions","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/jack-dorsey-bluesky-decentralized-social-media-opens-all-users.htm","publishDate":"2024-02-07T09:26:10","id":19390,"type":null,"title":"Jack Dorsey’s Decentralized Social Media Bluesky Removes Invite-Only Restrictions","category":["News "],"content":["Jack Dorsey-backed decentralized social media project Bluesky on Tuesday removed invite-only limitations and granted access to all users.","Since its launch in Feb. 2023, the platform used invite codes while experimenting with features such as moderation tools and personalized feeds.","Bluesky was launched as an alternative to centralized platforms like Twitter.","Its objective is to establish an open protocol for public discourse, giving users more control over their data and what they see. Originally dropped on iOS last year, it was invite-only for a good chunk of time.","Big milestone, with more to come!","We used invites to manage growth as we built out the rails for a new kind of distributed network. Now, we’re ready to open up.","In the coming weeks, expect updates on federation and composable moderation services. https:\/\/t.co\/DWbYbmQEU3","— Jay Graber 🦋 (@arcalinea) February 6, 2024","","Bluesky resembles the classic Twitter interface. Yet, it aims to offer users a personalized experience tailored to their preferences.","Getting started on the platform is easy, and posting works much like Twitter, with a 300-character limit.","“We’ve designed the app in a way that puts control back in your hands. Here, your experience online isn’t controlled by a single company. Whether it’s your timeline or content filters, on Bluesky, you can easily customize your social experience,” the team said.","H2\nBluesky uses an internally developed open-source framework called the AT Protocol, allowing external parties to understand its construction and ongoing developments. Dorsey introduced the project in 2019 while he was still running the show at Twitter. But after Elon Musk took over Twitter, Bluesky went its own way starting in 2023.","Yet, Dorsey doesn’t own the company — he just sits on the board, alongside Bluesky CEO Jay Graber.","Bluesky is currently working on two things at once — the AT protocol and the microblogging app. The team has made it clear that its “decentralized” system doesn’t use blockchain or cryptocurrencies.","Later this month, the project plans to release a trial version of “federation,” the feature that makes the network open and customizable.","“On Bluesky, you’ll have the freedom to choose (and the right to leave) instead of being held to the whims of private companies or black box algorithms. And wherever you go, your friends and relationships can go with you,” the team said.","According to data analysis firm SimilarWeb, Bluesky has been steadily growing since its launch. The firm observed spikes in user sign-ups after X introduced monthly fees and imposed limits on the number of posts users can read each day.","So far, the platform has 3.4m users and a total post count of over 144m, according to a Bluesky page that tracks user engagement.","A bunch of celebrities and politicians have already hopped on the Bluesky bandwagon, like Rep. Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez, Rep. Maxwell Frost from Florida, Sen. Brian Schatz from Hawaii, and Sen. Ron Wyden."],"entity":[{"type":"Feb. 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"February 6, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Florida","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bluesky","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hawaii","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Twitter","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Alexandria Ocasio","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Cortez","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Brian Schatz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jack Dorsey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Elon Musk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Maxwell Frost","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jay Graber","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Dorsey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ron Wyden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"ups","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Jack Dorsey","Social media"],"authors":["Shalini Nagarajan"]}