{"summary":"Baroness’ Letter Sparks Debate on UK’s AI Market Competition","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/uk-government-pushes-for-measures-on-ai-copyright-and-market-competition.htm","publishDate":"2024-05-03T17:54:18","id":19424,"type":null,"title":"Baroness’ Letter Sparks Debate on UK’s AI Market Competition","category":["News "],"content":["Baroness Stowell of Beeston, a member of the UK’s House of Lords, urged the British government to take a stronger stance on addressing copyright issues and ensuring fair competition within the UK’s AI market competition on May 2.","Baroness Stowell of Beeston wrote a letter to the UK Secretary of State","expressing her disappointment in the government’s insufficient efforts to modernize copyright laws in light of advancements in generative AI and large language models (LLMs).","We wrote to @michelledonelan following the Government's response to our report on large language models and #GenerativeAI. We called for:","📚Urgent action on copyright\n📊Focus on market competition\n🔬Clarity on research funding","Read the full letter ⬇️ pic.twitter.com\/ni3fdeM5ya","— Lords Communications and Digital Committee (@LordsCommsCom) May 2, 2024","","The letter also suggested policy discussions regarding oversight of the UK’s market competition. It reiterated the need for market competition to be an “explicit” policy objective, integrated into the design and review process of new policies and standards, and subject to thorough internal and external evaluations.","Baroness Stowell of Beeston’s public letter was in response to Michelle Donelan, the Secretary of State’s update on the government’s AI oversight and parliamentary recommendations on April 17, 2024.","It could be recalled that the UK’s House of Lords released a report on February 2 focusing on generative AI and large language models (LLMs). The report detailed the government’s emphasis on high-stakes AI safety, which could hinder international competition.","The report also examined AI trajectories for LLMs over the next three years and outlined necessary actions to ensure the UK can effectively respond to opportunities and risks in a timely manner.","In response to the report, Michelle Donelan stated that the government’s AI oversight is uptight and disclosed efforts to promote AI adoption across the UK to improve productivity across companies of all sizes and sectors and drive further economic growth.","","The UK’s Competition and Markets Authority (CMA) is actively scrutinizing Big Tech’s growing influence within the UK’s AI market competition.","Concerns arose over potential market dominance due to the increasing involvement of companies like Google, Amazon, Microsoft, Meta, and Apple.","We’re inviting comments on the partnerships, and other arrangements, between #Microsoft and #Mistral #AI, #Amazon and #Anthropic, and Microsoft and #Inflection AI.","Read more: https:\/\/t.co\/NlCXdHQjbw","— Competition & Markets Authority (@CMAgovUK) April 24, 2024","","A prime example is the CMA’s investigation into the partnership between Amazon and AI developer Anthropic, where Amazon invested $4 billion.","This scrutiny extends to other collaborations, such as Microsoft’s partnership with OpenAI, as the CMA seeks to ensure fair competition and prevent any negative impacts on the UK’s AI ecosystem."],"entity":[{"type":"UK’s House of Lords","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"May 2, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"May 2","content":"DATE"},{"type":"April 24, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Big Tech","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Amazon","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Competition & Markets Authority","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$4 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lords Communications and Digital Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Meta","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Baroness Stowell","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"CMA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Government","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April 17, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Microsoft","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UK Secretary of State","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"February 2","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Beeston","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Michelle Donelan","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["AI Market Competition","Artificial Intelligence","United Kingdom"],"authors":["Jimmy Aki"]}