{"summary":"UAE Integrates Cardano Blockchain for Enhanced Criminal Investigation Security","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/uae-integrates-cardano-blockchain-for-enhanced-criminal-investigation-security.htm","publishDate":"2024-03-11T20:00:32","id":19463,"type":null,"title":"UAE Integrates Cardano Blockchain for Enhanced Criminal Investigation Security","category":["Blockchain News "],"content":["During this year’s World Police Summit in Dubai on March 5-7, the United Arab Emirates made headlines by adopting Cardano blockchain technology to enhance the security of its criminal investigations. The Dubai Police’s use of the technology marks a major step towards blockchains integration into the mainstream.","The showcase with the Cardano-based project evidenced the secure exchange of forensic data with international security agencies like Interpol, spotlighting the technology’s efficacy in data management security.","According to Chris O, the creator of Cardano GhostFund DAO, the Dubai Police’s choice to employ Cardano highlights the blockchain’s potential for safe and unhackable data management.","He also stressed that using the blockchain guarantees that information is unaltered and makes it traceable for the different parties.","For example, technology may make it easier for international parties to share sensitive forensic data safely.","#Cardano fam, massive real world adoption update by @Cardano_CF!","One of the wealthiest nations in the world, UAE is employing @Cardano to secure its Criminal investigations!","The Dubai Police presented at the World Police Summit in Dubai a Cardano based pilot project. The… pic.twitter.com\/zjzXOJZCcM","— Chris O (@TheOCcryptobro) March 10, 2024","","Security expert Omar Shands commented on the Dubai Police’s adoption of the Cardano blockchain, saying blockchain is a valuable tool that is becoming increasingly relevant in the security sector.","Criminal investigations secured by the Cardano blockchain 🚓 👮‍♂️","🚨 Today the Dubai Police presented at the World Police Summit in Dubai an exciting blockchain-based pilot project. The project will showcase how sensitive data from criminal investigations can be shared securely…","— Omar Shands, President – Skypath Security (@Skypath_Pres) March 7, 2024","","The adoption of blockchain technology by the UAE’s law enforcement has the potential to set a global precedent for other countries seeking to enhance their security infrastructure through advanced solutions as well.","Blockchain technology holds immense potential to introduce unique and effective law enforcement practices, offering novel solutions to address contemporary criminal investigations and security challenges.","Proactive law enforcement worldwide uses blockchain technology to track criminals and their activities. It has shown huge potential and effectiveness in addressing money laundering, terrorism financing, and more.","Law enforcement organizations also have great potential to deploy blockchain analytics solutions to manage investigative data, policymaking, and compliance.","For instance, China leverages blockchain technology to generate tamper-proof data to ensure the security of judicial data.","Additionally, blockchain analytics can be deployed to manage investigative data, formulate policies, and ensure compliance. The UK’s National Crime Agency (NCA) has embraced blockchain detectives as part of its strategy to combat crypto crimes, for example."],"entity":[{"type":"Today","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Cardano","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Cardano blockchain","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"UK’s National Crime Agency (NCA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"the World Police Summit","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"March 7, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"United Arab Emirates","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Interpol","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dubai","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"’s World Police Summit","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cardano GhostFund DAO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Omar Shands","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"7","content":"DATE"},{"type":"March 5","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Dubai Police","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chris O","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"March 10, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"China","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"UAE","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chris","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["Blockchain technology","Cardano","UAE"],"authors":["Jimmy Aki"]}