{"summary":"Tiger Brokers Opens Door for Crypto Trading in Hong Kong + More Crypto News","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/tiger-brokers-opens-door-for-crypto-trading-in-hong-kong-more-crypto-news.htm","publishDate":"2024-01-26T13:54:44","id":19633,"type":null,"title":"Tiger Brokers Opens Door for Crypto Trading in Hong Kong + More Crypto News","category":["Altcoin News "],"content":["Get your daily, bite-sized digest of blockchain and crypto news – investigating the stories flying under the radar of today’s news.","In today’s edition:","__________","Brokerage group Tiger Brokers (HK) Global Limited has officially upgraded its Type 1 license to include a virtual asset dealing service, making the top of crypto news rounds today.","This makes it one of the first mainstream online brokerage firms in Hong Kong to receive approval for such a license upgrade, the press release said.","It added that,","“This successful upgrade opens the door for providing cryptocurrency trading services to Professional Investor clients in Hong Kong through its flagship platform, Tiger Trade.”","By integrating Tiger Brokers’ technology-driven brokerage expertise, the company aims to offer professional investors seamless trading of both traditional securities and cryptocurrencies on a unified platform.","Eligible clients – including Hong Kong residents with over HKD 8 million (USD 1.1 million) in investable assets or corporations with assets exceeding HKD 40 million (USD 5.2 million) – can incorporate crypto trading into their portfolios alongside other asset classes on the Tiger Trade platform.","In the future, the company also plans to open virtual asset trading to retail investors.","John Fei Zeng, Chief Financial Officer and Director of Tiger Brokers said investor demand for crypto continues growing in Hong Kong and globally.","He added that eligible clients will benefit from low costs as well.","Decentralized computing platform Chainlink and popular layer 2 scaling solution Arbitrum, have announced the mainnet beta release of Chainlink Functions, now live on Arbitrum One mainnet.","According to the press release, Chainlink Functions is a serverless, self-serve developer platform. It enables developers to easily connect their smart contracts to any API and trust-minimized computations.","Chainlink Functions acts as a decentralized compute runtime that’s useful to test, simulate, and run custom off-chain logic for Web3 apps.","“In many ways, Chainlink Functions acts as a trust-minimized, blockchain-connected version of existing serverless solutions such as AWS Lambda, GCP CloudFunctions, and more,” the announcement said.","Arbitrum developers can now leverage Chainlink Functions within their application on-demand. They can access the Functions documentation, experiment with the Chainlink Functions Playground, and create a subscription to get started.","In other crypto news today, Matty Taylor (former Head of Growth at Solana Foundation), Clay Robbins (former Principal at Slow Ventures), and Nate Levine (former software engineer at Stripe) have announced the launch of Colosseum.","They describe it as a new organization founded to discover, accelerate, and invest in builders looking to develop industry-defining innovations and startups powered by the Solana blockchain.","Through Colosseum, developers can compete in online hackathons, take ideas from concept to production, and begin working on their crypto startups.","The platform provides additional tools and resources for projects accepted into Colosseum’s Accelerator program.","Also, it is seeding projects with $250,000 in early capital.","Colosseum is set to host 2-3 hackathons per year, starting with the inaugural event on March 4, 2024.","The announcement stated that Solana Foundation’s hackathons have played an integral role in the ecosystem’s growth over the last three years. Under Taylor’s leadership, it said, the hackathons attracted over 60,000 participants across eight online hackathons and builders from over 200 countries.","Of these, 4,000 products were launched, and winners have raised $600 million in venture funding."],"entity":[{"type":"Chainlink Functions","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$250,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Solana Foundation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"March 4, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tiger Trade","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"today","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Colosseum","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$600 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Tiger Brokers’","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chief Financial Officer and Director of Tiger Brokers","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Taylor","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"last three years","content":"DATE"},{"type":"John Fei Zeng","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"GCP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tiger Brokers (HK) Global Limited","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Solana Foundation)","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"AWS Lambda","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"3","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Chainlink Functions Playground","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Matty Taylor","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Clay Robbins","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nate Levine","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["Arbitrum","ChainLink","Hong Kong"],"authors":["Sead Fadilpašić"]}