{"summary":"Alexandre Kech, Citigroup&#x27;s director of blockchain and digital assets, has left to join Swizterland&#x27;s Six Digital Exchange. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/175309\/citigroups-digital-asset-director-set-for-new-role-at-swiss-crypto-exchange","publishDate":"2022-10-06T11:36:57","id":1985,"type":null,"title":"Citigroup&#x27;s digital asset director set for new role at Swiss crypto exchange","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Alexandre Kech, Citigroup's director of blockchain and digital assets has left to join Six Digital Exchange.","Kech announced his departure to the digital assets exchange, which offers the trading, settlement, and custody of crypto assets, in a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.linkedin.com\/feed\/update\/urn:li:activity:6982665879016603648\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">LinkedIn post<\/a> earlier this week.&nbsp;","\"This may seem like a short tenure, and it is, but sometimes, an exceptional opportunity comes along,\" he said in the post. \"I will share more about it when I start my new exciting challenge in November.\"&nbsp;","Kech confirmed the departure to the exchange when The Block reached him for comment but did not provide further details on the role.&nbsp;","The departure follows similar executive departures from the banking giant to crypto companies.","In August, The Block <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/164954\/citi-head-of-forex-to-leave-bank-for-digital-assets-role-source\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a> that Citi head of global head of foreign exchange, Itay Tuchman, left the bank after more than two decades to head to a digital assets role. Last year, digital asset investment firm CoinFund <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/114582\/coinfund-hires-former-citigroup-exec-as-new-president-and-managing-partner\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">hired<\/a> former Citigroup exec Christopher Perkins to serve as its new president and managing partner.&nbsp;","This follows <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/news+\/140447\/mapping-out-the-great-citi-crypto-exodus\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">a string of departures<\/a> to leave the banking giant in search of new roles in the digital asset space. As per reports in April, no fewer than 15 top-flight Citi employees have traded traditional finance for digital asset-focused destinations over the past year. These include top jobs at Copper, Paxos, Genesis and the Provenance Blockchain Foundation.&nbsp;","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"TextRun SCXW53919687 BCX0\" lang=\"EN-US\" xml:lang=\"EN-US\" data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"NormalTextRun SCXW53919687 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Correction: This story has been updated to correct the date that Christopher Perkins left Citigroup to join CoinFund.&nbsp;<\/span><\/span><\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Paxos","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Citigroup","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alexandre Kech","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Christopher Perkins","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Itay Tuchman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Provenance Blockchain Foundation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Six Digital Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Citi","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["HIRING"],"authors":["Tom Matsuda","The Block"]}