{"summary":"Polygon Backed Game ‘Guild of Guardians’ Launches on Google Play and Apple","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/polygon-backed-game-guild-of-guardians-launches-on-google-play-and-apple.htm","publishDate":"2024-05-15T04:57:29","id":19884,"type":null,"title":"Polygon Backed Game ‘Guild of Guardians’ Launches on Google Play and Apple","category":["Blockchain News "],"content":["Play-to-earn game, Guild of Guardians, is being made available globally on Google Play and the Apple app store, for mobile devices.","Guild of Guardians, allows its players to earn $GOG tokens which are ERC-20 tokens that can be used across the Guild of Guardians ecosystem and universe. Play-to-earn games allow players to convert their rewards into cash.","In an announcement, Immutable Games said that its flagship title, Guild of Guardians, has over 1 million pre-registered users. The gaming firm is celebrating its mobile release with the launch of a cinematic launch trailer, followed by a behind-the-scenes look at the making of Guild of Guardians.","Guild of Guardians, along with Pixelmon, Metalcore, and My Pet Hooligan is backed by the Inevitable Games Fund. The $100 million fund was launched by Australian venture capital firm King River Capital, and the blockchain gaming firm Immutable and Polygon Labs.","Players of the Guild of Guardians can venture into Elderym, a fantasy world on the brink of destruction at the hands of the Dread. As the world’s last hope for salvation, players must form a team of Guardians and head out on a virtual adventure to conquer the darkness.","“This launch is the culmination of years of development and community building, and we can’t wait to show players a mobile game with dynamic gameplay, intuitive mechanics and a sustainable rewards system,” said Justin Hulog, chief studio officer for Immutable Games, in a press release.","According to the Guild of Guardians site, the $GOG tokens can be used to mint gaming NFTs – unlocking NFT ownership and additional in-game features and perks.","NFTs can be bought and sold in $GOG via the NFT marketplace — and 20% of the marketplace fee that the publisher charges must be paid in the $GOG token and is sent for active staking rewards. In future, the Guild of Guardians said it plans that token holders will be able to vote on game decisions via decentralized governance.","$GOG can be purchased on OKX and Sushiswap.","In 2024, Web3 gaming projects have seen an increase in funding. In April, Silicon Valley-based venture capital firm Andreessen Horowitz (a16z) founded by Marc Andreessen and Ben Horowitz said it is investing around $30 million in gaming startups this year.","Andrew Chen a general partner for a16z Games took to the social media platform X to share the funding announcement. Chen said the firm will invest the $30 million through its a16z Speedrun program and $750 will be allocated per startup. The deadline for applying for the funding is May 19 with those shortlisted will be notified at the end of July."],"entity":[{"type":"Marc Andreessen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$100 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"20%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"20","content":"DATE"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Andreessen Horowitz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Justin Hulog","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"GOG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Pixelmon","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ben Horowitz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"May 19","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$GOG","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Andrew Chen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"the Guild of Guardians","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Elderym","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$30 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Immutable Games","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"King River Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Guild of Guardians","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Polygon Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Silicon Valley","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$750","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["Apple","Guild of Guardians","Polygon Lab"],"authors":["Tanzeel Akhtar"]}