{"summary":"Spanish Lawmaker Turns Back on Politics – to Become a Bitcoin Guru","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/spanish-lawmaker-turns-back-politics-become-bitcoin-guru.htm","publishDate":"2023-03-21T10:30:00","id":19907,"type":null,"title":"Spanish Lawmaker Turns Back on Politics – to Become a Bitcoin Guru","category":["Blockchain News "],"content":["A Spanish lawmaker has turned his back on parliament and his political career and plans to become a Bitcoin (BTC), altcoins, and blockchain guru instead.","Per reports from Criptonoticias and ABC, Teodoro García Egea, the former General Secretary of the Popular Party, told journalists at a press conference that he would be leaving parliament and stepping down from his role as an MP.","Instead, he hinted, he will focus on helping adoption efforts for BTC and other tokens – and a publishing career. ","While explaining the reasons for his exit, he also announced the publication of a book named “Cryptoeconomics: Beyond Bitcoin – Opportunities in the New Financial System.”","García Egea was first elected to parliament in Murcia in January 2012 and rose to the role of “number two” in the Popular Party. ","In July last year, he was appointed Chairman of the lower chamber’s Road Safety Commission.","García Egea added that he would “withdraw from politics”. ABC reported that he intended to “dedicate himself fully to private activity focused on cryptocurrencies – his area of expertise.”","The same media outlet noted that García Egea had distanced himself from political life in the past 12 months and had only attended parliament when strictly necessary to take part in votes and “avoid being sanctioned.”","García Egea stated that he would continue to be a member of the Popular Party. And he said he would henceforth “be available to Spanish citizens” in a private capacity.","According to the book’s publisher, García Egea’s book focuses on BTC, as well as other tokens and blockchain technology.","The book’s blurb reads as follows:","“For many people, crypto is about [….] investing in Bitcoin. But it is much more than that. The arrival of blockchain technology and the development of decentralized finance and Web3 constitute unprecedented tools.”","Crypto awareness has risen to 76% in Spain. And the nation’s real estate sector is growing increasingly interested in crypto-powered transactions."],"entity":[{"type":"ABC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"General Secretary of the Popular Party","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"76%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"January 2012","content":"DATE"},{"type":"July last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Teodoro García Egea","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"New Financial System","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"García Egea","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Road Safety Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spain","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Popular Party","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Murcia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["Politics","Spain"],"authors":["Tim Alper"]}