{"summary":"BlackRock’s Spot Bitcoin ETF Now Holds $3 Billion in BTC","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/blackrocks-spot-bitcoin-etf-now-holds-3-billion-in-btc.htm","publishDate":"2024-02-02T18:01:08","id":19929,"type":null,"title":"BlackRock’s Spot Bitcoin ETF Now Holds $3 Billion in BTC","category":["Bitcoin News "],"content":["BlackRock’s recently launched iShares Bitcoin Trust (IBIT), a spot Bitcoin ETF, just hit a new milestone.","As of Friday, it holds just over 70,000 BTC tokens, worth just north of $3 billion at the current Bitcoin price around $43,200.","🚨 JUST IN: BlackRock now holds 70,005 $BTC worth over $2.98 billion for their spot #Bitcoin ETF.","They accumulated another 3,805 #BTC in the last 24 hours! pic.twitter.com\/Wv60brFuHt","— Josh (@CryptoWorldJosh) February 2, 2024","","As per crypto analyst @CryptoWorldJosh, the ETF accumulated another 3,805 in the past 24 hours.","Since its launch back on the 11th of January, BlackRock’s Spot Bitcoin ETF has enjoyed strong net inflows.","Indeed, BlackRock’s spot Bitcoin ETF has failed to attract at least $100 million in net inflows on only two trading days so far, as per ETF flow tracking website ETF.com.","BlackRock’s new spot Bitcoin ETF isn’t the only success story in the past month.","Since the SEC gave 11 spot Bitcoin ETF products the green light, others have also been performing well.","As of Thursday, Fidelity’s spot Bitcoin ETF (FBTC) had attracted net inflows of close to $2.5 billion, as per ETF.com.","Meanwhile, as per Blockwork’s ETF tracker, newly launched spot Bitcoin ETFs from Ark 21Shares, Bitwise, Invesco\/Galaxy, VanEck, Valkyrie, Franklin and WisdomTree have collectively attracted nearly $2 billion in assets under management (AUM).","Including Grayscale’s Bitcoin Trust (GBTC), spot Bitcoin ETFs currently have around $28 in AUM.","GBTC converted from a trust product into a spot ETF in January but has experienced outflows of around $6.1 billion.","Traders had bought GBTC on masse throughout 2023 when it was trading at a big discount to net asset value (NAV).","Upon converting to a spot ETF, those traders were then finally able to redeem their GBTC at NAV.","Profit-taking on this trade was thus a large driver of GBTC outflows.","GBTC’s high fees relative to its competitors could be another factor driving rotation into newly launched spot Bitcoin ETF products.","As per ETF.com, GBTC outflows have dropped to around $200 million per day this week.","Inflows into the other newly launched ETFs is thus currently outstripping GBTC outflows, adding a new demand tailwind to the Bitcoin market."],"entity":[{"type":"$3 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"last 24 hours!","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$100 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Bitwise","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"WisdomTree","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Invesco\/Galaxy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"AUM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Franklin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"February 2, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$200 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$2 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Bitcoin ETF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BlackRock","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$2.98 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$43,200","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$28","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Fidelity","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NAV","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Valkyrie","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"VanEck","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$6.1 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$2.5 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Josh (","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["Bitcoin","BlackRock's spot Bitcoin ETF"],"authors":["Joel Frank"]}