{"summary":"US Treasury officials debate the need for stringent crypto regulations to prevent misuse by terrorists and hostile nations.","webName":"beincrypto.com","link":"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/us-treasury-crypto-tool-terrorist\/","publishDate":"2024-04-09T13:00:00","id":2,"type":null,"title":"US Treasury Official Advocates for Strict Laws to Curb Crypto Use by Terrorists","category":["Regulation"],"content":["<strong>In a recent address to Congress, US Treasury Deputy Secretary Wally Adeyemo expressed urgent concerns. He emphasized the risk of increased crypto use by terrorist organizations and hostile nations. <\/strong>","Speaking to the Senate Banking, Housing and Urban Affairs Committee, Adeyemo advocated for legislative action. ","Adeyemo highlighted the need to thwart the misuse of crypto by groups like al Qaeda and Hamas, as well as countries such as Russia and North Korea.","“We need to build an enforcement regime that is capable of preventing this activity as more terrorists, transnational criminals, and rogue states turn to digital assets. That’s why we sent the Committee proposals to strengthen counter-terrorist financing authorities,” Adeyemo <a href=\"https:\/\/www.banking.senate.gov\/imo\/media\/doc\/adeyemo_testimony_4-9-243.pdf\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener nofollow\">wrote<\/a>.","However, a contrasting perspective was presented earlier by Brian Nelson, Undersecretary for Terrorism and Financial Intelligence. Nelson stated that the extent of <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/us-treasury-clears-crypto-terrorism-financing\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener\">crypto’s role in terrorism financing might be overestimated<\/a>. ","This statement followed an incident where initial reports from the Wall Street Journal, based on analytics from Elliptic, misinterpreted data, suggesting large crypto transactions linked to Hamas. Later, Elliptic clarified that <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/hamas-received-21000-crypto-donations\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener\">Hamas had received only $21,000 in crypto<\/a>, significantly less than reported.","<strong>Read more: <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/learn\/crypto-regulation\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener\">Crypto Regulation: What Are the Benefits and Drawbacks?<\/a><\/strong>","Despite the corrected data, over 100 lawmakers pursued strict cryptocurrency regulations. They acted on the initial inflated figures. Consequently, this legislative drive, anchored in national <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/learn\/top10-must-have-cryptocurrency-security-tips\/\" target=\"_blank\" class=\"glossary-only-link\">security<\/a> concerns, faced opposition for potentially stifling innovation and expatriating the crypto industry. ","Representative Tom Emmer criticized the hurried legislative process. He stressed the importance of accurate data in financial regulation debates.","Nonetheless, Adeyemo’s testimony also sheds light on the sophisticated tactics of rogue states like North Korea. These states accumulate illicit revenue through cryptocurrencies via complex cyber heists. The United Nations disclosed that North Korea’s <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/nation-made-3-billion-hacking-crypto\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener\">crypto-related cyberattacks have garnered an estimated $3 billion.<\/a> ","This sum significantly fuels its weapons programs, constituting a major part of its foreign currency revenue.","Furthermore, the discussion encompassed Russia’s adept use of cryptocurrencies to sidestep financial sanctions. <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/russian-smugglers-tether-buy-weapons\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener\">Russia allegedly employs stablecoins like Tether’s USDT to fund military<\/a> operations, including clandestinely acquiring crucial military hardware components.","Get guaranteed bonus up to $200 on Coinbase in 3 easy steps\n\n\t  ","Adeyemo called for <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/us-treasury-more-control-crypto\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener\">additional legislative backing to empower the Treasury<\/a> to combat digital currency misuse by malicious actors effectively. He advocated for comprehensive regulations targeting foreign cryptocurrency exchanges and money services.","Additionally, he emphasized the need to plug the gaps in existing laws. These gaps have emerged as virtual asset <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/learn\/crypto-wallets\/\" target=\"_blank\" class=\"glossary-only-link\">wallet<\/a> providers and cryptocurrency exchanges evolved after the establishment of current regulations.","<strong>Read more: <a href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/learn\/best-crypto-exchange-usa\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener\">7 Best Crypto Exchanges in the USA for Bitcoin (BTC) Trading<\/a><\/strong>","Echoing the Treasury’s concerns, Coinbase Global and Circle Internet Financial have <a href=\"https:\/\/www.reuters.com\/markets\/us\/us-treasurys-adeyemo-warns-malign-actors-are-using-virtual-assets-2024-04-09\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noreferrer noopener nofollow\">voiced<\/a> the need for regulatory clarity. They highlighted the competitive disadvantage US companies face due to the existing regulatory uncertainty.","Disclaimer","In adherence to the <a class=\"c-link\" href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/trust-project\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-stringify-link=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/trust-project\/\" data-sk=\"tooltip_parent\" aria-describedby=\"sk-tooltip-21920\">Trust Project<\/a> guidelines, BeInCrypto is committed to unbiased, transparent reporting. This news article aims to provide accurate, timely information. However, readers are advised to verify facts independently and consult with a professional before making any decisions based on this content. Please note that our&nbsp;<a class=\"c-link\" href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/terms-and-conditions\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-stringify-link=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/terms-and-conditions\/\" data-sk=\"tooltip_parent\">Terms and Conditions<\/a>,&nbsp;<a class=\"c-link\" href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/privacy-policy\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-stringify-link=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/privacy-policy\/\" data-sk=\"tooltip_parent\">Privacy Policy<\/a>, and&nbsp;<a class=\"c-link\" href=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/disclaimer\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-stringify-link=\"https:\/\/beincrypto.com\/disclaimer\/\" data-sk=\"tooltip_parent\">Disclaimers<\/a>&nbsp;have been updated."],"entity":[{"type":"Adeyemo","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Qaeda","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$3 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"North Korea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Senate Banking","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$21,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Russia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Elliptic","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$200","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Trust Project","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"United Nations","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Undersecretary for Terrorism and Financial Intelligence","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Urban Affairs Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"US Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wally Adeyemo","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tom Emmer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Congress","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hamas","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Brian Nelson","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Coinbase Global and Circle Internet Financial","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Harsh Notariya"]}