{"summary":"Thailand’s K-Bank Acquires 97% Stake in Parent Company of Satang Crypto Exchange","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/thailand-kbank-acquires-97-stake-in-satang-tech.htm","publishDate":"2023-10-30T06:47:43","id":20012,"type":null,"title":"Thailand’s K-Bank Acquires 97% Stake in Parent Company of Satang Crypto Exchange","category":["Blockchain News "],"content":["Thailand’s second-largest bank, Kasikorn Bank, widely known as K-Bank, has acquired a 97% stake in the parent company of the established Satang crypto exchange.","This strategic acquisition comes as K-Bank intensifies its efforts in the cryptocurrency sector, aiming to offer a comprehensive range of crypto services that comply with Thailand’s regulatory framework.","The deal, valued at 3.705 billion Thai baht (approximately $102.8 million), was executed through a newly established K-Bank subsidiary known as Unita Capital, Thailand Posts reported.","Unita Capital holds a specific mandate to invest in digital assets companies, aligning with K-Bank’s commitment to expanding its presence in the digital asset and cryptocurrency market.","Once the transaction concludes, Satang will undergo a rebranding process, emerging as Orbix.","This transformation signifies a broader shift in K-Bank’s digital strategy, as Orbix will encompass three additional subsidiaries: Orbix Custodian, Orbix Invest (a digital asset fund manager), and Orbix Technology, a blockchain technology developer.","Bank’s venture into the crypto sector comes on the heels of the bank’s recent launch of a $100 million fund dedicated to investments in web3, fintech, and artificial intelligence.","Notably, K-Bank’s rival, Siam Commercial Bank (SCB), has also been actively pursuing opportunities in the web3 and cryptocurrency domains, indicating the growing importance of these areas in the Thai financial landscape.","Udomsak Rakwongwan, a professor at Kasetsart University and co-founder of FWX.finance, a company in which K-Bank has invested, expressed that K-Bank has obtained a crypto exchange license and is actively pursuing additional licenses for crypto-related activities in Thailand.","Rakwongwan highlighted the distinctive nature of the Thai market, which enjoys substantial institutional support and presents a unique set of opportunities in the crypto and digital asset sphere.","Earlier, Thailand’s energy giant, Gulf, joined forces with Binance through its Gulf Innova fund to establish a regulated, local version of the exchange in the Thai market.","In a statement to local media, K-Bank revealed its ambition to capture a 20% share of the crypto market in Thailand by 2024."],"entity":[{"type":"Kasikorn Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Satang","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Orbix Technology","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$100 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"97%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"20%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Unita Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$102.8 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"fintech","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gulf","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gulf Innova","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"3.705 billion Thai baht","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Thailand","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Satang crypto","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kasetsart University","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Orbix","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Siam Commercial Bank (SCB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Udomsak Rakwongwan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Binance","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Crypto Exchange","Thailand"],"authors":["Jai Pratap"]}