{"summary":"Coinbase Card, the Visa debit card that allows users to spend cryptocurrency directly from their Coinbase accounts, can now be linked with Google Pay. The new option is currently live in 14 European countries - the U.K, Ireland, Belgium, Finland, France, Italy, Slovakia, Spain, Croatia, Czech Republic, Poland, Denmark, Norway, and Sweden.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/58935\/coinbases-visa-debit-card-can-now-be-linked-with-google-pay-to-spend-crypto","publishDate":"2020-03-17T05:46:34","id":2010,"type":null,"title":"Coinbase’s Visa debit card can now be linked with Google Pay","category":["CRYPTOCURRENCY"],"content":["Coinbase Card, the Visa debit card that allows users to spend cryptocurrency directly from their Coinbase accounts, can now be linked with Google Pay.&nbsp;","Announcing the news on Tuesday, Coinbase <a href=\"https:\/\/blog.coinbase.com\/you-can-now-use-coinbase-card-with-google-pay-19ef7706cfd4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a> Google Pay gives users a quick way to pay for everything - ranging from daily travel to end-of-year getaways - using their crypto “in the safest possible way.”","Coinbase claims to be the first company to let users make mobile payments with crypto.&nbsp;","The new option is currently live in 14 European countries - the U.K, Ireland, Belgium, Finland, France, Italy, Slovakia, Spain, Croatia, Czech Republic, Poland, Denmark, Norway, and Sweden.","“We are working to expand to other European countries later this year,” said Coinbase.","Notably, Apple Pay isn’t yet supported for Coinbase Card.","Coinbase <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/19139\/coinbase-launches-crypto-to-fiat-debit-card-in-the-uk-filling-gap-left-by-shift-shutdown\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">initially launched<\/a> its Visa debit card in April 2019 in the U.K. \"Making crypto easier to use and spend is central to our mission to create a more open financial system,\" Coinbase UK CEO Zeeshan Feroz said at the time.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nSince then, the card has gradually been made available in a total of 29 European countries. It is not available in the U.S. yet.&nbsp;","The card currently supports ten coins, including bitcoin (BTC), ether (ETH), XRP and DAI, and can be used to spend crypto as cash where Visa is accepted.","Last month, Coinbase also <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/56354\/coinbase-receives-visa-principal-membership-to-offer-more-features-for-its-debit-card\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">received<\/a> a Visa principal membership, which will allow it to provide more features for its debit card. It remains unclear what specific features will be offered, but Coinbase said at the time that it would “enrich the cryptocurrency payment experience” for users.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Czech Republic","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"France","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"\" Coinbase UK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.K.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Coinbase Card","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Spain","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Italy","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Denmark","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Belgium","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Finland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Norway","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sweden","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Croatia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Zeeshan Feroz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Poland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Slovakia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ireland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"April 2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google Pay","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["COINBASE","XRP"],"authors":["Yogita Khatri","The Block"]}