{"summary":"HashKey Partners with Victory Securities for Enhanced Custody and Trading Services","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/hashkey-partners-with-victory-securities-for-trading-services.htm","publishDate":"2024-03-28T10:16:25","id":20109,"type":null,"title":"HashKey Partners with Victory Securities for Enhanced Custody and Trading Services","category":["Blockchain News "],"content":["HashKey Exchange has formed a strategic partnership with Victory Securities to enhance virtual asset services in Hong Kong.","In an official announcement made by HashKey, the exchange has entered a collaboration with the Hong Kong Securities and Futures Commission (SFC) licensed investment management firm Victory Securities on March 28.","The collaboration focuses on enhancing virtual asset trading and custody services to meet investors’ growing demand. Victory Securities, notable for being the first in Hong Kong to receive SFC licensing for virtual asset services, contributes regulatory expertise to the partnership.","HashKey Exchange, through this collaboration, aims to expand its offerings to include trading of key cryptocurrencies like Bitcoin (BTC) and Ethereum (ETH), reinforcing its role in providing a wide range of virtual asset services within a secure and regulated environment.","“We are thrilled to have partnered with Victory Securities and to provide institutional clients with compliant, secure, and efficient solutions for virtual asset management,” said HashKey Group COO and HashKey Exchange CEO Livio Weng.","“This collaboration represents HashKey Exchange’s further strengthening of institutional business, continuously expanding the user base and business scale of institutional operations,” said Weng.","In addition, Victory Securities will participate in the upcoming Hong Kong Web3 Festival, a major global event organized by Wanxiang Blockchain and HashKey Group.","Scheduled from April 6 to 9 at the Hong Kong Convention and Exhibition Centre, the festival plans to gather key players from the web3 sector.","Get ready to connect with Anna Liu, General Manager of Tokenisation @HashKeyGroup at Hong Kong #Web3Festival .","Join us for a chance to meet an incredible lineup of #Web3 bigwigs this April: https:\/\/t.co\/ixVZ3GBPB7#Blockchain #Fintech #DigitalAssets #AIGC pic.twitter.com\/SsJw2hZcqw","— Web3Festival (@festival_web3) March 20, 2024","","At the event, Victory Securities will engage with industry leaders, project founders, investors, and regulators. Discussions will focus on the latest developments in web3, exploring innovative technologies and examining the impact of regulatory policies on the industry.","“We are actively embracing new trends, and our collaboration with HashKey Exchange holds significant importance for expanding the scope of our virtual asset trading services,” stated Victory Securities Executive Director Kennix Chan.","“We will further promote the integration of virtual assets with traditional finance and contribute to the advancement of Web3,” said Chan."],"entity":[{"type":"HashKey Group COO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wanxiang Blockchain","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"General Manager of Tokenisation @HashKeyGroup","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SFC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April 6","content":"DATE"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"March 28","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Hong Kong Convention and Exhibition Centre","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Anna Liu","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Victory Securities","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Victory Securities Executive Director Kennix Chan","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"HashKey Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"March 20, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"HashKey","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"HashKey Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hong Kong Securities and Futures Commission (SFC","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["HashKey","Hong Kong","Web3"],"authors":["Hongji Feng"]}