{"summary":"FTX’s Bankman-Fried Hints at Bitcoin Lightning Network Integration After Community Backlash","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/ftxs-bankman-fried-hints-at-bitcoin-lightning-network-integration-after-community-backlash.htm","publishDate":"2022-05-17T14:30:00","id":20117,"type":null,"title":"FTX’s Bankman-Fried Hints at Bitcoin Lightning Network Integration After Community Backlash","category":["Bitcoin News "],"content":[" ","After facing a backlash from the Bitcoin (BTC) community over comments to the Financial Times that Bitcoin is “not a payments network,” Sam Bankman-Fried, the billionaire CEO of crypto exchange FTX, now hints that his exchange may implement Bitcoin Lightning Network payments.","“Sounds right, will ping devs,” Bankman-Fried replied to a comment that suggested that “all is forgiven” if Lightning is integrated into FTX.","No other details about the possible integration were provided.","Michael Saylor, CEO of MicroStrategy and a major Bitcoin bull, told the exchange CEO that supporting Lightning will give FTX an advantage over others.","Supporting #Lightning⚡️ will give you a competitive advantage vs. all those exchanges and related #Bitcoin businesses that are slow to provide support for the protocol.","Others also offered their two cents, calling the founder of FTX “smart.”","“[Sam Bankman-Fried] changes his position on Bitcoin and sends order to devs to do something. Smart people reserve the right to change their mind. Sam is smart,” commented Jason A. Williams, a popular Bitcoin proponent and author of the book Bitcoin: Hard Money You Can’t F*ck With.\n\nDaily trading volume on FTX:","\n_____\nLearn more: \n– Lightning Network Adoption at Exchanges is Growing: This is Why It’s Good for Bitcoin\n– FTX’s Bankman-Fried Accused of Misleading Public Over Bitcoin as FT Picks His Words ‘Selectively’\n– Bitcoin Lightning Network Payments Jump Over 400%, 80M Users Have Access to Network"],"entity":[{"type":"Jason A. Williams","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lightning","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"400%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Lightning Network Adoption","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"two cents","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Financial Times","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fried Accused of Misleading Public Over Bitcoin","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"80M Users Have Access to Network","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MicroStrategy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Michael Saylor","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["Adoption","Bitcoin","Exchange","FTX","Lightning Network","Sam Bankman-Fried"],"authors":["Fredrik Vold"]}