{"summary":"On October 7th Frank Chaparro was joined by leaders from Apifiny, Ripple, and The Stellar Foundation to discuss the latest developments in international remittance. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/80699\/the-block-presents-the-state-of-international-remittance-presented-by-apifiny-2","publishDate":"2020-10-13T12:29:44","id":2013,"type":null,"title":"The Block Presents: The State of International Remittance — Presented by Apifiny","category":["WEBINAR"],"content":["On October 7, Frank Chaparro sat down with leaders from Apifiny, Ripple, and The Stellar Foundation to discuss the latest developments in international remittance.&nbsp;","In this event, panelists discussed:","Our panelists included:&nbsp;","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Thomas Trépanier<\/strong> – Head of Business Development, Roxe settlement network by Apifiny","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Lisa Nestor<\/strong> – Director, Partnership, Stellar Foundation","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Asheesh Birla<\/strong> – SVP of Product and Corporate Development, Ripple","You can watch the event in its entirety below:&nbsp;","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" src=\"https:\/\/www.youtube.com\/embed\/EUGZ0sRCPh0?start=1\" width=\"560\" height=\"315\" frameborder=\"0\" allowfullscreen=\"allowfullscreen\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>"],"entity":[{"type":"Birla<\/strong> – SVP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Apifiny","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Apifiny","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Stellar Foundation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lisa Nestor","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ripple","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"October 7","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Corporate Development","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Head of Business Development","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["The Block","The Block"]}