{"summary":"Top NFT News Today – 16 January, 2024","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/top-nft-news-today-16-january.htm","publishDate":"2024-01-16T12:34:20","id":20359,"type":null,"title":"Top NFT News Today – 16 January, 2024","category":["NFT News "],"content":["There is no such thing as a boring day in the non-fungible token (NFT) world.","In today’s NFT news selection, read about South Korean Starbucks launching a first-of-its-kind NFT collection, the Epic Games Store releasing the Nyan Heroes game, and Pudgy Penguins jumping straight into the top five collections of the day.","Learn more below.","Starbucks","continues its NFT journey. Specifically, Starbucks Korea announced the launch of its NFT project, ‘STARBUCKS STAR★LIGHT’, the first of its kind for the company in Asia, it said.","It is encouraging its customers to incorporate personal cups into their daily lives by offering limited edition NFTs as rewards.","꾸준히 개인 컵을 사용하는 버디들을 위한 단 하나뿐인 선물","내일부터 시작되는 스타벅스 NFT 에코 프로젝트에 참여해 보세요","✅자세한 내용은 스타벅스 코리아 인스타그램에서 확인해 보세요https:\/\/t.co\/woGEkFC2mP#스타벅스NFT #스타벅스NFT에코프로젝트 #Starbucks #StarbucksKorea #스타벅스 pic.twitter.com\/QubCLM1NeC","— starbuckskorea (@StarbucksKorea) January 15, 2024","","Starting January 16, Starbucks will gift NFT to Rewards customers who order beverages via Siren Order (mobile order) using their personal cups.","Notably, each purchase will earn one Eco Stamp, with a maximum of three stamps a day.","There are three tiers of collectible NFTs:","Furthermore, the NFTs are designed in collaboration with Korea’s major digital art platform ‘Print Bakery.’ They feature the works of artist DADAZ and many local artists.","They showcase diverse digital artwork based on the concept of ‘My Own Cup,’ featuring reusable cups and tumblers, the press release said.","“The functionality of the Starbucks NFTs will be limited, with restrictions on gifting, selling, or trading,” it added.","","The Nyan Heroes team has made the NFT news list today by announcing that it will release its upcoming PC battle royale shooter on the major digital distribution platform Epic Games Store, the developer of the massively popular Fortnite.","According to the FAQ, Nyan Heroes is a free-to-play, third-person hero shooter where intelligent cats pilot powerful mechs known as Guardians.","The game enables players to use NFTs, but it’s optional. The team said that,","“Primarily, NFTs will be used as an ownership layer for certain digital assets earnt or bought in the game.”","Nyan Heroes will eventually have a marketplace that will allow users to trade in-game items with each other for use in and out of gameplay sessions, it added.","The game uses the Solana blockchain. It doesn’t require an external wallet, but it supports a collection via Phantom Wallet.","The official release date is yet to be announced. A “coming soon” page is ready, stating this is an Early Access game. It means it is still under development and may change over time. It is free to play.","","Popular NFT collection Pudgy Penguins is the best performer today among the top 5 collections by sales volume.","According to CryptoSlam, its sales volume is up 153% over the past 24 hours. It has climbed to the fourth place.","Transactions are up 114%, buyers 38%, and sellers 67%.","It’s a big time for the project. In December, Pudgy Penguins announced the upcoming alpha launch of Pudgy World, a Web3 game based on the Ethereum Layer 2 network zkSync Era.","The team described the new game as “an immersive, digital environment” available to Pudgy Penguins NFT holders, Pudgy Toy owners, and all “adventurous gamers.”","They expect to launch the alpha soon, in Q1 of this year.","Meanwhile, the team announced on Tuesday that it partnered with Old Master Q (老夫子) for their 60th Anniversary.","We’re partnering with Old Master Q (老夫子), one of the biggest IPs in Asia, for their 60th Anniversary celebration.","Come visit us at the front of one the largest shopping malls in Malaysia, Fahrenheit88, from January 15 to February 24 as we welcome the Year of the Dragon. pic.twitter.com\/hIhtayZ46L","— Pudgy Penguins (@pudgypenguins) January 16, 2024","","“Working with the 60-year legacy of Old Master Q and having our IPs collaborate introduces the Pudgy Penguins brand to a completely new audience in Asia,” a tweet said.","Hong Kong artist Joseph Wong, the creator of Old Master Q, and Dato’ Joyce Yap, the CEO of Malaysia’s shopping giant Pavilion Kuala Lumpur, will launch a month-long pop-up event and exhibition."],"entity":[{"type":"STARBUCKS","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Malaysia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"January 15","content":"DATE"},{"type":"January 16","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Pudgy World","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"114%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Asia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Pudgy Penguins NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Joseph Wong","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CryptoSlam","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dato’ Joyce Yap","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Early Access","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"January 16, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"February 24","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Korea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"today","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Nyan Heroes","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"67%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"December","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FAQ","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"153%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Dragon","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"38%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Starbucks Korea","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"January 15, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Starbucks","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Pudgy Penguins","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Pavilion Kuala Lumpur","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Gaming","NFT","Pudgy Penguins"],"authors":["Sead Fadilpašić"]}