{"summary":"Bitcoin Pizza Day Menu: Jokes, Events, New Products and Kebab","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/bitcoin-pizza-day-menu-jokes-events-new-products-and-kebab-1835.htm","publishDate":"2018-05-22T13:14:00","id":20468,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin Pizza Day Menu: Jokes, Events, New Products and Kebab","category":["Bitcoin News "],"content":["Today is May 22, in the cryptoverse known as Bitcoin Pizza Day. Eight years ago, on this day in 2010, programmer Laszlo Hanyecz paid another Bitcoin talk forum user for two Papa John’s pizzas for the low, low price of 10,000 BTC (worth about USD 25 at the time.) Now, that amount would be worth around USD 80 million.","Nobody is going to let him forget that. There is a Twitter account @bitcoin_pizza, that only tweets how much those pizzas are worth every day, and how it compares to the previous day.","Is Hanyecz sorry that he didn’t HODL? He said last year in an interview with the New York Times, “It wasn’t like Bitcoins had any value back then, so the idea of trading them for a pizza was incredibly cool. No one knew it was going to get so big.”","And today, the whole crypto world celebrates. Searching “Bitcoin Pizza Day” on Facebook returns a long list of events all over the globe, marking this momentous occasion.","Also, some people tweet their own Bitcoin pizzas, like Huobi, a cryptocurrency exchange, did. Of course, we’d wager that these are worth significantly less than USD 80 million, but they sport the Bitcoin logo, so it’s close enough.","Some companies are using this day to introduce and advertise new products. Ledger, a cryptocurrency hardware wallet producer, announced that it has “designed a limited edition of our Nano S [wallet] to celebrate Laszlo’s historic moment.”","Others tell you, “Don’t be so hard on yourself the next time you make a bad purchase!”","In either case, you can look at it from another point of view as well: as Twitter user @marckenigsberg would put it, “8 years later and the price is exactly the same – 10,000 btc. It’s just fiat that’s devalued.”","But don’t forget about the altcoins either. Ethereum community in Berlin, ETHBerlin is celebrating Döner Kebab ETHBerlin day, presumably not to be outdone by a pizza.","Happy Bitcoin Pizza Day!\nAnd now we are really hungry."],"entity":[{"type":"Bitcoin Pizza Day","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Papa John","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2010","content":"DATE"},{"type":"New York Times","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"8 years later","content":"DATE"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Berlin","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bitcoins","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"USD 80 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Laszlo","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nano","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Laszlo Hanyecz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Huobi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"May 22","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["Bitcoin","Community","Huobi","Ledger"],"authors":["Sead Fadilpašić"]}