{"summary":"Investment bank Cowen adds two new hires to its crypto-division as the firm continues to hire and grow amid the crypto bear market.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/165739\/cowen-expands-digital-division-with-new-crypto-native-hires","publishDate":"2022-08-25T11:35:43","id":2047,"type":null,"title":"Cowen expands digital division with new crypto native hires","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Investment bank Cowen is adding two crypto native executives as it expands its crypto division.","Cowen Digital LLC has hired Blockchain.com's former head of institutional business development and a ex-Coinbase sales associate to the crypto arm, which <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/139032\/investment-bank-cowen-launches-digital-assets-division\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">launched<\/a> in March of this year, with customers able to trade 16 tokens, including bitcoin and ether. The 100-year-old firm's <a href=\"https:\/\/www.cowen.com\/news\/cowen-digital-expands-institutional-team-with-crypto-native-hires\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announcement<\/a> comes as it develops the business and expands into \"new growth areas.\"&nbsp;","Expect more hiring news from Cowen: The firm is actively hiring and expanding its team as it looks to build over the next five years, according to head of execution Eric Rose.&nbsp;","Jackie Rose, coming from Blockchain.com, becomes a director of institutional sales, and Chase Campbell will be a vice president of digital asset sales.","The team is led by Drew Forman, who spent five years as head of equity derivatives at Cowen. Forman previously worked as a trader at JPMorgan Chase and Nomura Securities.&nbsp;","The firm has been building up its infrastructure over the past few months and has partnered with Standard Custody and PolySign to provide custodial services.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Chase Campbell","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Jackie Rose","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Cowen Digital LLC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Standard Custody","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Nomura Securities","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cowen","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Drew Forman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Eric Rose","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}