{"summary":"Solana Labs COO Raj Gokal called FTX crisis a “crucible moment” for the Solana ecosystem.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/184839\/solana-labs-coo-says-this-is-a-crucible-moment-for-the-solana-ecosystem","publishDate":"2022-11-09T12:09:30","id":2054,"type":null,"title":"Solana Labs COO sees ‘crucible moment’ for ecosystem amid FTX crisis","category":["LAYER 1S"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Solana Labs COO Raj Gokal weighed in on the FTX crisis that will see its non-U.S. assets sold to Binance, calling it a “crucible moment” for the Solana ecosystem that has close ties to the collapsing crypto exchange.&nbsp;<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n\"Binance seems to care about the ecosystem, but they have a lot of work on their hands,\" <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/rajgokal\/status\/1590361772892225537\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">he wrote<\/a> on Twitter. \"I'm hopeful they can work out a good deal with FTX.\"<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The price of Solana’s native coin SOL has plummeted over 40% to $16.58 over the last 24 hours, with the price of Solana ecosystem tokens like Serum also <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/184619\/solana-ftt-and-serum-prices-plummet-on-back-of-ftx-collapse\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">collapsing<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on the back of the FTX crisis. The global selloff of crypto assets triggered by news of FTX's problems hit just as<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> $1 billion of SOL is set to <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/184667\/solana-tokens-worth-330-million-to-be-unlocked-in-24-hours\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">unstake<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in less than 24 hours. Representing 13% of the coin’s circulating supply, it’s the second-largest unstaking of SOL by validators, raising concerns of a further negative impact on price.<\/span>","","","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Image: CoinGecko.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“This crucible moment for the Solana<\/span> <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ecosystem is as difficult as the last one,\" Gokal <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/rajgokal\/status\/1590359525521264640\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">wrote<\/a>. \"The difference is there are 10x more of us to band together this time. Next time, there will be 10x more. Each time, we're stronger. The fundamentals are better.\"<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Solana Labs CEO Anatoly Yakovenko was keen to reassure the Solana community, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/aeyakovenko\/status\/1590356766889775107\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweeting:<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;“Solana Labs, a U.S. corporation, didn’t have any assets on FTX.com, so we still have tons of runway, and luckily still a small team.”<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Binance","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$1 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gokal","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"40%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Raj Gokal","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Solana Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$16.58","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Solana","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"13%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Anatoly Yakovenko","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["SOLANA"],"authors":["James Hunt","The Block"]}