{"summary":"Bankrupt FTX&#x27;s marshalled assets total $7 billion with a large chunk, about $1.2 billion, parked in SOL tokens, according to a court filing.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/250232\/ftx-assets-include-1-2-billion-of-sol-bahamas-property","publishDate":"2023-09-11T13:12:00","id":2059,"type":null,"title":"FTX assets include $1.2 billion of SOL, Bahamas property","category":["BANKRUPTCY"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bankrupt cryptocurrency exchange FTX's assets of around $7 billion include roughly $1.2 billion parked in <span class=\"articleTooltip\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"\/price\/33827\/solana-sol-usd\" class=\"articleTooltip__link\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"><img src=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2023\/10\/solana.png\" alt=\"\" title=\"\" class=\"articleTooltip__tokenImage\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">SOL<\/span> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText articleTooltip__tokenText_price articleTooltip__tokenText_positive\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">\n      +2.09%\n    <\/span><\/a> <!----><\/span> tokens, according to a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/restructuring.ra.kroll.com\/FTX\/Home-DownloadPDF?id1=MjUxODI3OA==&amp;id2=-1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">court filing<\/a>.","The filing, prepared for a creditor meeting on Sept. 11, also lists FTX as the owner of 38 properties in the Bahamas appraised at $199 million. The company had been based in the Bahamas while being incorporated in Antigua and Barbuda.","To date, nearly $2.6 billion in cash has been secured since FTX filed for bankruptcy in November of last year and liquidation of its assets began, the filing also shows.","The nearly $1.2 billion of SOL is FTX's largest digital asset holding, and what becomes of the massive stake has been the source of much speculation. Of FTX's $3.4 billion in token holdings, it also possesses $560 million in bitcoin and $192 million in ether, the filing shows.","The filing showed that 50 \"insiders\" including former CEO Sam Bankman-Fried and Caroline Ellison received a mix of cash, crypto, equity and real estate worth $2.2 billion.","Bankman-Fried is currently in a New York City jail awaiting an early October trial after prosecutors accused him of witness tampering for the leaking of a private diary of Ellison and the use an encrypted messaging app to contact a potential witness.","The former billionaire is facing as much as 100 years in prison if he is convicted on a slew of charges, including allegations that he and other FTX executives used billions of customer assets to make their own failed investments.&nbsp;","The prospect of FTX resuming business somehow via a reboot is still a possibility, according to the filing. After debtors began \"marketing\" the idea in May, 75 bidders have been contacted, the filing said.","\"Proposals are being evaluated,\" the filing said. \"Transaction timing will depend on nature of transaction, readiness of bidder and other considerations.\"","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"New York City","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ellison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Caroline Ellison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$2.2 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$192 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"+2.09%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Sept. 11","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$3.4 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$199 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"November of last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Antigua","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$560 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$7 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bahamas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$2.6 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"October","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$1.2 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Barbuda","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}