{"summary":"Worldcoin Price Rises on May 9 New ChatGPT Rumors and Traders Focus on AI Meme Coin for Gains","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/worldcoin-price-rises-on-may-9-new-chatgpt-rumors-and-traders-focus-on-ai-meme-coin-for-gains.htm","publishDate":"2024-05-07T15:37:48","id":20649,"type":null,"title":"Worldcoin Price Rises on May 9 New ChatGPT Rumors and Traders Focus on AI Meme Coin for Gains","category":["Industry Talk "],"content":["Worldcoin ($WLD), the biometric crypto project helmed by OpenAI CEO Sam Altman, has shot up a blistering 37% in the last seven to trade at $6.17 as of this writing.","A rumor that ChatGPT, OpenAI’s main offering, is launching a search engine next week spurred much of  Worldcoin’s rally over the last few days.","The main source of the rumor is the fact that a domain called search.ChatGPT.com now exists, although AI influencer and researcher Pete Huang believes it could drop on May 9, ahead of Google’s big conference, according to a social media post.","Search (dot) ChatGPT (dot) com","May 9th.","— Pete (@nonmayorpete) May 2, 2024","","According to Worldcoin’s trading chart, the market’s early March rally drove $WLD to set a new all-time high of $11.74 on March 10, although today’s price is just 52.7% of that.","However, Worldcoin holders can take some solace in the fact that their token has found strong psychological support above $4. ","With a relative strength index (RSI) of 53 and falling, there appears to be some light profit-taking today, although there’s likely to be strong buying momentum over the next two days.","Worldcoin outperformed the market leader this week.","By contrast, Bitcoin ($BTC) only rose 4% to trade at its current price of $64,140.14 as of Tuesday morning UTC, May 7. ","Worldcoin got an ambivalent response on launch last year due to its controversial premise: anyone wanting some $WLD has to visit a biometric eyeball scanner called the ”Orb”—these are found in Berlin, Dubai, London, Mexico City, Miami, New York City, San Francisco, Seoul, and Tokyo— and submit a snapshot of their eyeballs.","This data is then used alongside verification of government-issued ID to confirm a user’s personhood before distributing coins to them.","OpenAI says Worldcoin is building blockchain infrastructure to bank the world’s unbanked, enabling everyone “to broadly share the coming technological prosperity ” according to its website. “Privacy first. Owned by everyone.” reads the slogan.","With World ID, everyone can be unique online. Even Leo Messi 🇦🇷 pic.twitter.com\/oGHFrIxf4f","— Worldcoin (@worldcoin) May 3, 2024","","But many are skeptical, including Ethereum creator Vitalik Buterin who wrote a blog post listing his concerns of the protocol’s privacy, accessibility, centralization and security and said it could take years for it to work.","Lawmakers around the world are also keeping tabs on it, with press reports suggesting authorities in Mexico, Malaysia and Argentina have all aired similar concerns.","This year the project hit a new high back in January when it welcomed 16,000 Orb signups in a single day after surpassing the 5 million mark the preceding month.","If Worldcoin’s biometric eyeball database has investors thinking twice, they’re not alone. However, there are many other projects highlighting the potential of greater AI\/crypto integration.","One such project is the brand new WienerAI, a brand new meme token and AI companion that may yield some potentially eye-watering rallies on listing thanks to its core offering.","The presale has already quietly taken in $1.2 million.","Touted as a “Revolutionary AI Trading partner”, WienerAI ($WAI) is a digital companion that gives its owners user-friendly AI-enhanced trading advice, seamless swap functionality and zero fees. ","We Welcome Wiener Hoarders!","AI-Enhanced Trading. Sausages. A match made in heaven!","🌭🌭 pic.twitter.com\/2AeDUW2ssF","— WienerAI (@WienerDogAI) May 5, 2024","","The WienerAI smart contract was audited by Coinsult, a blockchain security platform that conducts security checks on various crypto and blockchain platforms. ","Around 20% of $WAI’s supply is for staking. WienerAI’s website encourages buyers to stake during the presale, in order to take advantage of the lucrative yield, which is currently 790% APY . ","Keep up-to-date with WienerAI news over on X and Telegram. ","Join the presale now over on the WienerAI website.",""],"entity":[{"type":"New York City","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"San Francisco","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"May 2, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Coinsult","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"4%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Miami","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$WAI","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Malaysia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"20%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Pete Huang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Vitalik Buterin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$1.2 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Worldcoin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Berlin","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"790%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Argentina","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$4","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$6.17","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Dubai","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"37%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"52.7%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"London","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bitcoin ($BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"May 3, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tokyo","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"May 7","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Mexico City","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$64,140.14","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Mexico","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"UTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Altman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Leo Messi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Welcome Wiener Hoarders!","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"March 10","content":"DATE"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$11.74","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"May 5, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$WLD","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"May 9","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Seoul","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"May 9th","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Pete (","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["AI","ChatGPT","Worldcoin"],"authors":["Tim Hakki"]}