{"summary":"In this episode of The Scoop, Cryptex co-founder Joe Sticco shares the details behind the upcoming JPEGz NFT index token, including why the index token is a good way to speculate on the future growth of the NFT sector.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/193431\/this-defi-project-created-a-way-to-bet-on-the-entire-nft-market","publishDate":"2022-12-09T05:00:05","id":207,"type":null,"title":"This DeFi project created a way to bet on the entire NFT market","category":["DEFI"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 123<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 4 of The Scoop was recorded live with <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro and Cryptex co-founder Joe Sticco.<\/strong><\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Or click here to watch the full interview on <a href=\"https:\/\/www.youtube.com\/watch?v=zGNiYt1GN_4&amp;t=3038s\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">YouTube<\/a>. Email feedback and revision requests can be sent to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"a9d9c6cdcac8dadde9ddc1cccbc5c6cac2cadbd0d9ddc687cac6c4\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK7625795785\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/i>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A DeFi protocol known as Cryptex offers a permissionless way to speculate on the total crypto market capitalization through its novel index token, TCAP.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Now, Cryptex is on the verge of releasing its newest index token, JPEGz, which will allow holders to track the total market cap of NFTs on Ethereum.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In this episode of The Scoop, Cryptex co-founder Joe Sticco shares the details behind the upcoming JPEGz NFT index token, including why the index token is a good way to speculate on the future growth of the NFT sector.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">According to Sticco, the list of NFT collections included in the JPEGz index token is dynamic, which ensures that whenever a hot new NFT project crops up in the future, it will be included in the index.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">As Sticco explains,<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“NFTs are literally in their infancy. I look at them now and it's like where crypto was in 2017 — we had that first bust cycle now, and now we're in the ground, and who knows what happens next, but JPEGz is going to be the ability to track the NFT market cap.”<\/span>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">During this episode, Chaparro and Sticco also discuss:<\/span><\/i>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Tron,&nbsp;<\/em><\/a><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.ledn.io\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ledn<\/a><\/em><\/b><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nAbout Tron<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Founded in 2013, Huobi Global is one of the largest virtual asset exchanges in the world. Huobi Global serves millions of users across international markets. Since its establishment, Huobi Global has committed to providing first class virtual asset investment services. Huobi Global's robust infrastructure, product innovation and capital strength provides a truly customer-centric and secure trading environment to help our international users to achieve their investment objectives. Please refer to Huobi's official website for more information: <a href=\"http:\/\/www.huobi.com\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">huobi.com<\/a>.<\/em>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Ledn<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong>Ledn was founded on the unshakeable conviction that digital assets have the power to democratize access to the global economy. We help you to experience the real life benefits of your Bitcoin without having to sell it. Start a savings account, take out a loan, or double your Bitcoin. For more information visit&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.ledn.io\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ledn.io<\/a><\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Sticco","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sticco","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Joe Sticco","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Huobi Global","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2013","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cryptex","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Huobi","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ledn<\/a><\/em><\/b><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nAbout Tron<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Founded","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ledn<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong>Ledn","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}