{"summary":"Within Congress, the Commodity Futures Trading Commission is picking up political momentum to regulate crypto markets directly. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/153898\/the-future-of-digital-asset-regulation-the-cftc-says-congressional-committee","publishDate":"2022-06-23T17:49:07","id":2070,"type":null,"title":"The future of digital asset regulation? The CFTC, says Congressional committee","category":["CONGRESS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Within Congress, the Commodity Futures Trading Commission is picking up political momentum to regulate crypto markets directly.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">On June 23, a subcommittee of the House Agriculture Committee held a hearing on “the Future of Digital Assets Regulation.” That future, by all appearances, looks a lot like it belongs with the Commodity Futures Trading Commission.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Should the CFTC have direct statutory authority to regulate cash markets,” asked new subcommittee chairman Sean Maloney (D-NY). Maloney’s inquiry reflects a long-running lingering question in Washington: which regulator should take point on crypto?<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“The CFTC is certainly up to the job,” answered Dr. Chris Brummer. “It obviously has to be financed and staffed properly.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Brummer is a Georgetown Law Professor, host of the Fintech Beat podcast, and a longstanding commentator on crypto law in DC. He continued: “Irrespective of which regulator is in charge, that regulator will have to have a builder’s mentality.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Since Rostin Behnam took over as chair of the CFTC, he’s been pushing for the legal green light from Congress to regulate crypto spot markets.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Currently, the CFTC only has enforcement authority, which means they do not have running data on crypto exchanges. The new authority would <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/133644\/before-senate-cftc-cites-crypto-as-basis-for-biggest-expansion-since-dodd-frank\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">entail a massive expansion<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> for the CFTC — but it’s a change the crypto industry seems to be on board with, especially since Gary Gensler took over at the Securities and Exchange Commission and began <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/117651\/elizabeth-warren-and-gary-gensler-place-coinbase-in-oversight-crosshairs\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">dubbing all centralized crypto exchanges<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to be securities exchanges.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Both the Senate and House Agriculture Committees have seemed receptive. Vocal exceptions today were Austin Scott (R-GA) and Bobby Rush (D-IL). But leadership seems united overall.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“I think it’s an excellent agency and they’re very well-positioned from what they’re currently doing and what they could do in the future,” Maloney told The Block of the CFTC following the hearing.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Glenn Thompson (R-PN), the ranking member of the full House Ag Committee, appeared at the hearing to plug his <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/144194\/congressman-introduces-digital-commodity-exchange-act-to-set-up-cftc-regime-for-crypto-exchanges\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Digital Commodity Exchange Act<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, which would establish a voluntary national regime for CFTC registration. David Scott (D-NY), the full committee chair and a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/140026\/ftx-derivatives-proposal-takes-center-stage-at-congressional-hearing-with-cftc-chairman\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">noted crypto critic<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, did not attend. Scott is thought to be suffering from poor health.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“I’ve heard criticism about the CFTC that it’s a permissive, light-touch regulator,” said ranking member Michelle Fischbach (R-MN). “Do you agree with that and if not, could you tell us some of your personal experiences as to why that criticism is unfounded?”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Given that Fischbach was directing her question to Vince McGonagle, a director at the CFTC, the response was, predictably, in the negative.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">But while this committee appears set to hand the CFTC more authority, few are willing to say overtly what many in the crypto space seem to assume this means: less authority for the SEC and, by extension, its oversight in Congress, the House Financial Services and Senate Banking Committees.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Overall it’s a big Washington-level conversation that transcends the CFTC, or the SEC, and frankly the Treasury Department, because it’s a transnational conversation,” Charles Hoskinson, a co-founder of Cardano and one of the witnesses, told The Block.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/152033\/congress-preps-hearing-on-future-of-digital-assets-regulation-for-later-this-month\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">broke the news of today’s hearing<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> last week. <\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Vince McGonagle","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Chris Brummer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Georgetown Law Professor","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"House Financial Services and Senate Banking Committees","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"David Scott (","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Michelle Fischbach","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Treasury Department","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Maloney","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gary Gensler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"House Ag Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fintech","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"June 23","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Charles Hoskinson","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"House Agriculture Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Glenn Thompson","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Washington","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Cardano","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Congress","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Rostin Behnam","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sean Maloney","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Commodity Futures Trading Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"House Agriculture Committees","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fischbach","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"CFTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Future of Digital Assets Regulation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Senate","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["CFTC","HOUSE AGRICULTURE COMMITTEE","SEC"],"authors":["Kollen Post","The Block"]}