{"summary":"OKX Partners with Manchester City to Mint Commemorative NFT Football Shirts","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/okx-partners-with-manchester-city-to-mint-commemorative-nft-football-shirts.htm","publishDate":"2024-04-22T13:29:30","id":20726,"type":null,"title":"OKX Partners with Manchester City to Mint Commemorative NFT Football Shirts","category":["Blockchain News "],"content":["OKX, a leading global cryptocurrency exchange, has teamed up with Manchester City to introduce commemorative football shirts that can be minted as Non-Fungible Tokens (NFTs).","The initiative, named “Unseen City Shirts,” presents Manchester City fans, the reigning English football champions, with the opportunity to own exclusive memorabilia and win exciting prizes.","","Unseen City Shirts. Dropped by OKX with @mancity 💙 ​\n​Two designs, two digital collectibles, mega rewards! ​\n​\nCollectible 1: The Roses and the Bees is here 🌹🐝​\n​\nClaim to win match tickets, a Play on Pitch space, a limited-edition shirt and more. ​\n​\nRead more 👉… pic.twitter.com\/dfENxNsVfn","— OKX (@okx) April 22, 2024","","On April 22, OKX announced the initiative to redesign the football team shirts to be minted as digital collectibles known as Non-Fungible Tokens (NFTs) by fans worldwide through the OKX app. These NFTs will be available for fans to mint from April 22 to 25.","This digital collectible, ‘The Roses and the Bees’, crafted by artist Christian Jeffery, pays homage to Manchester by incorporating iconic symbols such as the Lancashire Rose and the Manchester Worker Bee, emblematic of the city’s rich heritage.","Each minted collectible is randomly assigned a rarity level – Classic, Rare, or Ultra Rare. Depending on the rarity of the NFTs, fans can win exclusive prizes, including limited-edition physical versions of the football shirt, hospitality tickets to Manchester City matches, and unique play-on-pitch experiences.","Nuria Tarré, Manchester City’s Chief Marketing and Fan Experience Officer, highlighted the club’s strategic focus on attracting tech-savvy audiences and embracing digital ownership through initiatives like the NFT launch. She emphasized the importance of digital ownership in the Web3 era, noting that it revolutionized the ownership process.","Want to win with @okx? ✨","Claim your free Unseen City Shirt digital collectible with the chance to secure even more prizes! 🎁👇","— Manchester City (@ManCity) April 22, 2024","","Tarré also shared Manchester City’s commitment to exploring the possibilities of Web3 technology through partnerships like OKX and other avenues. She mentioned the club’s foray into Roblox in late 2022 and described Web3 environments as dynamic and progressive, offering opportunities for innovation and co-creation.","OKX’s ambitious goal to establish itself as the “first crypto lifestyle brand” has been spearheaded by Chief Marketing Officer Haider Rafique. This strategic vision has led the cryptocurrency exchange to secure multi-million dollar sponsorship agreements with prestigious sports franchises, including the Formula 1 team McLaren and the English Premier League team Manchester City.","Haider Rafique expressed excitement about engaging Manchester City’s global fanbase through the campaign. He highlighted the potential of Web3 technology to enhance fan experiences and the importance of laying foundational work to create utility-based ecosystems, starting with NFTs attached to physical goods.","Founded in 2017 and headquartered in the Republic of Seychelles, OKX boasts a substantial global presence, serving over 20 million customers across 180 international markets. The exchange provides trading support for leading cryptocurrencies such as Bitcoin, Ether, Polkadot, and Cardano.","OKX’s partnership with Manchester City has undergone significant expansion. In July 2022, the cryptocurrency exchange was appointed as the football club’s official training kit partner for the 2022-23 season. Before this, in June of the preceding year, OKX secured the position of Manchester City’s official sleeve partner, marking another milestone in the collaboration between the two entities."],"entity":[{"type":"2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Manchester Worker Bee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Manchester City’s Chief Marketing","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cardano","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"April 22","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Unseen City Shirts","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"23","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Christian Jeffery","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Manchester City","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Manchester City","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Seychelles","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"OKX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ultra Rare","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April 22, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"June","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Lancashire Rose","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Polkadot","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Manchester City (","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"McLaren","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Haider Rafique","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"July 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["Football","Manchester City","OKX"],"authors":["Hassan Shittu"]}