{"summary":"Nexon’s MMORPG MapleStory to Launch Web3 Version on Avalanche","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/nexons-mmorpg-maplestory-to-launch-web3-version-on-avalanche.htm","publishDate":"2024-03-12T08:14:31","id":20746,"type":null,"title":"Nexon’s MMORPG MapleStory to Launch Web3 Version on Avalanche","category":["Blockchain News "],"content":["Nexon, the South Korean video game developer, plans to launch a web3 version of MapleStory on the Avalanche blockchain, adding user-generated content and new gameplay mechanics.","The official blog post by Avalanche detailed that this version, named MapleStory N, will enable players to design and share their own creations within the game.","Set to be released in 2024, the project aims to combine Nexon’s gaming expertise with Avalanche’s blockchain capabilities, enhancing the player experience with additional interactive features.","The MapleStory Universe on Avalanche will introduce opportunities for creating user-generated content, a feature common in prominent web2 games. In MapleStory N, players will have the ability to construct their own worlds and receive rewards for their contributions to the community.","The blog predicted that “loyal Web2 gamers from across the world will get an expanded gaming experience on Avalanche, introducing them to the possibilities of Web3 gaming.”","According to Avalanche, MapleStory Universe will operate on a specialized Avalanche Subnet designed expressly for its ecosystem.","MapleStory Universe’s Partnership Lead Angela Son said, “Our partnership with Ava Labs will allow us to build a stable and complete blockchain ecosystem, enabling us to securely service various dApps along with MapleStory N to amplify our competitiveness.”","“I can’t imagine a bigger opportunity in web3 than what the Nexon Group is doing with MapleStory Universe, and we’re honored to power its next blockchain project with Avalanche,” said Ed Chang, Ava Labs Head of Gaming.","“We’ve been extremely impressed with the vision since our first conversation, and the focus on long-term sustainability could easily onboard millions of users on-chain,” stated Chang.","In June 2023, Nexon America announced that it started accepting cryptocurrencies for in-game purchases with services provided by BitPay.","The announcement elaborated on the digital assets supported, including Bitcoin (BTC), Ethereum (ETH), Litecoin (LTC), Dogecoin (DOGE), as well as stablecoins like Binance USD (BUSD), DAI, and Gemeni Dollar (GUSD)."],"entity":[{"type":"2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MapleStory Universe","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ava Labs Head of Gaming","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nexon America","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MapleStory N","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ava Labs","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nexon Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ed Chang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"MapleStory Universe’s Partnership Lead Angela Son","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gemeni Dollar","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nexon","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Chang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BitPay","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"LTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"June 2023","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["Avalanche","Gaming","Web3"],"authors":["Hongji Feng"]}