{"summary":"Jefferies-Backed Tradu Launches Fee-Friendly Crypto Exchange","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/jefferies-backed-tradu-launches-fee-friendly-crypto-exchange.htm","publishDate":"2024-05-08T08:24:56","id":20751,"type":null,"title":"Jefferies-Backed Tradu Launches Fee-Friendly Crypto Exchange","category":["News "],"content":["Tradu, a trading platform owned by Jefferies’ Stratos Group, went live with a new crypto exchange aimed at active traders on Wednesday.","Beginning May 8, crypto traders have the opportunity to invest in more than 40 coins, including Bitcoin and Ethereum on the platform, according to a statement.","In a bid to undercut competitors, the crypto exchange said it significantly lowers trading fees. Tradu claims fees are up to 95% lower than other platforms, with a standard commission of just 0.1% and additional rebates for larger trades. The comparison is based on a standard account type and information from broker websites, the statement said.","“The commission for a 1 BTC trade (at a price of $60,000) is just $30 at Tradu versus as much as $600 at other exchanges,” the company added.","Tradu, headquartered in London, operates as a multi-asset trading platform. In addition to facilitating crypto exchange transactions, it enables trading across a broad spectrum of assets, spanning stocks, indices, commodities, and forex, totaling over 10,000.","With customer service available 24\/5 in 15 languages, Tradu ensures global traders can access assistance and advice whenever required.","“We are bringing institutional-grade pricing and infrastructure to the retail crypto market, providing traders with upfront costs and tight, transparent spreads enabling active traders and investors to maximise their returns,” said Tradu CEO Brendan Callan.","The approval of spot Bitcoin ETFs in the US and Hong Kong has triggered an influx of institutions into the crypto space. Major players like BlackRock and Fidelity are leading the charge, and traditional finance (TradFi) is scrambling to establish a foothold.","These regulatory green lights allow institutions to invest in crypto through secure channels, fueling wider adoption and boosting the overall liquidity of the market."],"entity":[{"type":"$60,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$30","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"BlackRock","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$600","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tradu","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fidelity","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"0.1%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"95%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Jefferies’ Stratos Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"May 8","content":"DATE"},{"type":"London","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Brendan Callan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["Crypto exchanges","Crypto trader"],"authors":["Shalini Nagarajan"]}