{"summary":"Flowcarbon is launching a new NFT project, Flow3rs, that uses 75% of its proceeds to retire carbon credits. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/184234\/adam-neumanns-a16z-backed-startup-launches-carbon-offsetting-nft-project","publishDate":"2022-11-08T11:23:14","id":2080,"type":null,"title":"a16z-backed startup Flowcarbon launches carbon-offsetting NFT project","category":["NFT COLLECTIONS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Flowcarbon, a blockchain startup co-created by WeWork co-founder Adam Neumann, will launch an NFT project that uses a majority of its proceeds to buy carbon offsets.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Dubbed Flow3rs, the project will feature work from prominent NFT artists including Danny Cole of Creature World, Olive Allen, and Andre Oshea, among others. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A total of 200 NFTs will be sold, with 75% of the proceeds going to purchase the carbon offsets. The rest of the funds will go to the artists and service providers, a Flowcarbon spokesperson told The Block.&nbsp;<\/span>","While carbon offsets remain a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/news+\/109558\/ninepoint-bitcoin-etf-carbon-footprint-offsets\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">controversial<\/a> climate mitigation tool, more and more crypto firms look to offsets to mitigate their climate impact. <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/113291\/skybridge-capital-to-offset-carbon-of-its-bitcoin-holdings-through-credits-purchase\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">SkyBridge Capital<\/a>, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/109559\/gemini-pledges-offset-350k-tons-bitcoin-carbon-emissions\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Gemini<\/a> and <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/104940\/greenidge-bitcoin-mining-carbon-offsets\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Greenidge Generations<\/a> are among the firms that have looked to offsets to lower their net emissions.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The carbon credits will come from three specific nature based projects verified through the carbon registry Verra. Prices for the NFTs will be announced in the coming days.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Flowcarbon previously raised <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/148427\/adam-neumann-backed-blockchain-startup-flowcarbon-raises-70-million\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$70 million<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> led by the crypto-focused venture firm a16z. The firm uses blockchain-based tools to tokenize carbon credits.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Adam Neumann","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Danny Cole","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"SkyBridge Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"WeWork","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"75%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Andre Oshea","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Olive Allen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$70 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Greenidge Generations","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["NFT ARTISTS"],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}