{"summary":"BNB Won’t Hit ATH This Year but Might Reach USD 2,500 by 2030 – Survey","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/bnb-wont-hit-ath-year-but-might-reach-usd-2500-by-2030-survey.htm","publishDate":"2022-03-09T18:10:00","id":20980,"type":null,"title":"BNB Won’t Hit ATH This Year but Might Reach USD 2,500 by 2030 – Survey","category":["Altcoin News "],"content":[" ","BNB, the exchange token issued by Binance and used on the BNB Chain too, could reach a price of more than USD 500 this year, while further rise to close to USD 2,500 is in the cards by the year 2030, according to a panel of industry players surveyed by comparison website Finder.","According to an average of the panelists’ responses, BNB will be a good hold for investors for the rest of the year, with the coin looking at a potential gain of more than 30% to USD 527 by the end of 2022.","The panel, which consisted of industry players from the investment, fintech and crypto space, were asked for their price predictions for BNB by the end of 2022, 2025, and 2030.","Worth noting, however, is that the 2022 price prediction of USD 527 is not even an all-time high for the coin, which reached its high of close to USD 692 in May 2021.","Asked about their longer-term predictions for BNB, an average of the panelists’ responses indicated that the coin is looking at a price of USD 975 by the end of 2025, and USD 2,488 by the end of 2030.","Finder’s BNB price predictions for 2022, 2025 and 2030:","“BNB may very well be a dark horse running up to ETH. Its price is very affordable for the general consumer, but the only issue is how Binance as a company does…,” Desmond Marshall, Managing Director of investment advisory firm Rouge International, was quoted as saying.","Among those most bullish on BNB over the long-term was John Stefanidis, CEO of the NFT gaming company Balthazar, who said BNB could reach USD 3,000 by 2030.","“[…] having complied with regulation globally, it’s set up for long term success. Great [user experience], strong ventures team, excellent brand,” Stefanidis summarized Binance’s strengths as a company.","Despite being optimistic about the price this year, one panelist also warned about a lack of decentralization behind BNB, given that it has always been associated with the centralized exchange Binance.","“Binance’s association with [BNB Chain]\/BNB may lead people to question just how decentralized it is; however, the bright side is that the exchange can use its platform and name recognition to recruit the world’s best developers to create their projects on [the BNB Chain],” Daniel Polotsky, Founder of the crypto ATM provider CoinFlip was quoted as saying.","Overall, few of the panelists said BNB would be the best altcoin to hold in 2022. Out of all 14 respondents, only 7% said BNB would be this year’s best performer. Instead of BNB, 21% of the panellists favoured polkadot (DOT), followed by 14% that preferred terra (LUNA) and 10% who said cardano (ADA) would be the top altcoin.","At the time of writing (16:00 UTC), BNB, ranked 4th by market capitalization, traded at USD 397, up 4% over the past 24 hours but down 3% over the past 7 days. The price is up over 60% in a year.\n____\nLearn more: \n– Binance Joins Russian Banking Union, Will Head New Crypto Department\n– Binance Invests USD 200M in Forbes\n\n– Crypto Exchanges are Top Consumers of Bitcoin Block Space, Binance No 1\n– ‘Russian Ethereum’, Waves, Almost Triples Since Ukraine War Began\n\n– ETH Rises with Broader Market as Ethereum Fees Hit a 7-Month Low\n– Bitcoin Rally Gets Support From ‘Watershed’ Executive Order, Rising Stock Market"],"entity":[{"type":"Broader Market","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"4%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"10%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"USD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"60%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"30%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Top Consumers of Bitcoin Block Space","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2030","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Balthazar","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2025","content":"DATE"},{"type":"7%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"May 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"3%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Stefanidis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Forbes\n\n– Crypto Exchanges","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"21%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Almost Triples Since Ukraine War Began","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Rouge International","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Will Head New Crypto Department\n– Binance Invests USD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Desmond Marshall","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"14%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Daniel Polotsky","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"John Stefanidis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"ADA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance Joins Russian Banking Union","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Altcoins","Binance","BNB","Forecast","Survey"],"authors":["Fredrik Vold"]}