{"summary":"Someone Just Moved 50 Bitcoins, Prompting Speculations It’s Satoshi Nakamoto","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/someone-just-moved-50-bitcoins-prompting-speculations-it-s-s-6605.htm","publishDate":"2020-05-20T15:51:00","id":21023,"type":null,"title":"Someone Just Moved 50 Bitcoins, Prompting Speculations It’s Satoshi Nakamoto","category":["Bitcoin News "],"content":["50 bitcoins (BTC) (USD 477,500), minted in the first month of Bitcoin’s existence and untouched for more than 11 years were moved today, prompting a wave of speculations that Satoshi Nakamoto “has awakened.” However, multiple industry players denied that these coins were moved by Bitcoin’s creator.","Here is the transaction:","However, Jameson Lopp, CTO at crypto security specialist Casa, denied this is Satoshi, saying: “No. Y’all need to up your analysis game.”","Bitcoiner and partner at Castle Island Ventures, Nic Carter, also chimed in:","____","At pixel time (15:52 UTC), BTC trades at USD 9,584 and is down by 1% in a day, trimming its weekly gains to less than 5%.","The total number of spent outputs that were created more than 10 years ago:","{no_ads}"],"entity":[{"type":"Satoshi Nakamoto","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jameson Lopp","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Castle Island Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Satoshi","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"UTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"CTO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nic Carter","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Casa","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USD","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Bitcoin","Satoshi Nakamoto"],"authors":["Linas Kmieliauskas"]}