{"summary":"Ledger and FVCKRENDER Launch Limited-Edition Nano X, More Collabs Coming","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/ledger-and-fvckrender-launch-limited-edition-nano-x-more-collabs-coming.htm","publishDate":"2023-11-15T15:00:23","id":21048,"type":null,"title":"Ledger and FVCKRENDER Launch Limited-Edition Nano X, More Collabs Coming","category":["Altcoin News "],"content":["Hardware wallet giant Ledger has joined hands with the popular tech-digital artist FVCKRENDER to launch a limited-edition bundle.","The bundle, says the press release, “redefines the intersection of premium style and security in the realm of digital assets.”","We made something special for our FVCKRENDER X LEDGER COLLAB! https:\/\/t.co\/S7wxrCtfoN","— FVCKRENDER (@fvckrender) November 14, 2023","","it includes a custom Ledger Nano X wallet designed by FVCKRENDER, featuring a glossy chrome finish with unique laser-etched avatar art.","Nano X connects to a user’s phone with Bluetooth and comes with a large screen for ease of use.","The bundle also includes a Ledger x LVCIDIA Finery cap – the custom-made cap from the wallet maker’s collaboration with LVCIDIA Finery.","It has two pockets made to “securely hold your Ledger Nano X while on the move,” the press release said.","A Ledger spokesperson told Cryptonews that, should the cap get stolen,","“If you store your recovery phrase in a secure location accessible only to you, there’s no need to worry about potential loss.”","Notably, there will only be 100 bundles available for purchase.","They can be bought today on ledger.com for €199\/$199.","This specific collaboration aims to marry top-tier security with iconic design, offering enthusiasts a unique product where crypto and non-fungible tokens (NFTs) meet style, the spokesperson said.","And Ledger is not done for this year. The spokesperson told Cryptonews that,","“There will be another collaboration to be announced in December. Stay tuned.”","Meanwhile, this collaboration follows the successful one with LVCIDIA, a digital fine art platform founded by FVCKRENDER.","Ledger stated that the collaboration with FVCKRENDER ensures that crypto holders can “safeguard their investments while expressing premium style.”","FVCKRENDER is a self-taught futuristic tech-digital artist working out of Vancouver.","The press release notes that the artist has “a defining affinity” for sharp architectural geometry and future landscapes, creating art that pays “a dark homage to what may eventually reflect our very existence.”","Some of his clients include Supreme, Softest Hard, Columbia Records, Lil Nas X, Epic Records, Harpers Bazaar China, TOKiMONSTA, New Retrowave Records, High Snobiety, Puma, Spotify, Instagram, Le Cirque du Soleil, Lebron James, Dior, Hypebeast and many more.","Ian Rogers, Chief Experience Officer (CXO) at Ledger, commented that,","“Seeing FVCKRENDER’s creative vision come to life on a Ledger is an honor for us. […] Digital art is an early use case for digital ownership, and we’re proud to work with FVCKRENDER to pioneer digital + physical ownership examples.”","Founded in Paris in 2014, Ledger says that it sold more than 6 million devices to consumers in 200 countries. It has more than 100 financial institutions and brands as customers.","Ledger’s products include Ledger Stax, Nano S Plus, Nano X hardware wallets, LEDGER Live companion app, and Ledger Enterprise.","The company stated that it has 20% of the world’s crypto assets secured.","Ledger stated that its collaborations with FVCKRENDER and LVCIDIA exemplify the wallet maker’s commitment to “uncompromising security within the realm of digital assets through education.”","____","",""],"entity":[{"type":"2014","content":"DATE"},{"type":"November 14, 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Dior","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Paris","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"20%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"December","content":"DATE"},{"type":"New Retrowave Records","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lil Nas X","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lebron James","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Columbia Records","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ian Rogers","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"LVCIDIA Finery","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Vancouver","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Hypebeast","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Epic Records","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cirque du Soleil","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Harpers Bazaar China","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Instagram","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Nano","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ledger Enterprise","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$199","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Puma","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Art","Investment","Ledger","Wallet"],"authors":["Sead Fadilpašić"]}