{"summary":"The chief of Hong Kong&#x27;s financial watchdog has become frontrunner for the vacant FCA role.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/156322\/head-of-hong-kongs-financial-regulator-in-line-for-role-in-britain-sky-news","publishDate":"2022-07-07T10:11:12","id":212,"type":null,"title":"Head of Hong Kong’s financial regulator in line for role in Britain: Sky News","category":["REGULATION"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ashley Alder, CEO of Hong Kong’s financial regulator, is the leading candidate to become the next chairman of the UK's Financial Conduct Authority (FCA), Sky News <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/news.sky.com\/story\/hong-kong-financial-regulator-alder-lined-up-to-chair-fca-12647583\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on Thursday.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Charles Randell <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.fca.org.uk\/news\/press-releases\/charles-randell-step-down-fca-and-psr-chair-spring-2022\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in October 2021 that he intended to leave his role as chairman of the FCA, after assuming the position — in conjunction with the Payment System Regulator position — in 2018. Richard Loyd has been interim chair since Randell’s departure in the Spring.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Alder has served over ten years as head of Hong Kong’s financial watchdog, the Securities and Futures Commission (FSC), while also chairing the International Organisation of Securities Commissions.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The chair of the FCA plays a vital role in the economic regulation of Britain and the appointment of a new chair requires the approval of both the Chancellor and the Prime Minister. However, due to the latest developments in Westminister may block any confirmation in the near future.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Earlier this week Rishi Sunak, former Chancellor of the exchequer, stepped down from his role in light of fresh scandals facing the beleaguered Prime Minister of Britain Boris Johnson.&nbsp;<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Since then Johnson has announced Sunak’s replacement, only for him to step down a day later, seen 60 members of parliament resign and announced his impending resignation.<\/span>","The UK Treasury, which handles appointments to the FCA, didn't immediately respond to a request for comment from The Block.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Richard Loyd","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Securities and Futures Commission (FSC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FCA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Britain","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Johnson","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ashley Alder","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Charles Randell","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"October 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"UK's Financial Conduct Authority (FCA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Randell","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"International Organisation of Securities Commissions","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sky News","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Rishi Sunak","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Prime Minister of Britain Boris Johnson","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UK Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spring","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["FCA"],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}