{"summary":"Mercedes-Benz NXT Partners with Mojito to Launch New NFT Collection","webName":"cryptonews.com","link":"https:\/\/cryptonews.com\/news\/mercedes-benz-nxt-partners-with-mojito-to-launch-new-nft-collection.htm","publishDate":"2024-05-15T15:33:52","id":21301,"type":null,"title":"Mercedes-Benz NXT Partners with Mojito to Launch New NFT Collection","category":["NFT News "],"content":["Mercedes-Benz NXT, the German automotive giant’s Web3 arm, is launching a new non-fungible token (NFT) collection in partnership with Mojito, a suite for creating NFT marketplaces.","The collection is called ‘The Era of Technology’ and is the second of seven eras in the company’s ‘Icon’ series.","A limited supply of 780 exclusive collectibles will launch on May 21 at 18:00 CET.","The mint will be open for seven days, until May 28.","Notably, the team said that due to regulatory and taxation requirements, only collectors from the EU, Australia, Brazil, Japan, Singapore, South Korea, Switzerland, the U.K., the US, and Taiwan will be able to participate.","Minting is open to all, said the press release shared with Cryptonews.","The price is set at 0.08 ETH.","5\/ 🚀 Price – We have chosen a price of 0.08 eth, which is below the fixed price of the last era in terms of eth value. We believe this, including the discounts, is a fair price for all considering the current market conditions.","— Mercedes-Benz NXT (@MercedesBenzNXT) May 14, 2024","","Furthermore, there are two discount types.","First is a 30% discount for collectors of previous core collections: Maschine, Mercedes-Benz NXT Icons, and Mercedes-Benz NXT Eternities.","Second, a 15% discount is available to Superdackel holders.","Additionally, Maschine and Mercedes-Benz NXT Eternities collectors will receive mint passes.","Each will enable one free mint (excluding gas) or a reduced price. Mint passes are burned upon use.","Mercedes-Benz NXT Icons are a celebration of Mercedes-Benz’s design heritage, the release said.","The Mercedes-Benz design team, headed by Chief Design Officer Gorden Wagener, created the items.","The team designed the story to be told in seven eras, spanning from the present to the beginnings of automotive history.","","The first era (one of seven chapters) in the Mercedes-Benz NXT Icons collection is “The Era of Luxury.” It features current car production and celebrates the brand’s design legacy in the digital age.","Therefore, “The Era of Technology” is the second era. It features six iconic cars produced from 2000 to 2017.","These are Maybach Landaulet, Mercedes-Benz S 560 Cabriolet, Mercedes-Benz CLS 500, Mercedes-Benz G 63 AMG 6×6, Mercedes-Benz SL 65 AMG Black Series, and Mercedes-Benz SLS AMG Coupé.","Per the team, the items have 62 distinct traits organized into five visible categories.","This way, the collection enables fans to own a digital version of their favorite Mercedes.","10\/ To make collecting even smoother and more accessible to all, we have introduced instant on-demand crypto wallet creation through email and social logins. Also, credit card payments are now available, supporting all major cards.","— Mercedes-Benz NXT (@MercedesBenzNXT) May 14, 2024","","Meanwhile, “Mojito’s APIs and SDKs serve as the backbone of Mercedes-Benz NXT’s web3 infrastructure,” the announcement said.","It blends blockchain, NFTs, and user-friendly interfaces, as well as “the ease of web2 with the transformative capabilities of web3.”","Mojito focused on creating a portal that will make easy the tasks like streamlined token creation, customized smart contract deployment, automated token distribution, tiered discounts using tokengating, and customer management and reporting.","Additionally, it integrated WalletConnect and Metamask.","Mercedes-Benz NXT’s inaugural core collection was Maschine for which it partnered with renowned artist Harm van den Dorpel and art collective Fingerprints DAO.","It followed this up with Eternities for a small number of selected Mercedes-Benz customers, as well as Superdackel, an homage to the iconic nodding dog dashboard toy ‘Wackeldackel.’"],"entity":[{"type":"South Korea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"May 28","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Switzerland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"EU","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.K.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"30%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Taiwan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Australia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Mercedes","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"15%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"May 21","content":"DATE"},{"type":"AMG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Benz NXT","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"May 14, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2000","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gorden Wagener","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Brazil","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Japan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Benz NXT Icons","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Benz NXT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Benz NXT Eternities","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mercedes","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["NFT","NFT Marketplace"],"authors":["Sead Fadilpašić"]}