{"summary":"One trader said ether’s sell-off on positive news is typical \"buy the rumors, sell the facts\" behavior.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/markets\/2024\/05\/24\/bitcoin-ether-rally-cools-following-us-ether-etf-listing-approval\/","publishDate":"2024-05-24T09:11:02","id":21378,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin, Ether Rally Cools Following U.S. Ether ETF Listing Approval","category":["Markets"],"content":["Bitcoin (BTC) and ether (ETH) prices fell in the past 24 hours even as several ether exchange-traded funds (ETFs) were approved for listing on U.S. exchanges.","Ether has dropped 4% since the approval, CoinGecko data shows. It had risen 20% over the course of a week amid indications of pending approval and updated odds of the ETFs getting approved. The broad-based CoinDesk 20, a liquid index that tracks the biggest tokens, fell 4.5% over 24 hours and the crypto market cap lost 2.9% to $2.5 trillion.","“Ethereum's sell-off on positive news is a typical \"buy the rumors, sell the facts\" reaction of speculators,” Alex Kuptsikevich, a senior market analyst at FxPro, said in an email to CoinDesk. “We shouldn't be surprised if the price pulls back to the $3000 area again, returning to an important consolidation area. From these levels, large institutional investors can start building a position in ETFs.","“We saw the same in January after the approval of the Bitcoin ETF, which took 19% off its price in the following two weeks before there was a spectacular reversal,” he said.","The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) on Thursday approved key regulatory filings tied to ether ETFs, a historic milestone for the second-largest cryptocurrency. They are not, however, cleared to trade. Although the SEC approved the 19B-4 form that allows for the offering and listing of ETFs, it must still green light the funds' S-1 filings before investors can buy them.","The regulator approved documents for eight ETFs – from VanEck, Fidelity, Franklin, Grayscale, Bitwise, ARK Invest 21Shares, Invesco Galaxy and BlackRock – for listing on the Nasdaq, NYSE Arca, and Cboe BZX exchanges.","If the ETFs are approved for trading, a significant influx of institutional capital is likely. Standard Chartered predicted inflows of as much as $45 billion in the first 12 months.","Some traders say they expect ether to rally over 60% in the coming months, with a marked increase in futures and spot buying demand for the token in the past week.","Edited by Sheldon Reback."],"entity":[{"type":"Sheldon Reback","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"4.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2.9%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Bitwise","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"4%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"20%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"60%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Franklin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alex Kuptsikevich","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"19%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$3000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"1","content":"DATE"},{"type":"VanEck","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"4","content":"DATE"},{"type":"BlackRock","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Grayscale","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Fidelity","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CoinDesk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$2.5 trillion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Cboe","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Invesco Galaxy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$45 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Nasdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NYSE Arca","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Markets","Bitcoin","ether ETF"],"authors":["Shaurya Malwa"]}