{"summary":"The latest price moves in crypto markets in context for May 15, 2024.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/markets\/2024\/05\/15\/first-mover-americas-bitcoin-approaches-63k-ahead-of-us-cpi-data\/","publishDate":"2024-05-15T12:00:37","id":21431,"type":null,"title":"First Mover Americas: Bitcoin Approaches $63K Ahead of U.S. CPI Data","category":["Markets"],"content":["This article originally appeared in First Mover, CoinDesk’s daily newsletter, putting the latest moves in crypto markets in context. Subscribe to get it in your inbox every day.","Bitcoin made some cautious gains on Wednesday ahead of the latest inflation data from the U.S. BTC is priced at $62,775 at the time of writing, up 1.8% in 24 hours. The wider digital market, as measured by the CoinDesk 20 Index (CD20), also ticked up, adding 0.55%. April's U.S. Consumer Price Index (CPI) inflation data is due at 08:30 ET, with expectations that it will show a 3.4% year-on-year increase, slower than March's 3.5%. Some analysts expect a softer-than-expected CPI reading could lift bitcoin above $65,000.","Latest News: U.S. CPI Softer Than Expected at 0.3% in April; Bitcoin Rises to $63.7K","Bitcoin's mean transaction fee has reversed the post-halving spike, squeezing miners' revenue. Miners earn revenue from two sources: block rewards and transaction fees. Miners receive a fixed amount of BTC as a reward for adding new blocks, along with transaction fees for including transactions in the blocks they mine. The spike, driven by the new Runes protocol, helped to compensate for the block reward being cut in half, but this proved to be short-lived. In response, miners may liquidate around $5 billion worth of BTC in the coming months, according to Markus Thielen, head of 10x Research. \"Why would they keep inventory when the price is not going up?\" Thielen said.","Broker Canaccord Genuity expects Galaxy Digital's positive momentum to continue after the crypto financial services firm reported an increase in net income of 40% on Tuesday. Galaxy saw an increase in the number of trading counterparties with trading revenue rising 79%, Canaccord noted in a report, citing the approval of spot bitcoin ETFs in the U.S. as the major catalyst. Mike Novogratz’s firm also increased its proprietary mining hashrate and the Helios facility “presents an opportunity for Galaxy to pursue both mining and AI hosting over time,” the broker said. Galaxy's Toronto-listed shares fell 1.12% on Tuesday to close at C$12.41.","- Omkar Godbole","Edited by Sheldon Reback."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S. BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sheldon Reback","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"First Mover","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Galaxy Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1.8%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Omkar Godbole","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$5 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"3.4%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Markus Thielen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"0.3%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"40%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Toronto","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"1.12%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$62,775","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"79%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Mike Novogratz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$65,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$63.7K","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"3.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"0.55%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Thielen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"C$12.41","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Canaccord","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Canaccord Genuity","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["Bitcoin","Ether","First Mover"],"authors":["Jamie Crawley","Omkar Godbole"]}