{"summary":"The Block’s Frank Chaparro chats with Framework Ventures&#x27; Vance Spencer. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/104881\/nowhere-near-a-top-frameworks-vance-spencer-on-institutional-adoption-and-the-memecoin-mania","publishDate":"2021-05-14T11:27:53","id":2145,"type":null,"title":"&#x27;Nowhere near a top&#x27;: Framework&#x27;s Vance Spencer on institutional adoption and the memecoin mania","category":["DEFI"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 28 of Season 3 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block’s Frank Chaparro and Framework Ventures’ Vance Spencer.&nbsp;<\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"86f6e9e2e5e7f5f2c6f2eee3e4eae9e5ede5f4fff6f2e9a8e5e9eb\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/bakkt.onelink.me\/FTbR\/c2043775\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bakkt<\/a>, Kraken, and Exodus<\/strong><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/bakkt.onelink.me\/FTbR\/c2043775\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bakkt®<\/em><\/a><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;unlocks the $1.2+ trillion of digital assets that is currently held in cryptocurrencies, rewards and loyalty points, gaming assets and merchant stored value. We began in 2018 with the vision to bring trust and transparency to digital assets. Through the Bakkt Warehouse and Bakkt Bitcoin Futures and Options contracts, we serve institutional clients in an end-to-end regulated market with true price transparency. For consumers, Bakkt aggregates digital assets to enable instant liquidity and to empower users to trade, transfer and pay however they want.&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/bakkt.onelink.me\/FTbR\/c2043775\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Visit Bakkt.com<\/a>&nbsp;for more information<\/em><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Kraken<\/strong><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Whether you’re an experienced crypto trader or just starting out, Kraken has the tools to help you achieve financial freedom. With 50+ cryptocurrencies to choose from, industry-leading security and a wide variety of features to suit any investing strategy, Kraken puts the power in your hands to buy, sell and trade digital assets. Visit&nbsp;<\/em><a href=\"http:\/\/kraken.com\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kraken.com<\/em><\/a><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;to get started&nbsp;today.<\/em><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Exodus<\/strong><\/span>","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK3516976884\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","In Vance Spencer's view, the market is completely undercounting the amount of capital that's about to move into the crypto world from institutional investor circles.&nbsp;","The co-founder of the $1 billion-plus investment firm Framework Ventures would have a good sense of that trajectory, considering how Framework wrapped up a $100 million fundraise for a new fund in the decentralized finance market.","Announced Friday, backers of the new fund include the $40 billion investment firm Hall Capital Partners and unnamed endowments, according to a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.wsj.com\/articles\/crypto-venture-firm-framework-draws-institutional-support-11620990002\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">report<\/a> by The Wall Street Journal.&nbsp;","Spencer joined The Scoop (prior to the raise being made public) to unpack the case for Ethereum, which powers much of the DeFi market, the impact of Dogecoin mania, and institutional adoption of crypto.&nbsp;","\"The resounding sense that I get is that people are underestimating the amount of capital that's coming off the sidelines by probably 1 to 2 orders of magnitude,\" Spencer said.","Spencer said that Ethereum and Bitcoin are the two cryptos that are \"on the menu\" for the large investors and are both \"nowhere near a top.\"","Still, he added that the story of Ethereum \"has a lot more to be told in a world where there is not hyperinflation or there's not all these crazy things happening than [bitcoin's story].\"","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Bakkt Warehouse","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ethereum \"","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1.2+ trillion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$1 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$100 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$40 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Framework Ventures’ Vance Spencer","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Kraken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hall Capital Partners","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Framework Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Spencer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Vance Spencer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}