{"summary":"The latest price moves in crypto markets in context for May 14, 2024.","webName":"coindesk.com","link":"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/markets\/2024\/05\/14\/first-mover-americas-bitcoin-dips-below-62k-ahead-of-us-inflation-figures\/","publishDate":"2024-05-14T12:01:00","id":21487,"type":null,"title":"First Mover Americas: Bitcoin Dips Below $62K Ahead of U.S. Inflation Figures","category":["Markets"],"content":["This article originally appeared in First Mover, CoinDesk’s daily newsletter, putting the latest moves in crypto markets in context. Subscribe to get it in your inbox every day.","Bitcoin fell below $62,000 during the European morning on Tuesday, losing about 1.63% over 24 hours. The CoinDesk 20 Index (CD20), a broad measurement of the digital asset market as a whole, fell almost 1.1%. Ether declined more than 2% to just above $2,900, while solana was largely unchanged at $145. In the next 24 hours, attention will turn to inflation reports out of the U.S. The latest Producer Price Index (PPI) is set for release at 08:30 ET today and the Consumer Price Index (CPI) is due tomorrow. Stubbornly high inflation has previously put paid to hopes of rate cuts in the U.S., which can have the effect of a handbrake on risk assets such as crypto.","The rally in GameStop (GME) stock has prompted a surge in meme coins PEPE, FLOKI and MOG. A post on X by retail trader @TheRoaringKitty, who was at the center of the GME short squeeze in 2021, sent the video-game retailer's stock flying on Monday, triggering a rally in the major meme tokens. PEPE, FLOKI and MOG all jumped as much as 30% in the last 24 hours, suggesting traders may be preempting a repeat of the DOGE rally in 2021 which occurred following GME's surge. \"Roaring Kitty's return was perceived as bullish for meme coins because the market remembered that much of the GameStop mania of 2021 spilled over to $DOGE and other meme coins,” MOG token developer Shisui told CoinDesk in a message.","Coinbase (COIN) suffered a three-hour outage from 04:15 UTC on Tuesday, returning to use at 07:42, according to its status page. Website visitors had received a \"503 Service Temporarily Unavailable\" message beforehand. While the outage has been tackled, Coinbase noted that some users may still experience failure when sending crypto or withdrawing fiat. COIN shares were down around 2.25% at $195 during mid-morning in Europe before the U.S. market opened. The bitcoin price appeared to be unaffected. Coinbase had noted that \"Your funds are safe,\" in a post on X during the outage, and did not disclose anything further on the nature of the problem.","- Omkar Godbole"],"entity":[{"type":"First Mover","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"next 24 hours","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2.25%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"MOG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Omkar Godbole","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"GameStop (GME","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"30%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$DOGE","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Shisui","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$2,900","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"GME","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$145","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"U.S","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"GameStop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"UTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1.1%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"CoinDesk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1.63%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$62,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$195","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["Bitcoin","Ether","First Mover"],"authors":["Jamie Crawley","Omkar Godbole"]}