{"summary":"The former White House communications director discussed Elizabeth Warren&#x27;s role in financial services and banking, and Gary Gensler&#x27;s ambitions as chair of the SEC.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/227882\/scaramucci-warren-gensler","publishDate":"2023-04-24T09:27:25","id":2197,"type":null,"title":"Anthony Scaramucci calls out Elizabeth Warren and &#x27;sidekick&#x27; Gensler","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 39<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 5 of The Scoop was recorded with <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro and Stephanie Murray, and SkyBridge founder and managing partner Anthony Scaramucci<\/strong><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/strong><\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a>,<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Please send feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"ef9f808b8c8e9c9baf9b878a8d83808c84c18c80\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/i>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm\/?e=BLOCK7462319153\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Anthony Scaramucci is the founder and managing partner of SkyBridge Capital, an alternative asset manager with more than $2.2 billion in AUM, including $800 million in digital asset-related investments.","In this episode, Scaramucci explains how Elizabeth Warren's 2020 endorsement of Joe Biden positioned her as \"de facto president for financial services and banking,\" and why he believes her \"sidekick,\" SEC Chair Gary Gensler, is an \"ambitious, single-minded politician, not focused on serving the people.\"","FTX took a 30% stake in SkyBridge just two months before the exchange declared bankruptcy. Scaramucci has expressed interest in repurchasing FTX's stake in SkyBridge, as well as <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/227697\/scaramucci-ftx-skybridge\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">skepticism regarding the possibility of an FTX reboot later this year<\/a>.","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">During this episode, Chaparro, Murray and Scaramucci also discuss:<\/em>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors <i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"http:\/\/circle.com\/Scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Circle<\/a>&nbsp;and <a href=\"https:\/\/www.cleanspark.com\/theblock\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CleanSpark<\/a>.<\/i><\/b><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Circle<\/strong><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Circle is a global financial technology company helping money move at internet speed. Our mission is to raise global economic prosperity through the frictionless exchange of value. Visit <a class=\"c-link\" href=\"http:\/\/circle.com\/Scoop\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-stringify-link=\"http:\/\/Circle.com\/Scoop\" data-sk=\"tooltip_parent\" aria-describedby=\"sk-tooltip-398\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">circle.com\/Scoop<\/a> to learn more.<\/em><\/span>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About CleanSpark<\/strong>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CleanSpark (NASDAQ: CLSK) is America’s Bitcoin Miner™. Visit <a href=\"https:\/\/www.cleanspark.com\/theblock\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">cleanspark.com\/theblock<\/a> to learn more about the CleanSpark way.<\/span><\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Stephanie Murray","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"SkyBridge Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$2.2 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Murray","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Anthony Scaramucci","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"America","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"30%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gary Gensler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"SkyBridge","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Scaramucci","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Joe Biden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$800 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Elizabeth Warren","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","Stephanie Murray","The Block"]}