{"summary":"The Block analyzes the overall shift in lobbying and breaks down the crypto exchange lobby driving recent expansion. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/159545\/led-by-exchanges-crypto-industry-lobbying-grew-17-in-q2-despite-bear-market","publishDate":"2022-07-25T15:52:34","id":220,"type":null,"title":"Led by exchanges, crypto industry lobbying grew 17% in Q2 2022","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Despite market chaos and broad layoffs, the crypto industry has continued pouring money into lobbying programs.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">According to an analysis by The Block, cumulative lobbying expenditures by crypto firms in the second quarter of 2022 reached $6,751,500. For comparison, the previous quarter saw a total of $5,772,408.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">That figure represents an increase of just under 17%. The rise is particularly notable given that crypto’s market cap dropped from just over $2 trillion to under $900 billion during the same timeframe.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The market collapse has resulted in several notable firms falling into default or bankruptcy. Many other industry participants are enacting layoffs and belt-tightening measures.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Political influence spending is seemingly an exception.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Companies or entities that reported more than $100,000 in lobbying this quarter included Chainalysis, Celo Foundation, Dapper Labs, the DeFi Education Fund, BAM Trading Services dba Binance US, West Realm Shires Services Inc. dba FTX US, Foris DAX inc. dba Crypto.com, Meta Platforms via four contracts with outside lobbying firms (this analysis does not include Meta’s entire lobbying spending, which hit $5.39 million), Coin Center, Atlas Power Holdings and its portfolio company Greenidge Generation, Block Inc, Electronic Transactions Association, the Chamber of Digital Commerce, the Blockchain Association and Robinhood Markets.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto exchanges in particular drove the quarter's lobbying surge as they continued to expand their lobbying. Spending from crypto exchanges or organizations that expressly represent them grew from $1,190,030 to $2,210,000 between the two quarters.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The largest individual spender remains Coinbase, which reported $1 million. FTX, which has been conspicuously active on Capitol Hill, reported $270,000, including the launch of its <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/152268\/ftx-makes-former-senate-staffer-first-in-house-lobbyist-amid-capitol-hill-blitz\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">first in-house lobbying<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. Crypto.com declared $430,000, which as recently as the fourth quarter of last year reported none.&nbsp;<\/span>","","","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance US reported an increase in lobbying spending from $100,000 to $310,000 through contracts with Ice Miller Strategies and Hogan Lovells US. Gemini and Kraken reported smaller contracts as well.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Association of Digital Asset Marketplaces, or ADAM, which aims to become a self-regulatory organization for crypto exchanges, expanded a lobbying contract with Conaway Graves that it had first reported in March. Conaway Graves has become a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/158479\/meet-the-crypto-industrys-new-favorite-lobbyists\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">go-to for the crypto industry<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> since founders Mike Conaway and Scott Graves ended their cooling-off period following their respective tenures as a Congressman and staffer on the House Agriculture Committee.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Even Uniswap Labs, which codes the largest decentralized exchange, Uniswap, got into lobbying for the first time, reporting a new $10,000 contract with Diroma Eck &amp; Co.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Exchanges face a critical juncture before Congress. A huge ongoing political push aims to set up a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/144194\/congressman-introduces-digital-commodity-exchange-act-to-set-up-cftc-regime-for-crypto-exchanges\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">federal registration regime<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> for exchanges with the Commodity Futures Trading Commission. At the moment, the default practice is to register with state regulators as a money transmitter or money services business.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">However, the Securities and Exchange Commission under Chairman Gary Gensler has long signaled that it views many of these <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/158973\/sec-lists-nine-crypto-tokens-as-securities-following-coinbase-insider-trading-charges\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">exchanges as securities exchanges<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. The industry, however, has argued that the SEC has made a path to register opaque.&nbsp;<\/span>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Editor’s note: <\/b><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">For this analysis, The Block included crypto-native firms like Coinbase, as well as firms and entities whose political activities have focused on crypto issues, including Robinhood Markets, Block (formerly Square) and the Electronic Transactions Association. Though we did not include the full expenses from Meta (formerly Facebook), we did include contracts that Meta has with lobbying firms that indicate strong ties to crypto issues. This analysis did not include a number of banking and finance firms and associations that have been active in crypto-relevant issues.&nbsp;<\/span><\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">These numbers for Q1 differ from earlier analysis by The Block based on subsequent conversations with parties involved in lobbying activities and expanded searching.<\/span><\/i>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Greenidge Generation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$430,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Mike Conaway","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hogan Lovells US","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Block Inc","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$900 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Celo Foundation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Uniswap Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$270,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Chamber of Digital Commerce","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BAM Trading Services dba Binance US","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"second quarter of 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Chainalysis","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Meta","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Electronic Transactions Association","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$100,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$1 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Ice Miller Strategies","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Conaway Graves","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Blockchain Association","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Robinhood Markets","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Meta Platforms","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coin Center","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$2,210,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Kraken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"17%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Gary Gensler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$310,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$5,772,408","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Atlas Power Holdings","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Foris DAX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$5.39 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Association of Digital Asset Marketplaces","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"West Realm Shires Services Inc.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$2 trillion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"House Agriculture Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Congress","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$6,751,500","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Uniswap","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$10,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Diroma Eck &amp; Co.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Commodity Futures Trading Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"fourth quarter of last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$1,190,030","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Scott Graves","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE","COINBASE","FTX"],"authors":["Kollen Post","The Block"]}