{"summary":"A U.S. Court of Appeals court denied former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried’s appeal to be released from jail ahead of his trial.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/252435\/us-court-of-appeals-rejects-sam-bankman-frieds-efforts-for-pre-trial-release","publishDate":"2023-09-21T17:01:25","id":2201,"type":null,"title":"US Court of Appeals rejects SBF&#x27;s efforts for pre-trial release","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A U.S. Court of Appeals court denied former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried's appeal to be released from jail ahead of his trial.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bankman-Fried's attorneys had asked a New York district court to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/247689\/sam-bankman-frieds-lawyers-ask-for-temporary-release-from-jail\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">grant<\/span><\/a> the former billionaire's temporary release from jail in order to review documents ahead of his Oct. 3 trial.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We have reviewed the Defendant-Appellant's additional arguments and find them unpersuasive. Upon due consideration, it is hereby ORDERED that the motion for release pending trial is DENIED,” the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit <a href=\"https:\/\/ca2-showdocservices.azurewebsites.us\/api\/GetMergedFile?fileGuid=6b7be0d9-a6cb-4560-aec9-fb0b362f0a5e\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ruled<\/span><\/a> on Thursday.<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bankman-Fried <\/span><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">was sent to await trial in <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/244540\/ftx-judge-says-hes-revoking-bail-for-bankman-fried-inner-city-press\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">jail<\/span><\/a> in August after prosecutors accused him of witness tampering by leaking the private diary of former colleague and ex-girlfriend Caroline Ellison to the New York Times and using an encrypted message app to contact a potential witness.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"The record supports the district court's conclusion that there was probable cause to believe that the Defendant-Appellant attempted to tamper with two witnesses in violation of 18 U.S.C. § 1512(b), and specifically that he acted with unlawful intent to influence those witnesses,\" the appeals court wrote.<\/span>","<span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The appeals court also said the district court was right when it said that a person engaging in speech to commit a criminal offense, such as witness tampering, \"falls outside the zone of constitutional protection.\"&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bankman-Fried <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/236735\/judge-denies-motion-to-dismiss-most-charges-against-sam-bankman-fried\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s5\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">faces<\/span><\/a> over 100 years in prison if he is convicted on a slew of charges including fraud over allegations that he and other FTX executives used billions of customer assets to make their own failed investments. FTX filed for bankruptcy protection late last year.&nbsp;<\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Oct. 3","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Appellant","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York Times","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. Court of Appeals","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Caroline Ellison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Second Circuit","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fried","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}