{"summary":"A court should oppose the SEC&#x27;s move to take former Terra CEO Do Kwon’s deposition in the U.S. because he is detained, his lawyers argued.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253296\/do-kwon-argues-that-sec-bid-for-us-deposition-is-impossible","publishDate":"2023-09-27T14:37:02","id":2243,"type":null,"title":"Do Kwon says SEC&#x27;s ask for deposition in the US is impossible","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A New York court should oppose the Securities and Exchange Commission's move to take former Terraform Labs CEO Do Kwon's deposition in the U.S. because he is currently detained in Montenegro, Kwon's lawyers argued.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Last week, the SEC said the Southern District of New York should <a href=\"https:\/\/storage.courtlistener.com\/recap\/gov.uscourts.nysd.594150\/gov.uscourts.nysd.594150.58.0.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">grant<\/span><\/a> its request to ask Kwon questions in the U.S., but Kwon’s lawyers said that was impossible.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kwon was detained in Montenegro in March 2023 and later was found guilty by a court there of using a fake Costa Rican passport in an attempt to leave the country. Kwon was <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/235448\/do-kwon-found-guilty-in-montenegro-fake-passport-case\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">sentenced<\/span><\/a> to four months in jail in June. <\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Both the U.S. and South Korea have <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/223635\/do-kwon-extradition-montenegro\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">requested<\/span><\/a> to extradite Kwon.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The SEC <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/212695\/sec-charges-terraform-and-do-kwon-post-terra-collapse\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">charged<\/span><\/a> Terraform Labs and Kwon in February over its algorithmic stablecoin Terra USD, which collapsed last year.&nbsp;<\/span><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The agency accused both Terraform and Kwon of raising billions from investors by <\/span><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">offering and selling an inter-connected suite of crypto asset securities, many in unregistered transactions.\"<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Algorithmic stablecoins, like Terra USD, use market incentives via algorithms to maintain a stable price. Terra was linked to Luna, a governance token, to keep the prices stable. Terra USD crashed in May 2022, wiping out billions.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"South Korea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"May 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kwon","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"February","content":"DATE"},{"type":"March 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Luna","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Terra USD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"June","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Montenegro","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"the Southern District of New York","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}