{"summary":"PGA Tour and Autograph linked up to launch a golf-focused NFT platform that will sell PGA Tour highlights as digital collectibles.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/171074\/pga-tour-and-sports-memorabilia-firm-autograph-launch-new-golf-focused-digital-collectibles-platform","publishDate":"2022-09-19T13:51:00","id":2282,"type":null,"title":"PGA Tour and Autograph to launch golf-focused digital collectibles platform","category":["NFTS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">PGA Tour, a major organizer for professional men’s golf tournaments, and the Tom Brady co-founded sports memorabilia platform Autograph announced Monday that it will launch a new platform for golf digital collectibles.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This new platform will launch in 2023 and mint snippets of notable golf history, as well as the current 2021-2022 FedExCup Season, as NFTs for golf fans to collect.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“The PGA Tour is excited to work with Autograph to offer digital collectibles that highlight the most talented golfers in the world and their role in the sport’s history,” said PGA Tour Chief Legal Officer Len Brown in a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.pgatour.com\/company\/2022\/09\/19\/pga-tour-autograph-to-create-nft-platform-allowing-fans-to-own-moments-golf-history.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">statement<\/a>.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This is not the first time the PGA Tour got into NFTs, nor its first collaboration with Autograph. In April of this year, PGA Tours picked Autograph to mint Tour-licensed media as NFTs, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/golf.com\/news\/pga-tour-launching-multiple-nft-programs\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Golf.com<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> previously reported.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The FedExCup is a golf competition in which the winner can receive $18 million.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Launched in July of 2021, the NFT-based sports memorabilia platform Autograph not only sells sports moments but collections from athletes such as gymnast <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/116026\/simone-biles-to-release-nft-collection-via-tom-bradys-autograph-platform\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Simone Biles<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, golfer Tiger Woods, and football player Tom Brady, its co-founder. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Autograph raised <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/130880\/nft-autograph-170-million-series-b-funding\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$170 million<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in Series B funding in January.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"PGA Tours","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Golf.com","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"July of 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$18 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$170 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Tom Brady","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FedExCup Season","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FedExCup","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Len Brown","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tiger Woods","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"April of this year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"PGA Tour","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Simone Biles","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}