{"summary":"European Union leaders agreed that a digital euro is one of the legislative priorities for 2023 and 2024. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/195302\/digital-euro-on-eu-priorities-list-before-2024-elections","publishDate":"2022-12-15T06:58:48","id":229,"type":null,"title":"Digital euro on EU priorities list before 2024 elections","category":["INTERNATIONAL POLICYMAKING"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Presidents of the European Parliament, Council and Commission have <a href=\"https:\/\/www.europarl.europa.eu\/news\/en\/press-room\/20221214IPR64711\/eu-institutions-agree-on-joint-priorities-for-2023-and-2024\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">signed<\/a> a joint agreement outlining priorities before the next European elections in 2024. On the list of 164 legislations — some are already in negotiations, and others are yet to be put forward — is a central bank digital currency.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The European Commission <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/183632\/eu-commission-propose-legislation-digital-euro\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">promised<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to develop legislation for a digital euro “soon.” A spokesperson confirmed that the Commission plans to put forth a proposal in the second quarter of 2023.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The European Union’s anti-money laundering package also featured on the list of priorities. The AML regulation is in negotiations between policymakers in the European Parliament. Discussions have <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/173652\/europe-aml-rules-could-implicate-defi-daos-and-nfts\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">brought<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> decentralized finance, DAOs and NFTs into scope.&nbsp;<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">An EU-wide anti-money laundering authority to oversee provisions, including on crypto firms, is anticipated.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">As for the digital euro, the European Central Bank is currently working on a prototype with a selection of partners, including the <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/173711\/eu-policymakers-criticize-amazons-role-in-ecbs-digital-euro-development\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">contested<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Amazon. The design phase will wrap up in March 2023, followed by a decision on whether to implement a euro CBDC anticipated in October.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ECB executives <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/183646\/digital-euro-transaction-limits-store-value-caps\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">say<\/a> that a digital euro will likely have limited individual transactions<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;and caps on store-of-value.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"European Parliament","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Amazon","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"ECB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"EU","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"second quarter of 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"European Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"March 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"European Union","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Council and Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"European Parliament","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"European Central Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"AML","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"October","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["ECB","EUROPEAN COMMISSION","EUROPEAN COUNCIL","EUROPEAN PARLIAMENT"],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}