{"summary":"In this episode of The Scoop, Bitstamp USA CEO Bobby Zagotta discusses Bitstamp’s resiliency over the years, and explains how centralized exchanges can restore user confidence in the wake of FTX’s collapse.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/196717\/exchanges-are-counting-on-proof-of-reserves-to-restore-consumer-confidence-says-bitstamp-us-ceo","publishDate":"2022-12-21T05:00:39","id":2307,"type":null,"title":"Exchanges are counting on ‘proof-of-reserves’ to restore consumer confidence, says Bitstamp US CEO","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 127<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 4 of The Scoop was recorded live with <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro and Bitstamp USA CEO Bobby Zagotta.<\/strong><\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts.&nbsp;Email feedback and revision requests can be sent to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"88f8e7ecebe9fbfcc8fce0edeae4e7ebe3ebfaf1f8fce7a6ebe7e5\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm\/?e=BLOCK6569357916\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/i>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Founded in 2011, Bitstamp has navigated the ups and downs of multiple crypto market cycles over the years.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In this episode of The Scoop, Bitstamp USA CEO Bobby Zagotta discusses Bitstamp’s resilience, and explains how centralized exchanges can restore user confidence in the wake of FTX’s collapse.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">According to Zagotta, \"proof-of-reserves\" is an important step towards giving customers more visibility into how centralized exchanges manage customer assets:&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"On the one hand, the way many exchanges operate is pretty opaque; but on the other hand, blockchain technology creates the opportunity for radical transparency… Proof-of-reserves will allow customers to see that the assets on the exchange exceed the liabilities on the exchange.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Although large exchanges such as Binance, KuCoin and Crypto.com have all attempted to establish proof-of-reserves, the accounting firm conducting these reports announced last week that it is <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/195623\/mazars-pauses-crypto-audits\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">pausing<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> all work for its crypto exchanges clients, and others around the industry have been <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/193935\/skepticism-mazars-crypto-exchange\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">skeptical<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> of the legitimacy of these reports.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The current method for proof-of-reserves “is not perfect,” Zagotta says, because “it's a snapshot in time.”<\/span>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">During this episode, Chaparro and Zagotta also discuss:<\/span><\/i>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Disclaimer: Beginning in 2021, Michael McCaffrey, the former CEO and majority owner of The Block, took a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried. McCaffrey resigned from the company in December 2022 after failing to disclose those transactions.<\/em><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Tron,&nbsp;<\/em><\/a><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.ledn.io\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ledn,<\/a><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em><\/b><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nAbout Tron<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Founded in 2013, Huobi Global is one of the largest virtual asset exchanges in the world. Huobi Global serves millions of users across international markets. Since its establishment, Huobi Global has committed to providing first class virtual asset investment services. Huobi Global's robust infrastructure, product innovation and capital strength provides a truly customer-centric and secure trading environment to help our international users to achieve their investment objectives. Please refer to Huobi's official website for more information: <a href=\"http:\/\/www.huobi.com\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">huobi.com<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Ledn<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong>Ledn was founded on the unshakeable conviction that digital assets have the power to democratize access to the global economy. We help you to experience the real life benefits of your Bitcoin without having to sell it. Start a savings account, take out a loan, or double your Bitcoin. For more information visit&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.ledn.io\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ledn.io<\/a><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Bobby Zagotta","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2011","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Huobi Global","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2013","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Zagotta","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Zagotta","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ledn","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bitstamp USA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Huobi","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bitstamp","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"December 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ledn<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong>Ledn","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Michael McCaffrey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["BITSTAMP","CRYPTO"],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}