{"summary":"The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commissioner has also opened an investigation into Avraham Eisenberg, the self-confessed exploiter of the Mango Markets.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/200339\/sec-also-investigating-mango-exploiter-eisenberg-cftc-commissioner","publishDate":"2023-01-10T03:13:01","id":2318,"type":null,"title":"SEC also investigating Mango exploiter Eisenberg: CFTC Commissioner","category":["PEOPLE"],"content":["The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission is also investigating self-confessed Mango Markets exploiter Avraham Eisenberg over his role in extracting $110 million from the decentralized protocol.&nbsp;","Kristin Johnson, a Commodity Futures Trading Commission commissioner, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.cftc.gov\/PressRoom\/SpeechesTestimony\/johnsonstatement010923\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">noted<\/a> the SEC's parallel investigation in a statement published Monday. The CFTC <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/200255\/cftc-files-its-own-case-against-mango-markets-exploiter?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filed<\/a> its charges against Eisenberg, alleging manipulation of the decentralized swaps markets.","A spokesperson for the SEC did not immediately respond to an email sent out of hours seeking comment.","Eisenberg is currently in custody after the Department of Justice <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/198172\/mango-markets-exploiter-arrested-in-puerto-rico-for-alleged-market-manipulation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filed<\/a> criminal charges against him last month. He <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/177424\/mango-markets-exploiter-comes-clean-claims-all-actions-were-legal\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">admitted<\/a> on Twitter to being responsible for draining most of Mango Markets' capital, arguing that his trading strategy was legal and used the protocol as designed.&nbsp;","Investigators allege he illegally manipulated the price of Mango's own token, MNGO, to make substantial illicit profits.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Mango","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Department of Justice","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Avraham Eisenberg","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Commodity Futures Trading Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CFTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Eisenberg","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$110 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Kristin Johnson","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["CRIME","DEXS","EXPLOITS","SMART CONTRACTS"],"authors":["Benjamin Robertson","The Block"]}