{"summary":"Crypto.com said on Tuesday that it has become the latest exchange to gain regulatory approval in Italy.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/158449\/crypto-com-becomes-latest-exchange-to-gain-approval-to-operate-in-italy","publishDate":"2022-07-19T07:55:13","id":2331,"type":null,"title":"Crypto.com becomes latest exchange to gain approval to operate in Italy","category":["REGULATION"],"content":["Crypto.com said on Tuesday that it has become the latest exchange to gain regulatory approval in Italy from the <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Organismo Agenti e Mediatori (OAM).&nbsp;<\/span>","This allows it to provide <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">virtual currency and digital wallet services in the country in compliance with local regulations.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We are committed to building lasting growth in the region and will continue working with regulators to deliver a wide range of products and services to our valued customers,\" said Kris Marszalek, co-founder and CEO of Crypto.com, in a press release.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","According to the release, Crypto.com now has more than 50 million users worldwide.&nbsp;","The exchange also recently received registration in Greece from the <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Hellenic Capital Market Commission in-principle approval for a Major Payment Institution License from the Monetary Authority of Singapore, and provisional approval of its Virtual Asset License from the Dubai Virtual Assets Regulatory Authority.<\/span>","Crypto.com's approval follows that of Coinbase, which announced it had received the same approval <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/158077\/coinbase-approved-to-operate-as-crypto-asset-service-provider-in-italy\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">yesterday<\/a>. <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/149278\/binance-italy-wins-approval-to-operate-as-crypto-service-provider\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance Italy<\/a> was also approved at the end of May.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Greece","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Monetary Authority","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dubai Virtual Assets Regulatory Authority","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kris Marszalek","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Italy","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Organismo Agenti e Mediatori (OAM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hellenic Capital Market Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["COINBASE"],"authors":["Lucy Harley-McKeown","The Block"]}