{"summary":"Latin America cryptocurrency exchange Bitso has officially launched its app in Colombia.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/147647\/bitso-officially-launches-its-app-in-colombia","publishDate":"2022-05-18T14:25:57","id":2337,"type":null,"title":"Bitso officially launches its app in Colombia","category":["BITCOIN"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Latin American cryptocurrency exchange Bitso has officially launched its app in Colombia, allowing its residents to load pesos into their wallets using a widely-used online payment system connected to the country’s major banks.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The company <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/134811\/heres-why-crypto-unicorn-bitso-is-expanding-into-colombia\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced its expansion<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> into the South American country in February and has been working on a pilot program for cash-in and cash-out operations with Banco de Bogotá. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">But now, Bitso’s product is officially available to the wider Colombian public.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Using a popular online <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/support.bitso.com\/hc\/es-co\/articles\/6260521175060-Deposita-pesos-colombianos-desde-la-app-de-Bitso\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">payment method called PSE<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, Bitso users can open the wallet, load Colombian pesos and use the app to purchase assets such as Bitcoin, Ether, ApeCoin, Aave and Solana in addition to U.S. dollar-pegged stablecoins including Dai, Tether and TrueUSD.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Speaking at a launch event on May 17 in Bogotá, Bitso CEO Daniel Vogel explained that the exchange has been interested in the Colombian market for a while due to its potential. Colombia ranked 11th on Chainalysis’ latest global crypto adoption index, and Vogel noted in a press statement that an estimated <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$70 billion in crypto is traded here each month. Other exchanges with a local presence in Colombia include Buda.com, Binance and Ripio.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">And yet Bitso is announcing its Colombia launch just a week after one of the most volatile weeks in the history of crypto, in a market where many are still unfamiliar with digital assets. Not surprisingly, people across Latin America are asking questions.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Every regulator we’ve met has asked us about Terra and Luna,” Vogel said, noting that customers and media have also asked the company about what the recent market events have meant.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“I think we’re definitely in a crypto winter, it definitely feels that way,” Vogel added, noting that he likes building during such periods because it creates an environment for focusing on the fundamentals and attracting clients for the right reasons.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Of course, it's a lot easier to launch when the markets are hot, when there’s a lot of demand and whatnot, but you can build a lot more intentionally when that’s not happening,” said Vogel, who <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">added that he thinks last week will be a “blip” on the radar in the history of crypto.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Although Colombia could be ripe for crypto adoption, its use case is arguably less clear here than in places like Venezuela or Argentina where ongoing, unmanageable inflation makes it hard for consumers to save in local currencies. <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.bnnbloomberg.ca\/colombian-inflation-jumps-more-than-expected-to-21-year-high-1.1761876\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Prices have been rising here, too,<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> albeit at comparatively lower rates than some neighboring countries. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">But Vogel said that one situation piquing Colombians’ interest in crypto at the moment is the country’s upcoming <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2022-05-17\/colombia-s-sarmiento-sees-strong-growth-taming-election-risk\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">presidential election<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“A lot of people that we’ve met are sort of, a little bit unsure of the political situation, and what that might mean in terms of volatility of the Colombian peso,” Vogel said.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Vogel said that Bitso’s participation in the regulated sandbox will continue until the end of the year and that the company expects further crypto guidance from regulators in the next few months.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitso is a Gibraltar-registered company that also operates in Mexico, Brazil and Argentina. It counts more than 4 million users in those countries. <\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Venezuela","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"May 17","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Banco de Bogotá","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bogotá","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Latin America","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Brazil","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"February","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Mexico","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Vogel","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Colombia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Luna","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Argentina","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Gibraltar","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Daniel Vogel","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bitso","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ripio","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$70 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["PAYMENTS"],"authors":["Kristin Majcher","The Block"]}