{"summary":"Pakistan-based Game Storm Studios will team up with Ready Games to launch two new web3 games for mobile.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/156284\/game-storm-studios-ready-games-to-release-mobile-based-web3-games","publishDate":"2022-07-07T09:00:33","id":2411,"type":null,"title":"Game Storm Studios, Ready Games to release mobile-based web3 games","category":["GAMING AND METAVERSE"],"content":["&nbsp;","&nbsp;","Pakistan-based Game Storm Studios will team up with Ready Games to launch two new web3 games, according to a statement today.&nbsp;","The new project follows Ready Games’ entry into the web3 world in May, when it <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/business\/2022\/05\/06\/ready-games-raises-3m-to-bring-web-2-gaming-to-the-web-3-world\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">raised<\/a> $3 million in token sales to fund its new mobile web3 gaming arm. Among the investors were Bitkraft Ventures, Hashed, Mapleblock Capital, Mulana Capital and Polygon.","Compared to browser-based games, app blockchain games have been slow to take off due to concerns about how they fit into Apple and Google’s terms of service. Part of Ready Games’ web3 push involves helping web2 companies convert already existing games to web3 while complying with the rules of app stores.","Games Storm’s new blockchain-based games will both be pet-themed. According to its website, Game Storm has published over 1,000 non-web3 games in its over 10 years of operation and has offices in Pakistan, the US, India and Dubai. It mainly focuses on helping game builders create mobile applications for Android and iPhone.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Pakistan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"over 10 years of operation","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bitkraft Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$3 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Mapleblock Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mulana Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dubai","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"India","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Hashed","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Callan Quinn","The Block"]}