{"summary":"Galaxy Digital, the crypto merchant bank headed by Mike Novogratz, has hired former-Cumberland exec David Gross to lead global sales, according to an","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/34763\/galaxy-digital-snags-former-cumberland-and-credit-suisse-exec-david-gross-to-lead-global-sales","publishDate":"2019-08-06T10:35:10","id":2418,"type":null,"title":"Galaxy Digital snags former Cumberland and Credit Suisse exec David Gross to lead global sales","category":["PEOPLE"],"content":["Galaxy Digital, the crypto merchant bank headed by Mike Novogratz, has hired former-Cumberland exec David Gross to lead global sales, according to an internal memo sent out to the firm's counterparties.&nbsp;","Gross, a Wall Street veteran, left crypto trading giant Cumberland in February after an 11-month stint. He previously held positions as a director at Credit Suisse and Lehman Brothers, according to his <a href=\"https:\/\/www.linkedin.com\/in\/david-gross-24816522\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">LinkedIn profile.<\/a>","Gross will now be expected to put his nearly 15 years in convertible bond sales and trading to help turn Galaxy's fortunes around. The firm, which operates an over-the-counter trading desk in crypto as well as an investment and venture capital arm, had a difficult start to the year, announcing a&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/2019\/04\/29\/galaxy-digital-saw-272-6m-loss-in-2018\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$272.6 million loss in 2018<\/a>. In recent months, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/2018\/11\/11\/3-major-execs-have-left-mike-novogratzs-galaxy-digital-as-the-firm-makes-a-big-pivot\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">six execs also left the company<\/a>, including its <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/tiny\/galaxy-digital-cto-leaves-company\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CTO Mike McMahon<\/a>.&nbsp;","In his new role, Gross will&nbsp;be coordinating and driving sales across its three business units, according to a source. Gross will be reporting to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.linkedin.com\/in\/christopher-ferraro-23983165\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">president Chris Ferraro.<\/a>","Gross's former employer, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/daily\/21674\/new-tech-and-younger-faces-drws-cumberland-looks-different-its-counter-parties-say\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Cumberland<\/a>, is one of Galaxy's major OTC rivals. Its parent company, tech giant DRW, was among the first well-known high-frequency trading shops to dive into the over-the-counter trading market for crypto.","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/18466\/cumberlands-otc-desk-reports-mini-surge-of-large-btc-orders-in-a-single-hour-late-monday-night\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Cumberland<\/a> has also seen its own fair share of leadership changes. Gross's departure as global head of relationship management was followed by that of Bobby Cho and James Radecki, as well as by <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/2019\/06\/06\/cumberland-bids-farewell-to-its-global-head-and-final-og\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;Jason Leung,<\/a> leaving the unit with a younger, more tech-centric staff according to<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/2019\/05\/02\/new-tech-and-younger-faces-drws-cumberland-looks-different-its-counter-parties-say\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> sources.<\/a>","Galaxy, of which Novogratz owns just<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/2019\/01\/02\/galaxy-digital-spikes-23-after-novogratz-increases-his-stake-in-the-floundering-crypto-firm\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> shy of 80%,<\/a> is now looking to bolster its place in the market. It expanded its offering to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/2019\/06\/21\/mike-novogratzs-galaxy-digital-rolls-out-crypto-options-business-as-institutional-demand-grows\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">include<\/a> crypto options contracts last month.","The firm also hired former Coinbase OTC head Tim Plakas <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/tiny\/mike-novogratzs-galaxy-digital-snags-coinbase-otc-head\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">in May<\/a> to boost its trading efforts.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Galaxy Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"80%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"February","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Jason Leung","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Novogratz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Mike McMahon","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Galaxy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chris Ferraro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Lehman Brothers","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mike Novogratz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"David Gross","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Cumberland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bobby Cho","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"James Radecki","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tim Plakas","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Credit Suisse","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$272.6 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Coinbase OTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["CRYPTO"],"authors":["Isabel Woodford","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}