{"summary":"NASCAR takes first steps into metaverse through a new partnership with the team behind blockchain-based digital horse racing game ZED RUN.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/113691\/nascar-links-partnership-with-the-startup-behind-a-blockchain-based-digital-horse-racing-game","publishDate":"2021-08-05T15:52:08","id":2419,"type":null,"title":"NASCAR links partnership with the startup behind a blockchain-based digital horse racing game","category":["NFTS"],"content":["Can't make it to a horse race in person? Have no fear, because you could soon be able to attend one in the metaverse.","American auto racing company NASCAR has partnered with the developers behind the blockchain-based digital horse racing game ZED RUN to create a \"brand new, futuristic fandom experience,\" the Virtually Human Studio team <a href=\"https:\/\/sports.yahoo.com\/nascar-partners-zed-run-metaverse-180055877.html?guccounter=1&amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbS8&amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAAKi9zLW7uN61PhT1c3QUj8c7nmh1mZVtEjAFoiC7fEmrgW7_wjcQxn4mS0E7yr9BqPSs2UK5CUcCirpNVfMTk8N15m3KOy6wuHZMeLWiDkewAFKs9BX6VATB3vhEkA8nRJxuh5cbOJR_PwXSZYE-5_vYlj13aRJwhivFW_-HTfVC\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/a> Thursday.&nbsp;&nbsp;","The two companies are still finalizing details about distribution and sales, but to begin, VHS will work with NASCAR to create NASCAR-branded digital horses on its racing platform.&nbsp;","“Recreating what fandom means through the concept of ownership, the NASCAR and VHS partnership will lay the foundation by exploring innovation around NFTs and what it means to have skin in the game,” VHS CEO and co-founder Chris Laurent said in a statement.","According to Tim Clark, senior vice president, and chief digital officer at NASCAR, the racing company hopes to use blockchain technology as a \"launchpad\" to discover a new, \"deeply engaged\" audience.&nbsp;","\"Partnerships like the one with VHS, have the ability to revolutionize the NASCAR brand by bridging the gap between an age-old sport and innovative new technology,” Clark said.&nbsp;","Last month, VHS raised <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/112124\/a-startup-that-lets-you-race-nft-horses-has-raised-20-million-from-a16z-tcg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$20 million<\/a> in a Series A round, with participation from Andreessen Horowitz and TCG Capital Management. Its NFT gaming platform, ZEN RUN, allows users to train, breed and race digital horses. Owners can enter their horse NFTs into races via an entry fee and can also win prizes if their collectibles win on the digital track.&nbsp;","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Image courtesy ZED RUN<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Clark","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tim Clark","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"VHS","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Andreessen Horowitz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$20 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"NASCAR","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Virtually Human Studio","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chris Laurent","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"TCG Capital Management","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Saniya More","The Block"]}