{"summary":"Joseph Tsai, a crypto enthusiast and investor, will take over the reins as chair of Alibaba, the Chinese internet giant.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/235585\/crypto-curious-joseph-tsai-to-take-over-as-chair-at-alibaba","publishDate":"2023-06-20T05:16:44","id":2427,"type":null,"title":"Crypto curious Joseph Tsai to take over as chair at Alibaba","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Joseph Tsai, a crypto enthusiast and investor, will take over the reins as chair of Alibaba, the Chinese internet giant.","Alibaba Group Holding Limited <a href=\"https:\/\/www.businesswire.com\/news\/home\/20230619481579\/en\/Alibaba-Group-Announces-Chairman-and-CEO-Succession-Plan\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced earlier<\/a> today that Tsai, who is a co-founder of the company and serves currently as executive vice chairman, will succeed Daniel Zhang as chairman.","Tsai first <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/joetsai1999\/status\/1475705992964763655?s=20\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">aired his fondness for crypto<\/a> in a tweet in 2021, stating simply, “I like crypto.” He backed up his talk with an investment in FTX through his family office, Blue Pool Capital, according to a South China Morning Post <a href=\"https:\/\/www.scmp.com\/tech\/tech-trends\/article\/3206727\/ftxs-hong-kong-backers-include-blue-pool-capital-chuangs-china-capital-ausvic-pulsar-court-filing\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">report<\/a>. He has reportedly made additional investments in a number of crypto startups, including participation in web3 video platform <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/193286\/a16z-leads-6-9-million-investment-in-decentralized-video-platform-shibuya\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Shibuya's $6.9 million raise<\/a> in December 2022.","News of Tsai’s appointment comes with many speculating that China is mulling lifting crypto restrictions, after Beijing&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/232404\/beijing-web3-white-paper\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">published a whitepaper<\/a> promoting web3 as an “inevitable trend” for the future. Alibaba is a giant of e-commerce in China, with a market capitalization of $236 billion.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Beijing","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$236 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$6.9 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Joseph Tsai","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alibaba","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alibaba Group Holding Limited","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tsai","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tsai","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"South China Morning Post","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Shibuya","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"December 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Blue Pool Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Daniel Zhang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"China","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Ryan Weeks","The Block"]}