{"summary":"Two people in Estonia were arrested by the U.S. Department of Justice for a multi-company fraudulent crypto scheme worth $575 million.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/189014\/two-arrested-in-estonia-for-575-million-crypto-fraud","publishDate":"2022-11-22T05:50:29","id":243,"type":null,"title":"Two arrested in Estonia for $575 million crypto fraud","category":["LEGAL"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The U.S. Department of Justice has arrested two Estonian citizens in Tallinn, Estonia for their alleged multi-layered scheme based on shell companies used to launder fraud proceeds. The 18-count indictment <a href=\"https:\/\/www.justice.gov\/opa\/pr\/two-estonian-citizens-arrested-575-million-cryptocurrency-fraud-and-money-laundering-scheme\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">totals<\/a> $575 million.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sergei Potapenko and Ivan Turõgin, both 37, set up sham equipment-rental contracts for a crypto mining service called HashFlare and led victims to invest in a fake crypto bank called Polybius Bank which did not pay out customers’ dividends. Hundreds of thousands of people fell victim to the schemes, court documents show.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">HashFlare was active between 2015 and 2019, and allegedly resulted in proceeds worth<\/span> <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$550 million. The mining equipment apparently mined bitcoin at less than 1% of the computing power it claimed to have. Polybius was set up in 2017 and raised $25 million, which was sent to other bank accounts and crypto wallets the defendants owned.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“They tried to hide their ill-gotten gains in Estonian properties, luxury cars, and bank accounts and virtual currency wallets around the world,\" said Assistant Attorney General Kenneth A. Polite, Jr. from the Criminal Division in the Department of Justice. \"U.S. and Estonian authorities are working to seize and restrain these assets and take the profit out of these crimes.\"&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The money laundering scheme involved 75 properties, six luxury vehicles and thousands of cryptocurrency mining machines, according to the statement.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Turõgin and Potapenko were arrested on Nov. 20 and charged with “conspiracy to commit wire fraud, 16 counts of wire fraud, and one count of conspiracy to commit money laundering,” according to the Justice Department.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The FBI is currently investigating the case. If the duo is convicted, it may face a 20-year prison sentence. This will be up to a federal district court judge to rule.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2015","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Department of Justice","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Justice Department","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$550 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"FBI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S. Department of Justice","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Potapenko","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Polybius Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Criminal Division","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sergei Potapenko","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ivan Turõgin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Estonia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$25 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Nov. 20","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tallinn","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"1%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$575 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Kenneth A. Polite","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["CRIME"],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}