{"summary":"The Block&#x27;s research analyst Mike Rogers hosts a panel discussion with leaders driving the growth of stablecoins across the digital asset space.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/101823\/taking-stablecoins-mainstream-brought-to-you-by-gmo-trust-full-video","publishDate":"2021-04-15T14:25:20","id":2487,"type":null,"title":"Taking stablecoins mainstream — Brought to you by GMO-Trust | Full Video","category":["WEBINAR"],"content":["The Block’s research analyst Mike Rogers hosts a panel discussion with leaders driving the growth of stablecoins across the digital asset space.","View The Block Research’s latest report titled <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/97769\/stablecoins-bridging-the-network-gap-between-traditional-money-and-digital-value-brought-to-you-by-gmo-trust\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"nofollow noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stablecoins: Bridging the Network Gap Between Traditional Money and Digital Value<\/a>","In this event we discuss:","You can learn more about our panelists and watch the event in its entirety below:&nbsp;","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Our Panelists:<\/strong><\/span>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Edward Woodford<\/strong> – Co-founder, ZeroHash","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Samuel Lim<\/strong> – Chief Compliance Officer, Binance","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Marisa McKnight<\/strong> – Head of Product, Liquid","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ian McAfee<\/strong> – Co-founder and CEO, Shift Markets","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kurt Bierbower –<\/strong> SVP of Business Development, GMO-Trust","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"315\" src=\"https:\/\/www.youtube.com\/embed\/gJz-uEHkbFg\" title=\"YouTube video player\" width=\"560\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Network Gap Between Traditional Money and Digital Value","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"GMO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Marisa McKnight<\/strong> – Head of Product","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kurt Bierbower","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Mike Rogers","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Edward Woodford<\/strong> –","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"McAfee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Samuel Lim<\/strong> – Chief Compliance Officer","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SVP of Business Development","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sponsored","The Block"]}