{"summary":"Sony Music, whose Columbia Records label represents artists such as Adele, Lil Nas X and Harry Styles, made the filing at the end of August.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/167967\/harry-styles-and-adeles-record-label-files-trademarks-for-nft-backed-media","publishDate":"2022-09-06T07:42:28","id":2526,"type":null,"title":"Harry Styles and Adele&#x27;s record label files trademarks for NFT-backed media","category":["NFTS"],"content":["Sony Music has filed a trademark application for its Columbia Records logo to be used for NFT-backed media and music and podcast production.&nbsp;","The company, whose label represents international superstars such as Adele, Lil Nas X and Harry Styles, made the filing <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/KondoudisLaw\/status\/1567092720795095042\/photo\/1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">at the end of August<\/a>, according to a tweet from trademark attorney Mike Kondoudis.&nbsp;","The application suggests Sony is considering using NFTs as a kind of token gate to authenticate fans for downloadable audio and video recordings and for live performances — a move that would bring NFT authentication for the music industry somewhat mainstream.&nbsp;","The Block contacted Sony Music about the potential scope of the initiative but had not heard back before publication time.&nbsp;","This is not the first time Sony Music has flirted with the idea of using NFTs to further its business interests. Earlier this year the Solana-based music NFT marketplace Snowcrash announced it had partnered with both Sony and Universal Music Group. At the time, the platform said it plans to release Bob Dylan and Miles Davis NFTs later this year.&nbsp;","Sony's label RCA Records also expanded into China earlier this year. The enterprise has billed itself as a web3 venture which looks to back artists experimenting with streaming, gaming, VR, AR, NFTs and the metaverse.","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/117946\/blockchain-based-music-platform-audius-raises-5-million-from-music-industry-giants\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Former Sony ATV\/Music executive Martin Bandieralso backed<\/a> a $5 million fundraise for Audius, a blockchain-based music streaming platform with over six million monthly users.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Sony ATV\/Music","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Davis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sony","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sony Music","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Columbia Records","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Adele","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Universal Music Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bob Dylan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Harry Styles","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"RCA Records","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Martin Bandieralso","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Mike Kondoudis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"China","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$5 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Lucy Harley-McKeown","The Block"]}