{"summary":"Screenshots shared by a Facebook official show that Facebook NFTs will appear under a &#x27;digital collectibles&#x27; tab on a user&#x27;s profile. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/155340\/facebook-launches-nft-feature-for-select-group-of-us-creators","publishDate":"2022-07-01T06:35:32","id":2558,"type":null,"title":"Facebook launches NFT feature for select group of US creators","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Meta has begun the roll out of a non-fungible token (NFT) feature on Facebook, just a week after chief executive Mark Zuckerberg had <a href=\"https:\/\/www.facebook.com\/zuck\/posts\/rolling-out-more-ways-for-creators-to-make-money-on-facebook-and-instagram-and-s\/10114534084040871\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/a> the plan.&nbsp;","The feature will initially be open to a select group of US-based creators; similar to how the company <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/145758\/meta-to-start-testing-digital-collectibles-on-instagram\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">rolled out<\/a> NFTs on Instagram a month ago. Zuckerberg's Facebook post announcing the move also said the company is looking into augmented reality NFTs and 3D NFTs using the company's Spark AR software platform.&nbsp;","The news was also announced on Wednesday by Meta product manager Navdeep Singh on <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/navdeep_ua\/status\/1542291276883582979?s=20&amp;a\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Twitter<\/a>. Screenshots shared by Singh show that Facebook NFTs will appear under a 'digital collectibles' tab on a user's profile.&nbsp;","On Instagram, NFTs are backed by Ethereum and Polygon blockchains with Solana and Flow support coming soon. Third-party wallets compatible with Instagram include Rainbow, MetaMask and Trust Wallet, with Coinbase, Dapper, and Phantom coming soon. The same will be true for Facebook, said a rep from the company to The Block.","There is no timeline yet on when this will be available to users more widely, said a Facebook rep. &nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Rainbow","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Navdeep Singh","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Dapper","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Singh","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mark Zuckerberg","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Anushree Dave","The Block"]}