{"summary":"PayPal surged nearly 11% after the close after reporting transaction revenue of $6.27 billion, up 8% from the year earlier.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/161063\/paypal-pops-after-market-as-revenue-eps-beat-expectations","publishDate":"2022-08-02T16:37:12","id":2576,"type":null,"title":"PayPal pops post-market as Elliott confirms stake, revenue, EPS beat expectations","category":["CRYPTOCURRENCY"],"content":["PayPal surged nearly 13% after the close after reporting a $2 billion stake by Elliott Investment Management and transaction revenue of $6.27 billion, up 8% from the year earlier.","\"As one of PayPal's largest investors, with an approximately $2 billion investment, Elliott strongly believes in the value proposition of PayPal,\" said Jesse Cohn, managing partner at Elliott. \"Today's announcement highlights a number of steps that have been underway and are being initiated to help realize the significant value opportunity at the company.\"","Transaction revenue, which accounts for 92% of all revenue, includes fees for the purchase and sale of cryptocurrencies. The company reported total revenue of $6.8 billion, up 9% on the year, and besting the estimate by $20 million, and Non-GAAP earnings per share of $0.93, beating the estimate by $0.06, according to Seeking Alpha.","Revenue is expected to reach more than $27 billion for the year, compared with about $25 billion in 2021.","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This story has been updated to include Elliot Investment's Management's stake in PayPal, and with comments from Jesse Cohen, managing partner at Elliot.&nbsp;<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$25 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"92%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"9%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"8%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$6.27 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"PayPal","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$0.93","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Elliott","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Elliot","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Elliot Investment's Management","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Elliott","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Elliott Investment Management","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jesse Cohen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jesse Cohn","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"13%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$20 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$27 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$0.06","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$2 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$6.8 billion","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["CRYPTO","PAYMENTS"],"authors":["Christiana Loureiro","The Block"]}