{"summary":"In this episode of The Scoop, Adam Dell, Founder and CEO of Domain Money, walks through some of the fatal mistakes made by recently collapsed crypto lenders and explains what a responsible approach to portfolio management looks like in the digital asset space.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/157718\/domain-money-ceo-on-responsible-crypto-asset-management-and-where-failed-lenders-went-wrong","publishDate":"2022-07-15T09:26:26","id":2584,"type":null,"title":"Domain Money CEO on responsible crypto asset management and where failed lenders went wrong","category":["THE BLOCK"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">64<\/strong><\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 4 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block's Frank Chaparro and Adam Dell,&nbsp; founder and CEO of Domain Money.<\/i><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"b8c8d7dcdbd9cbccf8ccd0dddad4d7dbd3dbcac1c8ccd796dbd7d5\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i><\/span>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK8553552904\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">As the industry continues to cope with fallout from the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/153713\/inside-cryptos-biggest-deleveraging-event-and-the-three-arrows-capital-fallout\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">implosion<\/a> of Three Arrows Capital, July has been a brutal month for crypto lenders, with both <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/155990\/crypto-broker-voyager-digital-files-for-chapter-11-bankruptcy\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Voyager Digital<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> and <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/157647\/celsius-bankruptcy-documents-claim-1-2-billion-balance-sheet-gap\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Celsius<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> declaring bankruptcy, and other prominent lenders including Genesis, BlockFi and Blockchain.com incurring severe losses<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In the case of Celsius — which is now reporting a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/157647\/celsius-bankruptcy-documents-claim-1-2-billion-balance-sheet-gap\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$1.2 billion<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> hole<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in its balance sheet — retail investors have a long road to recovering any of the crypto they deposited in the platform.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In this episode of The Scoop, Domain Money founder and CEO Adam Dell walks through some of the fatal mistakes made by the recently collapsed crypto lenders and explains what a responsible approach to portfolio management looks like in the digital asset space.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In contrast to the way Celsius allegedly deployed users' funds into levered strategies, Dell says it is important that Domain Money remains market neutral:<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"We don't take balance sheet risk. And so many of the entities you mentioned were using their clients' funds to basically take levered positions in the market.\"<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Domain Money is also looking to differentiate itself through quality portfolio managers. Dell has brought in teams from Goldman Sachs and Bridgewater to help construct and manage portfolios in the hope that veterans from traditional finance will be able to use their experience to manage the volatility of the crypto market.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">While the contagion stemming from Three Arrows Capital and rampant global inflation have caused crypto prices to plummet, Dell says this is healthy in the long-run:&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"I'm a little bit conflicted in that I certainly want all of our investors to have positive returns in any timeframe, but I also think this is, in the long-term, a very good thing for this industry to go through to weed out the bad actors, to weed out the momentum and meme-focused investors, and have a set of investments thrive and grow over time that are solving real world problems.\"<\/span>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">During this episode, Chaparro and Dell also:<\/span><\/i>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors <em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.chainalysis.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Chainalysis<\/a>&nbsp;&amp;<\/em>&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.iwc.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC Schauffhausen<\/a><\/em><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/b>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Chainalysis<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nChainalysis is the leading blockchain data platform. We provide data, software, services, and research to government agencies, exchanges, financial institutions, and insurance and cybersecurity companies in over 60 countries. Backed by Accel, Addition, Benchmark, Coatue, Paradigm, Ribbit, and other leading firms in venture capital, Chainalysis builds trust in blockchains to promote more financial freedom with less risk. For more information, visit <a href=\"https:\/\/www.chainalysis.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">www.chainalysis.com<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About IWC Schaffhausen<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC Schaffhausen is a Swiss luxury watch manufacturer based in Schaffhausen, Switzerland. Known for its unique engineering approach to watchmaking, IWC combines the best of human craftsmanship and creativity with cutting-edge technology and processes. With collections like the Portugieser and the Pilot’s Watches, the brand covers the whole spectrum from elegant timepieces to sports watches. For more information, visit <a href=\"https:\/\/www.iwc.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC.com<\/a><\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Switzerland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coatue","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Chainalysis<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nChainalysis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Benchmark","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Three Arrows Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"IWC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chainalysis<\/a>&nbsp;&amp;<\/em>&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.iwc.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Schaffhausen","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"IWC Schaffhausen<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC Schaffhausen","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Voyager Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bridgewater","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Paradigm","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Domain Money","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Adam Dell","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Accel","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ribbit","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Goldman Sachs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dell","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1.2 billion","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["CRYPTO","FINTECH"],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}