{"summary":"Binance and Kazakhstan have formalized their shared interest in developing and regulating the national cryptoasset market.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/174399\/binance-signs-agreement-with-kazakhstan-and-plans-regional-hub","publishDate":"2022-10-03T06:53:52","id":2612,"type":null,"title":"Binance signs agreement with Kazakhstan and plans regional hub","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto exchange Binance signed an agreement with Kazakhstan’s Financial Monitoring Agency to formalize their shared interest in developing the digital asset market in the country.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The ‘memorandum of agreement’ expresses mutual support in developing cryptoasset and data circulation as well as targeting illicit trade.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance “plans to expand its Kazakhstani office”, Kazakh President Kassym-Jomart Tokayev <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.inform.kz\/en\/world-s-largest-crypto-exchange-binance-builds-a-hub-in-kazakhstan-for-the-entire-region_a3984292\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in a plenary discussion last Wednesday, explaining that the exchange plans to build a “hub for the entire region.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance received <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.binance.com\/en\/blog\/ecosystem\/binance-secures-preliminary-regulatory-approval-to-operate-in-kazakhstan-8070712715201585813\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">authorization<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to operate in the country in August from the Astana Financial Services Authority. The exchange giant also signed an <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.binance.com\/en\/blog\/ecosystem\/binance-signs-mou-with-the-ministry-of-digital-development-of-the-republic-of-kazakhstan-421499824684903899\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">agreement<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> with the Ministry of Digital Development of Kazakhstan in May when Binance CEO CZ met with President Kassym-Zhomart Tokayev and other top Kazakh officials.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The developments in Kazakhstan are part of Binance’s wider global law enforcement training program to link up local and international financial authorities to “fight together against cyber and financial crimes globally,” as CZ said in a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/cz_binance\/status\/1576864543564701696\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweet<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> announcing of the news.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The training program is already completed in France, Germany, Italy, the UK, Norway, Canada, Brazil, Paraguay and Israel, as Binance continues to seek approval and registration in countries worldwide. <\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Canada","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Norway","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ministry of Digital Development of Kazakhstan","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"France","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Brazil","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Zhomart Tokayev","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"last Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"UK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CZ","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kazakhstan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Paraguay","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Israel","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Kassym","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jomart Tokayev","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Astana Financial Services Authority","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Germany","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Kazakhstan’s Financial Monitoring Agency","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Italy","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE","CZ"],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}