{"summary":"The cash-and-stock deal is expected to be announced this week. When completed, that would make it one of the largest acquisitions in the crypto space. CoinMarketCap is the most popular crypto data aggregator, drawing 207.2 million visitors in the last six months, according to SimilarWeb.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/60371\/binance-is-set-to-acquire-coinmarketcap-the-deal-could-be-worth-as-much-as-400-million","publishDate":"2020-03-31T03:15:06","id":2630,"type":null,"title":"Binance is set to acquire CoinMarketCap; worth up to $400 million","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["Binance is in the final stages of talks to acquire CoinMarketCap, The Block has learned.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nThe crypto exchange is looking to pay as much as $400 million for the deal, people familiar with the deal told The Block. <br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nThe cash-and-stock deal is expected to be announced this week. When completed, that would make it one of the largest acquisitions in the crypto space.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nOther terms of the deal remain unclear. The Block has reached out to both Binance and CoinMarketCap for comments and will update this story should we hear back. <br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nJust earlier this year, Binance CEO Changpeng “CZ” Zhao <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/51969\/binance-ceo-says-some-major-strategic-acquisitions-are-in-the-works-for-2020\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a> that there are two acquisitions in the pipeline that he is “very excited” about. These are “major” and will have a “significant impact,” CZ said at the time. The CoinMarketCap deal could be one of those two deals.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nIt is worth noting that CoinMarketCap has not raised any external funding to date and is “entirely bootstrapped,” Carylyne Chan, chief strategy officer of CoinMarketCap, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/43460\/coinmarketcap-now-publishes-interest-rates-on-cryptocurrencies-allowing-users-to-compare-and-choose\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">told The Block<\/a> last October. “We don't plan to raise any funds soon; we can still continue bootstrapping and scaling at this point,\" Chan said at the time.","CoinMarketCap is the most popular crypto data aggregator, drawing 207.2 million visitors in the last six months, according to SimilarWeb. Binance, on the other hand, drew 113.8 million visitors in the last six months. CoinMarketCap's traffic is 80% more than that of Binance's.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nPeople familiar with the matter told The Block that CoinMarketCap's ability to drive a significant amount of traffic is one of the major reasons for the acquisition. CoinMarketCap was founded in 2013 by the anonymous Brandon Chez in Delaware, U.S.&nbsp;<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n","","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Source: SimilarWeb, The Block Research&nbsp;<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nBinance, on the other hand, remains the most visited crypto exchange with 21.3% traffic share as of March 2020. It is in a neck-and-neck competition with Coinbase, which has a share of 21%.&nbsp;<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n","","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">UPDATE<\/strong> (April 7, 2:05 AM EST): This story has been updated to include the latest data of web traffic among crypto exchanges.&nbsp;<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"80%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Delaware","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Chan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2013","content":"DATE"},{"type":"21%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"SimilarWeb","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block Research&nbsp;<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nBinance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Carylyne Chan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"March 2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance's","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$400 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"earlier this year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"April 7","content":"DATE"},{"type":"October","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Brandon Chez","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"21.3%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"CoinMarketCap","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE","CZ"],"authors":["Yogita Khatri","The Block"]}