{"summary":"The founders of defunct hedge fund Three Arrows Capital were served subpoenas on Twitter.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/199598\/three-arrows-capital-founders-subpoenaed-by-tweet","publishDate":"2023-01-05T13:09:43","id":2651,"type":null,"title":"Three Arrows Capital founders subpoenaed by tweet ","category":["LEGAL"],"content":["Founders of the failed crypto hedge fund Three Arrows Capital were served subpoenas on Twitter by the fund’s liquidators, the latest wrinkle in the firm’s unusual bankruptcy case.","<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Three Arrows Capital founders&nbsp;Kyle Davies&nbsp;and&nbsp;Zhu Su have been on the run since their billion-dollar hedge fund collapsed last year. Liquidators claim the pair have been reluctant to participate in bankruptcy proceedings, leading to the unusual <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/3ACLiq\/status\/1611018579532742657\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Twitter subpoena<\/span><\/a>.<\/span>","<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The complicated Three Arrows Capital bankruptcy proceedings are playing out in the United States, Singapore and the British Virgin Islands. The fund is being liquidated by financial advisory firm Teneo, which asked a&nbsp;Southern District of New York&nbsp;court for the authority to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/177798\/three-arrows-capital-liquidators-seek-subpoenas-amid-reported-regulatory-scrutiny\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">subpoena<\/span><\/a> the founders via Twitter and email last year.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span><\/span>","“We remain focused on diligently advancing the liquidation process for Three Arrows Capital Limited in order to maximize asset recoveries on behalf of creditors,” the joint liquidators said in a statement. “The founders have unfortunately resisted cooperating in these efforts, and as such, we have received authority from courts in both the US and Singapore to serve them targeted and comprehensive discovery demands through email and their frequently-used Twitter accounts.”","Davies’ subpoena was granted by a U.S. court, while a dual subpoena was granted by a Singapore court.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","The subpoenas order the founders to provide information to the firm’s liquidators later this month. Liquidators are seeking documentation of the firm’s accounts, digital assets and any books, papers or records pertaining to the company. The subpoena also seeks information on Starry Night Capital and curator Vincent Van Dough, among other entities.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Kyle Davies","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Starry Night Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Three Arrows Capital Limited","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Vincent Van Dough","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"liquidators later this month","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Teneo","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"British Virgin Islands","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"United States","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Stephanie Murray","The Block"]}