{"summary":"Laser Digital, the crypto subsidiary of Japanese financial services giant Nomura, has invested in Webn to bring more crypto-related services to financial institutions.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/240248\/alan-howard-backed-web3-incubator-gets-fresh-funds-from-nomuras-laser-digital","publishDate":"2023-07-19T03:49:52","id":2660,"type":null,"title":"Alan Howard-backed web3 incubator gets fresh funds from Nomura’s Laser Digital","category":["VENTURE CAPITAL"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Laser Digital, the crypto subsidiary of Japanese financial services giant Nomura, has invested in <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Web<\/span><sup data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">n<\/span><\/sup><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, an incubator <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/146212\/alan-howard-crypto-interview\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">backed by Alan Howard<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, as they seek to bring more cryptocurrency-related services to established financial institutions.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">As part of the partnership, Jez Mohideen, chief executive officer of Laser Digital, will <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">join the board of Web<sup data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">n<\/sup><\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;as a non-executive director, the company said in an announcement today. Laser Digital and Web<sup data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">n<\/sup><\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;did not disclose the size of the investment.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Established in late 2021, Web<sup data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">n<\/sup><\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;has incubated a number of web3 businesses, including cryptography research house Geometry, DeFi protocol Trufin and non-custodial staking provider Twinstake.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Himanshu Panwar, CEO of Web<sup data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">n<\/sup><\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;Group UK, told The Block in an exclusive interview that the company looks to incubate startups with a focus on bringing crypto technologies to traditional financial services.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Web<sup data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">n<\/sup> Group, with a team of 25, aims to “bridge the gap between large financial institutions and the web3 domain,” Panwar said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“The quality of the conversation we're having with institutional counterparties is increasing both in terms of frequency and the depth of the conversation,” said Olivier Dang, head of ventures at Laser Digital.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Many institutions are showing interest in asset tokenization, according to Dang.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Outside the U.S., we see definitely increasing interest from institutions looking to enter into the asset class, not necessarily just about bitcoin and ether, but also with regards to asset tokenization,” he said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">When it comes to incubation scope, Panwar said that Web<sup data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">n<\/sup><\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> only builds “as many businesses as we can do justice to.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We set a realistic target for ourselves to incubate and build out two to three new businesses every calendar year, roughly,” Panwar added.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Jez Mohideen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Himanshu Panwar","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Laser Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Web<sup data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">n<\/sup><\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;Group UK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nomura","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alan Howard","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"n<\/sup> Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Olivier Dang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Panwar","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["STARTUP ACCELERATORS"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}