{"summary":"Meta has partnered with digital fashion company DressX to launch items on Meta&#x27;s Avatar Store.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/158569\/meta-partners-with-digital-fashion-startup-dressx-to-launch-virtual-clothes","publishDate":"2022-07-19T17:05:48","id":2695,"type":null,"title":"Meta partners with digital fashion startup DressX to launch virtual clothes","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Meta is partnering with digital fashion startup DressX to provide new avatar fashion looks on Meta's Avatar Store.","DressX outfits will be available starting July 19, and users can purchase and wear them on avatars across Meta platforms, including Messenger, Facebook, and Instagram and VR headset Quest.&nbsp;","The startup is based in Los Angeles and launched in 2020 with a mission to offer digital-only collections from brands and 3D designers. According to its Crunchbase profile, the company has raised $3.3 million in <a href=\"https:\/\/www.crunchbase.com\/organization\/dressx\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">funding<\/a> and was the first digital fashion brand to launch a collection on Roblox. It has also previously worked with H&amp;M to launch virtual fashion for the brand and was a finalist for LVMH's 2022 Innovation Award.","Most recently, the brand worked with Jason Wu to <a href=\"https:\/\/nft.dressx.com\/marketplace\/nft\/119\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">create and auction off a digital version<\/a> of Michelle Obama's 2009 Inaugural Ball gown.&nbsp;","Fashion and luxury brands are experimenting with ways to increase their presence in virtual worlds, in order to get a share of what analysts at Morgan Stanley have predicted to be a $50 billion market for luxury brands. Digital fashion creators and enthusiasts <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/157186\/burberry-launches-virtual-handbags\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">say<\/a> that it provides a form of self-expression and individuality that otherwise gets lost in online communication.&nbsp;","DressX joins a list of other big-name brands that have added virtual clothes in Meta's marketplace, including Balenciaga, Prada, and Thom Browne, as The Block <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/152808\/meta-partners-with-balenciaga-prada-and-tom-brown-and-launches-digital-fashion-marketplace\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">covered<\/a>&nbsp;last month.","Outfits cost anywhere between $2.99 to $8.99. The marketplace, which was first introduced in select countries including Canada, the US, Mexico, and Thailand, will be introduced in other countries in the future.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$3.3 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Canada","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Thom Browne","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$8.99","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Meta","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Los Angeles","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"LVMH","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mexico","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Balenciaga","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2009","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$50 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Meta","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$2.99","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Thailand","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Jason Wu","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Michelle Obama","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"July 19","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Prada","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Morgan Stanley","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"H&amp;M","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Anushree Dave","The Block"]}