{"summary":"Ten months after Voyager Digital filed for bankruptcy protection, customers could recover some cash and crypto.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/231248\/voyager-liquidation-june","publishDate":"2023-05-17T17:45:53","id":2709,"type":null,"title":"Voyager liquidation could start Friday","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Failed crypto lender Voyager Digital could start liquidating on Friday, aiming to begin returning cash and crypto to customers by June 1.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","A bankruptcy court judge approved Voyager’s liquidation procedures during a hearing on Wednesday, 10 months after <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/155990\/crypto-broker-voyager-digital-files-for-chapter-11-bankruptcy\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Voyager filed for bankruptcy protection<\/a> in the U.S. Bankruptcy Court for the Southern District of New York<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","“We are working with Voyager to go effective under the plan as soon as possible (as early as this Friday),” the Voyager Official Committee of Unsecured Creditors <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/VoyagerUCC\/status\/1658942955875442689\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said on Twitter<\/span><\/a>. “We are still working towards making initial distributions available no later than June 1.”<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","Voyager’s liquidation comes after <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/228240\/binance-voyager-deal-bankruptcy\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance.US pulled out of a court-approved deal to buy<\/span><\/a> the firm's assets last month. <span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The plan included a liquidation \"toggle\" option in the event that Binance.US walked away, which Voyager then initiated.<\/span>&nbsp;The deal had faced <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/217075\/sec-staff-believe-binance-us-is-operating-an-unregistered-securities-exchange\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">government scrutiny.<\/a> Binance.US blamed the U.S. regulatory environment when it terminated the plan.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","Customers are expected to initially recover nearly 36% of their claim amounts, <a href=\"https:\/\/cases.stretto.com\/voyager\/faqs\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">according to Voyager<\/span><\/a>, although that percentage could eventually increase depending on the success of a claim dispute between Voyager and the failed crypto behemoth FTX. Voyager customers can receive their recoveries in cash, supported coins, or via USDC for unsupported coins and Voyager’s VGX token.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S. Bankruptcy Court","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"June 1","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Southern District of New York","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Voyager","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Voyager","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"36%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"USDC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"last month","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Voyager Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Voyager Official Committee of Unsecured Creditors","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Stephanie Murray","The Block"]}