{"summary":"Other blockchains are advertising themselves to developers closing their shops on Terra after its collapse.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/147037\/polygon-juno-and-fantom-blockchains-try-to-lure-terras-projects","publishDate":"2022-05-16T08:16:09","id":2727,"type":null,"title":"Polygon, Juno and Fantom blockchains try to lure Terra&#x27;s projects","category":["CRYPTO ECOSYSTEMS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Polygon, Juno and Fantom blockchains are trying to atract Terra-based projects, following the collapse of its ecosystem.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","Last week, the collapse of the TerraUSD (UST) stablecoin led to a knock-on effect of a 99.9% price crash for its related token Luna (LUNA). During the incident, the network was halted twice to stem the bleeding and while it has been restarted, several on-chain functions are still disabled. <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The incident led to the total value of assets on Terra falling from over $31 billion to around $400 million, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/defillama.com\/chain\/Terra\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">according<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to DeFiLlama. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Facing a major liquidity crunch, some developers behind Terra-hosted applications have <\/span>packed their bags for other chains.&nbsp;<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Among those who decided to close down their Terra protocols included various NFT and DeFi-based projects like <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/teamkujira.medium.com\/the-future-of-kujira-485d43c4729c\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kujira<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,<\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/staderlabs\/status\/1525193382599208960\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Stader Labs<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, LunaBulls, LunarFlip, and Hero NFT.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In response to this migration, blockchain teams are making bids to attract these developers by offering them supportive capital and other resources.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ryan Wyatt, CEO of Polygon Studios — the NFT, gaming, and metaverse arm of Polygon — <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/Fwiz\/status\/1525887462093910016\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/span><\/a> on Twitter that <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">his team was closely collaborating with Terra-based projects to help them migrate to its chain.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We will be putting capital and resources against these migrations to welcome the developers and their respective communities to our platform,” Wyatt stated.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Polygon wasn’t the only blockchain that appealed to developers building products in the Terra ecosystem.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Juno, an interoperability-focused smart contract network, introduced a new governance <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.mintscan.io\/juno\/proposals\/23\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">proposal<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> asking approval for incentives for 1 million JUNO tokens ($7 million) for Terra projects who wish to move their apps. Juno's proposal notified that several Terra projects had expressed interest in migrating to Juno Network. Juno’s blockchain shares similarity with Terra’s technical architecture as both of them rely on the Cosmos SDK (the code used by projects in the Cosmos ecosystem).&nbsp;<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Fantom blockchain also <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/FantomFDN\/status\/1525914276157964288\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/a> that it is offering grants, marketing and ecosystem connections to Terra projects looking for a new blockchain.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nBeyond this, representatives and founders from other blockchains — Regen Network, FetchAI, <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/StargazeZone\/status\/1525969217874452481\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stargaze<\/a> and <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/InjectiveLabs\/status\/1524955935164116993\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Injective Protocol<\/a> — have also encouraged migrating Terra-based projects to consider their chains.<\/span>","<i data-stringify-type=\"italic\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">For more breaking stories like this, make sure to follow The Block on&nbsp;<\/i><i data-stringify-type=\"italic\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a class=\"c-link\" tabindex=\"-1\" href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/TheBlock__\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-stringify-link=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/TheBlock__\" data-sk=\"tooltip_parent\" data-remove-tab-index=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Twitter<\/a><\/i><i data-stringify-type=\"italic\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/i>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"DeFiLlama","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$31 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"1 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ryan Wyatt","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$7 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Cosmos SDK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Regen Network","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"99.9%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Hero NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fantom","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cosmos","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Wyatt","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$400 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Terra","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Terra","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Juno Network","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UST","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Vishal Chawla","The Block"]}