{"summary":"Originally built on Solana, the move will come with new features for the Tiny Colony ecosystem.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/201445\/tiny-colony-game-bids-farewell-to-solana-will-migrate-to-immutablex","publishDate":"2023-01-13T09:00:50","id":274,"type":null,"title":"Tiny Colony game bids farewell to Solana, will migrate to ImmutableX","category":["METAVERSE & NFT"],"content":["Construction and management simulation game Tiny Colony will migrate to ImmutableX.","Originally built on Solana, the move will come with new features for the Tiny Colony ecosystem, dubbed \"the Tinyverse,\" including a built-in crypto wallet and the option to pay for in-game assets in fiat.&nbsp;","It will join the Australian-based Immutable's roster of games including Gods Unchained, Illuvium, Guild of Guardians and Ember Swords.","Tiny Colony is not the only project that’s announced plans to leave Solana of late. In December, two of the largest NFT projects on Solana, DeGods and y00ts — both the product of NFT creator Rohun Vora, who goes by the pseudonym “Frank DeGods” — <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/197892\/top-solana-nft-projects-degods-y00ts-are-headed-to-ethereum-and-polygon\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a> they would bridge to Ethereum and Polygon this year.","Hit by an exploit and the collapse of FTX last year — FTX's former CEO Sam Bankman-Fried had been a vocal supporter of Solana — Solana has also had to contend with increasing competition among chains for projects.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Share of games by blockchain as of Nov. 30, 2022. Source: <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockresearch.com\/2022-review-of-web3-gaming-194089\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block Research<\/a><\/span>","New gaming-focused chains have been trying to attract new projects from other chains with grants and promises of greater support. Among them, South Korean blockchain Klaytn successfully <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/164497\/defi-kingdoms-to-leave-harmony-for-metaverse-focused-blockchain\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">lured Defi Kingdoms away<\/a> from Harmony last year.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"fiat","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frank DeGods” —","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Illuvium","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tiny Colony","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"December","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Rohun Vora","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Colony","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Guild of Guardians","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Solana — Solana","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nov. 30, 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ember Swords","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Solana","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Callan Quinn","The Block"]}