{"summary":"A Treasury undersecretary is slated to guide Congress through the department&#x27;s reasoning on stablecoins in the next two weeks.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/132827\/house-and-senate-hearings-on-stablecoins-will-spotlight-official-behind-treasury-report-sources","publishDate":"2022-02-02T15:47:26","id":2750,"type":null,"title":"House and Senate hearings on stablecoins will spotlight official behind Treasury report: sources","category":["CONGRESS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Hearings on stablecoins before both the House and Senate in the next two weeks are scheduled to feature just one witness: The Treasury official spearheading recent work on stablecoins, sources tell The Block.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Nellie Liang, the Treasury’s undersecretary for domestic finance, is slated to appear before the House Financial Services Committee on February 8 and before the Senate Banking Committee will host Liang on February 15, according to four staffers and sources with knowledge of the matter. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In both cases, Liang is likely to be the sole witness, though sources indicate that the plan for the Senate hearing remains more malleable.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Neither committee has published their witness lists as of press time. The Financial Services Committee <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/financialservices.house.gov\/events\/eventsingle.aspx?EventID=409026\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">only<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> includes the hearing title: “Digital Assets and the Future of Finance: The President’s Working Group on Financial Markets’ Report on Stablecoins.”&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Banking Committee, meanwhile, had not yet added the hearing to its <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.banking.senate.gov\/hearings\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">schedule<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, only including it in an email to press that mentions a hearing called “Examining the President’s Working Group on Financial Markets Report on Stablecoins.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In both cases, the committees are planning on a deep dive into the report itself. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">While the crypto industry may be displeased with not having a seat at the table, they have been at a number of other recent hearings, including <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/127515\/senate-hearing-on-stablecoins-forecasts-new-regulations-but-from-where\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">another focused on stablecoins<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> before the Banking Committee in December.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Liang’s centrality to the conversation makes sense. The President’s Working Group is a joint effort involving the Federal Reserve, the Securities and Exchange Commission and the Commodity Futures Trading Commission. However, the Treasury Secretary — currently Janet Yellen — chairs the President's Working Group (PWG).&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Given that the PWG’s stablecoin concerns focused on prudential risk — specifically, whether these tokens are verifiably backed by appropriate funding — Yellen delegated the report to Liang.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Beyond summarizing the stablecoin market for policymakers, the <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/122890\/us-treasury-releases-long-awaited-report-on-stablecoin-risk-features-request-for-new-laws\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">report made recommendations<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> for more transparency in stablecoin reserves and redemption practices. Most controversially, the PWG report advised Congress to pass new law limiting stablecoin issuance to insured depository institutions. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">That effectively limits the field to banks, though stablecoin issuer Circle has said it is seeking that registration while also denying that it should be required of future issuers.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Limiting issuance has proved controversial with lawmakers on both sides of the aisle, as it seems to lock in incumbents, whether they be established crypto firms like Circle or traditional giants of finance like JPMorgan Chase, and lock out potential newcomers. The Treasury has, however, seemed to maintain its support for the restriction, a push that Liang is still spearheading.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The report subsequently leveled the threat of action by the Financial Stability Oversight Council in the absence of new legislation on stablecoins. However, speaking with <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.politico.com\/news\/2021\/11\/17\/treasury-undersecretary-nellie-liang-522884\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Politico’s Victoria Guida<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> shortly after the report’s November release, Liang said “in the absence of legislation, FSOC can try to take some actions. But it’s not a full substitute.”<\/span>","The Treasury's press office did not respond to a request for comment as of publication time.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Nellie Liang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"February 15","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Federal Reserve","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Financial Services Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Banking Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Janet Yellen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Working Group (PWG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Liang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"President’s Working Group on Financial Markets Report","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"PWG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Senate Banking Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"House Financial Services Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Future of Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Yellen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Financial Stability Oversight Council","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Working Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Congress","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"December","content":"DATE"},{"type":"House","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Working Group on Financial Markets","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Politico’s Victoria Guida","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"February 8","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Commodity Futures Trading Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Senate","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["JANET YELLEN","TRADFI BANKS"],"authors":["Kollen Post","The Block"]}