{"summary":"The Block spoke with FBI Special Agent Vicki Anderson-Gregg to learn more about Cuyahoga County&#x27;s efforts to prevent financial crime victims from sending bitcoins to scammers.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/103467\/fbi-cleveland-ohio-scams-bitcoin-atms","publishDate":"2021-04-30T16:40:36","id":2767,"type":null,"title":"FBI aids Ohio county to help stop scam victims from sending money via bitcoin ATMs","category":["HACKS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The number of scams that involve would-be victims buying bitcoin has risen high enough in Cleveland’s <\/span><a href=\"http:\/\/executive.cuyahogacounty.us\/en-US\/Bitcoin-ATM-Scams.aspx\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Cuyahoga County<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that the Federal Bureau of Investigations (FBI) has gotten involved.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Cuyahoga County Department of Consumer Affairs teamed up with the FBI to place <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/ReporterHannah\/status\/1387498711777959947\/photo\/1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">signs<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> around Bitcoin ATMs warning people about possible scams, such as someone claiming to need a bitcoin for an IRS payment, utility bills, or a law enforcement investigation.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We have a very active financial crimes unit in Cleveland,” said Vicki Anderson-Gregg, Special Agent for the Cleveland Division of the FBI. “We joined a partnership with the County Scam Squad to put out this alert.”&nbsp;<\/span>","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.cleveland19.com\/2021\/04\/28\/scam-squad-puts-up-scam-warning-signs-bitcoin-atm-machines-across-cuyahoga-county\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Local reporting in Cleveland<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> shows that, in one instance, a scammer pretended to be a victim’s son in need of bail money to pressure the victim into sending $9,000 in Bitcoin. But an observant clerk halted the situation before a transaction could take place. In another case, the scammer feigned being a Social Security Administration representative and claimed the victim's Social Security number was involved in drug trafficking, money laundering, or other illicit activity. The victim would then be urged to pay the scammer through a Bitcoin ATM to \"resolve\" the situation.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">There are 212 Bitcoin ATMs in Cleveland, Ohio, according to the Bitcoin ATM tracking website <a href=\"https:\/\/coinatmradar.com\/city\/210\/bitcoin-atm-cleveland\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CoinATMRadar<\/a>. However, there are no exact number of crimes that have taken place to date that involve the use of a Bitcoin ATM.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“It is really difficult to capture numbers in regards to these types of scams, because people are embarrassed that they fell for it and don't report it,” the Special Agent told The Block. “We think it is much more significant than actually reported.”&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">While the statistics on Bitcoin ATM crime rates are sparse, the <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.ic3.gov\/Media\/PDF\/AnnualReport\/2020_IC3Report.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">2020 FBI Internet Crime Complaint Center (IC3) Internet Crime Report<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> shows that there were 35,229 victims of virtual currency-related crime last year. The Cuyahoga County and FBI effort to educate people on scams and Bitcoin ATMs in an attempt to lower this number.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We really want to get the word out so that people are not victims — it is extremely difficult, pretty much impossible, to retrieve the money once they have sent it,” Anderson-Gregg said.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Should someone fall victim to a financial scam the Special Agent advised they fill out an <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.ic3.gov\/Home\/ComplaintChoice\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IC3 intake form<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. “Similar scams are grouped together and disseminated to the appropriate field office if it meets our threshold,” adds Anderson-Gregg. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">One bad actor usually scams multiple people and can face charges of wire fraud, mail fraud, and “the typical white collar\/financial crime charges\" if they're caught, according to Anderson-Gregg.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Social Security Administration","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Anderson","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bitcoin ATM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ohio","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"FBI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"IRS","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$9,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Cleveland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Cuyahoga County","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"County Scam Squad","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cuyahoga County Department of Consumer Affairs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Vicki Anderson","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Federal Bureau of Investigations (FBI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gregg","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}