{"summary":"Grayscale Investments, a crypto asset management company, is venturing into the crypto indices business with indices provider FTSE Russell.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/259073\/grayscale-launches-new-crypto-indices-product-for-the-next-bull-run","publishDate":"2023-10-24T08:30:03","id":2832,"type":null,"title":"Grayscale launches crypto indices product with FTSE Russell","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Grayscale Investments, a crypto asset management company, is venturing into the crypto indices business together with the London-based indices provider FTSE Russell, a London Stock Exchange subsidiary.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">They will join forces to offer crypto-curious investors a product called Crypto Sector Index Series, the firms announced Tuesday morning. It will include several indices tracking the prices of various buckets of digital assets according to their use cases.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The groups will include: cryptocurrencies that serve as a medium of exchange of store of value (like bitcoin, litecoin), smart contract projects (like ether, solana, polygon), tokens representing financial services (uniswap, compound, curve), coins representing art, gaming and media assets (NFT projects) and projects oriented on real-life applications (chainlink, filecoin and others), according to the announcement.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">To weigh assets inside each bucket against each other, the indices will use a square root of each cryptocurrency market capitalization, said Grayscale’s director of ETFs Inkoo Kang: this way, the most capitalized ones, like bitcoin, will not have an outsized effect on the whole group, and investors will be able to get a more diverse exposure.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Last week, New York Attorney General Letitia James <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/258365\/nyag-files-complaint-against-gemini-genesis-dcg-michael-moro-and-barry-silbert-over-earn-product-and-covering-up-1-billion-hole\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filed a complaint<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> against the Grayscale parent company DCG, its other subsidiary Genesis, crypto exchange Gemini, former Genesis CEO Michael Moro and DCG CEO Barry Silbert.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The NYAG said Gemini and Genesis misled the public about its joint product Earn, for which Gemini lent users’ funds to Genesis. Genesis then lent those funds out to counterparties including the failed crypto trading funds Three Arrows Capital and Alameda Research. Both companies were also <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/202293\/sec-charges-over-gemini-genesis-earn-program-latest-shot-at-crypto-lending\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">sued<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> by the SEC for the Earn product in January and have been <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/237642\/geminis-winklevoss-demands-1-47-billion-payment-from-dcg-in-final-offer\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">fighting<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> with each other over responsibility for the lost user funds.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"DCG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Michael Moro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gemini","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Letitia James","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NYAG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gemini","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Grayscale Investments","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Barry Silbert","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"London Stock Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"morning","content":"TIME"},{"type":"London","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Genesis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTSE Russell","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["ASSETS"],"authors":["Anna Baydakova","The Block"]}