{"summary":"OneCoin&#x27;s head of legal pleaded guilty to charges after prosecutors said she participated in a scheme that caused investors to lose billions. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/262478\/onecoin-legal-chief-pleads-guilty-to-money-laundering-and-wire-fraud-doj","publishDate":"2023-11-09T12:15:20","id":2880,"type":null,"title":"OneCoin legal chief pleads guilty to money laundering and wire fraud: DOJ","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">OneCoin's head of legal and compliance pleaded guilty to wire fraud and money laundering charges on Thursday after prosecutors said she participated in a scheme that caused investors to lose billions.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Irina Dilkinska, 42 of Bulgaria, could face up to 10 years in prison for her participation in what prosecutors are calling a crypto pyramid scheme, according to a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.justice.gov\/usao-sdny\/pr\/head-legal-and-compliance-multibillion-dollar-cryptocurrency-pyramid-scheme-onecoin\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">statement<\/span><\/a> from the U.S. Attorney's Office for the Southern District of New York.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"As OneCoin's so-called 'Head of Legal and Compliance' Irina Dilkinska accomplished the exact opposite goal of her position,\" said U.S. Attorney Damian Williams. \"As she has now admitted, Dilkinska facilitated the laundering of millions of dollars of illicit profits OneCoin accrued through its multi-level-marketing scheme. The dedicated prosecutors of this Office and our law enforcement partners will continue to pursue this important case until every defendant is brought to justice.\"<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Dilkinska's guilty plea comes a few months after OneCoin founder<\/span> <span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Karl Sebastian Greenwood, 46, was <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/250564\/one-coin-co-founder-sentenced-to-20-years-and-fined-300-million\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">sentenced<\/span><\/a> to 20 years in prison after prosecutors<\/span><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> accused him of cheating 3.5 million investors and using the money for five-star resorts, a private plane and a yacht. Greenwood had previously pleaded <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/195825\/onecoin-co-founder-karl-sebastian-greenwood-pleads-guilty-doj\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">guilty<\/span><\/a> to wire fraud and money laundering.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Dilkinska's sentencing is scheduled for Feb. 14, 2024.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Greenwood co-founded OneCoin in 2014 with the so-called Crypto Queen-turned-fugitive Ruja Ignatova. Ignatova faces similar charges to Greenwood, but has not been seen since 2017 when she took a flight to Greece. She was added to the FBI’s Top Ten Most Wanted List in June 2022, the attorney's office said previously.<\/span>","<span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">On Thursday, prosecutors asked people to reach out with information about Ignatova's whereabouts. The FBI is offering a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.fbi.gov\/wanted\/topten\/ruja-ignatova\/@@download.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s5\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reward<\/span><\/a> of up to $250,000 for information leading to her arrest.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2014","content":"DATE"},{"type":"June 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$250,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Greece","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bulgaria","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Irina Dilkinska","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Damian Williams","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Greenwood","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FBI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Crypto Queen","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ignatova","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"millions of dollars","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Karl Sebastian Greenwood","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"the Southern District of New York","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dilkinska","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Feb. 14, 2024","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["CRIME"],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}