{"summary":"The 2022 Consensus festival is a showcase and celebration of all that crypto has to offer. Thousands of the world&#x27;s brightest minds and impactful voices will take over Austin, Texas, June 9-12. Expect to see events and parties in the days before and after!","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/149606\/consensus-2022-the-festival-for-the-decentralized-world-is-happening-in-austin-june-9-12","publishDate":"2022-06-01T09:00:38","id":2886,"type":null,"title":"Consensus 2022 - The Festival For the Decentralized World Is Happening in Austin, June 9-12","category":["SPONSORED"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The 2022 Consensus festival is a showcase and celebration of all that crypto has to offer. Thousands of the world's brightest minds and impactful voices will take over Austin, Texas, June 9-12. Expect to see events and parties in the days before and after!&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Featuring speakers including Sam Bankman-Fried, Changpeng Zhao, Edward Snowden, Punk 6529 and many more, Consensus will ignite hard-hitting conversations and spark critical debates on how these technologies are reshaping the world.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">See Web 3 ecosystems come to life and immerse yourself in all that blockchain technology has to offer at dedicated venues for decentralized autonomous organizations (DAO), developers, non-fungible tokens (NFT), the metaverse, sports, finance, talent recruitment and more.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This festival will cover all sides of blockchain, crypto, Web 3 and the metaverse. Hosted by CoinDesk, Consensus is one of the largest, and longest-running crypto festivals.&nbsp;<\/span>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/consensus2022\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Use code THEBLOCK for 20% off your pass<\/a>! Ticket prices increase on June 8.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This post is commissioned by CoinDesk<\/i><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;and does not serve as a testimonial or endorsement by The Block. This post is for informational purposes only and should not be relied upon as a basis for investment, tax, legal or other advice. You should conduct your own research and consult independent counsel and advisors on the matters discussed within this post. Past performance of any asset is not indicative of future results.<\/i><\/span>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/strong>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Edward Snowden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Austin","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"June 9","content":"DATE"},{"type":"12","content":"DATE"},{"type":"20%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"June 8","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Punk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CoinDesk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Changpeng Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Texas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sponsored","The Block"]}