{"summary":"Xterio and XPLA build out the library of games built on the XPLA mainnet through this partnership. XPLA was a prior investor in Xterio.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/173251\/game-developer-xterio-partners-with-blockchain-gaming-platform-xpla","publishDate":"2022-09-28T08:00:02","id":2902,"type":null,"title":"Game developer Xterio partners with blockchain gaming platform XPLA","category":["GAMING AND METAVERSE"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Xterio, a game development firm valued at $300 million, has partnered with the blockchain gaming platform XPLA.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">XPLA is operated by the South Korean gaming studio Com2Us and was a prior investor in Xterio’s <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/166447\/web3-game-developer-xterio-raises-40-million-in-saft-sale\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$40 million<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> raise via a SAFT sale. Through this partnership, Xterio and XPLA plan to bolster their offerings of blockchain-based games built on XPLA.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In addition, XPLA now has access to Xterio’s exclusive relationship with the mobile and AAA Swiss game developer FunPlus, which also has participated in Xterio’s SAFT sale.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Our partnership with Xterio continues the development of XPLA and will bring a new element of entertainment for our users to enjoy,” said Kyu Lee, president of Com2Us, in a press release.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Xterio’s SAFT sale occurred on Aug. 30, 2022. It was co-led by FunPlus, Makers Fund, FTX Ventures and XPLA, with additional participation from Animoca Brands, HashKey, Foresight Ventures, Infinity Ventures Crypto and Matrix Partners, The Block previously reported. <\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Xterio","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Animoca Brands","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Matrix Partners","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kyu Lee","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$40 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$300 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Aug. 30, 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Foresight Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"XPLA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Infinity Ventures Crypto","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}