{"summary":"The London Stock Exchange has been exploring the potential for using blockchain to improve the trading process of traditional assets, its executive said.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/248920\/lse-group-looks-to-build-blockchain-powered-trading-venue-financial-times","publishDate":"2023-09-04T02:18:42","id":2913,"type":null,"title":"LSE Group looks to build blockchain-powered trading venue: Financial Times","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The London Stock Exchange Group is doubling down on its plan to develop a blockchain-powered trading venue, a company executive <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.ft.com\/content\/ce177de8-2828-4fe2-827f-1c25dcbc99ff\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">told the Financial Times<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Murray Roos, head of capital markets at the LSE Group, told the UK media outlet that it has asked Julia Hoggett, head of the London Stock Exchange, to lead the project.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Roos said that the company has been exploring the potential of blockchain but made it clear that the exchange group was not building anything that would support crypto assets.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“The idea is to use digital technology to make a process that is slicker, smoother, cheaper and more transparent... and to have it regulated,” Roos continued, adding that the initiative aims to improve the trading process for traditional assets.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The LSE is far from the only traditional financial markets operator exploring potential use cases for blockchain technology.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BlackRock CEO Larry Fink<\/span> <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/220498\/blackrock-larry-fink-digital-assets-letter\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said in March, in a letter to shareholders,<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that the tokenization of asset classes could offer the prospect of driving efficiencies in capital markets, \"shortening value chains and improving cost and access for investors.\"&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In July, the Bank for International Settlements said in a report that the <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/239208\/bis-slams-crypto-in-new-report-says-reality-doesnt-live-up-to-decentralized-vision\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tokenization of claims on real-world assets<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> is one way traditional finance and crypto could work together. The organization added that this could result in the growth of crypto itself \"as new money gets channeled into such tokenized assets.\"<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Julia Hoggett","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BlackRock","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"London Stock Exchange Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Larry Fink","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bank for International Settlements","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Roos","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"London Stock Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Murray Roos","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Financial Times","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"LSE Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"LSE","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["FINTECH"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}