{"summary":"Each pack of Solana Summer Shandy will be redeemable via the Solana-based NFT from Monday. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/166199\/barreldao-sells-out-nft-linked-solana-summer-shandy-beer","publishDate":"2022-08-28T11:34:56","id":2930,"type":null,"title":"BarrelDAO sells out NFT-linked Solana Summer Shandy beer","category":["NFTS"],"content":["Brewery and distillery-focused DAO barrelDAO launched a collection of non-fungible tokens (NFTs) on Friday redeemable for a limited edition Solana-themed beer — and its already sold out.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","The 333 NFTs sold for 1.35 SOL (about $45) each. Each resembles a receipt entitling the owner to a 16-pack of Solana Summer Shandy. However, 17 are currently listed on Magic Eden with a floor price of 2.49 SOL ($79.61).","Each NFT will be redeemable for the beer — which is not an official product of Solana Labs — from Monday.","During the creation process, the company said 20 community members served as taste testers for the formulation of the final project, ultimately coming up with a 4% ABV lemonade shandy.","NFT artist Mark Lauthier designed the artwork for the can. Its design features NFT projects including DeGods, Degenerate Ape Academy, Okay Bears, Solana Monkey Business, Thugbirdz, Cets on Creck, Catalina Whale Mixer and John Lê’s “The First Edition.”","Co-founder and CEO of Barrel Labs, Dave Goldman, said that about 20 of the NFT avatars featured in the designs are owned by barrelDAO. The others were made available for use via a licensing agreement with the original owners of the NFTs.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"John Lê","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$45","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Dave Goldman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"4%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Solana Monkey Business","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Barrel Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Okay Bears","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Solana Summer Shandy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$79.61","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Degenerate Ape Academy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Catalina Whale Mixer","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Solana Labs —","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thugbirdz","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Mark Lauthier","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Magic Eden","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["SOLANA"],"authors":["Callan Quinn","The Block"]}