{"summary":"In this episode of The Scoop, Brevan Howard’s Co-Heads of Ventures Peter Johnson and Colleen Sullivan share what types of projects they are looking to invest in, as well as what segments of the crypto market they believe are seeing the most interest from existing brands.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/176302\/crypto-adoption-is-seeing-brands-like-gucci-take-center-stage-say-co-heads-of-brevan-howard-digital","publishDate":"2022-10-12T05:00:42","id":2947,"type":null,"title":"Crypto adoption is seeing brands like Gucci take center stage, say co-heads of Brevan Howard Digital","category":["VENTURE CAPITAL"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 98<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 4 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro and Brevan Howard Co-Heads of Ventures Peter Johnson and Colleen Sullivan.<\/strong><\/i><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"92e2fdf6f1f3e1e6d2e6faf7f0fefdf1f9f1e0ebe2e6fdbcf1fdff\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK4033729035\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/i><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In August, it was <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/161633\/brevan-howard-raises-more-than-1-billion-for-crypto-fund-blockworks\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that asset management firm Brevan Howard raised over $1 billion to invest in the crypto industry.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In this episode of The Scoop, Brevan Howard’s Co-Heads of Ventures Peter Johnson and Colleen Sullivan break down their investment thesis and explain what segments of the crypto market they believe are seeing the most interest from existing brands.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">While traditional financial institutions are slowly moving their way into the crypto ecosystem, Sullivan points out that many traditional brands have already fully entered crypto via NFTs, metaverse experiences, and gaming:<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Look at Goldman, JPMorgan, Citi, they're all involved in crypto to a certain extent — not to the degree we would have thought — but the institutions that are here are the Gucci's, the Nike's, the Tiffany's, the Dolce and Gabbana, Balmain, Balenciaga.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Blockchain gaming is one subset of the crypto market that Brevan Howard has recently been allocating to; just last week the firm co-led a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/174638\/brevan-howard-and-morgan-creek-lead-web3-gaming-startups-40-million-series-a-bloomberg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$40 million Series A<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> for Web3 gaming startup Horizon Blockchain Games.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Outside of gaming, the digital asset opportunities Brevan Howard is looking to invest in relate to practical use cases. As Johnson explains,<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“What we're really excited about right now is moving beyond just speculative trading and where are the real world use cases that we're seeing crypto start to gain adoption.”<\/span>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">During this episode<\/span><\/i><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, <\/span><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Chaparro, Johnson, and Sullivan also discuss:<\/span><\/i>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors <a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Tron<\/em><\/a><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em><\/b>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Tron<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/b><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TRON is dedicated to accelerating the decentralization of the internet via blockchain technology and decentralized applications (dApps). Founded in September 2017 by <a href=\"https:\/\/www.hejustinsun.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">H.E. Justin Sun<\/a>, the TRON network has continued to deliver impressive achievements since MainNet launch in May 2018. July 2018 also marked the ecosystem integration of <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bittorrent.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BitTorrent<\/a>, a pioneer in decentralized web3 services boasting over 100 million monthly active users. The TRON network completed full decentralization in December 2021 and is now a community-governed DAO. | <a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/hackathon\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TRONDAO<\/a> | <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/trondao\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Twitter<\/a> | <a href=\"https:\/\/discord.gg\/tron\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Discord<\/a> |<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"BitTorrent","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gabbana","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$40 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Balmain","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Brevan Howard","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nike","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"May 2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Colleen Sullivan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Peter Johnson","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"September 2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"H.E. Justin Sun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Citi","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gucci","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July 2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Brevan Howard’s","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sullivan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Balenciaga","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Johnson","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"December 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Goldman","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"last week","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dolce","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tiffany","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Brevan Howard","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Brevan Howard Co-Heads","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}