{"summary":"Can Sun, the former general counsel of FTX who became a key witness in the criminal trial of ex-FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried, is behind a new exchange","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/262701\/former-ftx-general-counsel-who-testified-against-sbf-to-lead-new-exchange-backpack-wsj","publishDate":"2023-11-11T15:16:08","id":2981,"type":null,"title":"Former FTX general counsel who testified against SBF to lead new exchange Backpack: WSJ","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Can Sun, the former general counsel of FTX who became a key witness in the criminal trial of ex-FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried, is behind a new exchange launching in beta later this month and hoping to sell a 10% stake to investors at a 100 million valuation, according to the Wall Street Journal.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Backpack, the Web3 digital wallet company founded and led by Armani Ferrante, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/260114\/backpack-launching-cryptocurrency-exchange-with-dubai-license\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> the exchange late last month, though Sun's involvement wasn't publicly disclosed. Claire Zhang, Ferrante's wife and a former legal deputy of Sun's, also sits on the executive board of Trek Labs, the Dubai-based legal entity that will do business as Backpack Exchange. The exchange received a license from the Dubai Virtual Assets Regulatory Authority, or VARA, which regulates digital assets in the region.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The WSJ report <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.wsj.com\/finance\/currencies\/key-witness-at-sam-bankman-fried-trial-to-launch-new-crypto-exchange-80d1edce?mod=latest_headlines\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">states<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that Sun's Trek Labs employs other former FTX legal and compliance employees and that he disclosed his FTX associations in investor materials and regulatory filings. Sun <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/258573\/inside-sbfs-trial-ftx-general-counsel-quit-after-he-learned-of-massive-hole-in-balance-sheet\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">testified against<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Bankman-Fried under a no-prosecution agreement and denied knowledge of the fraudulent schemes perpetrated by FTX executives, stating he resigned the day after he learned of the massive hole in FTX's balance sheet.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ferrante, an ex-Alameda Research engineer, was also professionally set back by the FTX collapse. The collapse led to Ferrante <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/227170\/ftx-funded-startup\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">losing most of the $20 million<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> he raised in an investment round co-led by FTX Ventures just weeks before FTX's bankruptcy in November 2022. Ferrante didn't immediately respond to a request for comment.&nbsp;<\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"ex-Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"10%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Claire Zhang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Armani Ferrante","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Backpack Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Trek Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dubai","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Dubai Virtual Assets Regulatory Authority","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ferrante","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"VARA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$20 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"November 2022","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Zack Abrams","The Block"]}