{"summary":"Bitcoin returned to the $19,000 level for the first time in two months on Thursday.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/202283\/bitcoin-steady-above-19000-at-the-us-close-as-traditional-markets-rise","publishDate":"2023-01-13T16:21:24","id":2982,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin nears $20,000 as traditional markets rise in US","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["Bitcoin was up 0.6% at the close of U.S. markets, trading around $19,460 while traditional markets reversed earlier losses to close higher. The coin briefly crossed the $20,000 threshold on Coinbase later in the evening, according to TradingView data.&nbsp;&nbsp;","The biggest cryptocurrency is up almost 16% over the past seven days, according to CoinGecko.","The S&amp;P 500 and Nasdaq both started the day lower, only to close at 0.38% and 0.71%, respectively.","Bitcoin returned to the $19,000 level on Thursday for the first time since Nov. 8, when the FTX implosion was kicking off.","","","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/chart\/xAJYa739\/?symbol=COINBASE%3ABTCUSD\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BTCUSD chart by TradingView<\/a><\/span>","Coinbase closed up more than 5%, Silvergate rose above 3% and Galaxy Digital increased 1.72%.","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">(Updates to show bitcoin briefly passed $20,000 threshold on Coinbase.)<\/em>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Disclaimer: Beginning in 2021, Michael McCaffrey, the former CEO and majority owner of The Block, took a series of loans from founder and former FTX and Alameda CEO Sam Bankman-Fried. McCaffrey resigned from the company in December 2022 after failing to disclose those transactions.<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Galaxy Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"TradingView","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"3%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"0.6%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$20,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$19,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"evening","content":"TIME"},{"type":"S&amp;P","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"0.71%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Nov. 8","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"16%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"December 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$19,460","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"0.38%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Michael McCaffrey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"1.72%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Nasdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["COINBASE","EQUITY MOVERS"],"authors":["Christiana Loureiro","The Block"]}