{"summary":"Dorsey said he believes that Bitcoin could be a &quot;critical&quot; financial tool for certain communities in the US.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/151104\/jay-z-and-jack-dorsey-fund-education-program","publishDate":"2022-06-09T10:59:59","id":2988,"type":null,"title":"Jay-Z and Jack Dorsey fund bitcoin education program","category":["BITCOIN"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Starting this summer, residents of Marcy Houses in Brooklyn will be eligible to receive free Bitcoin education classes as part of a new initiative funded by Twitter founder Jack Dorsey and rapper Shawn “Jay-Z” Carter.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Dorsey announced the project, called The Bitcoin Academy, in a series of <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/jack\/status\/1534894500061106177\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweets<\/a> on Thursday. This isn’t just about bitcoin,” he said, “it’s about long-term thinking, local economies, and self-confidence.”&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The education program, which will be led by educators Lamar Wilson and Najah J. Roberts, was <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">designed in collaboration with Crypto Blockchain Plug and Black Bitcoin Billionaire. The project's <a href=\"https:\/\/thebitcoinacademy.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">website<\/a> describes its goal as to reduce existing barriers to financial services among residents and provide education about Bitcoin specifically and finance in general.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">According to the website, the classes will teach residents about Bitcoin, how it works, why they should care, and how they can build their financial future. Participants in the program will receive free MiFi devices and a one-year limited data plan, plus smartphones if needed.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Bitcoin is becoming a critical tool for many in Africa and Central and South America,\" Dorsey said. \"We believe the same potential exists within communities in the US.”<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Bitcoin Academy","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Carter","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Lamar Wilson","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Shawn “Jay","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jack Dorsey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"South America","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Marcy Houses","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Najah J. Roberts","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Crypto Blockchain Plug and Black Bitcoin Billionaire","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Brooklyn","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Dorsey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"summer","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Africa","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN"],"authors":["Sam Venis","The Block"]}