{"summary":"NiftyApes joins an increasing number of early stage NFT-focused debt financiers receiving venture capital interest.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/179068\/coinbase-ventures-participates-in-4-2-million-funding-round-for-niftyapes","publishDate":"2022-11-01T08:00:02","id":3041,"type":null,"title":"Coinbase Ventures participates in $4.2 million funding round for NiftyApes ","category":["NFTS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">NiftyApes, a firm that lets users take out loans on any NFT collection, has raised $4.2 million in seed funding.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The firm joins a trend of NFT-focused debt financiers receiving interest from venture capitalists.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Variant and FinTech Collective led the round. Additional participants include Robot Ventures, Polygon, Coinbase Ventures, The LAO, FlamingoDAO, Ryan Sean Adams, David Hoffman, Eric Conner, Anthony Sassano, Cyrus Younessi, DC Investor, James Young, James Duncan, Nadav Hollander and Brendan Forster.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">NiftyApes will use the funds to grow its team and continue expanding the firm, founders Zach Herring and Kevin Seagraves told The Block.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">NiftyApes intends to augment the secondary debt economy for NFTs, moving it away from the predatory lending practices that benefit the wealthy in web2 settings. NiftyApes intends to do this through facilitating market competition to refinance an NFT loan automatically.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Another NFT-focused debt financing firm to recently receive funding is MetaStreet, which raised <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/176984\/dragonfly-and-opensea-back-10-million-raise-for-nft-financing-firm-metastreet\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$10 million<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on Oct. 13 with help from OpenSea and Dragonfly Capital.<\/span>","While NFT floor prices have fallen due to the bear market, so-called blue-chip NFTs, or popular NFT projects, remain highly valuable, making them as attractive an asset to use on collateral in the debt economy.&nbsp;","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/nft-non-fungible-tokens\/art-collectibles\/art-and-collectibles-nft-trade-volume\/embed\" title=\"Art and Collectibles NFT Trade Volume\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$4.2 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Nadav Hollander","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Polygon","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"James Duncan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Cyrus Younessi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"DC Investor","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"David Hoffman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Anthony Sassano","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ryan Sean Adams","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"James Young","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FinTech Collective","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Brendan Forster","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Oct. 13","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Coinbase Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"OpenSea","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kevin Seagraves","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Eric Conner","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Zach Herring","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$10 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Dragonfly Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Robot Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}