{"summary":"DeGods and y00ts, two of Solana&#x27;s leading non-fungible token (NFT) collections, have announced plans to move to Ethereum and Polygon.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/197892\/top-solana-nft-projects-degods-y00ts-are-headed-to-ethereum-and-polygon","publishDate":"2022-12-26T05:43:05","id":3054,"type":null,"title":"Top Solana NFT projects DeGods &amp; y00ts are headed to Ethereum and Polygon","category":["NFT COLLECTIONS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">DeGods and y00ts, two of the leading non-fungible token collections on Solana, have announced plans to bridge to Ethereum and Polygon early next year, the teams <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/degodsnft\/status\/1607156858019794944?s=46&amp;t=aJ7C6sL6HyjOL996VMWw7Q\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/a> on Twitter.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The two collections were created on Solana in October 2021 by Rohun Vora, an NFT creator who goes by the pseudonym “Frank DeGods.” They are the two most significant NFT projects on the Solana blockchain in terms of floor price.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The DeGods collection will migrate to Ethereum, aiming to compete with NFT blue chips like Bored Ape Yacht Club, CryptoPunks and others. Its floor price is 460.00 SOL ($5,221), which tops the entire NFT market on Solana. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Meanwhile, y00ts —&nbsp;with a floor of 140 SOL ($1600) —&nbsp;is planned to move over to Polygon, a sidechain of Ethereum that allows for faster and cheaper transactions.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In a <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/i\/spaces\/1mrGmkzzLBQxy\/peek\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Twitter Spaces<\/a>, Vora said that Ethereum and Polygon would individually serve as the new homes for the collections, helping them to tap into a broader NFT user base. He added that the migration would happen with the help of a cross-chain bridge. However, the team hasn't yet provided the technical details about the migration and how the so-called bridge will work. Those details will be revealed later.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“The details of the bridge will be released when it's ready and tested. This has never been done before at this scale. We want to make sure that it's airtight,” the DeGods team <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/DeGodsNFT\/status\/1607156859152248832\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">noted<\/a>.<\/span>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/nft-non-fungible-tokens\/art-collectibles\/art-and-collectibles-nft-trade-volume\/embed\" title=\"Art and Collectibles NFT Trade Volume\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Polygon","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$5,221","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bored Ape Yacht Club","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"October 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Vora","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Rohun Vora","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frank DeGods","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Solana","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$1600","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["POLYGON","SOLANA"],"authors":["Vishal Chawla","The Block"]}