{"summary":"Through MiCA regulation, EU member states can bring down ads and websites of non-EU-authorized entities. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/192083\/eu-financial-regulator-offshore-crypto-companies","publishDate":"2022-12-05T08:11:49","id":309,"type":null,"title":"EU financial regulator to address off-shore crypto companies","category":["INTERNATIONAL POLICYMAKING"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In light of FTX’s collapse, activities of off-shore crypto companies operating in the EU are under a microscope for the bloc's regulators.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The European Securities and Markets Authority is responsible for establishing implementation details on the Markets in Crypto-Assets (MiCA) regulation, which is expected to be enacted in 2024 at the earliest.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">All member states will have the power to “bring down advertisements and websites for unauthorized crypto venues,” said Jan Ceyssens, head of digital finance in the European Commission, at an event in London. “Once MiCA will be there […] authorities will track down those who may still be active but not have the authorization.\"<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We will have common ESMA guidelines which will indicate what is reverse solicitation as opposed to what is covered by the rules,” Ceyssens added, referring to a technique that enables off-shore companies to continue accessing the EU market, even without a license.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The issue of reverse solicitation surfaced in last week’s FTX hearing at the European Parliament. Steffen Kern, head of the risk analysis and economics department at ESMA, said that reverse solicitation is a “particularly pronounced problem” in crypto and is a matter of concern for the regulator.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"This market is by and large an offshore market,\" Kern added. \"In many cases, we don't even know in which jurisdiction the assets are located, which doesn't make things any easier.\" Kern also noted that players outside the EU are expected to continue playing a dominant crypto-market role.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"European Parliament","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"ESMA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"EU","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jan Ceyssens","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"European Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Steffen Kern","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"European Securities and Markets Authority","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"London","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Crypto","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Kern","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["EUROPEAN COMMISSION"],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}