{"summary":"Investment app, Stash, closed a debt round for $52.6 million after it the company revealed it would expand crypto access for its customers.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/177383\/unicorn-investment-app-stash-closes-debt-round-for-52-6-million","publishDate":"2022-10-14T18:05:33","id":3101,"type":null,"title":"Unicorn investment app Stash closes debt round for $52.6 million","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The $52.6 million convertible debt round followed Stash’s early October announcement that it would support subscriber purchases for eight digital assets including ETH and BTC.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stash previously closed a Series G fundraise with a $125 million capital infusion in February 2021.<\/span>","<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Investment app startup Stash raised $52.6 million via debt offering after expanding services to include support for eight cryptocurrencies including ETH and BTC.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stash raised funds from a dozen investors according to a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.sec.gov\/Archives\/edgar\/data\/1647051\/000164705122000002\/xslFormDX01\/primary_doc.xml\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filing<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that showed the offering for convertible debt, which is changeable into shares or another form of the issuing entity’s equity, opened on Sept. 6. CoinDesk first <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/business\/2022\/10\/14\/investing-app-stash-raises-526m-weeks-after-expanding-access-to-cryptocurrencies\/?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=onecryptofeed&amp;utm_campaign=headlines\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a> the news.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In early Oct 2022 Stash announced an expansion of its fully managed portfolio services, launched in January of the same year, to include support for purchases of Bitcoin, Bitcoin Cash, Ethereum, Chainlink, Avalanche, Ethereum Classic, Solana, and Uniswap tokens.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Valued at <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.cnbc.com\/2021\/02\/03\/investing-app-stash-raises-125-million-as-it-looks-to-add-new-customers-just-not-day-traders-.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">roughly $1.4 billion<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> the company held a $125 million Series G fundraise in Feb 2021, led by holding company Eldridge, with additional capital from investment management company T. Rowe Price.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stash did not immediately respond to The Block’s request for comment.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$1.4 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Uniswap","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"T. Rowe Price","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chainlink","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Eldridge","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$52.6 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"February 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Feb 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$125 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Sept. 6","content":"DATE"},{"type":"October","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ethereum Classic","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["DEBT FINANCING"],"authors":["Jeremy Nation","The Block"]}