{"summary":"The finance asset marketplace Tradeteq is launching a U.S. Treasury Bond token on the XDC network. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/247905\/securitize-tokenizes-u-s-treasury-bond-yield-fund-for-accredited-investors","publishDate":"2023-08-29T11:08:11","id":3106,"type":null,"title":"Securitize tokenizes U.S. Treasury Bond yield fund for accredited investors","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Tradeteq, a financial asset marketplace and securitization-as-a-service provider based in London, has launched an exchange-traded U.S. Treasury Yield (USTY) fund as a digital asset.&nbsp;","The San Francisco-based firm <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/241382\/securitize-launches-tokenized-security-in-europe\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Securitize<\/a>, which tokenizes real world assets, has tokenized the shares of USTY on the Layer 1 blockchain XDC Network.","The USTY token gives investors access to a yield from a U.S. Treasury ETF in addition to exposure to U.S. Treasury securities, according to a company statement. Accredited investors can obtain the USTY token starting Tuesday.&nbsp;","“USTY combines the flexibility and accessibility of cryptocurrencies with the stability of a U.S. Treasury ETF, creating an efficient and seamless investment experience,” said Nils Behling, chief operating officer of Tradeteq, in a statement.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"San Francisco","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Nils Behling","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S. Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"London","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S. Treasury ETF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tradeteq","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USTY","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}