{"summary":"Brett Harrison, former president of FTX U.S., plans to share information on the crypto exchange’s operations.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/200054\/former-ftx-u-s-president-harrison-says-hell-share-information-on-exchange-in-time","publishDate":"2023-01-09T01:08:19","id":3139,"type":null,"title":"Former FTX US president Harrison says he&#x27;ll share information on exchange &#x27;in time&#x27;","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["Brett Harrison, former president of FTX U.S., plans to share information on the crypto exchange’s operations.","Harrison <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/BrettHarrison88\/status\/1612261507659694082?s=20&amp;t=7YkasbmGNpxz2gwfoikoqw\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">responded<\/a> to a post on Twitter asking what he knew about FTX’s U.S. unit, and when, by simply stating, “I’ll share in time.”","He <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/172744\/ftx-us-president-harrison-is-stepping-down\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">stepped down<\/a> as president of FTX U.S. in September last year, before the crisis that sank the exchange ensued. Before joining FTX U.S. in May 2021, Harrison was a high-speed trading executive at Citadel Securities.","In late December, it emerged that Caroline Ellison, former CEO of FTX’s sister trading firm Alameda Research, and FTX co-founder and former CTO Gary Wang — both top lieutenants of former FTX boss Sam Bankman-Fried — were <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/197342\/bankman-fried-in-fbi-custody-ellison-wang-plead-guilty-and-are-cooperating\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">cooperating with prosecutors<\/a> after pleading guilty to criminal charges.","Question marks remain, however, about the fate of other key figures involved in FTX and Alameda. Recent reports suggest authorities are <a href=\"https:\/\/markets.businessinsider.com\/news\/currencies\/nishad-singh-ftx-engineer-sam-bankman-fried-crypto-fraud-case-2023-1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">scrutinizing<\/a> the role former FTX engineering director Nishad Singh played in the firm’s collapse.","Harrison did not immediately respond to a request for comment on what information he plans to share.","A report on Dec. 2 from The Information suggests he is currently <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/191865\/former-ftx-us-head-brett-harrison-tries-raising-money-for-new-startup-the-information\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">trying to raise money<\/a> for a new startup that will sell crypto trading software to large investors.","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Harrison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"May 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Caroline Ellison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"September last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Nishad Singh","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"December","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gary Wang —","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Dec. 2","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Citadel Securities","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Brett Harrison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Ryan Weeks","The Block"]}