{"summary":"From technical innovations to social and economic implications, listen to The Block editorial staff&#x27;s top picks of the 2022 season of The Scoop.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/197760\/the-scoop-editors-picks-top-episodes-recapping-the-2022-crypto-landscape","publishDate":"2022-12-30T06:30:21","id":3153,"type":null,"title":"The Scoop Editors&#x27; Picks: Top episodes recapping the 2022 crypto landscape","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Throughout this landmark year, The Scoop podcast provided a window into the individuals, ideas and stories shaping the burgeoning crypto industry. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">From CEO interviews with Coinbase's Brian Armstrong, a16z General Partner Chris Dixon and former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried — and their thoughts on everything from technical innovations to social and economic implications — here are The Block editorial staff's top picks of the 2022 season of The Scoop.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/153713\/inside-cryptos-biggest-deleveraging-event-and-the-three-arrows-capital-fallout\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Inside crypto's 'biggest deleveraging event' and the Three Arrows Capital fallout<\/a><\/strong>","In June, Three Arrows Capital's insolvency caught many in the crypto world by surprise.","In this episode, Wintermute CEO Evgeny Gaevoy and The Block's Larry Cermak analyze the fallout from the Three Arrows meltdown and explain the massive deleveraging this event caused in the crypto markets.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Evgeny Gaevoy","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Larry Cermak","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Three Arrows Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"June","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Brian Armstrong","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Wintermute","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chris Dixon","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Davis Quinton","The Block"]}