{"summary":"RGB represents the “best opportunity” for issuing stablecoins like USDT on Bitcoin, according to Bitfinex CTO Paolo Ardoino.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/258350\/bitfinex-rgb-bitcoin-stablecoins","publishDate":"2023-10-19T07:24:37","id":3199,"type":null,"title":"Paolo Ardoino sees RGB as &#x27;best opportunity&#x27; to issue stablecoins on Bitcoin","category":["STABLECOINS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The chief technology officer at crypto exchange Bitfinex Paolo Ardoino told The Block in an interview that the RGB protocol represents the “best opportunity” for issuing stablecoins on Bitcoin. Ardoino views RGB as the the “rightful successor” to Omni after <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Tether <\/span><span class=\"articleTooltip\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"\/price\/248350\/tether-usdt-usd\" class=\"articleTooltip__link\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"><img src=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2023\/10\/Tether.png\" alt=\"\" title=\"\" class=\"articleTooltip__tokenImage\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">USDT<\/span> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText articleTooltip__tokenText_price articleTooltip__tokenText_positive\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">\n      +0.047%\n    <\/span><\/a> <!----><\/span><\/span> <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/245976\/tether-discontinues-usdt-bitcoin-kusama-bitcoin-cash\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">discontinued<\/a> its use to issue the USDT stablecoin.","“With regard to Omni, we believe RGB actually represents the best opportunity to have a modern, scalable, client-side smart contract system that allows tokens on Bitcoin,” Ardoino said. “Many prominent people in the Bitcoin community are in fact aligned in supporting RGB, and we believe that RGB integrates all the right ingredients to be the rightful successor of Omni.”","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.rgbfaq.com\/what-is-rgb\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">RGB<\/a> is a smart contracts system and off-chain protocol for Bitcoin and the Lightning Network, which allows for the minting and issuing of Bitcoin-based digital assets. It was originally envisioned in 2016 by Bitcoin educator Giacomo Zucco as a \"non-blockchain based asset system,\" utilizing earlier ideas from Bitcoin Core developer Peter Todd, according to its website.","Omni was the first layer that Bitfinex's sister firm, Tether, used in 2014, enabling it to issue stablecoins on the Bitcoin blockchain.","This year, Tether announced it was <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/245976\/tether-discontinues-usdt-bitcoin-kusama-bitcoin-cash\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">discontinuing support for Omni<\/a> in August, alongside Kusama and Bitcoin Cash SLP implementations as usage dwindled compared to increasing demand on Ethereum and Tron — which currently dominate USDT supply.","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/stablecoins\/usd-pegged\/usdt-supply-by-blockchain-daily\/embed\" title=\"USDT Supply by Blockchain\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Tether has now completely ceased minting USDT on Omni, though users can continue redeeming the tokens or swap them to other chains for several months.","“Unfortunately, Omni suffered from a recent lack of support that impaired its ability to sustainably develop,” Ardoino said.","“Tether is evaluating a timeline for a possible issuance of USDT over RGB,” he added. Tether is an active contributor to RGB and previously said it planned to return to issuing the stablecoin on Bitcoin via RGB.","Developer Lightning Labs also released a similar solution to RGB called <a href=\"https:\/\/lightning.engineering\/posts\/2023-10-18-taproot-assets-v0.3\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Taproot Assets<\/a> yesterday, initially on Bitcoin, but with Lightning Network support expected to follow.","Ardoino holds positions at both Bitfinex and Tether. Last week, Tether <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/256298\/tether-paolo-ardoino-new-ceo\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">promoted<\/a> Ardoino to CEO and remains in his position as Bitfinex CTO.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2014","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2016","content":"DATE"},{"type":"crypto exchange Bitfinex Paolo Ardoino","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"RGB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Peter Todd","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bitfinex","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kusama","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bitcoin Cash SLP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"+0.047%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Giacomo Zucco","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ardoino","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Lightning Network","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitfinex CTO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Omni","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN","TETHER"],"authors":["James Hunt","The Block"]}