{"summary":"MicroStrategy&#x27;s stock price has fallen amid a downturn in crypto prices and the world&#x27;s financial markets.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/148456\/microstrategy-trading-at-18-month-low-following-crypto-and-stock-market-drop","publishDate":"2022-05-24T11:12:41","id":3270,"type":null,"title":"MicroStrategy trading at 18-month low following crypto and stock market drop","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Michael Saylor’s MicroStrategy is trading down over 50% month-to-month following bitcoin’s price tumult.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">MicroStrategy was trading at 18-month lows on Tuesday as cryptocurrency prices continue to fall in tandem with broader financial markets.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Shares in Michael Saylor's software company were trading at $188.50 at the time of writing, according to Nasdaq data <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/chart\/?symbol=NASDAQ%3AMSTR\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">via<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> TradingView. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This represents a drop of more than 55% over the past month, down from $427.05 on April 25.<\/span>","","","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">MicroStrategy’s massive bet on bitcoin – it and its entities <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.microstrategy.com\/en\/investor-relations\/press\/silvergate-bank-issues-205-m-loan-to-macrostrategy-collateralized-by-bitcoin_03-29-2022\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">currently<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> hold 129,218 bitcoins –&nbsp; is now in the red having fallen below the average purchase price of $30,700.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitcoin (BTC) was <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/chart\/?symbol=COINBASE%3ABTCUSD\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">trading at<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> $28,746 dollars, at the time of writing, having <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/146513\/bitcoin-price-markets-negative-crypto-terra-ethereum-solana-blockchain\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">fallen below $30,000<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on May 12 following the collapse of Terra's stablecoins TerraUSD (UST). This spread across the crypto market putting downward pressure on all digital assets.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The last time MicroStrategy was trading at these levels was on November 9, 2020, when it was trading at $183. At that time bitcoin (BTC) was trading at $16,410.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">However, the software company’s bet on bitcoin is only one mitigating factor for the drop in share price.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Broader financial markets have been rattled by a tough macroeconomic landscape as governments and central banks address rapidly growing inflation flowing the pandemic.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">For instance, the US Federal Reserve has promised to begin reducing its $9 trillion balance sheet from next month, as it aims to stem rising inflation.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This has left most major US stock indexes down year-to-date. The S&amp;P 500 lost 18.91%, the Nasdaq Composite is down 29.50% and the Dow Jones slipped 13.99% since January. <\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"US Federal Reserve","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"TradingView","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$427.05","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"S&amp;P","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"29.50%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"50%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$28,746 dollars","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"April 25","content":"DATE"},{"type":"13.99%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$183","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$9 trillion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Michael Saylor","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$30,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"55%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$188.50","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$30,700","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"18.91%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"November 9, 2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Terra","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nasdaq Composite","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UST","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MicroStrategy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nasdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"May 12","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$16,410","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN","MICROSTRATEGY"],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}