{"summary":"In this episode of The Scoop, the Blockchain Association’s executive director Kristen Smith shares the objectives of the new Blockchain Association PAC, and why she believes Congress is the appropriate authority to design a regulatory framework for the crypto industry.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/173805\/kristin-smith-unpacks-the-new-blockchain-association-pac","publishDate":"2022-10-03T05:00:45","id":3274,"type":null,"title":"Kristin Smith unpacks the new Blockchain Association PAC","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 94<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 4 of The Scoop was recorded at SALT New York 2022 on September 13 with <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro, and Blockchain Association's executive director Kristin Smith.<\/strong><\/i><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"87f7e8e3e4e6f4f3c7f3efe2e5ebe8e4ece4f5fef7f3e8a9e4e8ea\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i><\/span>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK8485673895\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Blockchain Association recently <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/169329\/blockchain-association-launches-new-pac-to-back-pro-crypto-candidates\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">launched<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> a new political action committee (PAC) designed to build relationships with pro-crypto congressional candidates.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In this episode of The Scoop, the Blockchain Association’s executive director Kristin Smith shares the objectives of the new Blockchain Association PAC, and why she believes Congress is the appropriate authority to design a regulatory framework for the crypto industry.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">As Smith explains, the Blockchain Association PAC is intended to promote pro-crypto candidates:<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“For us, this PAC is really about building relationships… This isn't the type of PAC where we go and buy a bunch of airtime or print out a bunch of mailers and spend a few hundred thousand dollars or $1,000,000 in a single race.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">While SEC chair Gary Gensler recently <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/170415\/gensler-multiple-crypto-regulators-could-undermine-securities-rules\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">remarked<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that multiple crypto regulators could undermine the SEC’s efforts, Smith believes the Congress is in the best position to effectuate change:<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We need Congress to step in and help sort through these issues because they are the ones that can grant new authority and they're the ones that have the flexibility to design a regulatory system that matches the risks that we see in crypto.”<\/span>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">During this episode, Chaparro and Smith also discuss:<\/span><\/i>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors <a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Tron<\/em><\/a><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em><\/b>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Tron<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/b><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TRON is dedicated to accelerating the decentralization of the internet via blockchain technology and decentralized applications (dApps). Founded in September 2017 by <a href=\"https:\/\/www.hejustinsun.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">H.E. Justin Sun<\/a>, the TRON network has continued to deliver impressive achievements since MainNet launch in May 2018. July 2018 also marked the ecosystem integration of <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bittorrent.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BitTorrent<\/a>, a pioneer in decentralized web3 services boasting over 100 million monthly active users. The TRON network completed full decentralization in December 2021 and is now a community-governed DAO. | <a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/hackathon\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TRONDAO<\/a> | <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/trondao\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Twitter<\/a> | <a href=\"https:\/\/discord.gg\/tron\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Discord<\/a> |<\/em><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/b>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Blockchain Association","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BitTorrent","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kristin Smith","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Blockchain Association PAC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Smith","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Gary Gensler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"May 2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"September 2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"H.E. Justin Sun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"July 2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$1,000,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Congress","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Blockchain Association’s","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"December 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"September 13","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"PAC","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["CFTC","CONGRESS","CRYPTO","SEC"],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}