{"summary":"The sidechain that hosts Axie Infinity&#x27;s play-to-earn game plans to reopen its bridge next week, three months after suffering a $600 million exploit.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/153984\/axie-infinitys-ronin-ethereum-bridge-to-restart-next-week","publishDate":"2022-06-24T05:27:39","id":3279,"type":null,"title":"Axie Infinity&#x27;s Ronin Ethereum bridge to restart next week","category":["METAVERSE & NFT"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ronin, an Ethereum-linked sidechain that hosts the Axie Infinity play-to-earn game, plans to reopen its bridge next week, <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">three months after it suffered a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/139761\/axie-infinitys-ethereum-sidechain-ronin-hit-by-600-million-exploit\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$600 million exploit<\/a>.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Ronin development team, funded by Axie Infinity creator Sky Mavis, confirmed in a <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/Ronin_Network\/status\/1539999232563740673\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Twitter post<\/a>&nbsp;yesterday the bridge will restart on June 28. The development team had earlier scheduled the bridge to restart this Thursday, but it got slightly delayed.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Our engineering team has been hard at work preparing for the bridge to re-open,\" the team stated in the tweet, adding that restarting the Bridge requires a network hard fork in which <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/140165\/ronin-replaces-compromised-validators-and-plans-to-bolster-security-after-600-million-hack\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">validators<\/a> plan to upgrade their software.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">On March 23, hackers later identified as the North Korean group Lazarus, took control over five out of the nine validator nodes on Ronin, allowing them to steal 173,600 ETH and 25.5 million USDC from the bridge. Following the incident, it's bridge was halted.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">With the bridge going back online this coming Tuesday, the team has promised to reimburse those affected by the exploit.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In April, the game's creator Sky Mavis raised <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/140800\/sky-mavis-raises-150-million-from-binance-to-reimburse-ronin-hack-victims\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$150 million<\/a> from investors, including crypto exchange Binance and venture capital firms Andreessen Horowitz and Paradigm. This amount, plus Sky Mavis' own funds, will help reimburse affected users.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Lazarus","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Axie Infinity","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$600 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"March 23","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Infinity","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ronin","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Andreessen Horowitz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sky Mavis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"June 28","content":"DATE"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$150 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Mavis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Vishal Chawla","The Block"]}