{"summary":"British national Christopher Hamilton is facing extradition to the US to face charges stemming from the OneCoin cryptocurrency scam.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/166751\/cryptoqueen-accomplice-faces-extradition-to-the-u-s-over-onecoin-ponzi-scheme-law360","publishDate":"2022-08-31T09:16:08","id":3294,"type":null,"title":"Cryptoqueen accomplice faces extradition to the U.S. over OneCoin ponzi scheme: Law360","category":["THE BLOCK"],"content":["\"Cryptoqueen\" accomplice Christopher Hamilton is facing extradition to the U.S. after a British judge rejected his bid to delay the process on Tuesday.","District Judge Nicholas Rimmer rejected the bid to hold off on extradition, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.law360.com\/whitecollar\/articles\/1525777\/briton-to-be-extradited-to-us-in-onecoin-crypto-fraud-case\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Law360<\/a> reported. Hamilton is accused of laundering $105 million in connection with the OneCoin ponzi scheme.&nbsp;","OneCoin, led by the now infamous international fugitive Ruja Ignatova known as the \"Cryptoqueen,\" sold educational cryptocurrency trading packages to its members, who were then given commissions to sell packages to more new members. At its peak, the company claimed to have as many as 3 million members from around the globe.","OneCoin \"induced investors all over the world to invest in this actually worthless currency,\" <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/146251\/ruja-ignatova-europes-most-wanted-cryptoqueen-crime-scam-ponzi\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">according<\/a> to <a href=\"https:\/\/eumostwanted.eu\/#\/ignatova-ruja\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Europol<\/a>. The Ponzi scheme is estimated to have netted about $4 billion. Ignatova is on Europe and the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/155109\/onecoin-founder-ruja-ignatova-to-be-added-to-fbis-most-wanted-list\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">FBI's most wanted list<\/a>. It is widely considered the biggest scam yet in the history of crypto.&nbsp;","Hamilton's co-accused Robert McDonald avoided extradition on human rights grounds. McDonald cares for his wife who suffers from progressive multiple sclerosis, according to Law360, and per the judge's written statement separation from his wife would \"be extremely harsh in light of her poor health.\" This is based on <a href=\"https:\/\/www.echr.coe.int\/documents\/guide_art_8_eng.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Article 8 of the European Convention of Human Rights<\/a>, which includes the right to respect for private and family life.","The case will now be seen by Secretary of State Priti Patel, at which point Hamilton is entitled to appeal the decision.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Christopher Hamilton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$4 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Europol","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Robert McDonald","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Secretary of State Priti Patel","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FBI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$105 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Nicholas Rimmer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Hamilton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"European Convention of Human Rights","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}