{"summary":"Decentralized mapping network company Hivemapper has raised $18 million in a Series A funding round.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/140231\/hivemapper-raises-18-million-to-create-decentralized-mapping-network","publishDate":"2022-04-05T08:00:20","id":3299,"type":null,"title":"Hivemapper raises $18 million to create decentralized mapping network","category":["STARTUPS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Decentralized mapping network company <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/hivemapper.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Hivemapper<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> has raised $18 million in a Series A funding round.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The round brings the company’s total financing to date to $23 million, according to a statement on Tuesday. The company declined to disclose Hivemapper's valuation.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Investment firm Multicoin Capital led the round, with participation from Craft Ventures, Solana Capital, Shine Capital, Spencer Rascoff’s 75 and Sunny Ventures — as well as previous investors Spark Capital, Founder Collective and Homebrew.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">US-based Hivemapper is a blockchain-based mapping network that turns dashcam footage into “<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">state of the art” maps that are “constantly evolving.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">It rewards map contributors who capture 4K street-level imagery with the network’s native token HONEY. Map editors then process the dashcam data, carry out quality assurance, and annotate contributor imagery. These editors also receive HONEY for their efforts.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Tech giants such as Google, Apple and Alibaba currently dominate the digital mapping market, which — according to Hivemapper — is worth about $300 billion.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">But the incumbents may face growing competition, with <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.reuters.com\/business\/exclusive-us-probe-google-maps-picks-up-speed-sources-2022-03-30\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reports<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> last week that the US Justice Department had “breathed new life” into an investigation into Google Maps and alleged anti-trust violations.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Mapping is an extremely complex, expensive, and time-consuming process. Only the largest and most capitalized tech companies in the world have the resources to do digital mapping, and even with all those resources street-level imagery in many parts of the world is only updated once every two years,” said Ariel Seidman, co-founder and CEO of Hivemapper.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“This causes cascading logistical, municipal, and political problems. However, maps have the potential to be near real-time. An open-source, community-owned map is the only way to continuously construct a living, breathing, ever-updating view of our world,” he said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Hivemapper said it will use the newly raised funds to further develop its network. It plans to launch its mainnet this summer and will continue to onboard new contributors.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In addition, the company will begin shipping its own $449 crypto-integrated dashcam from July.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">As part of the financing, co-founder and CEO of Nova Labs, Amir Haleem, will also join Hivemapper's board of directors.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Shine Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$449","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Ariel Seidman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Craft Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alibaba","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Amir Haleem","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$18 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google Maps","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$300 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Multicoin Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Homebrew","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Solana Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$23 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"US Justice Department","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nova Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spencer Rascoff","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"summer","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Hivemapper","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Callan Quinn","The Block"]}