{"summary":"Crypto stocks traded lower in line with crypto prices, despite the downturn one asset manager remains keen on bitcoin.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/187521\/bitcoin-ether-decline-stocks-sink-and-ark-is-warm-on-gbtc","publishDate":"2022-11-16T10:21:56","id":3312,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin, ether decline, stocks sink and Ark is warm on GBTC","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["Crypto markets slid on Wednesday as altcoins surrendered gains made at the top of the week.&nbsp;","Bitcoin was down 2.6% at $16,479 over the past day, while ether lost 4.5% to trade at $1,207, according to data compiled by CoinGecko.","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/symbols\/BTCUSD\/?exchange=COINBASE\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BTCUSD chart by TradingView<\/span><\/a>","Altcoins, which had <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/187090\/uniswap-token-gains-as-trading-volumes-jump-bitcoin-ether-slip\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">risen<\/a> earlier in the week, fell even more. Polygon's MATIC traded down 5.9% to $0.90, Polkadot's DOT shed 4.7% to $5.72, and Solana's SOL plunged 6.4% to $13.96.","The native coin of Chiliz, the home of socios and sports fan tokens, was up 4% over the past 24 hours. Several international teams — Argentina and Portugal — offer fan tokens through partnerships with socios. The fan token chain could be benefiting from the FIFA World Cup, which kicks off on Sunday.&nbsp;","Publicly traded companies exposed to cryptocurrencies or focused on blockchain technology traded down at the open.","Coinbase dropped around 10% shortly after 9:30 a.m. ET. Goldman Sachs lowered its price target for the exchange to $41 last week. The investment bank maintained its sell rating.&nbsp;","Jack Dorsey's Block was down over 3.2%, according to Nasdaq data via TradingView.&nbsp;","Crypto bank Silvergate also fell at the open, shedding 6%. Silvergate <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/187315\/silvergate-stock-sinks-12-on-ftx-links\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tanked<\/a> 12% on Tuesday as fears over the firm's exposure to FTX spread.&nbsp;","Elsewhere, Michael Saylor's MicroStrategy — which owns 130,000 BTC — slipped 5%.&nbsp;","The S&amp;P 500 and the Nasdaq were down 0.54% and 1.1%, respectively.","Ark Invest followed up Monday's GBTC <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/187045\/ark-invest-picks-up-2-8-million-worth-of-grayscale-bitcoin-trust-shares\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">purchase<\/a> by <a href=\"https:\/\/ark-funds.com\/ark-trade-notifications\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">adding<\/a> a further 273,327 shares worth $2.6 million on Tuesday. Cathie Wood's fund has purchased over $5.4 million in GBTC shares this week.&nbsp;","Grayscale <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/187553\/grayscale-says-products-are-operating-business-as-usual-following-genesis-withdrawal-freeze?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a> on Wednesday that it had no exposure to Genesis — a separate Digital Currency Group firm that has <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/187516\/genesis-halts-customer-withdrawals-in-wake-of-three-arrows-and-ftx-collapses-coindesk\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">halted<\/a> customer withdrawals.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Silvergate","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"0.54%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"GBTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"6%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"4.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"TradingView","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Portugal","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"4.7%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"SOL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"4%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"10%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"12%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"S&amp;P","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$5.4 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"3.2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$5.72","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Argentina","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Cathie Wood","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FIFA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Michael Saylor","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sunday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$41","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$1,207","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"5.9%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2.6%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"6.4%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$2.6 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"1.1%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$0.90","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Digital Currency Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jack Dorsey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Goldman Sachs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chiliz","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$16,479","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"CoinGecko","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$13.96","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"MicroStrategy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"9:30 a.m. ET","content":"TIME"},{"type":"Nasdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN","EQUITY MOVERS","ETHEREUM"],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}