{"summary":"Voyager&#x27;s Official Committee of Unsecured Creditors tweeted that Voyager has not transferred any assets to FTX, and confirmed that the company&#x27;s planned deal to sell its assets to FTX has not been completed. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/185542\/voyager-has-no-assets-on-ftx-says-deal-not-done","publishDate":"2022-11-10T14:06:37","id":3352,"type":null,"title":"Voyager has no assets on FTX, says deal not done","category":["BANKRUPTCY"],"content":["Bankrupt crypto lender Voyager has not transferred any crypto or assets to FTX, Voyager's Official Committee of Unsecured Creditors <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/VoyagerUCC\/status\/1590775946105135104\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweeted<\/a>.","Voyager's planned deal to sell its assets to FTX has not been completed, the committee said. The committee represents the interests of Voyager's unsecured creditors in the firm's ongoing Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection case.","\"We want to make clear that the FTX\/Voyager transaction has not been consummated,\" the creditor committee said. \"Voyager has not transferred any crypto or other assets to FTX in connection with the transaction.\"","Voyager's creditor committee said it is taking \"all steps necessary\" and \"evaluating all options\" to protect creditors.","A bankruptcy judge in the U.S. Bankruptcy Court for the Southern District of New York <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/179080\/voyager-urges-creditors-to-vote-yes-on-court-approved-ftx-sale\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">approved<\/a> Voyager's plan to sell its assets to FTX US in October.","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S. Bankruptcy Court","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Southern District of New York","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Voyager's Official Committee of Unsecured Creditors","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"October","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Voyager","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BANKRUPTCY FILINGS","FTX"],"authors":["Kristin Majcher","The Block"]}