{"summary":"Mysten Labs bought back an equity stake from FTX for $96 million, as the exchange&#x27;s ongoing bankruptcy unfurls.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/226502\/mysten-ftx","publishDate":"2023-04-14T15:29:08","id":3397,"type":null,"title":"Mysten Labs buys back stake from FTX for $96 million","category":["LAYER 1S"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Mysten Labs, creator of the Layer 1 blockchain Sui, has repurchased an equity stake bought by FTX less than a year ago.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The total buyback price of $96 million also includes “<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">all of FTX’s warrant rights to purchase Sui tokens,” Mysten said in a statement. The <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sui blockchain, developed at Meta, has <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/214964\/mysten-labs-ceo-evan-cheng-wants-to-do-web3-venture-capital-better\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">garnered<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> a significant amount of interest from investors. Since late 2021, the company has raised a total of $336 million, according to The Block Pro's Deals Dashboard.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<a href=\"https:\/\/www.businesswire.com\/news\/home\/20230414005397\/en\/Mysten-Labs-Completes-Repurchase-of-Stake-Held-by-FTX\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">FTX's investment in Mysten<\/a> was part of a $300 million Series B funding round from September 2022, according to the statement.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We are very pleased to close this transaction, which speaks to the tremendous confidence we have in our capabilities, technology and partnerships,” said Mysten Labs Co-Founder and CEO Evan Cheng.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The buyback was part of FTX’s <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/225273\/ftx-bankruptcy-bills\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">bankruptcy proceedings<\/a>, according to Mysten.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$336 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Mysten","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sui blockchain","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Meta","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"blockchain Sui","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Evan Cheng","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Deals Dashboard","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"September 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$300 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$96 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Mysten","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}