{"summary":"Fanatics sells majority stake in NFT shop Candy Digital amid slumping digital assets market.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/199477\/fanatics-to-sell-candy-digital-stake-to-galaxy-amid-slumping-nft-market-cnbc","publishDate":"2023-01-05T10:11:03","id":3415,"type":null,"title":"Fanatics sells majority stake in NFT shop Candy Digital to group led by Galaxy and ConsenSys Mesh","category":["METAVERSE & NFT"],"content":["Fanatics is selling its majority stake in NFT shop Candy Digital.","The sports merchandising comp<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">any owned by Michael Rubin is no longer Candy Digital's principal shareholder after a new round of Series A1 financing, according to Candy Digital. The new wave of financing is led by crypto billionaire Mike Novogratz's Galaxy Digital and ConsenSys Mesh.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nFanatics' divestment comes amid a prolonged downturn in digital assets, which has seen NFT trading volumes plummet along with cryptocurrency prices.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n“We believe that the Candy team is well-positioned to capitalize on the rising demand for NFT products and expand into new industries and markets,\" said Novogratz in a statement.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nFanatics retains a smaller ownership stake in the NFT company, a Candy Digital spokesman said by email.&nbsp;<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nEarlier in the day CNBC reported that Fanatics was seeking to divest its 60% stake in Candy Digital, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.cnbc.com\/2023\/01\/04\/fanatics-is-divesting-its-60percent-stake-in-nft-company-candy-digital.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">citing an internal email.<\/a><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Once valued at $1.5 billion, Candy Digital <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/190479\/candy-digital-nft-shop-lays-off-large-number-of-employees-amid-market-deterioration\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">laid off a large number of its employees<\/a> at the end of last year. The company was founded in 2021 and backed by both Novogratz and <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Gary Vaynerchuk.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Candy Digital has worked on NFT projects linked to major brands like Major League Baseball, NASCAR, World Wrestling Entertainment and Netflix.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Neither Fanatics or Galaxy Digital responded to requests for comment.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Updates with confirmation of the Series A1 financing and Fanatics' retention of a small stake in Candy Digital.<\/em><\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Galaxy Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Netflix","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CNBC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"60%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$1.5 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Novogratz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Michael Rubin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Mike Novogratz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gary Vaynerchuk","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Candy Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["TRADING CARD GAMES"],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}