{"summary":"An NFT project centered around Bud Light has launched, targeting consumers over the age of 21.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/131863\/beer-giant-anheuser-busch-launches-nft-project-for-bud-light","publishDate":"2022-01-27T09:30:28","id":3418,"type":null,"title":"Beer giant Anheuser-Busch launches NFT project for Bud Light","category":["STARTUPS"],"content":["New NFT project “Bud Light N3XT Collection” launches alongside a new no carb beer.","This is Bud Light’s first move into NFTs, but not the first for parent company Anheuser-Busch InBev.","Bud Light maker Anheuser-Busch is launching an NFT project which will feature 12,722 unique tokens.","The project, called “Bud Light N3XT Collection” will be available to consumers 21 and over. The NFTs are part of a larger launch of the company’s first zero-carb beer. <br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nWith the purchase of an NFT, consumers will have the opportunity to vote on Bud Light NEXT merchandise, have access to Bud Light NEXT brand and partner events, and more.&nbsp;","“So there will probably be a lot more than that, that won't be disclosed at the announcement time. But there's a roadmap to come,” Corey Brown, senior digital director for Bud Light, told The Block.&nbsp;","Increasingly, consumer and luxury brands have been moving into utility NFTs, which offer both a digital experience and tangible value through product offerings and other perks. Just this month, The Block has reported on brands like <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/130087\/clothing-retailer-gap-launches-nft-collection-on-tezos\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Gap<\/a>, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/130407\/shoe-company-crocs-is-eyeing-an-nft-play-according-to-trademark-application\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crocs<\/a>, and <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/131037\/adidas-originals-and-prada-announce-a-user-generated-nft-project\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Prada<\/a> moving into the NFT space.","This isn’t Anheuser-Busch's first move into NFTs. The brewery company, which has a family of brands including Bud Light, Shock Top, and Hoegaarden, launched its first NFT sale featuring 1,936 unique Budweiser digital beer can designs in November. The collection <a href=\"https:\/\/adage.com\/article\/digital-marketing-ad-tech-news\/budweisers-first-nfts-sell-out-under-hour\/2383936\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">sold out<\/a> in an hour.","Despite the success, NFTs are still new and experimental for the company.","“It’s new for us, for Bud Light. I think the most important thing is making sure that we are keeping our consumers in mind. That this isn’t a marketing stunt. We’ve done a lot so far to make sure that we have the right partners in the space and we’re doing things as authentically to the community as we can,” said Brown.","Brown says the company is taking a long-term approach with more things brewing in the coming months.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Brown","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Anheuser","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Crocs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Busch","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Hoegaarden","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bud Light","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Busch InBev","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Corey Brown","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Anushree Dave","The Block"]}