{"summary":"There are 13 FTX storage units and $2.4 million in cars up for sale soon.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/210651\/ftx-liquidators-play-storage-wars-in-hunt-for-saleable-assets","publishDate":"2023-02-10T14:01:45","id":342,"type":null,"title":"FTX liquidators play &#x27;Storage Wars&#x27; in hunt for saleable assets","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["Bound to hit the market soon are a half a million dollars worth of office furniture and equipment and 13 storage units in the Bahamas full of FTX's \"physical goods.\"","Although there's little chance of unearthing rare valuables, those office items and whatever is in the storage units will soon be up for grabs. That's according to a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.pwc.com\/bs\/en\/services\/business-restructuring-ftx-digital-markets\/assets\/seventh-affidavit-of-kevin-cambridge-filed-8th-february-2023.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">report<\/a> from liquidators tasked with digging through the bankrupt crypto exchange's leftover assets.","The list of assets also includes $2.4 million in vehicles, of which the report dryly notes \"there is no longer a need for the company to maintain the current fleet size.\"","They are looking to sell them as soon as possible in order to avoid the depreciation of their value.","Also coming to market will be whatever's inside the company's head office in the Bahamas, which had its locks changed and is secured on site.","The company had a total of $219.5 million in cash in banks as of Nov. 10, the report said. The list included Fidelity Bank, Silvergate Bank, Deltec Bank and Moonstone Bank, in addition to other institutions whose names were left out as liquidators seek to recover those funds.","Liquidators have also asked for the transfer of $46.7 million in USDT held in an account in the name of FTX Digital and are waiting for Tether to transfer them into their custody, the report said.","In total, the company had $1.2 billion in assets at the end of October of last year, the report said.","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$2.4 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Silvergate Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fidelity Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"million dollars","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"October of last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Moonstone Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bahamas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$219.5 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Nov. 10","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$46.7 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Deltec Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1.2 billion","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Catarina Moura","The Block"]}