{"summary":"","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/79373\/the-block-presents-the-state-of-international-remittance-presented-by-apifiny","publishDate":"2020-09-30T14:47:24","id":3466,"type":null,"title":"The Block Presents: The State of International Remittance —  Presented by Apifiny","category":["WEBINAR"],"content":["On Wednesday October 7th The Block’s Director of News, Frank Chaparro, takes a look at the latest developments around international remittance.&nbsp;","You can register for the event and learn about our panelists below:&nbsp;","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" title=\"The State of International Remittance — Presented by Apifiny | The Block\" src=\"https:\/\/app.livestorm.co\/p\/baaf17dd-a38c-45ea-bccf-f5809ce7e6aa\/form\" width=\"100%\" height=\"360\" frameborder=\"0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Thomas Trépanier – Head of Business Development, Roxe settlement network by Apifiny<\/strong>","Thomas Trepanier has over 20 years of experience in the financial services and software development industry. At Apifiny, he helps lead business development for Roxe, the company’s global instant settlement network. Previously he led the fintech business vertical for Global Accelerated Ventures (GAV), where he was responsible for leading the fintech business, including onboarding new innovative methodologies and technologies. Prior to GAV, he spent over 15 years working in software development and financial services at SWIFT, DTCC (Omgeo), SunGard (FIS), Brown Brothers Harriman and The Bank of New York Mellon.","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Lisa Nestor – Director, Partnership<\/strong>","Lisa is a researcher and business strategist with a passion for financial inclusion. At SDF Lisa supports Stellar’s Enterprise Ecosystem, driving business growth and value for enterprise partners. Prior to joining the SDF, Lisa was a business development volunteer with the Peace Corps in Mauritania, worked as a researcher at the Centre for Microfinance in India and supported product marketing and growth at Payoff. Lisa holds an MBA from UCLA Anderson.","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Asheesh Birla – SVP of Product and Corporate Development, Ripple<\/strong>","Asheesh is the SVP of Product and Corporate Development at Ripple, which he first joined in 2013 to lead the development of their product suite. Asheesh is an industry expert on blockchain and is a frequent contributor, speaker, and advisor on blockchain and cryptocurrency. Asheesh started his career as an entrepreneur over 15 years ago in Silicon Valley, where he founded a content management company that he later sold to Thomson Reuters, becoming their VP of Global Technology in 2005. After leaving Thomson Reuters in 2010, he advised and led product design at a number of startups in Silicon Valley. Asheesh currently serves on the boards of Bitso and MoneyGram, and was featured in Fortune Magazine’s The Ledger 40 under 40 in 2018."],"entity":[{"type":"Mauritania","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2010","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2013","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Lisa","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Global Accelerated Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Corporate Development","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"fintech","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Apifiny","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Peace Corps","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ripple","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"SDF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SDF Lisa","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Thomson Reuters","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2005","content":"DATE"},{"type":"MoneyGram","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DTCC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Birla – SVP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UCLA Anderson","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SunGard (FIS","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Brown Brothers Harriman","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SVP of Product and Corporate Development","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thomas Trepanier","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Wednesday October","content":"DATE"},{"type":"India","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Silicon Valley","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Bank of New York Mellon","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Head of Business Development","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"VP of Global Technology","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sponsored","The Block"]}