{"summary":"A fresh request from former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried to get out of jail was denied by a court of appeals.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/264375\/court-denies-sam-bankman-frieds-latest-request-for-release","publishDate":"2023-11-22T13:20:45","id":3484,"type":null,"title":"Court denies Sam Bankman-Fried&#x27;s latest request for release","category":["LEGAL"],"content":["The U.S. Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit denied the latest attempt for release by Sam Bankman-Fried, and he'll have to stay in jail as his lawyers try and appeal his case.","\"We have reviewed the Defendant-Appellant's additional arguments and find them unpersuasive,\" Clerk of Court Catherine O’Hagan Wolfe wrote in a letter dated Nov. 21. The court pointed out that Bankman-Fried had tried to tamper with two witnesses ahead of his original trial.","\"The record shows that the district court thoroughly considered all of the relevant factors, including the Defendant-Appellant's course of conduct over time that had required the district court to repeatedly tighten the conditions of release,\" the court <a href=\"https:\/\/storage.courtlistener.com\/recap\/gov.uscourts.nysd.590940\/gov.uscourts.nysd.590940.348.0.pdf\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ruled<\/a>.&nbsp;","After a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/tag\/sbf-trial\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">month-long trial<\/a>, Bankman-Fried was <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/261240\/sam-bankman-fried-convicted-on-all-counts-report\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">found guilty<\/a> on Nov. 2 by a jury on seven criminal counts of defrauding&nbsp; customers, lenders, and investors of FTX. He is awaiting sentencing scheduled for March 28.","The disgraced former CEO was initially put under <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/201323\/unemployed-and-under-house-arrest-sam-bankman-fried-faces-enormous-legal-bills\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">house arrest<\/a> at his parents' residence in Palo Alto, California in January, but in October the court <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/244540\/ftx-judge-says-hes-revoking-bail-for-bankman-fried-inner-city-press\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">revoked<\/a> his bail after he leaked Caroline Ellison's diary to the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.nytimes.com\/2023\/07\/20\/technology\/ftx-caroline-ellison-bankman-fried.html\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">New York Times<\/a>, texted witnesses and spoke to the press while awaiting his trial.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Palo Alto","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Appellant","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York Times","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. Court of Appeals","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Caroline Ellison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"March 28","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Second Circuit","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Catherine O’Hagan Wolfe","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"California","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nov. 2","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Nov. 21","content":"DATE"},{"type":"October","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["FTX","SBF TRIAL"],"authors":["Anna Baydakova","The Block"]}