{"summary":"Mastercard made its latest crypto play on Tuesday as it partnered with BitOasis to bring customers in the Middle East and North Africa crypto-linked payment cards.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/179691\/bitoasis-inks-deal-with-mastercard-to-launch-crypto-linked-payment-cards","publishDate":"2022-10-25T11:00:01","id":3497,"type":null,"title":"BitOasis inks deal with Mastercard to launch crypto-linked payment cards","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Cryptocurrency exchange BitOasis is partnering with Mastercard to offer customers crypto-linked payment cards.","BitOasis will offer physical and virtual cards linked to their exchange accounts, <a href=\"https:\/\/blog.bitoasis.net\/mastercard-and-bitoasis-sign-strategic-partnership-across-mena-to-launch-crypto-linked-cards\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">according<\/a> to a statement from the firm. The first cards are set to launch in early 2023.","The crypto-linked payment cards will be available to BitOasis customers across the Middle East and North Africa (MENA). Final settlement will be fiat-based, per the announcement.","Today's announcement represents Mastercard's latest crypto play, having <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/142286\/nexo-offers-payment-card-allowing-users-to-retain-their-crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">partnered<\/a> with crypto lender <a href=\"https:\/\/nexo.io\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Nexo<\/a> in April to offer a similar crypto-backed payment card. The Nexo card is linked to a crypto-backed credit line, allowing investors to spend as much as 90% of the fiat value of their crypto assets.&nbsp;","In 2021, the firm <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/123596\/mastercard-to-launch-crypto-linked-payment-cards-in-asia-pacific\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">partnered<\/a> with several firms across the Asia Pacific, including Amber Group, CoinJar, and Siam Commercial bank-owned exchange platform Bitkub to offer crypto-linked payment cards.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Middle East","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"90%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"fiat","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mastercard","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Amber Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nexo","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Asia Pacific","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"North Africa","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Siam Commercial","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}