{"summary":"The Treasury has staked out its vision for crypto policy, sort of.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/141097\/treasury-secretary-yellen-lays-out-principles-for-cryptocurrency-regulation","publishDate":"2022-04-07T11:27:48","id":3555,"type":null,"title":"Treasury Secretary Yellen lays out principles for cryptocurrency regulation","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Treasury has staked out its vision for crypto policy, sort of.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">On April 7, Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen gave a speech on digital assets — the <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/141010\/treasury-secretary-yellens-first-speech-on-crypto-will-focus-on-existing-laws-except-for-stablecoins\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">first of its kind during her term<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. The speech is an early response to <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/136883\/janet-yellen-says-bidens-crypto-executive-order-supports-responsible-innovation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">President Biden’s March executive order<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> calling for agencies to coordinate efforts on cryptocurrency policy. In that respect, it is the first response of its kind from any agency.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Speaking at American University’s Don Myers Technology &amp; Innovation Building, Yellen took the stage to Stevie Wonder’s Superstition and left to Creedence Clearwater Revival’s Have You Ever Seen the Rain, setting up a notable contrast between a sleek contemporary lecture hall and 50-year-old pieces of Americana.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Yellen’s speech featured no bombshells — indeed, it seemed careful not to alarm stakeholders in the cryptocurrency industry. Instead, she carefully framed cryptocurrencies and her prognosis for their regulation in relation to historical parallels.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Casting back to Alexander Hamilton and the private banknotes that precipitated the National Banking Act under Lincoln, Yellen affirmed “A crisis catalyzed reform.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">What does this mean in the context of cryptocurrencies? Like others in the administration — most conspicuously <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/117675\/crypto-lending-staking-custody-gensler-sec\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Securities and Exchange Commission Chair Gary Gensler<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> — have suggested, cryptocurrencies and the firms that handle them largely fall under existing statutory categories.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Digital assets may be new, but many of the issues they present are not. We have enjoyed the benefits of innovation in the past, and we have also confronted some of the&nbsp; unintended consequences,” said Yellen, explaining:<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“The principle of tech neutrality is also applicable to concerns related to tax evasion, illicit&nbsp; finance, and national security – topics that are particularly pertinent in the world today. It’s <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">illegal to evade taxes, launder money, or avoid sanctions. It doesn’t matter whether you’re using&nbsp; checks, wires, or cryptocurrency.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Despite this, Yellen maintained the <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/122890\/us-treasury-releases-long-awaited-report-on-stablecoin-risk-features-request-for-new-laws\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">President’s Working Group’s push for new legislation<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> when it comes to stablecoins. She did not, however, explicitly support the PWG’s original push to restrict stablecoin issuance to insured depository institutions.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Treasury in general and Yellen, in particular, have had a busy week. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">On Wednesday, she appeared before the <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/140892\/congresswoman-calls-yellen-to-account-for-work-on-targeting-crypto-in-russian-sanctions-evasion\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">House Financial Services Committee to testify<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on the state of international finance, a conversation that focused heavily on the Treasury’s sanctions on Russia. The day before, the Treasury <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/140739\/us-sanctions-worlds-largest-darknet-market-and-linked-russian-crypto-exchange\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">sanctioned Russia-based darknet market Hydra<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> and associated crypto exchange Garantex, an action that Yellen made mentioned in her two subsequent appearances.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Working Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Janet Yellen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"American University’s Don Myers Technology &amp; Innovation Building","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gary Gensler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Creedence Clearwater Revival","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"PWG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lincoln","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Russia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"April 7","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alexander Hamilton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"House Financial Services Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Biden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Yellen","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["JANET YELLEN"],"authors":["Kollen Post","The Block"]}