{"summary":"FTX founder Sam Bankman-Fried supports knowledge tests and disclosures beyond cryptocurrency derivatives markets.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/177461\/ftx-ceo-backs-knowledge-test-for-trading-wide-range-of-derivatives","publishDate":"2022-10-15T19:57:36","id":3556,"type":null,"title":"FTX CEO backs knowledge test for trading wide range of derivatives","category":["POLICY"],"content":["FTX founder Sam Bankman-Fried seems to be in agreement with Commodity Futures Trading Commission’s (CFTC’s) Christy Goldsmith Romero over disclosures and knowledge tests for derivatives trading, but said they need not be constrained to digital currencies.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The comments come as CFTC officials weigh in on proper oversight and regulation for crypto.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">FTX’s Sam Bankman-Fried agrees with CFTC Commissioner Christy Goldsmith Romero over the benefits of disclosures and knowledge tests for trading, but took to Twitter to add they need not be crypto-specific.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bankman-Fried’s comments came in response to those of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission official, who called for the establishment of a household retail investor category to provide additional consumer protections.&nbsp;<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","\"Establishing a household retail investor category could give them more consumer protections. For example, disclosures written in a way that regular people understand or could be used when weighing rules on the use of leverage,\" Romero tweeted.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“100% agree on disclosures, knowledge tests, etc.,” Bankman-Fried tweeted in response, adding that such tests need not be relegated solely to digital currencies. <br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Disclosure mandates and knowledge-based tests for a wide-range of intermediaries like futures commissions merchants and could make sense, according to the billionaire.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bankman-Fried’s statements on disclosure and testing coincides with FTX's <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.reuters.com\/business\/finance\/ftx-chief-welcomes-more-regulation-cftc-weighs-its-crypto-derivatives-proposal-2022-04-28\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">bid<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to launch a U.S. &nbsp;crypto futures. Indeed, FTX already <a href=\"https:\/\/ftx.us\/derivs\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">outlined<\/a> a proposed knowledge test for its U.S. derivatives product, the founder <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/SBF_FTX\/status\/1581413040943116288?s=20&amp;t=8h2NOwvfuyDLVcgTij4T3A\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweeted<\/a>.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">As the debate over crypto-related consumer protections, and how lawmakers should codify guidelines continues, lately the CFTC indicated it would not be lax towards crypto. CFTC Chair Rostin Behnam <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/177367\/dont-expect-the-cftc-to-be-light-touch-if-it-gains-crypto-oversight-power-says-benham\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">expressed<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> a desire for more direct authority over marketplaces.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The position held by Behnam falls in line with statements from Securities and Exchange Commission leader Gary Gensler, who <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/177224\/gensler-supports-granting-cftc-more-power-over-spot-markets\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">indicated<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> the CTFC could have greater authority over certain digital currencies during a speech at Georgetown University's Financial Markets Quality Conference in Washington.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Romero","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Washington","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Rostin Behnam","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Christy Goldsmith Romero","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Georgetown University's Financial Markets Quality Conference","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"100%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Gary Gensler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Commodity Futures Trading Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"CFTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["CFTC"],"authors":["Jeremy Nation","The Block"]}