{"summary":"On July 27th Frank Chaparro hosted the third installment of The Exchange, The Block&#x27;s APAC focused webinar series.   In this installment, Frank was joined by panelists from major companies from both East and West to explore a single question: How investments interest from the West impacts the East.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/73250\/the-exchange-institutional-investments-from-east-to-west-full-webinar","publishDate":"2020-07-29T14:03:43","id":3566,"type":null,"title":"The Exchange - Institutional Investments from East to West | Full Webinar","category":["THE BLOCK"],"content":["On July 27th Frank Chaparro hosted the third installment of The Exchange, The Block’s APAC focused webinar series.&nbsp;","In this installment, Frank was joined by panelists from major companies from both East and West to explore a single question: How investment interest from the West impacts the East.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Our Panelists:&nbsp;<\/strong><\/span>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Michael Sonnenshein<\/strong> – Managing Director, Grayscale Investments","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Dong (Daniel) Yan<\/strong> – COO, Matrixport","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kyle Davies<\/strong> – Co-founder &amp; Chairman, Three Arrows Capital","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Seth Ginns<\/strong> – Head of Liquid Investments &amp; Managing Partner, CoinFund","You can view the webinar in its entirety below:","<iframe src=\"https:\/\/www.youtube.com\/embed\/cs1C4t5oqI0\" width=\"560\" height=\"315\" frameborder=\"0\" allowfullscreen=\"allowfullscreen\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Matrixport","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Daniel) Yan<\/strong> – COO","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kyle Davies","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"APAC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Grayscale Investments","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Head of Liquid Investments &amp; Managing Partner","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Seth Ginns","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"East","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"East and West","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Michael Sonnenshein","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["The Block","The Block"]}