{"summary":"San Bankman-Fried’s parents allegedly directed at least $5.5 million in donations to their employer Stanford University.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/251956\/stanford-university-plans-to-return-millions-of-dollars-received-from-ftx-bloomberg","publishDate":"2023-09-20T02:35:01","id":3575,"type":null,"title":"Stanford University plans to return millions of dollars received from FTX: Bloomberg","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stanford University said it plans to return the “gifts” worth millions of dollars it received from bankrupt cryptocurrency exchange FTX, according to a Bloomberg report.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A spokesperson for the university <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2023-09-19\/stanford-says-will-return-entirety-of-gifts-received-from-ftx\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">told Bloomberg<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that it has been “in discussions with attorneys for the FTX debtors to recover these gifts and we will be returning the funds in their entirety.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stanford’s comment comes after FTX <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/251658\/ftx-sues-sbf-parents\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">sued the parents of FTX founder Sam Bankman-Fried<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> — Joseph Bankman and Barbara Fried — on Monday, aiming to recover millions of dollars in “fraudulently transferred and misappropriated funds.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“From November 2021 to May 2022, Bankman led the charge in directing FTX Group donations of more than $5.5 million to his employer, Stanford University,” a Monday court filing said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Stanford spokesperson said that the university received gifts from the FTX Foundation and FTX-related entities — mainly for pandemic-related prevention and research, according to the report.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The court filing showed that Bankman and Fried, both Stanford Law School professors, allegedly “exploited their access and influence” within FTX to enrich themselves by millions of dollars.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bankman and Fried allegedly pushed for tens of millions of dollars in political and charitable contributions, including to Stanford University, “which were seemingly designed to boost Bankman’s and Fried’s professional and social status at the expense of the FTX Group,” the filing said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In response to the complaint, the legal representatives to Bankman-Fried's parents <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/251778\/legal-representatives-of-sbfs-parents-say-ftxs-claims-are-completely-false\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said the claims were “completely false.”<\/span><\/a>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“This is a dangerous attempt to intimidate Joe and Barbara and undermine the jury process just days before their child’s trial begins. These claims are completely false,\" Sean Hecker, counsel to Joe Bankman, and Michael Tremonte, counsel for Barbara Fried, told The Block.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Mr. Ray and his massive team of lawyers, who are collectively running up countless millions of dollars in fees while returning relatively little to FTX clients, know better,\" they said.<\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ray","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Stanford University","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sean Hecker","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$5.5 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"millions of dollars","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Michael Tremonte","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Joseph Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"November 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Stanford spokesperson","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Barbara","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Joe Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"May 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Barbara Fried","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Barbara Fried —","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Stanford Law School","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"tens of millions of dollars","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Joe","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX Foundation","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BANKRUPTCY FILINGS","FTX","SAM BANKMAN-FRIED"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}