{"summary":"Two of the hottest projects working on institutional crypto trading platforms have been building out their teams, The Block has learned. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/1806\/bakkt-and-erisx-staff-up-as-institutional-crypto-gets-ready-to-hit-wall-street","publishDate":"2018-10-16T12:52:50","id":3582,"type":null,"title":"Bakkt and ErisX staff up as institutional crypto gets ready to hit Wall Street","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Two of the hottest projects working on institutional crypto trading platforms have been building out their teams,&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block&nbsp;<\/em>has learned.&nbsp;<\/span>","Intercontinental<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;Exchange's Bakkt and ErisX, a Chicago-based firm, both have ambitions to dominate the institutional market for cryptocurrency trading. Bakkt, which was announced with much fanfare in August, is looking to launch a market for trading physically delivered bitcoin futures, whereas ErisX is aiming to launch its platform for crypto trading by Q2 of 2019. It has&nbsp;<\/span>aspirations<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;to launch a derivatives market on top of the spot market. A source close to Bakkt told this reporter that the firm's first day of trading for its product will be December 12. Originally the firm was planning a November launch. Both ErisX and Bakkt count a long list of major Wall Street firms as backers.&nbsp;<\/span>","[related id = 1]In the meantime, the two firms are building out their teams, sources close to the company's operations tell&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block<\/em>.&nbsp;At Bakkt, Adam White is set to join the company as chief operating officer, as&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block<\/em> first reported<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.&nbsp;<\/i>White, who previously led Coinbase's institutional efforts, reports to Bakkt CEO Kelly&nbsp;Loeffler. Brian Cooper, a 10-year ICE veteran, has also joined the project's team, a person familiar with the situation told this reporter, as director of operations. Laura Edelman, a financial sales representative, is also focusing on the launch of Bakkt's futures product. A person familiar with the firm's operations said the marketplace would start off small with only a few clients trading.&nbsp;","Still, the source said: \"Sprecher has a track record of overcoming the impossible so there is hope,\" referring to ICE chief executive Jeff Sprecher. Sprecher is the husband of Bakkt CEO Loffler.&nbsp;","ErisX announced Tuesday three new members of its team:","The team is mostly made up of employees of Eris Exchange, the precursor of the new crypto platform. ErisX was announced in September.&nbsp;","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The post has been updated to correct Michael Piracci's title. He joined ErisX as senior counsel, not chief compliance officer.<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Bakkt","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"December 12","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bakkt","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Eris Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kelly&nbsp;Loeffler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bakkt","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Loffler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Adam White","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jeff Sprecher","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sprecher","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Michael Piracci","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Intercontinental<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chicago","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Brian Cooper","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Laura Edelman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}