{"summary":"The latest webinar from The Block Research brought together DeFi stakeholders from around the world to discuss the latest trends.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/75208\/defi-east-west-research-webinar","publishDate":"2020-08-19T12:07:30","id":3615,"type":null,"title":"The Exchange: DeFi Trading from East to West | Full Video","category":["WEBINAR"],"content":["In this new webinar, The Block’s Director of Research Larry Cermak was joined by industry executives who explored the DeFi trading trends from East to West.","The panelists discussed the recent DeFi boom and their thoughts on developing trends, including:&nbsp;","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Panelists:&nbsp;<\/b>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Matthew Graham<\/strong> – CEO, Sino Global Capital","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Andrew Kang<\/strong> – Managing Partner, Mechanism Capital","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Kyle Davies<\/strong> – Co-founder, Three Arrows Capital","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Flex Yang<\/strong> – CEO, Babel Finance","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Sam Bankman-Fried<\/strong> – CEO, FTX &amp; Alameda Research","You can watch the video in it's entirety below:&nbsp;","<iframe src=\"https:\/\/www.youtube.com\/embed\/Qqc5feBccBw\" width=\"560\" height=\"315\" frameborder=\"0\" allowfullscreen=\"allowfullscreen\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"The Block’s Director of Research Larry Cermak","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kyle Davies","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX &amp; Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Andrew Kang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Babel Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"West","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sino Global Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Matthew Graham","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["The Block","The Block"]}