{"summary":"WhaleFin, the flagship digital asset platform of Amber Group, announced a partnership with a leading non-profit organization, Whale and Dolphin Conservation (“WDC”).","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/130511\/whalefin-partners-with-non-profit-organization-whale-and-dolphin-conservation","publishDate":"2022-01-18T08:00:43","id":3618,"type":null,"title":"WhaleFin Partners with Non-Profit Organization Whale and Dolphin Conservation","category":["SPONSORED"],"content":["<a href=\"https:\/\/www.whalefin.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">WhaleFin<\/a>, the flagship digital asset platform of <a href=\"http:\/\/www.ambergroup.io\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Amber Group<\/a>, announced a partnership with a leading non-profit organization, Whale and Dolphin Conservation (“WDC”). As part of the partnership, WhaleFin adopted a 46-year-old female humpback whale named Salt, widely known as the most famous whale in the world.","\nThis collaboration comes on the heels of Amber Group’s recent launch of WhaleFin, an “all-in-one” digital asset platform positioned to empower diverse market participants of all backgrounds to build and manage wealth in a continuously transforming digital era.","\nAs an integral part of Amber Group’s larger <a href=\"https:\/\/www.whalefin.com\/web\/sustainability?client_language=en-US\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">sustainability initiative<\/a>, WhaleFin is committed to leveraging the power of the crypto industry and collaborating with organizations and institutions worldwide to promote industry-wide climate action and increase awareness for whales and dolphins’ protection.","\n“Partnering up with WDC was an easy decision after learning about their mission and all the great things they do. At Amber Group, we strive to maintain supportive environmental governance standards while expanding upon our digital asset products with longevity and sustainability in mind,” said Michael Wu, CEO of Amber Group and WhaleFin Product Lead. “Our company’s success is inextricably linked to the sustainability of the world, and we want to utilize our platform to help make a difference for whales and dolphins that play a vital role in the marine ecosystem.”","\nWhaleFin’s collaboration with WDC is one of Amber Group’s key milestones in helping create a more sustainable planet.","\nLast October, Amber Group solidified a <a href=\"https:\/\/ambcrypto.com\/amber-group-partners-with-moss-earth-to-buy-2m-carbon-offsets\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">strategic partnership<\/a> with climate tech company Moss Earth to help combat climate change. Amber Group purchased $2 million worth of Moss Carbon MCO2 tokens, approximately enough to offset the cost of over 280,000 bitcoin transactions. <br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nWhile the partnership between WhaleFin and WDC makes overcoming the ongoing battle to ensure funding for research, maintenance of habitat protection, and marine wildlife conservation one step closer, there is still much work to be done.","\n“We need to protect and restore the ocean as if our lives depend on it, because they do,” said Chris Butler-Stroud, Chief Executive at WDC. “With the support from companies like Amber Group, we can scale up our conservation work to support ocean-based solutions to the climate crisis and in doing so, protect every whale for their sake and ours.”","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About WhaleFin<\/strong><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nWhaleFin is the flagship digital asset platform powered by the fintech unicorn Amber Group. Founded in 2017, Amber Group operates globally with offices in Asia, Europe, and the Americas. The firm provides a full range of digital asset services spanning investing, financing, and trading. Amber Group is backed by prominent investors including Paradigm, Dragonfly, Pantera, Polychain, Sequoia, and Tiger Global. For more information, visit www.whalefin.com.","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Whale and Dolphin Conservation<\/strong><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nWhale and Dolphin Conservation (WDC) is the leading charity dedicated to the protection of whales and dolphins. WDC has thirty years’ experience funding vital conservation, education, and research projects around the globe. WDC is a Registered Charity in England and Wales with the number 1014705 and Scotland with the number SC040231. For more information, visit https:\/\/uk.whales.org."],"entity":[{"type":"WhaleFin Product Lead","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Polychain","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tiger Global","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Amber Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"England","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Stroud","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Asia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Chris Butler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Dolphin Conservation<\/strong><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nWhale","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dragonfly","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Moss Earth","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Pantera","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sequoia","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"WDC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Michael Wu","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"fintech unicorn Amber Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wales","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$2 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Scotland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Americas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Dolphin Conservation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"October","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Moss Carbon","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sponsored","The Block"]}