{"summary":"Crypto prices were mostly flat on the day, declining slightly after the market opened. Bitcoin&#x27;s 30-day volatility reached its highest point since early December.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/205046\/investor-jeremy-grantham-dismisses-bitcoins-latest-rally-as-crypto-prices-tread-water","publishDate":"2023-01-24T11:36:45","id":3626,"type":null,"title":"Investor Jeremy Grantham dismisses bitcoin&#x27;s latest rally as crypto prices tread water","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["Cryptocurrency prices meandered in early trading, with bitcoin unable to break past $23,000 on a consistent basis. Crypto stocks were marginally lower.&nbsp;","Bitcoin gained 0.1% in the past day to $22,900 at 11:15 a.m. EST, according to TradingView data. BNB is bucking the trend, up 3.4% over the past 24 hours.","","","Bitcoin's 30-day volatility reached its highest point since early December when it reached 42.2%, according to The Block's data. The Block defines volatility as the standard deviation of the last 30 days' daily percentage change in BTC price.","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/crypto-markets\/prices\/annualized-btc-volatility-30d\/embed\" title=\"Annualized BTC Volatility (30D)\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Ether declined marginally, down 0.2% around $1,620, and Cardano slid 0.4%. Avalanche jumped 3.2%, according to data from CoinGecko.","The global crypto market cap continues to trade above $1 trillion, according to The Block's data.&nbsp;","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/crypto-markets\/prices\/crypto-total-marketcap\/embed\" title=\"Crypto Total Marketcap\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","The recent rally caught the eye of chief investment strategist of Grantham, Mayo, &amp; van Otterloo Jeremy Grantham, who sees a 17% downside for the S&amp;P 500, which is up 5% year-to-date.&nbsp;","The increase in crypto prices isn't down to any \"exotic\" reasons, Grantham said. It's likely this is just \"crypto’s usual style of behaving like the most speculative stocks, almost all of which had a terrible 2022.\"","Crypto-related stocks traded lower in early trading. Coinbase was down 1.7%, as of 11:10 a.m. EST, according to Nasdaq data.","Shares in crypto-friendly bank Silvergate dipped 1.7%, to about $15.70, after <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/204795\/bitcoin-mining-stocks-rise-while-silvergate-shares-soar\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">soaring<\/a> 17% during Monday's session.","MicroStrategy dropped 0.3% to about $250, and Jack Dorsey's Block slipped 0.6% to around $81.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"42.2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Mayo","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Grantham","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"11:10 a.m. EST","content":"TIME"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"3.4%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"S&amp;P","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"3.2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"0.3%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"0.1%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"11:15 a.m. EST","content":"TIME"},{"type":"17%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$1 trillion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$81","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Cardano","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"1.7%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Otterloo Jeremy Grantham","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"0.6%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"0.4%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"December","content":"DATE"},{"type":"0.2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$1,620","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Jack Dorsey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$23,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$22,900","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Grantham","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$15.70","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"MicroStrategy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$250","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Nasdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE","BITCOIN","BNB","CARDANO","COINBASE","EARNINGS","ECONOMIC INDICATORS","EQUITY MOVERS","ETHEREUM"],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","Sam Venis","The Block"]}