{"summary":"More millennials hold a bitcoin-tied investment product in their investment portfolios than Netflix stock, according to a recent report from brokerage","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/49451\/bitcoin-more-popular-than-netflix-stock-among-millennials-gbtc-one-of-their-top-5-equity-holdings","publishDate":"2019-12-06T01:45:06","id":3648,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin more popular than Netflix stock among millennials; GBTC one of their top 5 equity holdings","category":["BITCOIN"],"content":["More millennials hold a bitcoin-tied investment product in their investment portfolios than Netflix stock, according to a recent report from brokerage giant Charles Schwab.","The report, <a href=\"https:\/\/pressroom.aboutschwab.com\/press-release\/schwab-corporate-retirement-services-news\/schwab-report-self-directed-401k-balances-ho\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">published<\/a> Wednesday, showed that millennials (currently <a href=\"https:\/\/www.kasasa.com\/articles\/generations\/gen-x-gen-y-gen-z\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">aged<\/a> between 25-39) have a higher holding in Grayscale’s Bitcoin Trust (GBTC) investment product at 1.84% than Netflix stock at 1.58%. Schwab publishes this report every quarter and collects data from nearly 142,000 retirement plan participants who currently have balances between $5,000 and $10 million in their Schwab Personal Choice Retirement Account.","GBTC is also more popular than stocks of Warren Buffett’s conglomerate Berkshire Hathaway, Walt Disney, Microsoft, and Alibaba.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; Top 10 equity holdings across generations&nbsp;<\/strong>","","","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">GBTC<\/strong><\/span><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nDigital Currency Group-owned Grayscale <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/47476\/grayscale-makes-bet-that-more-government-oversight-will-lure-billions-to-its-crypto-fund\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">launched<\/a> GBTC in 2013 as a private placement to accredited investors and, in 2015, received approval from the Financial Industry Regulatory Authority (FINRA) to offer publicly-traded shares.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nGBTC is arguably the most successful cryptocurrency investment product, which<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/daily\/43598\/preview\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> saw<\/a> a total cumulative inflow of $304.4 million for the 12 months ending in September. Grayscale once also filed for a bitcoin exchange-traded product (ETF) in 2017, but later that year withdrew its application as the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) rejected the Winklevoss Brothers’ bitcoin ETF.","To date, the SEC has not approved any <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/tag\/bitcoin-etf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">bitcoin ETF<\/a> proposal, citing market manipulation and fraudulent activity concerns. However, if the regulator ever approves one, GBTC and other bitcoin investment products could lose traction, some market observers <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/daily\/43598\/preview\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">told The Block<\/a> last month.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Gen X and baby boomers?<\/strong>","Notably, GBTC is not in the top 10 equity holdings by Gen X (currently <a href=\"https:\/\/www.kasasa.com\/articles\/generations\/gen-x-gen-y-gen-z\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">aged<\/a> between 40-54 years) and baby boomers (55-75 years). Both the generations’ top three equity holdings are Apple, Amazon and Berkshire Hathaway stocks, per the Schwab’s report.","The average account balance for all participants in the third quarter of 2019 was $276,929, nearly identical to the $276,547 from the previous quarter and 1% above the average balance from the third quarter of 2018 ($275,362), per the report. Baby Boomers had the highest account balances at an average of $394,064, followed by Gen X at $213,018, and millennials at $68,756.","Schwab is currently the biggest investment brokerage firm in the U.S. with $3.2 trillion in assets under management. Just last month, the company announced that it is <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/48328\/brokerage-giant-charles-schwab-set-to-acquire-crypto-friendly-rival-td-ameritrade-for-26b\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">set to acquire<\/a> crypto-friendly rival TD Ameritrade for $26 billion. The deal is expected to close in the second half of 2020 and the combined entity will manage over $5 trillion in client assets and serve 24 million client accounts.","Schwab and TD Ameritrade have two very different approaches to the cryptocurrency market; the former doesn’t yet allow any crypto trading services, while the latter offers trading in bitcoin futures via derivatives exchange giant CME Group and is also an investor in crypto exchange ErisX. The Block recently reported that the Schwab-TD deal <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/daily\/48467\/charles-schwabs-26b-takeover-of-tdameritrade-casts-uncertainty-over-crypto-trading-ambitions\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">could cast doubt<\/a> on the potential for crypto trading on TD and may also impact ErisX.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Amazon","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CME Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Schwab","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"second half of 2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"1.58%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Berkshire Hathaway","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Warren Buffett","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$5 trillion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"TD Ameritrade","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$276,547","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2015","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ameritrade","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2013","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Netflix","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Financial Industry Regulatory Authority (FINRA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Schwab","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Schwab Personal Choice Retirement Account","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$304.4 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$275,362","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$276,929","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Winklevoss Brothers’ bitcoin ETF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Charles Schwab","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Microsoft","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$3.2 trillion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"last month","content":"DATE"},{"type":"1.84%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"54 years","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$10 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$68,756","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"39","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$5,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Alibaba","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$26 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"75","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$394,064","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Digital Currency Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Walt Disney","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$213,018","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"1%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"third quarter of 2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"third quarter of 2019","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Yogita Khatri","The Block"]}