{"summary":"Bitcoin was lower but trading above $16,100, while ether also slipped, down to about $1,170, according to CoinGecko.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/190258\/bitcoin-ether-track-traditional-markets-lower-amid-china-covid-restrictions-unrest","publishDate":"2022-11-28T08:47:03","id":3660,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin, ether track traditional markets lower amid China Covid restrictions, unrest","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["Bitcoin and ether slipped more than 2% at 8:30 a.m. ET, tracking traditional markets lower, spooked by unrest in China over protests against Covid-19 restrictions.","Bitcoin was lower but trading above $16,100, while ether also slipped, down to about $1,170, according to CoinGecko.","","","&nbsp;","People have taken to the streets in a number of Chinese cities to protest against the government after a house fire in Xinjiang killed 10. Citizens are blaming Covid restrictions for a delay in responding to the blaze.","U.S. equity futures are lower on the news. Coinbase dropped more than 2% in pre-market trading alongside Silvergate, which fell nearly 5%, and Block, down 1.5%.","Markets will be watching for indications of future rate increases as St. Louis Fed President James Bullard and New York Fed President John Williams speak later today.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$16,100","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Xinjiang","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"19","content":"DATE"},{"type":"5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"1.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"St. Louis Fed","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"8:30 a.m. ET","content":"TIME"},{"type":"$1,170","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"New York Fed","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CoinGecko","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"John Williams","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"China","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"James Bullard","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Christiana Loureiro","The Block"]}