{"summary":"In this episode of Policy Scoop, host Aislinn Keely speaks with Taras Kulyk of mining firm Core Scientific and New York Assembly Member Clyde Vanel for a deep dive into the policy dialogues around mining, from the federal level down to local communities.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/148533\/policy-scoop-with-aislinn-keely-crypto-meets-real-world-concerns-in-mining-policy-discussion","publishDate":"2022-05-25T06:00:40","id":3665,"type":null,"title":"Policy Scoop with Aislinn Keely: Crypto meets real world concerns in mining policy discussion","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">45<\/strong><\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 4 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block’s Aislinn Keely and Core Scientific SVP of Growth Taras Kulyk &amp; NYS Assemblyman Clyde Vanel.<\/i><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"c5b5aaa1a6a4b6b185b1ada0a7a9aaa6aea6b7bcb5b1aaeba6aaa8\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK4908343781\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/i><\/span>","Much of the policy conversation surrounding crypto is concerned with Wall Street-minded issues that mostly take place in the digital world – investor protection, cybersecurity, licensure to provide online financial services. But the policy conversation surrounding proof-of-work mining is asking crypto to contend with real-world issues. Mining firms are answering to environmental narratives, concerns of noise pollution and questions as to how a data center can better a community.","This episode of Policy Scoop takes a deep dive into the policy dialogues around mining, from the federal level down to local communities. Host Aislinn Keely sits down with Taras Kulyk, Senior VP of Growth at mining firm Core Scientific, to talk about regulators' and lawmakers' views on proof-of-work mining and how the industry is meeting those concerns.&nbsp;","\"It all boils down to the executive order from the Biden administration that's dealing with a wide swath of things. But the environmental impact kind of became the key rallying mark for digital asset miners in the United States,\" said Kulyk. \"The good thing is, is it seems like there's a lot of misinformation that can be very easily quelled and dealt with within Washington, specifically that for some reason, legislators think that digital miners produce CO2.\"","New York Assembly Member Clyde Vanel also joins the show to talk about the proposed mining moratorium in the state, and why he thinks it's not the answer to environmental concerns. Vanel shares how he's seen mining firms positively shape some of New York's communities, and why he's hopeful for its role in the state.","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In this episode of Policy Scoop, Keely also chats with Kulyk and Vanel on:<\/em>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors <a href=\"http:\/\/www.fireblocks.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Fireblocks<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/coinbase.com\/prime\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Coinbase Prime<\/a>&nbsp;&amp;&nbsp;<a href=\"http:\/\/crossriver.com\/crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Cross River<\/a><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/b><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Fireblocks is an enterprise-grade platform delivering a secure infrastructure for moving, storing, and issuing digital assets. Fireblocks enables exchanges, lending desks, custodians, banks, trading desks, and hedge funds to securely scale digital asset operations through the Fireblocks Network and MPC-based Wallet Infrastructure. Fireblocks serves over 725 financial institutions, has secured the transfer of over $1.5 trillion in digital assets, and has a unique insurance policy that covers assets in storage &amp; transit. For more information, please visit&nbsp;<a href=\"http:\/\/www.fireblocks.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">www.fireblocks.com<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Coinbase Prime<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Coinbase Prime is an integrated solution that provides institutional investors with an advanced trading platform, secure custody, and prime services to manage all their crypto assets in one place. Coinbase Prime fully integrates crypto trading and custody on a single platform, and gives clients the best all-in pricing in their network using their proprietary Smart Order Router and algorithmic execution. For more information, visit&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/coinbase.com\/prime\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">www.coinbase.com\/prime<\/a>.<\/em>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Cross River<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/b><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Cross River is powering today’s most innovative crypto companies, with banking and payments solutions you can rely on, including fiat on\/off ramp solutions. Whether you are a crypto exchange, NFT marketplace, or wallet, Cross River’s API-based, all-in-one platform enables banking as a service, ACH &amp; wire transfers, push-to-card disbursements, real-time payments, and virtual accounts and subledgers. Request your fiat on\/off ramp solution now at <a href=\"http:\/\/crossriver.com\/crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">crossriver.com\/crypto<\/a>.<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"New York Assembly Member Clyde Vanel","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1.5 trillion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Coinbase Prime<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Coinbase Prime","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cross River","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Washington","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Aislinn Keely","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kulyk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Keely","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Cross River<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/b><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Cross River","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Policy Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Taras Kulyk","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Core Scientific SVP of Growth Taras Kulyk &amp; NYS Assemblyman Clyde Vanel","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fireblocks Network","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MPC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Biden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Coinbase Prime<\/a>&nbsp;&amp;&nbsp;<a href=\"http:\/\/crossriver.com\/crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Cross River<\/a><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/b><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Fireblocks","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"United States","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN","MINING"],"authors":["Aislinn Keely","The Block"]}