{"summary":"The Wall Street Journal reported that CZ plans to step down and plead guilty to violating criminal U.S. anti-money laundering requirements.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/264044\/binance-ceo-cz-is-in-talks-about-stepping-down-forbes","publishDate":"2023-11-21T12:09:24","id":3666,"type":null,"title":"Binance CEO Changpeng &#x27;CZ&#x27; Zhao plans to step down: reports","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Changpeng 'CZ' Zhao, the CEO of the crypto exchange giant Binance, is in talks about stepping down, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.forbes.com\/sites\/davidjeans\/2023\/11\/21\/binance-ceo-cz-in-discussions-to-step-down-as-criminal-investigation-ends\/?sh=8cc91124acac\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Forbes<\/a> reported, citing a source familiar with the matter.&nbsp;","The New York Times reported that Zhao agreed to plead guilty to money laundering violations, citing court papers. As part of the plea, he will pay a $50 million fine and will also step down, the paper <a href=\"https:\/\/www.nytimes.com\/2023\/11\/21\/technology\/binance-changpeng-zhao-pleads-guilty.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a>, saying he's barred from future involvement in the company.&nbsp;","The Wall Street Journal <a href=\"https:\/\/www.wsj.com\/finance\/currencies\/binance-ceo-changpeng-zhao-step-down-plead-guilty-01f72a40\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a> separately that Zhao plans to step down. The deal could preserve the company’s ability to continue operating, the WSJ cited sources as saying.&nbsp;","A departure could come as part of a $4 billion settlement the firm is negotiating with the U.S. Department of Justice, Forbes added. On Monday, Bloomberg reported that the DOJ was seeking billions to end its years-long investigation of the firm.&nbsp;","Longtime executive Richard Teng, currently Binance's head of regional markets outside the U.S., is being considered to take the role, Forbes <a href=\"https:\/\/www.forbes.com\/sites\/davidjeans\/2023\/11\/21\/richard-teng-a-top-contender-for-new-binance-ceo-as-cz-steps-down\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a>, citing sources.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance's <span class=\"articleTooltip\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"\/price\/248351\/bnb-bnb-usd\" class=\"articleTooltip__link\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"><img src=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2023\/10\/bnb-icon2_2x.png\" alt=\"\" title=\"\" class=\"articleTooltip__tokenImage\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">BNB<\/span> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText articleTooltip__tokenText_price articleTooltip__tokenText_positive\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">\n      +0.20%\n    <\/span><\/a> <!----><\/span> token fell on the news of Zhao's possible departure, declining 7.1% to $242.71 at 1:10 p.m ET, according to CoinGecko. It had risen yesterday after initial reports of a possible settlement.&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/span>","The Department of Justice will hold a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/264010\/justice-department-set-to-announce-settlement-with-binance-bloomberg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">press conference<\/a> at 3:00 p.m. ET on Tuesday. Bloomberg News <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/264010\/justice-department-set-to-announce-settlement-with-binance-bloomberg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a> earlier in the day that the announcement involved a Binance settlement.&nbsp;","Binance did not immediately to a request for comment from The Block.&nbsp;","(<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Updates with WSJ report.<\/em>)","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"WSJ","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$4 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S. Department of Justice","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Richard Teng","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$242.71","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"DOJ","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"+0.20%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Department of Justice","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York Times","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"7.1%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Forbes","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1:10 p.m ET","content":"TIME"},{"type":"Forbes","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CoinGecko","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg News","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"3:00 p.m.","content":"TIME"},{"type":"$50 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"the U.S.","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE","CZ"],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}