{"summary":"The Crypto Council for Innovation has announced new hires to lead its legal and government affairs teams.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/159580\/crypto-council-for-innovation-hires-legal-and-lobbying-leadership","publishDate":"2022-07-26T08:00:05","id":3699,"type":null,"title":"Crypto Council for Innovation hires legal and lobbying leadership","category":["POLICY"],"content":["The Crypto Council for Innovation (CCI) is hiring two long-term government insiders on the trade association's leadership team.&nbsp;","In an announcement shared with The Block, CCI said it has hired Linda Jeng and Brett Quick in leadership roles.","Formerly a leader in policy at the Coinbase and Circle-founded Centre Consortium, Jeng previously has worked at the Federal Reserve and US Treasury Department.","Quick joins CCI from the Financial Services Forum. She was a former staffer on the Senate Banking and House Financial Services Committees and has lobbied on behalf of the Financial Services Forum as well as S&amp;P Global. She will be CCI's first in-house lobbyist, a representative told The Block. The firm only just announced its entrance into a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/158479\/meet-the-crypto-industrys-new-favorite-lobbyists\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">contract for the Sternhell Group<\/a> to lobby on its behalf earlier this month.&nbsp;&nbsp;","Owing to heavy-hitting backers, CCI made a splash when it was announced in the spring of 2021, but remained fairly quiet until January of this year, when <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/132506\/crypto-council-for-innovation-names-former-wef-exec-sheila-warren-as-ceo\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sheila Warren became executive director<\/a>. The council subsequently made its <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/141070\/crypto-council-for-innovation-announces-leadership-team-and-first-full-time-hires-including-former-senator\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">first full-time hires<\/a> in April and has been increasing its presence both in Washington, DC, and globally.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"CCI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Federal Reserve","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sheila Warren","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Linda Jeng","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Financial Services Forum","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Brett Quick","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Washington","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Centre Consortium","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sternhell Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"spring of 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Circle","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"US Treasury Department","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"S&amp;P Global","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DC","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Crypto Council for Innovation (CCI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Senate Banking and House Financial Services Committees","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"the Financial Services Forum","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Kollen Post","The Block"]}