{"summary":"Tesla CEO Elon Musk may share a virtual stage with Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey next month, following a Twitter conversation.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/109806\/event-confirms-elon-musk-will-discuss-bitcoin-with-jack-dorsey-in-july","publishDate":"2021-06-28T05:02:19","id":3732,"type":null,"title":"Elon Musk discussion with Jack Dorsey still uncertain for July conference","category":["BITCOIN"],"content":["<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Update: After this article was published, the spokesperson for the event said they made a mistake in saying the event was confirmed — now saying that it is not 100% confirmed. We have updated the headline and article to reflect this.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em>","Tesla CEO Elon Musk may have a discussion with Twitter CEO Jack Dorsey about bitcoin at The B Word event in July, as was originally suggested on Twitter.","The two tech leaders <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/109613\/elon-musk-may-debate-jack-dorsey-at-an-upcoming-bitcoin-event\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">agreed to participate<\/a> in such a talk on Twitter but with Musk's playful attitude, it wasn't necessarily clear that he was being serious. While a spokesperson for the virtual event originally confirmed that the discussion would take place, they now state that the event is not 100% confirmed.","It all started when Musk <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/elonmusk\/status\/1408244133400023048\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">made a joke<\/a> in response to one of Dorsey's tweets supporting the event. In reference to the event's name, he suggested it might stand for \"bicurious.\" Dorsey shrugged this off as \"bizarre,\" before suggesting the two should have a conversation at the event, calling it \"THE talk.\"","Musk agreed, stating \"<span class=\"css-901oao css-16my406 r-poiln3 r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">For the Bitcurious? Very well then, let’s do it<\/span>\" with a winky face emoji.","The conversation will bring together Dorsey, who is a diehard bitcoin advocate — with a strong penchant for the Lightning network — and Musk, who has a complicated relationship with the cryptocurrency.","While Musk indirectly <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/94155\/tesla-has-bought-1-5-billion-bitcoin-btc\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">purchased $1.5 billion of bitcoin<\/a> via Tesla, he has also <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/elonmusk\/status\/1392780304138473473\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">criticized<\/a> the environmental impacts of the cryptocurrency itself, along with <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/elonmusk\/status\/1408246196603346947\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">making fun<\/a> of its passionate community.","Unlike Dorsey, who is solely focused on bitcoin, Musk also has a strong fondness for dogecoin, a memecoin based on the Shiba Inu breed of dog. During the Bitcoin Miami event earlier this month, the Tesla CEO even <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/elonmusk\/status\/1400620080090730501\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweeted<\/a> a Linkin Park meme about finding someone else, accompanied by the word bitcoin and a breaking heart emoji — causing bitcoin's price to drop by more than $2,000.","The B Word event will take place on July 21 online, and will also feature speakers including ARK Invest founder Cathie Wood, Blockstream CEO Adam Back, and former acting and deputy director of the U.S. Central Intelligence Agency (CIA), Michael Morell.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"July 21","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Michael Morell","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Linkin Park","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tesla","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bitcoin Miami","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$1.5 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Jack Dorsey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Elon Musk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. Central Intelligence Agency (CIA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"100%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Cathie Wood","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Adam Back","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Musk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$2,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Shiba Inu","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Dorsey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Dorsey","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN","ELON MUSK","TWITTER"],"authors":["Tim Copeland","The Block"]}