{"summary":"21.co, the parent company of 21Shares, has raised $25 million at $2 billion valuation, making it &quot;Switzerland&#x27;s largest crypto unicorn.&quot;","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/167976\/21shares-parent-company-raises-25-million-at-2-billion-valuation","publishDate":"2022-09-06T08:12:08","id":3743,"type":null,"title":"21Shares parent company raises $25 million at $2 billion valuation","category":["VENTURE CAPITAL"],"content":["<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">21.co, the parent company of crypto investing firm 21Shares, has raised $25 million in a funding round led by Marshall Wace. <\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The fundraising brings the company’s post-money valuation to $2 billion, making it \"Switzerland's largest crypto unicorn,” the company said in a release. Other investors in the round include Collab+Currency, Quiet Ventures, ETFS Capital and Valor Equity Partners.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">21Shares announced its newly formed parent company on Tuesday alongside the funding round.<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;134233117&quot;:false,&quot;134233118&quot;:false,&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335551550&quot;:1,&quot;335551620&quot;:1,&quot;335559685&quot;:0,&quot;335559737&quot;:0,&quot;335559738&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Founded in 2018, the investment firm is now the world's largest issuer of cryptocurrency exchange-traded products (ETPs). <\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;134233117&quot;:false,&quot;134233118&quot;:false,&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335551550&quot;:1,&quot;335551620&quot;:1,&quot;335559685&quot;:0,&quot;335559737&quot;:0,&quot;335559738&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Amun Holdings, which owned both 21Shares and token-provider Amun, announced <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.globenewswire.com\/news-release\/2021\/05\/11\/2227187\/0\/en\/Amun-and-21Shares-the-Largest-Issuer-of-Cryptocurrency-ETPs-Announces-Investors-Including-Catherine-Wood-and-Anthony-Pompliano.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">a fundraising round back in May 2021<\/span><\/a><span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> with backers including Morgan Creek Digital and Ark Investment Management’s CEO Cathie Wood.<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;134233117&quot;:false,&quot;134233118&quot;:false,&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335551550&quot;:1,&quot;335551620&quot;:1,&quot;335559685&quot;:0,&quot;335559737&quot;:0,&quot;335559738&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">21.co is now designed to unite 21Shares with Amun and other upcoming crypto projects, 21.co co-founder Hany Rashwan told The Block. He said 21.co's product stack is like Amazon Web Services, helping other asset managers and customers bring products to market.<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The firm ended 2021 \"on a nine-figure revenue run rate and has seen sustained inflows, even during down markets,” according to the release.<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The new round – which was closed amid 2022's struggling crypto markets – will be used to drive growth through expansion into key markets, product launches and hiring.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The investment firm has already been expanding its operations in Europe and the Middle East. The firm appointed Sherif El-Haddad to <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/news+\/166990\/52-key-crypto-hires-exits-and-moves-august-2022\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">lead its market operation<\/span><\/a><span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in the Middle East in August. It also made several key hires in Europe from leading investment banks, like JPMorgan and Barclays.<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;134233117&quot;:false,&quot;134233118&quot;:false,&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335551550&quot;:1,&quot;335551620&quot;:1,&quot;335559685&quot;:0,&quot;335559737&quot;:0,&quot;335559738&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The United Arab Emirates is quickly becoming a crypto hub with many leading crypto companies securing <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/157506\/okx-joins-growing-list-of-crypto-companies-approved-to-operate-in-dubai\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">approval to operate<\/span><\/a><span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in Dubai. In March, the <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/136994\/dubai-creates-agency-for-virtual-asset-regulation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">city set up<\/span><\/a><span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> the Dubai Virtual Asset Regulatory Authority (VARA) to oversee digital asset regulation.<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;134233117&quot;:false,&quot;134233118&quot;:false,&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335551550&quot;:1,&quot;335551620&quot;:1,&quot;335559685&quot;:0,&quot;335559737&quot;:0,&quot;335559738&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Hany Rashwan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Barclays","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Switzerland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ark Investment Management’s CEO Cathie Wood","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dubai Virtual Asset Regulatory Authority (VARA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"United Arab Emirates","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Dubai","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$25 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$2 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Middle East","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"May 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Morgan Creek Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sherif El","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Amazon Web Services","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Valor Equity Partners","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Marshall Wace","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Haddad","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Amun Holdings","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Kari McMahon","Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}