{"summary":"Byte Trading, a crypto market maker specialized in derivatives, has raised $7 million in a seed funding round.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/130653\/crypto-market-maker-byte-trading-raises-7-million-in-seed-funding","publishDate":"2022-01-18T13:06:42","id":3833,"type":null,"title":"Crypto market maker Byte Trading raises $7 million in seed funding","category":["VENTURE CAPITAL"],"content":["<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Byte Trading, a crypto market maker specialized in derivatives, has raised $7 million in a seed funding round.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sharing the news exclusively with The Block on Tuesday, Byte Trading said Switzerland-based venture capital firm Redalpine, which is an <a href=\"https:\/\/redalpine.com\/portfolio\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">investor in<\/a> popular startups such as Robinhood and N26, led the round. Other investors in the round included Possible Ventures, L1 Digital, and D4 Ventures.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">As part of the deal, Redalpine general partner Harald Nieder and Possible Ventures partner Simon Leicht have also joined Byte Trading's board of directors, Byte Trading co-founder Dominik Vacikar told The Block.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This was an equity funding round and will help Byte Trading expand its team, integrate more exchanges, and grow its assets under management (AUM) by 50 times within this year, said Vacikar.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Vacikar declined to comment on Byte's current exchange partners and AUM but said the firm has a \"very small piece\" of the daily volume of crypto derivatives. When asked how it plans to gain market share in a competitive market-making space, Vacikar said his and his co-founder Jan Hoekman's background in alternative datasets is the firm's unique advantage.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Many crypto market makers come from a background in traditional finance, said Vacikar. But since crypto markets behave differently from traditional markets because they are driven by more forces than just the order book, such as momentary sentiment, they require a different approach, according to Vacikar.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"We think many traditional players overlook this fact and mainly apply the same playbook as in traditional markets, and that's where our background has been very beneficial,\" he said.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Byte Trading plans to remain focused on crypto derivatives, said Vacikar, when asked if the firm plans to support spot markets as well.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Byte Trading is the first new crypto-focused market maker to recently emerge in the public sphere. Wintermute <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/55373\/crypto-market-maker-wintermute-trading-raises-seven-figure-seed-funding-to-enhance-its-platform\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">raised<\/a> its seed round in early 2020 and is today one of the largest crypto market makers, alongside Alameda Research, Jump Trading, GSR, and Cumberland DRW.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Vacikar said Byte Trading has been profitably market-making since its launch early last year. <\/span><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">There are currently eight people working for Byte Trading, and Vacikar said he is currently hiring for several roles, mainly engineering.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"GSR","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Switzerland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$7 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Vacikar","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Harald Nieder","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"AUM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Jan Hoekman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Byte Trading","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Possible Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Simon Leicht","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Dominik Vacikar","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cumberland DRW","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Yogita Khatri","The Block"]}