{"summary":"Santander, HSBC, Deutsche Bank, BankProv, Bridge Bank, Mercury, Multis and Series Financial are among banks still reportedly willing to work with crypto.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/219551\/some-banks-are-still-willing-to-play-ball-with-crypto-coindesk","publishDate":"2023-03-14T03:45:28","id":3854,"type":null,"title":"Some banks are still willing to play ball with crypto: CoinDesk","category":["FINANCE FIRMS"],"content":["The high-profile failures of Silicon Valley Bank, Silvergate and Signature Bank have left something of a void for crypto firms needing banking partners — but certain banks remain open for business.","Santander, HSBC, Deutsche Bank, BankProv, Bridge Bank, Mercury, Multis and Series Financial are among the banks still reportedly willing to work with crypto firms.","The list is based on messages — <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/business\/2023\/03\/14\/santander-hsbc-deutsche-and-others-still-willing-to-serve-crypto-clients-after-banking-failures-dcg-says\/?utm_campaign=coindesk_main&amp;utm_term=organic&amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_content=editorial&amp;utm_medium=social\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">obtained<\/a> by CoinDesk — exchanged between staff at the outlet's parent company Digital Currency Group, who had been discussing the pursuit of new banking partners for portfolio companies.","DCG also contacted BlackRock, JPMorgan and Bank of America — as well as international banks Revolut, United Overseas Bank and Bank Leumi — according to CoinDesk.","Even if some tradfi banks are still willing to play ball with crypto firms in the U.S., however, services may be restricted based on crypto exposure.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Deutsche Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DCG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"HSBC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BlackRock","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Mercury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bridge Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bank of America","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bank Leumi","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CoinDesk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Digital Currency Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Signature Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"United Overseas Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Silicon Valley Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CoinDesk —","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["CRYPTO BANKS AND LENDERS","FINTECH","INVESTMENT FIRMS","TRADFI BANKS"],"authors":["Adam James","The Block"]}