{"summary":"Circle disclosed its FTX-related equity investments.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/187594\/circle-holds-a-little-more-than-10-million-in-ftx-related-equity-investments","publishDate":"2022-11-16T11:47:49","id":3895,"type":null,"title":"Circle holds a little more than $10 million in FTX-related equity investments","category":["FINANCE FIRMS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stablecoin issuer Circle, days after proclaiming it had a very small exposure to FTX, disclosed in a Securities Exchange Commission filing that it holds about $10.6 million in equity investments related to the FTX Group.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Circle is a tiny equity holder of FTX, and FTX is a tiny equity holder of Circle. Circle is also a tiny equity holder of Kraken, Coinbase and BinanceUS,\" Circle CEO Jeremy Allaire <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/jerallaire\/status\/1590232998422937601?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweeted<\/a> on Nov. 9.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The company behind stablecoins USD Coin (USDC) and Euro Coin (EUROC) is one of several firms that have disclosed exposure to FTX since the crypto exchange filed for bankruptcy protection on Nov. 11.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Circle <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.sec.gov\/Archives\/edgar\/data\/1876042\/000110465922118597\/tm2124445-21_s4a.htm\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">disclosed<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> the amount of its equity investments related to FTX in a Nov. 14 Securities and Exchange Commission filing regarding a planned acquisition by special purpose acquisition company Concord Acquisition Corp, which would make Circle a public company traded on the New York Stock Exchange.<\/span>","A Sept. 30 monthly attestation of Circle’s assets shows that nearly 47.3 billion USD Coins were in circulation, backed by nearly $47.5 billion worth of U.S. dollars held in custody accounts.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The company also noted in the filing that it has “historically performed payment processing services for and issued and redeemed USDC for the FTX Group,” and plans to record FTX-related impairment in the fourth quarter.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“The company has suspended its services and transactions with the FTX Group and is in process of evaluating the impact on provision of future services to the FTX Group and the potential indirect financial impact of the FTX Group bankruptcy,” Circle wrote.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Allaire has <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/184503\/circle-ceo-allaire-calls-ftx-crisis-cryptos-lehman-brothers-moment\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">referred <\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">to the FTX crisis as crypto’s Lehman Brothers moment.<\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Jeremy Allaire","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Concord Acquisition Corp","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"New York Stock Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$10.6 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Nov. 9","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Euro","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kraken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$47.5 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"EUROC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sept. 30","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Lehman Brothers","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nov. 11","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Nov. 14","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Securities Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"the fourth quarter","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["FTX","USDC"],"authors":["Kristin Majcher","The Block"]}