{"summary":"The game will be free-to-play, include web3 elements and is slated to launch this fall for the NBA&#x27;s 2022-2023 season. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/168321\/sorare-partners-with-nba-to-launch-fantasy-basketball-game","publishDate":"2022-09-07T12:20:25","id":3946,"type":null,"title":"Sorare partners with NBA and NBPA to launch fantasy basketball game","category":["METAVERSE & NFT"],"content":["<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The web3 sports fantasy game developer Sorare will launch a fantasy basketball game in partnership with the National Basketball Association (NBA) and National Basketball Players Association (NBPA). <\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The game will be free-to-play and include digital collectibles. It is slated to launch sometime this fall, in time for the NBA’s 2022-2023 season, according to a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/pr.nba.com\/nba-nbpa-sorare-partnership\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">release<\/span><\/a><span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Our partnership with Sorare will give NBA fans an entirely new way to engage with our teams and players,” said NBA commissioner Adam Silver in a statement. “With Sorare’s emerging NFT fantasy platform, we see significant opportunities to broaden our community of fans and grow NBA basketball around the world.”<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sorare is an Ethereum-based NFT platform that already offers digital collectibles for a fantasy soccer game. Last year, the firm scored <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/118094\/fantasy-soccer-nft-sorare-scores-680-million-raise-softbank\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$680 million<\/span><\/a><span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in funding to reach a $4.3 billion valuation. <\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sorare also signed on tennis star <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/130899\/serena-williams-appointed-as-board-advisor-for-nft-platform-sorare\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Serena Williams<\/span><\/a><span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on its board in January of this year to help expand new sports categories.<\/span>","The NBA is not new to the NFT world. In March of 2021, the NBA and NBPA <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/97020\/nba-rising-stars-rosters-nft-top-shot\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">collaborated<\/a> with Dapper Labs' NBA Top Shot to release hand-picked highlights from the 2020-2021 season. The collection NBA Top Shot was once the king of the NFT market and accounted for the majority of weekly NFT transactions for months following its launch in December 2020. That had sharply declined by mid-2021, according to The Block's data dashboard.&nbsp;","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/nft-non-fungible-tokens\/art-collectibles\/art-and-collectibles-nft-trade-volume\/embed\" title=\"Art and Collectibles NFT Trade Volume\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"fall","content":"DATE"},{"type":"NBA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Adam Silver","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sorare","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$680 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"NBPA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"National Basketball Association (NBA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"December 2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$4.3 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Serena Williams","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"National Basketball Players Association (NBPA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"March of 2021","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["GAME","SORARE"],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}