{"summary":"Swiss crypto bank Sygnum has raised $90 million in Series B funding. The firm is now valued at $800 million.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/129363\/crypto-bank-sygnum-raises-90-million-series-b-now-valued-800-million","publishDate":"2022-01-06T04:05:27","id":4005,"type":null,"title":"Crypto bank Sygnum raises $90 million, now valued at $800 million","category":["VENTURE CAPITAL"],"content":["Sygnum, a regulated crypto bank and asset manager, has raised $90 million in a Series B funding round. The firm is now valued at $800 million.","Sun Hung Kai &amp; Co., a Hong Kong-listed financial services company, led Sygnum's Series B funding. Other investors in the round included Animoca Brands, SBI Holdings, Siam Commercial Bank’s digital investment arm SCB 10X, and Canadian investment firm Meta Investments.","Sygnum's employees also participated in the Series B round, as with all its prior fundraising rounds. These employees, co-founders, board members, and management team continue to hold majority ownership of the company, said Sygnum.","Sygnum said its business grew significantly in 2021, with consolidated gross revenues increasing tenfold, assets under administration growing to over $2 billion, and its institutional client base nearing 1,000.","Sygnum <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/120198\/sygnum-bank-exec-explains-how-swiss-wealth-channels-are-opening-up-to-crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">provides<\/a> various crypto services, including spot and options trading, custody, crypto-backed fiat loans, institutional banking, and asset management products. It has a Switzerland banking license and a Singapore asset management license.","With fresh capital in hand, Sygnum plans to offer new products and services focused on decentralized finance (DeFi). These include permissioned DeFi pools, such as <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/129277\/aave-arc-permissioned-defi-platform-fireblocks-first-whitelister\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Aave Arc<\/a>, and asset management products focused on DeFi. Last month, Sygnum Bank launched a DeFi structured investment product called DeFi+ Core that provides diversified exposure to the DeFi sector.","“Savvy digital asset investors are increasingly looking for novel opportunities in the frontiers of Web 3.0, including DeFi, NFTs, play-to-earn gaming and the metaverse”, said Sygnum Singapore co-founder and CEO Gerald Goh. “We look forward to partnering with our strong global network of strategic investors to expand our suite of fully-regulated digital asset offerings and solutions into these emerging verticals.”","Sygnum's Series B lead investor Sun Hung Kai, for instance, will develop crypto-focused products with the bank to expand its fund management offerings.","The Series B round brings Sygnum's total funding to date to over $120 million. The bank has <a href=\"https:\/\/www.insights.sygnum.com\/post\/sygnum-secures-strategic-investment-from-sbi-digital-asset-holdings-to-accelerate-next-growth-phase\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">previously raised<\/a> $30 million during August 2020 and February 2021. Funding amounts of its other rounds remain unknown.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Sygnum","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Meta Investments","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Switzerland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sygnum","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"August 2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gerald Goh","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"SBI Holdings","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$30 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$90 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Animoca Brands","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Siam Commercial Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"February 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$120 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"SCB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$800 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Sun Hung Kai &amp; Co.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sygnum Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$2 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Sygnum Singapore","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["SERIES B"],"authors":["Yogita Khatri","The Block"]}