{"summary":"CRV fell below the $0.40 level after tokens bought over the counter from Curve Finance’s founder Michael Egorov were transferred to Binance.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/250745\/crv-fell-below-40-cents-as-otc-tokens-bought-from-founder-sent-to-binance","publishDate":"2023-09-13T09:23:39","id":4042,"type":null,"title":"CRV falls below $0.40 as tokens bought from founder sent temporarily to Binance","category":["DEFI"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The price of <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Curve DAO <\/span><span class=\"articleTooltip\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"\/price\/248437\/curve-dao-crv-usd\" class=\"articleTooltip__link\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"><img src=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2023\/10\/Curve.png\" alt=\"\" title=\"\" class=\"articleTooltip__tokenImage\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">CRV<\/span> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText articleTooltip__tokenText_price articleTooltip__tokenText_negative\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">\n      -1.30%\n    <\/span><\/a> <!----><\/span><\/span> tokens fell below $0.40 after <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/243183\/michael-egorov-has-sold-a-total-of-106-million-crv-for-42-million\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CRV bought over-the-counter<\/a> from the DeFi project’s founder, Michael Egorov, were transferred earlier today.","Blockchain security firm Peckshield noted that one of Egorov’s counterparties, “0xb0b8”, who received 2.5 million CRV for one million USDT in early August, <a href=\"https:\/\/x.com\/PeckShieldAlert\/status\/1701869915291234695?s=20\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">transferred 609,000 CRV tokens to Binance<\/a>. “Investors who bought CRV from Michael Egorov at $0.40 are currently at a loss,” web3 data analytics platform <a href=\"https:\/\/x.com\/lookonchain\/status\/1701874407034306941?s=20\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Lookonchain added<\/a>.","The motivation for the transfer remains uncertain. However, the OTC counterparty <a href=\"https:\/\/etherscan.io\/address\/0xb0b851bf44499edec30795bef7ac4d5f9dd632d0#tokentxns\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">sent back the 609,000 CRV<\/a> a few hours later, according to on-chain data, as the token price recovered slightly.","CRV is currently trading at exactly $0.40, according to CoinGecko — down 3% over the last 24 hours.","Egorov <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/243183\/michael-egorov-has-sold-a-total-of-106-million-crv-for-42-million\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">sold 106 million of CRV for $46 million<\/a> in early August in deals aimed at reducing potential liquidation risks associated with his <a href=\"https:\/\/debank.com\/profile\/0x7a16ff8270133f063aab6c9977183d9e72835428\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">outstanding debt<\/a> across various DeFi platforms. Egorov has been working to repay some of this debt to mitigate liquidation risks by selling the CRV tokens for stablecoins. &nbsp;","The token sales included transactions with entities including crypto trading firm <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/sandraaleow\/status\/1687191897171972096\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Wintermute<\/a>, Tron founder Justin Sun — who <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/242455\/justin-sun-buys-2-9-million-crv-tokens-in-an-otc-deal-announces-partnership-with-curve?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">purchased<\/a> 5 million CRV — and NFT investor Jeffrey Huang (Machi Big Brother). An anonymous entity <a href=\"https:\/\/etherscan.io\/token\/0xd533a949740bb3306d119cc777fa900ba034cd52?a=0xf510dc673c5e4a8c274a98c758fe33fc4838be79\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">secured<\/a> the largest OTC deal with Egorov, purchasing 17.5 million CRV tokens.","The sales followed a 30% decline in the price of CRV to $0.50 after a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/242066\/curve-finance-factory-pools-targeted-due-to-reentrancy-vulnerability\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">security exploit affected multiple Curve Finance liquidity pools<\/a> on July 30.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CRV\/USD price chart. Image <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coingecko.com\/en\/coins\/curve-dao-token\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CoinGecko<\/a><\/span>.","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Disclosure: Wintermute co-founder Evgeny Gaevoy sits on The Block’s board.<\/span><\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Wintermute","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Egorov","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"CRV","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July 30","content":"DATE"},{"type":"3%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"-1.30%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Justin Sun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Wintermute","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$0.50","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$0.40","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"USD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"30%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Evgeny Gaevoy","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Curve Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Michael Egorov","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tron","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Peckshield","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$46 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Machi Big Brother)","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jeffrey Huang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["DEXS"],"authors":["James Hunt","The Block"]}