{"summary":"Delta Blockchain Fund CEO discusses the impact of the recent crypto surge on the early-stage venture landscape.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/263274\/2023-q4-funding","publishDate":"2023-11-16T08:03:04","id":4105,"type":null,"title":"Here&#x27;s how private valuations are reacting to crypto&#x27;s latest rally","category":["VENTURE CAPITAL"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 98<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 5 of The Scoop was recorded with <b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro and Delta Blockchain Fund Founder &amp; CEO Kavita Gupta<\/b><\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on <a href=\"https:\/\/www.youtube.com\/channel\/UCqjFueYMJ78eF6G0lGLzzpQ\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Youtube<\/a>, <\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a>,<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Please send feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"0979666d6a687a7d497d616c6b65666a62276a66\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm\/?e=BLOCK5123914990\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Kavita Gupta is the founder and CEO of Delta Blockchain Fund.","Gupta — a former executive at ConsenSys — <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/118046\/former-consensys-venture-exec-launches-50-million-fund-with-backing-from-large-family-offices\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">launched<\/a> the fund in September 2021 and it currently sits at $125 million AUM.","In this episode of The Scoop, Gupta discusses how the recent surge in crypto prices has impacted the venture landscape, and shares what sectors of the market she is paying the most attention to.","According to Gupta, most early-stage crypto valuations are still fairly reasonable — which is leading to a steady stream of activity amongst veteran VCs in the space.","\"Smarter, seasoned VCs have actually been more active in this market because it's the right valuation — it's also told you which founders are here to stay.\"","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors <a href=\"https:\/\/www.paypal.com\/crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">PayPal.<\/em><\/a><\/b><\/span>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Make your crypto move with PayPal. Get started today at <a href=\"https:\/\/www.paypal.com\/crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">PayPal.com\/crypto<\/a><\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Gupta","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Gupta","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Delta Blockchain Fund Founder &amp; CEO Kavita Gupta","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"September 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kavita Gupta","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"PayPal","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Delta Blockchain Fund","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$125 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}