{"summary":"Crypto exchange Coinbase is hiring Daniel Seifert from German fintech firm Solarisbank to lead European expansion, Bloomberg reports.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/177584\/coinbases-new-regional-managing-director-to-lead-european-expansion","publishDate":"2022-10-17T04:38:31","id":4124,"type":null,"title":"Coinbase&#x27;s new regional managing director to lead European expansion: Bloomberg","category":["HIRING"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Coinbase is hiring the chief operating officer from the fintech platform Solarisbank. Daniel Seifert, Coinbase’s new addition, will serve as the Europe regional managing director, Bloomberg <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2022-10-17\/coinbase-hires-fintech-executive-to-lead-european-expansion\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reports<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The role is geared towards achieving international expansion,<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Nana Murugesan, vice president of international and business development, told Bloomberg.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Coinbase successfully <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/172035\/coinbase-successfully-registers-with-the-dutch-central-bank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">registered<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in the Netherlands in September, and in <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/158077\/coinbase-approved-to-operate-as-crypto-asset-service-provider-in-italy\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Italy<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in July.&nbsp;<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Murugesan further shared with Bloomberg that the crypto exchange has eyes on France and Spain for regulatory approval next year.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Seifert will take on the post after nearing three years in his COO role at Berlin-based Solarisbank. Previously, he was <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">head of operations and customer support at Swiss investment bank UBS Partner, and an associate partner at consultancy McKinsey &amp; Company, his LinkedIn profile <a href=\"https:\/\/www.linkedin.com\/in\/danielseifert\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">shows<\/a>. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Coinbase set up a base in Europe in 2018 when it established its Ireland headquarters. In 2019, it gained an <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/43158\/coinbase-receives-e-money-license-in-ireland-to-further-expand-into-europe\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Irish e-money license,<\/span><\/a> <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">which gave it passported access to<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> the European Union and the European Economic Area.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Daniel Seifert","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"European Union","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"France","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"the Netherlands","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Berlin","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Solarisbank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nana Murugesan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"European Economic Area","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Spain","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Italy","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"UBS Partner","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"fintech platform Solarisbank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ireland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"McKinsey &amp; Company","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["COINBASE","FINTECH","HIRING"],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}