{"summary":"Robinhood has announced that it is introducing its long-awaited crypto wallet and transfer features to select customers.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/118271\/robinhood-rolling-out-crypto-wallet-transfer-features","publishDate":"2021-09-22T09:00:15","id":4130,"type":null,"title":"Robinhood is rolling out crypto wallet and transfer features","category":["STARTUPS"],"content":["Online brokerage Robinhood announced Wednesday that it is rolling out its long-awaited crypto wallet and transfer features to make it easier for customers to send and receive cryptocurrencies.","Starting next month, select Robinhood customers can begin testing the features, said the company. More customers will be able to join at a later date through a waitlist, it added. The announcement comes a day after Bloomberg <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2021-09-20\/robinhood-testing-a-crypto-wallet-feature-in-long-awaited-move\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a> that Robinhood is testing the features, citing a beta version of its iPhone app.","Robinhood says crypto aligns \"perfectly\" with its mission to democratize finance for all because crypto was born out of a mission to return power to the people.","Robinhood currently offers crypto buying and selling services. The wallet feature will allow customers to store and move their crypto holdings in and out of their apps. That means customers can send their crypto to other wallet addresses and receive supported cryptocurrencies into their accounts. Robinhood currently <a href=\"https:\/\/robinhood.com\/us\/en\/support\/articles\/commission-free-cryptocurrency-investing\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">supports<\/a> seven cryptocurrencies: Bitcoin (BTC), bitcoin cash (BCH), bitcoin SV (BSV), dogecoin (DOGE), ether (ETH), ether classic (ETC), and litecoin (LTC).","As for storing crypto in the wallet, Robinhood said it is supporting security features such as identity verification, multi-factor authentication, and email and phone verification.","Earlier this month, Robinhood also <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/116961\/robinhood-announces-new-crypto-investing-feature-as-it-looks-to-bulk-up-offering\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/a> the launch of a crypto recurring investments feature that allows customers to buy crypto automatically at regular intervals. That feature has now been made available to all customers, said the company.","Robinhood started its crypto trading offering in 2018. The offering has grown to become a lucrative business line for the company. Between Q2 2020 and Q2 2021, Robinhood's transaction-based revenues from crypto trading increased by a whopping 4,282%, as The Block <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/114967\/crypto-grows-from-2-to-41-of-robinhoods-total-revenue-in-past-year\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a> last month. Notably, 62% of the company's crypto transaction-based revenue was attributable to dogecoin trades.","Robinhood Crypto is currently available in all U.S. states and the District of Columbia, except for Hawaii, Nevada, New Hampshire, and West Virginia.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"West Virginia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"BCH","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"4,282%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Robinhood","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hawaii","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"62%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"New Hampshire","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"District of Columbia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Nevada","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"LTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["ROBINHOOD"],"authors":["Yogita Khatri","The Block"]}