{"summary":"DCG&#x27;s portfolio takes a hit and the market begins to speculate, about a month after troubled crypto lender Genesis Global Capital suspended its Gemini Earn program.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/195951\/digital-coin-group-tokens-sparking-market-speculation","publishDate":"2022-12-17T13:14:15","id":4143,"type":null,"title":"Digital Currency Group tokens red across board, sparking market speculation","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Assets on the Digital Currency Group portfolio have taken a hit over the last 24 hours, triggering market speculation.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">It has been a month since troubled crypto lender Genesis Global Capital, daughter company of DCG, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/187545\/genesis-global-capital-suspends-redemptions-with-impact-spreading-to-gemini\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">suspended<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> redemptions.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“DCG and Genesis have highly competent teams. In normal circumstances neither would pay 15%-30% of slippage to rapidly exit long-held positions over the weekend, so observers are naturally speculating this was a forced event of some kind,” Rich Rosenblum, president of trading firm GSR, told The Block on Saturday.<\/span>","Messari DCG portfolio 12:42 ET on 12\/17","Filecoin in particular has seen a significant decline.&nbsp;","\"It’s by far the most traded of the portfolio in the last 24 hours,\" Rosenblum said. \"It could be due to there being a highly developed borrowing market for FIL, which resulted in more selling once a -15% intraday threshold was breached. You need to stake FIL to mine it. Miners often borrow FIL by leveraging their other holdings.\"","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ran Neuner, CEO of Onchain Capital, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/cryptomanran\/status\/1604096800646107136\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">speculated<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in a tweet that DCG may be dumping as it tries to repay a $1.5 billion loan to Genesis, or it could be heading toward bankruptcy as it exhausts its liquid assets.&nbsp;<\/span>","Bitvavo crypto exchange <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/195902\/bitvavo-unable-to-access-280-million-euros-held-at-dcg\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">wrote<\/a> in a company blog on Friday that DCG is “experiencing liquidity problems” and has&nbsp; “suspended repayments.”<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Updates with corrected name of Digital Currency Group. Previous post said Digital Coin Group.<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"FIL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DCG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"last 24 hours","content":"DATE"},{"type":"GSR","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Digital Coin Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Rosenblum","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$1.5 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Digital Currency Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"30%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"-15%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Neuner","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Rich Rosenblum","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"15%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Saturday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Onchain Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["GEMINI"],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}