{"summary":"Ripple has lost its CFO who began working with the company in 2021. Kristina Campbell has joined Maven Clinic, according to her LinkedIn.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/255486\/ripple-cfo-kristina-campbell-exits-company","publishDate":"2023-10-09T11:46:41","id":4156,"type":null,"title":"Ripple CFO Kristina Campbell exits company","category":["PEOPLE"],"content":["Ripple's Chief Financial Officer Kristina Campbell has left the company after about two and a half years.","Campbell's LinkedIn profile shows that she no longer works at Ripple and instead, as of this month, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.fiercehealthcare.com\/digital-health\/chutes-ladders-reproductive-health-provider-wisp-names-first-female-ceo\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">started working<\/a> as CFO at Maven Clinic, a digital health care provider. The Harvard-educated executive previously worked several years in financial services before joining Ripple in April 2021.","\"We’re grateful for Kristina’s leadership over the past 2+ years and her contributions to the company as we’ve experienced strong global momentum, business growth and navigated regulatory headwinds,\" a Ripple spokesperson said by email. \"Ripple remains in strong financial standing and is laser-focused on its continued success in key markets around the world.\"","Ripple has been <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/254625\/judge-torres-rejects-the-secs-motion-for-an-interlocutory-appeal-in-ripple-case\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">engaged in a battle<\/a> with the Securities and Exchange Commission, with the regulatory agency suing the company. A trial is slated for next year.","The crypto market has been exceedingly volatile thanks in large part to a prolonged bear market, and layoffs have been common. Ripple, meanwhile, has been <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/254590\/ripple-obtains-digital-asset-license-from-monetary-authority-of-singapore\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">making inroads<\/a> in markets outside the U.S., including the Asia Pacific region.&nbsp;&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"April 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Campbell","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chief Financial Officer Kristina Campbell","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Maven Clinic","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Asia Pacific","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Kristina’s","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Harvard","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"the U.S.","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}