{"summary":"Williams Racing Forumla 1 racecars two feature NFTs.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/242599\/kraken-gives-fans-chance-to-put-nft-on-an-f1-racecar-at-austin-grand-prix","publishDate":"2023-08-01T12:12:47","id":4164,"type":null,"title":"Kraken gives fans chance to put NFT on F1 racecar at Austin Grand Prix","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kraken revved up the next phase of its plan to stir engagement and boost its customer base via its <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/223391\/kraken-f1-williams-racing\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">partnership<\/a> with <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Williams Racing's Formula 1 team, this time by offering contestants the chance to pick what NFT appears on racecars competing in the upcoming <a href=\"https:\/\/circuitoftheamericas.com\/event\/f1\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">U.S. Grand Prix<\/a>.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The crypto exchange took to Twitter to announce the sweepstakes ahead of the race set to start in less than three months. \"Want to see your favorite NFT at 200+ mph in front of millions of racing fans?\" Kraken asked <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/krakenfx\/status\/1686377219491598337\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">in a post<\/a>.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Winners of the contest will be able to choose to have their favorite PFP appear on one of two Williams Racing cars competing in the U.S. event scheduled for <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">for October 22 in Austin, Texas.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Earlier this year, Kraken announced plans to \"showcase KrakenNFT customer-owned digital collectibles\" on its cars throughout the F1 season. Other crypto companies to have previously partnered with F1 teams have included FTX and <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/232800\/formula-1s-red-bull-racing-forges-crypto-alliance-with-mysten-labs\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Mysten Labs<\/a>.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Although the regulatory landscape for cryptocurrency exchanges in the U.S. remains murky, Kraken hopes its promotional efforts will aid efforts to expand on recent gains and nab additional customers in the U.S. Last month, the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/240124\/kraken-share-of-us-spot-trading-volumes-reaches-18-month-high\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">company said<\/a> its share of U.S. trading volumes had more than doubled during the previous 18 months.&nbsp;<\/span>","","","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"PFP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mysten Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Williams Racing","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Austin","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"October 22","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Texas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Kraken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["KRAKEN"],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}