{"summary":"Members of the UK parliament committee investigating the collapse of FTX are not satisfied with Binance&#x27;s coooperation, Bloomberg reports.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/188007\/binances-role-in-ftx-collapse-unclear-to-uk-lawmakers-bloomberg","publishDate":"2022-11-17T10:08:54","id":4237,"type":null,"title":"Binance’s role in FTX collapse unclear to UK lawmakers: Bloomberg","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">UK lawmakers are not convinced by the evidence Binance provided to understand its role in the collapse of FTX, according to a member of Parliament.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance sent answers to questions from the UK’s parliamentary committee investigating the downfall of FTX following a hearing on Monday, including on its role in the collapse of FTX. FTX was a major competitor of Binance's prior to its failure and subsequent bankruptcy.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“It doesn’t really give us the real background detail,” Alison Thewliss, a member of the Treasury Committee, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2022-11-17\/binance-evidence-on-ftx-ftt-bnb-collapse-unacceptable-uk-lawmakers-say\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in a Bloomberg interview. “I’m sure the committee will be asking more questions to get to the details of what happened here, because there are wider implications for this collapse and for the crypto sector as a whole.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In response to the question of what role it played in FTX's collapse, Binance shared a series of news articles since the catalytic leak incriminating FTX for mishandling its funds on Nov. 2. The Treasury Committee reportedly expected to review Binance's internal records, including the decision to unload its holding of FTT, FTX’s native token.&nbsp;<\/span>","“We don’t have much ability to push for more than we’ve received,” Treasury Committee Harriett Baldwin said in the interview.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The committee’s recommendations for crypto regulations in the UK based on the inquiry into Binance and FTX will be impacted, Thewliss said in the Bloomberg report.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">UK policymakers are working on more comprehensive rules for digital assets. The national regulator, the Financial Conduct Authority, is currently responsible for licensing crypto firms based on anti-money laundering compliance. With the new laws in the works, the FCA will have broader control over crypto assets.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance is also <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/187692\/binance-role-in-ftx-collapse-crypto-meltdown-under-congressional-scrutiny\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">under scrutiny<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in the U.S., where the House Financial Services Committee will <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/187617\/u-s-house-committee-to-hold-hearing-on-ftx-collapse-and-crypto-fall-out\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">hold<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> a December hearing on FTX's downfall and the state of the crypto industry.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance and the UK Treasury Committee have been contacted for further comment.&nbsp;<\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"FCA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Financial Conduct Authority","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alison Thewliss","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Harriett Baldwin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"December","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Treasury Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thewliss","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nov. 2","content":"DATE"},{"type":"UK Treasury Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Parliament","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"House Financial Services Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"” Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"the U.S.","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE","FTX","UK PARLIAMENT"],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}