{"summary":"Crypto custodian Casa will offer customers the ability to store ethereum amid the fallout from FTX.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/190825\/ethereum-storage-coming-to-custodian-casa-as-centralized-exchanges-lose-their-luster","publishDate":"2022-11-30T09:00:52","id":425,"type":null,"title":"Ether storage coming to Casa as centralized exchanges lose their luster","category":["CRYPTO INFRASTRUCTURE"],"content":["<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto firm Casa will offer customers the ability to store ether, with its CEO referencing the FTX collapse as a reason for its appeal.<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“A lot of people learned the hard lesson of why holding your own keys is important,” CEO Nick Neuman told The Block in an interview. “I hope we can use this as an industry turning point to continue educating people on the importance of self custody.”<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","Casa is launching a refreshed app in January that will provide ether self-storage on its platform in addition to bitcoin as it says the shortcomings of keeping cryptocurrency on centralized exchanges like FTX and Binance become apparent. Centralized exchange spot trading volumes decreased by 26% to $544 billion in October from the previous month, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockresearch.com\/october-by-the-numbers-2-181588\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">according<\/a> to The Block Research.&nbsp;","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Over the last few weeks there has been a “huge” number of new users joining the platform, Neuman said.<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The addition of ether is only one part of the “next phase of the company’s journey,” which will include initiatives such as new membership plans.<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;134233117&quot;:false,&quot;134233118&quot;:false,&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335551550&quot;:1,&quot;335551620&quot;:1,&quot;335559685&quot;:0,&quot;335559737&quot;:0,&quot;335559738&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In May, the firm raised $21 million to build an API that connects Casa to other financial applications. Neuman said the effort is driven by the belief that “everything in our digital lives will be protected by private keys.”<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;134233117&quot;:false,&quot;134233118&quot;:false,&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335551550&quot;:1,&quot;335551620&quot;:1,&quot;335559685&quot;:0,&quot;335559737&quot;:0,&quot;335559738&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> &nbsp;<\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Nick Neuman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$21 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Casa","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$544 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Neuman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"26%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"October","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["FTX","SECURITY FIRMS","WALLET MAKERS"],"authors":["Sam Venis","The Block"]}