{"summary":"FTX, which filed for U.S. Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection on Friday, is now under investigation in its headquarters of the Bahamas.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/186548\/ftx-under-investigation-for-possible-criminal-misconduct-in-the-bahamas","publishDate":"2022-11-13T14:29:11","id":4272,"type":null,"title":"FTX under investigation in the Bahamas for possible criminal misconduct","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["FTX, which filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection in the U.S. on Friday, is now under investigation in its headquarters of the Bahamas.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n\"In light of the collapse of FTX globally and the provisional liquidations of FTX Digital Markets Ltd., a team of financial investigators from the Financial Crimes Investigation Branch are working closely with the Bahamas Securities Commission to investigate if any criminal misconduct occurred,\" the Royal Bahamas Police Force said in a release posted to <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/RBPFPolice\/status\/1591864528291221504?s=20&amp;t=jkEGfhqEQpZJFP9WeJo3tg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Twitter<\/a> Sunday.","FTX Digital Markets is a subsidiary of FTX Trading and is licensed and regulated in the Bahamas.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nFTX, one of the world's largest crypto exchanges, is also&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/185750\/ftx-faces-sec-and-cftc-investigation-bloomberg\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">facing an investigation<\/a> by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) and Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) into its mismanagement of customer funds and relationships with FTX.US and Alameda Research.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nThere has been increased speculation this weekend on the whereabouts of now-former CEO Sam Bankman-Fried, who <a href=\"https:\/\/www.reuters.com\/technology\/ftx-founder-bankman-fried-says-he-is-bahamas-2022-11-12\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">told Reuters<\/a> on Saturday he was in the Bahamas. A later <a href=\"https:\/\/cointelegraph.com\/news\/sam-bankman-fried-is-under-supervision-in-bahamas-looking-to-flee-to-dubai\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">report<\/a> said he and two former FTX associates were “under supervision” by Bahamian authorities.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nFTX spent $74 million over the past year buying up residential property around its headquarters, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/186386\/ftx-spent-74-million-on-real-estate-in-the-bahamas-this-year-exclusive\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block reported Saturday<\/a>. FTX is known for its communal setup on the island, where teammates work and live.","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Sunday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Royal Bahamas Police Force","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"weekend","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bahamas Securities Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Reuters","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bahamas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$74 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Financial Crimes Investigation Branch","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX Digital Markets Ltd.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX Digital Markets","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Saturday","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["CRIME","FTX"],"authors":["Jason Shubnell","The Block"]}