{"summary":"The Block Research analyst Ryan Todd hosted a panel discussion exploring the importance of node infrastructure.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/101702\/node-infrastructure-and-why-its-important-full-video","publishDate":"2021-04-14T17:00:52","id":4276,"type":null,"title":"Node infrastructure and why its important | Full Video","category":["SPONSORED"],"content":["The Block Research analyst Ryan Todd hosted a panel discussion exploring the importance of node infrastructure. In the event we discussed:","You can learn more about our panelists and watch the full event below:&nbsp;","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sam Lessin<\/strong> – General Partner, Slow Ventures","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Meltem Demirors<\/strong> – CSO, CoinShares","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Anatoly Yakovenko <\/strong>– Co-founder, Solona","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Konstantin Richter<\/strong> – Founder &amp; CEO, Blockdaemon","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"315\" src=\"https:\/\/www.youtube.com\/embed\/7cZexqG75Os\" title=\"YouTube video player\" width=\"560\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Ryan Todd","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Solona","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"General Partner","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Blockdaemon","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Slow Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CSO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Lessin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Block Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Konstantin Richter<\/strong> – Founder &amp; CEO","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sponsored","The Block"]}