{"summary":"Crypto industry experts believe Congress could pass new stablecoin regulations in the next year.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/176322\/circle-ceo-house-legislation-best-shot-for-digital-dollar-competition","publishDate":"2022-10-11T12:58:49","id":4293,"type":null,"title":"Circle CEO: House legislation ‘best shot’ for digital dollar competition","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span class=\"x_x_x_ContentPasted0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto industry experts believe Congress could pass new stablecoin regulations in the next year<\/span>","<span class=\"x_x_x_ContentPasted0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A stablecoin bill drafted by lawmakers on the House Financial Services Committee is the country’s “best shot” to compete in digital dollar currency, Circle CEO Jeremy Allaire said.<\/span>","<span class=\"x_x_x_ContentPasted0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto industry players are optimistic that lawmakers could pass a new stablecoin law next year, they said during a financial conference in Washington, D.C.<\/span>","<span class=\"x_x_x_ContentPasted0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"I think it is the best shot the U.S. has right now to compete in digital dollar currency,” Circle CEO Jeremy Allaire said. <\/span>","<span class=\"x_x_x_ContentPasted0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The legislation is under <\/span><a class=\"x_x_x_ContentPasted0\" title=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/171565\/draft-stablecoin-bill-in-congress-to-require-fed-state-regulator-approval\" href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/171565\/draft-stablecoin-bill-in-congress-to-require-fed-state-regulator-approval\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">discussion<\/a><span class=\"x_x_x_ContentPasted0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> by the House Financial Services Committee. The bill would allow for private stablecoin issuers to register through financial regulators, provided they meet certain standards. The legislation would also require the Federal Reserve to report to Congress on the possibility of a central bank digital currency.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"x_x_x_ContentPasted0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The legislation \"does a very good job of establishing what this new form of digital currency money is,\" Allaire said.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"x_x_x_ContentPasted0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Allaire made his remarks at a fintech conference hosted by Georgetown Law School, alongside Crypto Council for Innovation CEO Sheila Warren and Bank of International Settlements Economic Adviser and Head of Research Hyun Song Shin.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"x_x_x_ContentPasted0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Warren, a major industry advocate, expressed optimism that the bill, which has <\/span><a class=\"x_x_x_ContentPasted0\" title=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/175080\/despite-call-for-congress-to-act-new-crypto-laws-look-unlikely-this-year\" href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/175080\/despite-call-for-congress-to-act-new-crypto-laws-look-unlikely-this-year\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">stalled in committee<\/a><span class=\"x_x_x_ContentPasted0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, could “really solidify” in the next year.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"x_x_x_ContentPasted0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Financial Stability Oversight Council, a committee of senior regulators chaired by Treasury Secretary Janet Yellen, released a report last week encouraging lawmakers to pass new stablecoin regulations. The move could give the legislation new momentum.<\/span><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/b>","<span class=\"x_x_x_ContentPasted0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Shin believes there is a role for stablecoins in the financial ecosystem, but said they could look like banking products from a regulatory perspective.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"x_x_x_ContentPasted0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“If it looks like a bank deposit, if it actually works like a bank deposit, then it should be regulated like a bank deposit,” Shin said.<\/span>","<span class=\"x_x_x_ContentPasted0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Banks are at different stages of internal discussion around stablecoins, Shin added. The BIS is not <\/span><span class=\"x_x_x_ContentPasted0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"here to foist some kind of agenda,\" Shin said, but will \"point out what’s feasible.”<\/span>","<span class=\"x_x_x_ContentPasted0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Banks are at different stages of internal discussion, different stages in the domestic debate,\" Shin said. “I think there is a role for stablecoins in this ecosystem.”<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Jeremy Allaire","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Federal Reserve","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bank of International Settlements Economic Adviser","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sheila Warren","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Shin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Washington","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Janet Yellen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Congress","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BIS","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Allaire","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Circle","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Georgetown Law School","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Crypto Council","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"House Financial Services Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"D.C.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Head of Research Hyun Song Shin","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Financial Stability Oversight Council","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Stephanie Murray","The Block"]}