{"summary":"District Judge Analisa Torres rejected the SEC’s move to certify for interlocutory appeal and set trial dates for next year.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/254625\/judge-torres-rejects-the-secs-motion-for-an-interlocutory-appeal-in-ripple-case","publishDate":"2023-10-03T19:49:33","id":4300,"type":null,"title":"Judge Torres rejects the SEC&#x27;s motion for an interlocutory appeal in Ripple case","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">District Judge Analisa Torres rejected the Securities and Exchange Commission’s move to certify for interlocutory appeal in its battle with crypto firm Ripple, noting the agency did not demonstrate that the appeal would “materially advance the ultimate termination of the litigation.”<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“For the reasons stated above, the SEC’s motion for certification of interlocutory appeal is DENIED, and the SEC’s request for a stay is DENIED as moot,” Torres said in an <a href=\"https:\/\/ecf.nysd.uscourts.gov\/cgi-bin\/show_temp.pl?file=file0.409272609084052.pdf&amp;type=application\/pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">order<\/span><\/a> on Tuesday in the U.S. District Court for the Southern District of New York.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A trial is then set for April 23, 2024. Ripple and the SEC are expected to submit pretrial filings by the end of the year, Torres said.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Prior to the final pretrial conference, counsel for both parties, along with the parties themselves, shall meet in person for at least one hour to discuss settlement of this matter,” Torres said. <\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In August, the SEC filed a motion in the U.S.<\/span><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> District Court in the Southern District of New York, asking it to certify for interlocutory appeal. At the time, SEC lawyers <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/246372\/sec-asks-court-to-certify-for-interlocutory-appeal-in-ripple-labs-case\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">argued<\/span><\/a> that the way in which the court handles the Ripple case could have a \"substantial impact\" on other pending litigation like those between the regulatory agency and top crypto trading platforms Binance and Coinbase.<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The SEC wanted to appeal the part of the decision about the programmatic sales as well as “other distributions” that included offers and sales of XRP in exchange for goods and services.<\/span>","<span class=\"s5\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Torres <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/239559\/sec-faces-wake-up-call-after-ripple-ruling-though-appeal-likely\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s6\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ruled<\/span><\/a><\/span><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in July that some of Ripple’s sales of XRP did not violate securities laws. She also ruled that other direct sales of the token to institutional investors were securities, leaving a partial win for the SEC.<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The SEC first brought a lawsuit against Ripple and its executives in 2020. The agency accused the firm of raising $1.3 billion in 2020 through the sale of XRP and has also sued CEO Brad Garlinghouse and co-founder Christian Larsen.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$1.3 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. District Court","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.<\/span><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> District Court","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Brad Garlinghouse","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"” Torres","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Torres","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Analisa Torres","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Southern District of New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"April 23, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"the Southern District of New York","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"XRP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Christian Larsen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["SEC"],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}