{"summary":"OMA3 is now in the process of creating working groups to explore topics such as legal problems pertaining to web3. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/181648\/open-metaverse-alliance-membership-web3-builders","publishDate":"2022-11-01T07:46:28","id":4329,"type":null,"title":"Open Metaverse Alliance opens up membership to web3 builders","category":["GAMING AND METAVERSE"],"content":["Open Metaverse Alliance (OMA3) has officially launched today and is offering memberships across two tiers, sponsor and creator.","First announced in July with the hope of establishing standards between metaverse platforms, it is now in the process of creating working groups to explore topics such as legal problems pertaining to web3.&nbsp;","When it was originally <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/159147\/animoca-brands-metaverse-platforms-launch-interoperability-dao\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/a>, the majority of associated members had links to Hong Kong-based game software and venture capital firm Animoca Brands. OMA3 includes Animoca Brands, The Sandbox (which is one of its subsidiaries) and several brands the company has invested in — Alien Worlds, Dapper Labs, Splinterlands, Star Atlas and Upland.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","It also includes Decentraland, with which Animoca Brands has collaborated on projects Cryptovoxels, Meta Metaverse, Space, Superworld and Wivity. Bored Ape Yacht Club creator Yuga Labs and web3 domain provider Unstoppable Domains have also joined.","The group will be governed by a decentralized autonomous organization and has been in progress since 2021, according to a <a href=\"https:\/\/decrypt.co\/113261\/open-metaverse-alliance-says-it-wont-let-meta-define-future-of-the-internet\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">report<\/a> by Decrypt.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Metaverse Alliance (OMA3)","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Star Atlas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bored Ape Yacht Club","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dapper Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Meta Metaverse","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Animoca Brands","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wivity","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Upland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Decentraland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Splinterlands","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["INTEROPERABILITY"],"authors":["Lucy Harley-McKeown","The Block"]}