{"summary":"Former White House communications Director Anthony Scaramucci says there was fraud at FTX.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/202261\/scaramucci-changes-tone-on-ftx-says-its-clear-now-there-was-fraud","publishDate":"2023-01-13T13:55:12","id":4347,"type":null,"title":"Scaramucci changes tone on FTX, says it&#x27;s clear there was fraud now","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Anthony Scaramucci has done a 180 on FTX.","\"It's very clear now that there was fraud,\" the SkyBridge Capital founder <a href=\"https:\/\/www.cnbc.com\/2023\/01\/13\/scaramucci-says-skybridge-can-buy-back-ftx-stake-this-year-alleges-sbf-committed-fraud.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">told<\/a> CNBC. \"We'll, of course, have to let the legal system determine all of those things.\"","Scaramucci had been hesitant to proclaim fraud in the immediate aftermath of the collapse of the crypto exchange last year, telling CNBC TV at the time that he didn't want to use the word \"because that's actually a legal term.\" Scaramucci told The Block that the guilty <a href=\"https:\/\/www.cnbc.com\/2022\/12\/22\/ftxs-gary-wang-alamedas-caroline-ellison-plead-guilty-to-federal-charges-cooperating-with-prosecutors.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">pleas<\/a> last month of FTX co-founder Gary Wang and former Alameda Research co-CEO Caroline Ellison changed his mind.","Bankman-Fried's FTX Ventures <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/168848\/ftx-ventures-to-take-30-stake-in-skybridge-capital-cnbc\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">took<\/a> a 30% stake in SkyBridge Capital in September, with the partnership born out of Scaramucci's involvement with the SALT conference, Bankman-Fried said at the time.&nbsp;The SkyBridge founder has reiterated the fund's intention to buy back the FTX stake this year.","<span class=\"TextRun SCXW237480110 BCX0\" lang=\"EN-US\" xml:lang=\"EN-US\" data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"NormalTextRun SCXW237480110 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We’re waiting for the clearance from the bankruptcy people, the lawyers, and the investment bankers to figure out exactly what we’re going to be buying back and when,”<\/span><\/span><span class=\"EOP SCXW237480110 BCX0\" data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;134233117&quot;:false,&quot;134233118&quot;:false,&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335551550&quot;:1,&quot;335551620&quot;:1,&quot;335559685&quot;:0,&quot;335559737&quot;:0,&quot;335559738&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> he said. <\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"SkyBridge Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Caroline Ellison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Anthony Scaramucci","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"CNBC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fried","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"30%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SkyBridge","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gary Wang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Scaramucci","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["FTX","SAM BANKMAN-FRIED"],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}