{"summary":"The move comes nearly a week after Anchorage&#x27;s partnership with Digital Prime Technologies to enable institutional crypto lending services.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/263334\/anchorage-digital-launches-custody-and-trading-separately-managed-accounts-for-registered-investment-advisors","publishDate":"2023-11-16T10:13:01","id":4374,"type":null,"title":"Anchorage Digital launches custody and trading separately managed accounts for registered investment advisors","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["U.S.- based federally chartered crypto bank Anchorage Digital announced new offerings for registered investment advisors. ","The new custody and trading separately managed accounts (SMA) gives RIAs custody and settlement services with a focus on security and compliance, according to a company <a href=\"https:\/\/www.anchorage.com\/insights\/anchorage-digital-launches-registered-investment-advisor-offering\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">release<\/a>. Anchorage launched the accounts with its partners Eaglebrook Advisors and <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/245918\/securitize-onramp\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Onramp Invest<\/a>, a subsidiary of Securitize, a firm that tokenizes private investments.","“After the recent SEC custody rule proposal, demand from RIAs for a qualified crypto custodian is higher than ever before. Leveraging our status as the only OCC-chartered digital asset bank, our new offering enables RIAs to access the digital asset class through safe, secure and regulated infrastructure,\" said Anchorage Digital co-founder and president Diogo Mónica in a statement.&nbsp;","The move marks Anchorage's second major crypto partnership this month. The firm paired with institutional crypto lending provider Digital Prime Technologies on Nov. 7, in which Anchorage would act as the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/262083\/tokenet-launches-crypto-lending-with-anchorage\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">custodian<\/a> for institutional investors borrowing and lending digital assets.&nbsp;","Anchorage's SMA partner Eaglebrook Advisors also <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/174436\/cathie-woods-ark-invest-partners-with-eaglebrook-advisors\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">partnered<\/a> with Cathie Wood's Ark Invest to refine accessibility to crypto investment strategies in late last year.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Anchorage Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cathie Wood","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"OCC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Diogo Mónica","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Anchorage","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Eaglebrook Advisors","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Digital Prime Technologies","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nov. 7","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SMA","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["CRYPTO BANKS AND LENDERS"],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}