{"summary":"A group of web3 companies has banned together to unveil a new alliance focused on privacy.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/176823\/web3-companies-launch-privacy-focused-alliance-at-devcon","publishDate":"2022-10-12T19:42:35","id":4406,"type":null,"title":"Web3 companies launch privacy-focused alliance at Devcon","category":["PRIVACY"],"content":["A group of web3 companies has launched an alliance focused on raising awareness about the need for data privacy following U.S. sanctions on coin mixer Tornado Cash, as well as a legal defense fund to support its mission.&nbsp;","Web3 companies including <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">p0xeidon labs,<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Nym Technologies<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Secret Network from SCRT Labs<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Orchid<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Railgun<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Status <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">and Oasis Foundation’s <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Oasis Network are participating in the alliance.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"The Universal Privacy Alliance [UPA] aims to protect privacy regardless of the blockchain or technology stack,\" the group said in a statement. \"<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">It provides the foundation for privacy at the native level, thereby providing the security and democracy emerging technologies need to thrive.\"<\/span>","The alliance also unveiled the UPA Legal Defense Fund, which it says will support its main goal of \"<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">defending the right to experiment, build, and use full-stack privacy technologies.\"&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"This move comes amidst a rising tide of censorship, suppression, and even criminalization of privacy technologies,\" the UPA said in its statement.<\/span>","Organizers behind the Universal Privacy Alliance unveiled the new group at an Oct. 11 side event during the Ethereum Foundation's Devcon conference in Bogota, Colombia. The launch, which took place at the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.youtube.com\/watch?v=S7tsyMnqcCU\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ZK House<\/a> hackerspace, featured remarks via video conference from former intelligence contractor Edward Snowden.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Railgun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Edward Snowden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Nym Technologies","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bogota","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"ZK House","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"UPA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ethereum Foundation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Universal Privacy Alliance [UPA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Colombia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"UPA Legal Defense Fund","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Oct. 11","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Universal Privacy Alliance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Devcon","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Oasis Foundation’s <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Oasis Network","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Kristin Majcher","The Block"]}