{"summary":"Singapore&#x27;s regulator has now approved 14 digital payment token service license applicants in the past two years.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/153488\/singapore-crypto-com-genesis-sparrow-approval","publishDate":"2022-06-22T07:44:18","id":4415,"type":null,"title":"Singapore provisionally approves Crypto.com, Genesis and Sparrow for payments","category":["REGULATION"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Monetary Authority of Singapore (MAS) gave in-principle approval to Crypto.com, Genesis and Sparrow to offer crypto payment services in the country.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Deputy Prime Minister of Singapore, Heng Swee Keat, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.mas.gov.sg\/news\/speeches\/2022\/speech-by-mr-heng-swee-keat-deputy-prime-minister-and-coordinating-minister-for-economic-policies-at-the-opening-of-point-zero-forum-on-22-june-2022\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a><\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;on Wednesday that three additional digital payment token service license applicants had received in-principle approval — bringing the total to 14.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“There are many other good use cases within the broader digital asset ecosystem. We should therefore take the same approach as earlier tech waves,” he said. Before going on to say “Singapore remains keen to work with blockchain and digital asset players.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Major Payment Institution License enables companies to offer a range of payment services, including offering customers in Singapore cryptocurrency services or digital payment token (DPT) services.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kris Marszalek, CEO and co-founder of Crypto.com, noted the high standards set by MAS and said they help to foster innovation. “We look forward to continuing to collaborate with the MAS and deepening our roots in Singapore – a flourishing market for fintech innovation, renowned for its well-regulated&nbsp; business environment,” he <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/crypto.com\/company-news\/crypto-com-receives-in-principle-approval-from-the-monetary-authority-of-singapore\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">concluded<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Today’s announcement comes just three weeks after MAS <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/149403\/singapore-regulator-announces-plans-to-explore-blockchain-use-cases\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> plans to research use cases for decentralized finance (DeFi) on public blockchains. The plans are known as Project Guardian and include partners such as JPMorgan, Marketnote and DBS.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sparrow and Genesis did not immediately respond to requests for comment from The Block. <\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"DPT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"DBS","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kris Marszalek","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Monetary Authority of Singapore (MAS","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Genesis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"MAS","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Marketnote","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Heng Swee Keat","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}