{"summary":"Floor co-founders break down how increased liquidity is causing NFT market structure to evolve. Listen now.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/228908\/floor-nft-market","publishDate":"2023-05-01T09:36:49","id":4437,"type":null,"title":"NFT prices are falling as projects with strong communities remain resilient","category":["ORGANIZATIONS"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 42<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 5 of The Scoop was recorded with <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro, and Floor co-founders Christine Brown and Chris Maddern<\/strong><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/strong><\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a>,<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Please send feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"3848575c5b594b4c784c505d5a54575b53165b57\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/i>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm\/?e=BLOCK2562421061\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","NFT floor prices and trading volume are in decline. However, for NFT projects with strong communities, now is the time to stand out from the pack, according to Floor co-founders Christine Brown and Chris Maddern. Floor, which aims to be an '<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/204629\/nft-price-tracker-floor-acquires-web3-analytics-firm-wgmi\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">everything app<\/a>' for NFTs, raised $8 million from a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/150906\/nft-price-tracker-floor-raises-8-million-in-series-a-funding\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Series A<\/a> funding round in June of 2022.","In this episode, Brown and Maddern discuss how increased liquidity in NFT markets is accelerating price discovery and where value is accumulating in this new paradigm of NFT market structure.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsor <i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.cleanspark.com\/theblock\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CleanSpark<\/a>.<\/i><\/b><\/span>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About CleanSpark<\/strong>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CleanSpark (NASDAQ: CLSK) is America’s Bitcoin Miner™. Visit <a href=\"https:\/\/www.cleanspark.com\/theblock\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">cleanspark.com\/theblock<\/a> to learn more about the CleanSpark way.<\/span><\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Maddern","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$8 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"America","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"June of 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Brown","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Chris Maddern","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Christine Brown","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}