{"summary":"South Korean regulators are mulling plans for the crypto industry following Terra&#x27;s collapse this month.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/148491\/terras-vortex-of-death-brings-scrutiny-from-south-korean-regulators","publishDate":"2022-05-24T12:41:38","id":4491,"type":null,"title":"Terra’s &#x27;vortex of death&#x27; brings scrutiny from South Korean regulators","category":["REGULATION"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The National Assembly in South Korea held a meeting on Tuesday to discuss the fallout from the Terra collapse, while representatives from domestic crypto companies were also present.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">South Korea’s financial regulators came together on Tuesday to discuss how to address fallout from this month’s collapse of the TerraUSD stablecoin.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Financial Supervisory Service (FSS), the Fair Trade Commission (FTC) and the Financial Service Commission (FSC) shared updates following an emergency meeting held at the National Assembly, according to local news reports.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TerraUSD, an algorithmic stablecoin on the Terra blockchain known by its ticker UST, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/146722\/terra-says-it-has-halted-blockchain-for-second-time-in-24-hours\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">de-pegged<\/a> from the dollar in catastrophic fashion this month, destroying more than $40 billion in value for investors. The Financial Intelligence Unit, the investigations unit of the FSC, referred to the incident — which saw the supply of luna soar in an effort to stabilize UST’s price — as a “vortex of death,” YNA News <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/n.news.naver.com\/mnews\/article\/001\/0013201240?sid=101\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> today.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">According to the FIU, there were 100,000 luna holders in Korea before the collapse — and this number increased sharply to 180,000 in the 10 days after UST lost its peg.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The FSS revealed on Tuesday that it plans to inspect the premises of companies that provide financial services related to the Terra blockchain, following its collapse, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/n.news.naver.com\/mnews\/article\/008\/0004750160?sid=100\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">according to a report by Money Today<\/span><\/a>.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Speaking after the event, Chan-woo Lee, senior vice president of the FSS, said that the possibility of the crisis affecting traditional financial markets was still low and in order to prevent the risk on-site investigations would be conducted.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">These inspections will look at payment services related to Terra, how the services are maintained, the status of withdrawal funds and the standards in place to protect users.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In addition to this the FSS will develop a research service aimed at analyzing the risk of cryptocurrencies and digital assets that circulate on domestic exchanges. The service will then classify these assets according to their risk characteristics.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">South Korea’s FTC announced plans to examine cryptocurrency exchanges compliance with guidance from last year relating to terms and conditions, according to local reports from <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.yna.co.kr\/view\/AKR20220524118600002?input=1195m\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">YNA News<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.&nbsp;<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Last year the FTC recommended that 16 domestic exchanges, including Bithumb Korea and Dunamu, should correct their existing terms and conditions as they were unfavorable to users.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Starting in June, we will intensively check whether the recommendations for correction of 20 types of unfair terms and conditions are implemented, and issue a correction order if necessary,\" it said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Following the meeting on Tuesday, the FSC <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.yna.co.kr\/view\/AKR20220524110100002?input=1195m\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> it was actively reviewing new cryptocurrency regulation relating to stablecoins and decentralized finance (DeFi), YNA news reported.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"The characteristics of virtual assets such as decentralization, anonymity and transboundary nature make it essential to secure consistency with global regulations and strengthen the cooperative system to secure regulatory effectiveness,\" the FSC noted, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.yna.co.kr\/view\/AKR20220524110100002?input=1195m\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">according<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to local reports.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The regulator went on to stress the importance of global regulatory consistency. Noting that consideration must be given to trends discussed by international institutions like the Bank of International Settlements and the Financial Stability Board, as well as the US executive order on crypto.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Local reports noted that there are 13 bills pending in the National Assembly at present relating to the crypto industry, including the Electronic Financial Transactions Act.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"South Korea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"FSS","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Financial Service Commission (FSC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Financial Supervisory Service","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bank of International Settlements","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FSC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Terra","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Terra blockchain","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Financial Stability Board","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"YNA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$40 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Financial Intelligence Unit","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Korea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"YNA News","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fair Trade Commission (FTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"National Assembly","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bithumb Korea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"June","content":"DATE"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"FIU","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Money Today","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UST","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}