{"summary":"Yi Xiao, a former provincial-level official, was sentenced to life in jail for wrongdoings, including supporting crypto mining.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/246694\/china-life-prison-crypto-mining-corruption","publishDate":"2023-08-22T06:59:49","id":4497,"type":null,"title":"China sentences former party official to life in prison for crypto mining corruption, power abuse","category":["LEGAL"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">China has sentenced a former party official to life imprisonment for corruptive activities, including those related to cryptocurrency mining, a Chinese court <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.court.gov.cn\/fabu\/xiangqing\/409502.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">pronounced<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> today.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Yi Xiao, a former provincial-level official in the southeastern province of Jiangxi, was accused of abusing his power to facilitate crypto-mining activities.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The court trial in Hangzhou, a city in East China’s Zhejiang province, found that, from 2008 to 2021, Xiao took advantage of his positions, including his role as a vice chairman of the Jiangxi provincial committee of the People’s political consultative conference, to illegally accept more than 125 million yuan ($17.1 million) in bribes, the court said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Also, when Xiao served as a party secretary of Fuzhou city from 2017 to 2021, he assisted companies engaged in crypto mining, “resulting in significant losses to public property, national and people’s interests,” the court said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">As a result, Xiao was sentenced to life imprisonment, deprived of political rights for life and had all personal property confiscated.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Unlike its neighboring Hong Kong, which is actively developing the crypto and Web3 industries, China banned all crypto transactions on the mainland in September 2021.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">China <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/105973\/china-inner-mongolia-crypto-bitcoin-mining-ban-measures\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">started<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> a broader crackdown on crypto mining in May 2021 in some provinces.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Last week, a local court in the Guangxi autonomous region <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/244929\/chinese-filecoin-mining-firm-charged-for-allegedly-orchestrating-83-3-million-pyramid-scheme\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> it heard a case of Shenzhen Shikongyun Technology, one of the largest Filecoin mining firms in China, for its alleged involvement in an $83.3 million pyramid scheme.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Guangxi","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"May 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Yi Xiao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$17.1 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"September 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"East China","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2008","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Xiao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Hangzhou","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"125 million yuan","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Fuzhou","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Jiangxi","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Shenzhen Shikongyun Technology","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"China","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Zhejiang","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$83.3 million","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["ASIAN REGULATION","COURT HEARINGS","CRIME"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}