{"summary":"In this episode of The Scoop, Sam Bankman-Fried describes how a legacy payment system linked FTX’s future to Alameda’s fate, and why regulators and auditors alike failed to discover this relationship.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/192005\/2-hour-sit-down-with-sam-bankman-fried-on-the-ftx-scandal","publishDate":"2022-12-05T05:00:45","id":4553,"type":null,"title":"2-hour sit-down with Sam Bankman-Fried on the FTX scandal","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 121<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 4 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro, and Sam Bankman-Fried, co-founder of FTX and Alameda Research.<\/strong><\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Or click here to watch the full interview on <a href=\"https:\/\/www.youtube.com\/watch?v=zGNiYt1GN_4&amp;t=3038s\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">YouTube<\/a>. Email feedback and revision requests can be sent to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"54243b303735272014203c3136383b373f37262d24203b7a373b39\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK7074136408\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/i>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In this episode of The Scoop, Sam Bankman-Fried describes how a legacy payment system linked FTX’s future to Alameda Research’s fate, and explores why regulators and auditors alike failed to discover this relationship.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">According to Bankman-Fried, many FTX customers would fund their accounts via direct wire transfers to Alameda Research bank accounts:<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“What that flow I think looked like was basically: Bob wires $100 straight to Alameda Research, and then Alameda effectively ledger transfers $100 to Bob on FTX.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">SBF has claimed that wired customer funds contributed to <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/191955\/sbf-says-he-can-only-speculate-about-where-wired-alameda-funds-ended-up-wsj\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">over half<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> of Alameda’s position on FTX, likely totaling over $5 billion, as reported by The Wall Street Journal.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In hindsight, SBF says a “reasonably responsible” way of managing direct wire transfers would have been only debiting Alameda’s primary FTX account. In practice, however, wired customer funds were being credited from an Alameda stub account that SBF says “was specifically meant to be a ledger for wire transfers.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">When pressed on how regulators and auditors failed to uncover the extent of Alameda’s relationship to FTX, SBF alleged that customer positions — including Alameda’s — were not part of FTX’s balance sheet:<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“This was effectively a customer negative position, and many customers had negative positions open on FTX … Those were not part of FTX's assets or liabilities, they were customer assets and liabilities, and so FTX's financials were not directly impacted by this.”<\/span>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">During this episode, Chaparro and Bankman-Fried also discuss:<\/span><\/i>","","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Tron,&nbsp;<\/em><\/a><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.ledn.io\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ledn, <\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"http:\/\/athleticgreens.com\/scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Athletic Greens<\/a><\/strong><\/span><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em><\/b><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nAbout Tron<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Founded in 2013, Huobi Global is one of the largest virtual asset exchanges in the world. Huobi Global serves millions of users across international markets. Since its establishment, Huobi Global has committed to providing first class virtual asset investment services. Huobi Global's robust infrastructure, product innovation and capital strength provides a truly customer-centric and secure trading environment to help our international users to achieve their investment objectives. Please refer to Huobi's official website for more information: <a href=\"http:\/\/www.huobi.com\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">huobi.com<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Ledn<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong>Ledn was founded on the unshakeable conviction that digital assets have the power to democratize access to the global economy. We help you to experience the real life benefits of your Bitcoin without having to sell it. Start a savings account, take out a loan, or double your Bitcoin. For more information visit&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.ledn.io\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ledn.io<\/a><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Athletic Greens<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong>Build a Foundation for Better Health. It’s time to reclaim your health and arm your immune system with convenient, daily nutrition! Fill nutrient gaps, promote gut health, and support whole-body vitality with AG1. One daily serving delivers a potent blend of 9 health products—a multivitamin, minerals, probiotics, adaptogens and more—working together to help you feel like your healthiest self. For more information visit <a href=\"http:\/\/AthleticGreens.com\/Scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">AthleticGreens.com\/Scoop<\/a><\/span><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Huobi Global","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2013","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$5 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fried","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ledn","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Huobi","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ledn<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong>Ledn","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Athletic Greens<\/a><\/strong><\/span><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em><\/b><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nAbout Tron<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Founded","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$100","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ledn.io<\/a><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Athletic Greens<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong>Build a Foundation for Better Health","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SBF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}