{"summary":"NFT unicorn Candy Digital laid of a large number of its employees roughly a year after the company&#x27;s valuation shot to $1.5 billion.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/190479\/candy-digital-nft-shop-lays-off-large-number-of-employees-amid-market-deterioration","publishDate":"2022-11-29T07:24:55","id":4573,"type":null,"title":"Candy Digital NFT shop lays off large number of employees amid market deterioration","category":["METAVERSE & NFT"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Digital collectibles firm Candy Digital, financially backed by industry heavyweights Mike Novogratz and Gary Vaynerchuk, has cut a large number of jobs — perhaps as much as half of its employees — roughly a year after the company achieved <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/121632\/nft-startup-candy-digital-raises-100-million-in-series-a-round\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">unicorn status<\/a> when its valuation shot to $1.5 billion.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Earlier Monday on Discord, Candy Digital’s Head of Customer Experiences <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Megan Merrick announced the company had been forced to reduce its workforce amid “<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">challenging macroeconomic” conditions and “rapidly deteriorating market conditions.” <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sportico <a href=\"https:\/\/www.sportico.com\/business\/tech\/2022\/candy-digital-layoffs-nfts-1234696807\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">first reported<\/a> the layoffs, saying that more than a third of the company’s roughly 100 employees had been let go, citing anonymous sources. One laid off employee, who preferred to remain anonymous, told The Block that as many as half of Candy Digital employees may have been let go. The employee added their dismissal didn't come as a surprise given the current downturn engulfing companies operating in crypto-related fields.&nbsp;<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Both Candy Digital and its majority owner, the sports themed, e-commerce player Fanatics, did not immediately respond to requests for comment.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Candy Digital, which primarily creates sports focused, non-fungible tokens, is backed by web3 leaders like<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Novogratz, Vaynerchuk and Michael Rubin. The company achieved its unicorn status last October after raising <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$100 million in Series A financing.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Insight Partners and Softbank Vision Fund 2 co-led the funding round which included investors like former NFL quarterback Peyton Manning, Connect Ventures, Will Ventures, Gaingels, Com2Us, and Athletes Syndicate through a partnership with Chaos Ventures. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">While Candy Digital has teamed up with world-renowned brands like Major League Baseball, World Wrestling Entertainment (WWE) and Netflix, weekly sales volumes for digital collectibles have plummeted since April, crashing by as much as 95% at one point. Layoffs among web3 companies have been grabbing headlines in recent weeks. Earlier this month, Candy Digital's rival Dapper Labs <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/182461\/dapper-labs-feldman-a-difficult-day-as-company-lays-off-22-of-staff\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">laid off almost<\/a> one-quarter of its employees.<\/span>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/nft-non-fungible-tokens\/nft-overview\/weekly-trade-volume-of-nfts\/embed\" title=\"Weekly Trade Volume of NFTs by Category\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Connect Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$100 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Peyton Manning","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Netflix","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Athletes Syndicate","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Novogratz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"quarter","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Michael Rubin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Mike Novogratz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Candy Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Discord, Candy Digital’s Head of Customer Experiences <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Megan Merrick","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chaos Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Major League Baseball","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gaingels","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$1.5 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Vaynerchuk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"95%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Will Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gary Vaynerchuk","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"October","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Softbank","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}