{"summary":"The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission has sued Binance Holdings Ltd. and CEO Changpeng Zhao, Bloomberg News reported, citing a federal court filing.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/233146\/us-sec-sues-binance-ceo-zhao-for-breaking-securities-rules","publishDate":"2023-06-05T11:17:43","id":4583,"type":null,"title":"US SEC sues Binance, CEO Zhao for breaking securities rules: Bloomberg","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission has sued Binance Holdings Ltd. and CEO Changpeng Zhao, Bloomberg News <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2023-06-05\/sec-sues-binance-and-ceo-zhao-for-breaking-us-securities-rules\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a>, citing a federal court filing.","The suit accused them of breaking U.S. rules, Bloomberg said.","\"Our team is all standing by, ensuring systems are stable, including withdrawals, and deposits,\" Zhao said on <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/cz_binance\/status\/1665740237979492353\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Twitter<\/a>. \"We will issue a response once we see the compliant. Haven't seen it yet. Media gets the info before we do.\"","The price of bitcoin fell immediately following the news, declining 2.6% to $26,412, according to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/symbols\/BTCUSD\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TradingView<\/a>.","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This story is developing and will be updated.<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$26,412","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"TradingView","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2.6%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Changpeng Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bloomberg News","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Binance Holdings Ltd.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE"],"authors":["Nathan Crooks","The Block"]}