{"summary":"IEX president Ronan Ryan broke down the market data debate and where it&#x27;s headed in the crypto realm on this week&#x27;s episode of The Scoop.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/74737\/ronan-ryan-exchanges-data","publishDate":"2020-08-12T16:21:57","id":4591,"type":null,"title":"IEX head on why bitcoin exchanges will eventually charge for market data","category":["PODCASTS"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 32 of Season 2 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block’s Frank Chaparro and Ronan Ryan, president of IEX, the Investor’s Exchange.<\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"2959464d4a485a5d695d414c4b45464a424a5b50595d46074a4644\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode of The Scoop is brought to you by Bitstamp, the original global cryptocurrency exchange. Since 2011, Bitstamp has been a cornerstone of the industry, earning the trust of over four million individuals and top financial institutions looking for a reliable trading venue. <\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Whether you’re trading on our web platform, mobile app or industry-leading APIs, Bitstamp gives you the professional-grade tools you need to execute your strategy.&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/bitstamp.net\/app?r=pro%E2%80%93&amp;utm_source=Website&amp;utm_medium=podcast&amp;utm_campaign=theblock&amp;utm_content=ctaapp\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Download the Bitstamp app<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or visit&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.bitstamp.net\/pro\/?utm_source=Website&amp;utm_medium=podcast&amp;utm_campaign=theblock&amp;utm_content=ctaweb\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitstamp.net\/Pro<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;to learn more and start trading today!<\/i>","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK5262613537\" width=\"100%\" height=\"200\" frameborder=\"0\" scrolling=\"no\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","The cost of market data is an ongoing debate in the traditional finance world, but in crypto, not so much. But during this week's episode of The Scoop, Ronan Ryan, head of IEX, the Investor's Exchange, said that's going to change.","The method by which Wall Street exchanges make money hand over fist is <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/daily\/69481\/why-crypto-exchanges-arent-likely-to-charge-for-market-data-anytime-soon\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">all but nonexistent<\/a> in the digital asset space, with none of the major digital asset exchanges charging for market data. This is because trading fees are more than high enough to keep the lights on.&nbsp;","Still, Ryan told The Scoop that he'd seen this before in the U.S. equities market. Once, equities exchanges rarely charged for data. Now, it's the standard. Ryan saw the change first-hand, since IEX is a U.S.-based exchange dealing primarily in equities. Once a fledgling firm, it now does more volume than the London Stock Exchange.&nbsp;&nbsp;","\"Maybe U.S. equities is kind of like a litmus test and it was just slightly ahead of the grain in terms of what you'll see in your [the digital asset] space,\" he said. \"But I wouldn't be surprised to see exchanges charging for data down the line like exchanges used to not charge for data in U.S. equities.\"","Regulators have also begun to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.wsj.com\/articles\/sec-justice-department-to-scrutinize-exchanges-market-data-business-11592864481\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">take notice<\/a>, with the Securities and Exchange Commission and the Department of Justice partnering to take a closer look at market data fees from exchanges like Nasdaq and the New York Stock Exchange. Ryan broke down the market data discussion from both the traditional and crypto viewpoints on this week's episode. He also explored:","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen to this week's episode on Apple, Spotify, Google Play, Stitcher or wherever you listen to podcasts.<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Investor’s Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ryan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Department of Justice","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2011","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ronan Ryan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York Stock Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Stock Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bitstamp","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"London","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nasdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Aislinn Keely","The Block"]}