{"summary":"SEC Commissioner Hester Peirce spoke on The Scoop podcast about where crypto regulation could be headed in the next few years.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/213074\/sec-planting-its-regulatory-flag-as-congress-still-to-pick-a-regulator-secs-peirce","publishDate":"2023-02-20T05:00:14","id":4596,"type":null,"title":"SEC planting its regulatory flag as Congress still to pick a regulator: SEC’s Peirce","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Securities and Exchange Commission is attempting to “plant its regulatory flag,\" while Congress is still mulling which agency will be police crypto, said Hester Peirce, a commissioner at the regulator.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The SEC has been busy with enforcement actions against crypto firms and individuals, bringing two cases over just the last week. The SEC brought charges against Terraform Labs and its CEO Do Hyeong Kwon over its collapsed algorithmic stablecoin Terra USD on Thursday. Then on Friday morning the agency charged and settled with NBA Hall of Famer Paul Pierce for unlawfully touting a token.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We’re going to struggle for a while to get to a place where we really are productively regulating it,” Peirce, a Republican commissioner appointed to the agency, told The Block’s Frank Chaparro on <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/213160\/commissioner-peirce-on-the-secs-unimaginative-approach-to-regulation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Scoop podcast<\/a>. <\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A lot of what happens next is up to Congress and what agency they pick to regulate, Peirce added. &nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Lawmakers have introduced comprehensive legislation as well as smaller bills to regulate sections of the industry, which would have to be reintroduced this year. <\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Some <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/211777\/senate-republican-drafting-proof-of-reserve-legislation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">legislation<\/span><\/a> may already on the way. Senator Thom Tillis, a North Caroline Republican, is drafting a bill that would require digital asset exchanges and custodians operating in the U.S. to provide an independently verified proof-of-reserves for their assets. Massachusetts Democrat Senator Elizabeth Warren <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/211783\/warren-pledges-to-reintroduce-crypto-anti-money-laundering-bill\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">pledged<\/span><\/a> to reintroduce a bill to tighten anti-money laundering rules for crypto firms during a Senate Banking Committee hearing on Feb. 14. &nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Peirce is often at odds with the other commissioners at the regulator, and just last week<\/span><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> was the lone vote against a proposed rule to tighten crypto custody requirements. She spoke on the podcast <\/span><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> about how crypto exchanges could be regulated in the future. SEC Chair Gary Gensler has repeatedly said they need to register with the agency.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“One of the problems that you have is that all of these trading platforms are likely to have on them assets that no one thinks are securities,” Peirce said. “And we’re not used to having platforms that trade securities alongside non-securities. That’s going to be an issue that we have to resolve.”&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The next two years will be “consequential” for how the cryptocurrency industry develops in the long term, she said.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Correction: Peirce is one of two Republican commissioners currently appointed to the SEC; this article originally stated she was the only Republican on the commission.&nbsp;<\/em><\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Hester Peirce","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Caroline Republican","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Congress","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"” Peirce","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Feb. 14","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gary Gensler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Terra USD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Peirce","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"morning","content":"TIME"},{"type":"Thom Tillis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Senate Banking Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Hyeong Kwon","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NBA Hall of Famer Paul Pierce","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Elizabeth Warren","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}