{"summary":"Cameron Winklevoss left his spot on Gemini Europe&#x27;s board of directors on October 12.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/177602\/cameron-winklevoss-steps-down-from-gemini-europes-leadership-altfi","publishDate":"2022-10-17T05:22:08","id":460,"type":null,"title":"Cameron Winklevoss steps down from Gemini Europe&#x27;s leadership: AltFi","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["Cameron Winklevoss left his spot on Gemini Europe's board of directors, <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">AltFi<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.altfi.com\/article\/9990_cameron-winklevoss-steps-down-as-director-of-gemini-europe?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_campaign=daniel-lanyon\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> reports<\/a>, citing a Companies House filing. The investor, billionaire and co-founder of crypto exchange Gemini officially stopped being the director of its European branch on October 12. A spokesperson from the company confirmed the news to AltFi via email.<\/span>","Cameron Winklevoss and his twin brother, Tyler Winklevoss, remain President and CEO at Gemini. The pair established the crypto exchange in 2014.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Gemini's latest Europe-related news follows last week's&nbsp;<\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/177584\/coinbases-new-regional-managing-director-to-lead-european-expansion\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">expansion<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;into Ireland. The exchange became the first virtual assets service provider on October 11.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Looking further at company movements, Gillian Lynch stepped up as the new lead for Gemini's European branch on October 14&nbsp;after the former head,&nbsp;Blair Halliday, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/177012\/kraken-poaches-geminis-head-of-uk-to-run-its-uk-operations\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">shifted<\/a> over to the Kraken crypto exchange.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2014","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gemini Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Gemini","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gemini","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Companies House","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"October 11","content":"DATE"},{"type":"October 12","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tyler Winklevoss","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"October 14","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Kraken crypto","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cameron Winklevoss","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"last week","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Blair Halliday","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ireland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Gillian Lynch","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["GEMINI","KRAKEN"],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","Adam James","The Block"]}