{"summary":"In a recently recorded episode of The Scoop, Mercer discussed the firm&#x27;s recent growth and what it&#x27;s been like to operate a digital asset exchange in the midst of the ongoing financial and health crisis.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/65679\/an-fx-exchange-veteran-explains-growing-a-crypto-exchange-and-weathering-the-covid-19-storm","publishDate":"2020-05-19T04:00:15","id":4614,"type":null,"title":"An FX trading veteran on building an institutional crypto exchange and navigating Covid-19","category":["THE BLOCK"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 20 of Season 2 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block’s Frank Chaparro and LMAX Group CEO David Mercer.<\/i>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/a>, or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to&nbsp;<a target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"b0c0dfd4d3d1c3c4f0c4d8d5d2dcdfd3dbd3c2c9c0c4df9ed3dfdd\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/span><\/a>.<\/em>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode of The Scoop is brought to you by&nbsp;<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitstamp<\/strong>,&nbsp;the original global cryptocurrency exchange. Since 2011, Bitstamp has been a cornerstone of the industry, earning the trust of over four million individuals and top financial institutions looking for a reliable trading venue. Whether you’re trading on our web platform, mobile app or industry-leading APIs, Bitstamp gives you the professional-grade tools you need to execute your strategy.&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/bitstamp.net\/app?r=pro%E2%80%93&amp;utm_source=Website&amp;utm_medium=podcast&amp;utm_campaign=theblock&amp;utm_content=ctaapp\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Download the Bitstamp app<\/b><\/a>&nbsp;or visit&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.bitstamp.net\/pro\/?utm_source=Website&amp;utm_medium=podcast&amp;utm_campaign=theblock&amp;utm_content=ctaweb\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitstamp.net\/Pro<\/b><\/a>&nbsp;to learn more and start trading today!<\/em>","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK2836516914\" width=\"100%\" height=\"200\" frameborder=\"0\" scrolling=\"no\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Institutional crypto exchange LMAX Digital closed out its second year by 10x-ing its trade volumes, trading $75 billion worth of crypto in the past 12 months, the firm revealed exclusively to The Block.","Since its launch two years ago, the firm has facilitated $85 billion in trades, according to a Tuesday press release.&nbsp;Last year's monthly high was $8.6 billion traded in June of 2019, and that month saw the firm's daily record high on June 27, when $1.25 billion was traded on the exchange.&nbsp;","CEO of LMAX Group David Mercer said the firm has become the primary price discovery venue, having grown to command a sizable portion of the spot cryptocurrency market. LMAX Digital has seen 41.9% growth from Q4’19 to Q1’20. Its volume in Q4’19 was $14.0 billion while in Q1'20, it reached $19.8 billion.","","","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Source: The Block Research, Cryptosheets, CryptoCompare<\/span>","Still, the firm's market share relative to other exchanges has stagnated recently after briefly surpassing Coinbase in November 2019.","","","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Source: The Block Research, Cryptosheets, CryptoCompare<\/span>","Now, with two years of growth under its belt, the firm is looking to expand its reach. Mercer told The Block that the firm is looking to add its trade and market data to more leading market reference indices, as well as expand its product portfolio with the growth of the asset class.&nbsp;","In a recently recorded episode of The Scoop, Mercer discussed the firm's recent growth and what it's been like to operate a digital asset exchange in the midst of the ongoing financial and health crisis. The Block's Frank Chaparro and Mercer also explore:","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"41.9%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2011","content":"DATE"},{"type":"November 2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"June of 2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$14.0 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bitstamp","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"June 27","content":"DATE"},{"type":"LMAX Group David Mercer","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"LMAX Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$8.6 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$85 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$1.25 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"'20","content":"DATE"},{"type":"LMAX Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Mercer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"David Mercer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$19.8 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$75 billion","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Aislinn Keely","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}