{"summary":"Bitpanda, a Vienna-based crypto investment business, today announced a licensing deal with Coinbase, the exchange operator.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/232023\/bitpanda-coinbase-deal","publishDate":"2023-05-24T19:01:43","id":4618,"type":null,"title":"Bitpanda strikes licensing deal with Coinbase","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Bitpanda, the Vienna-based crypto investment business, has inked a licensing deal with Coinbase.","The arrangement will see Coinbase added as a liquidity provider for Bitpanda Technology Solutions, Bitpanda’s “investing-as-a-service” arm, which will also begin using Coinbase Prime’s custody services.","The deal will pave the way for clients of Coinbase Institutional outside of the United States to white-label Bitpanda’s investing-as-a-service platform, according to the announcement.","Institutional clients of the platform can integrate trading infrastructure to begin offering their own customers trading, investment and custody tools for a range of assets, including stocks and crypto. Austrian bank Raiffeisenlandesbank, German neobank N26, French fintech firm Lydia and the UK’s Plum are already using the service.","In today’s announcement, both firms emphasized that they are regulated entities with high KYC standards.","“Bitpanda and Coinbase share an ambition — to make investing in digital assets safe and secure in a regulated way,” said Lukas Enzersdorfer-Konrad, deputy CEO and COO of Bitpanda, in a written statement. “At a time of unparalleled opportunity for the industry to harness the potential of digital assets for its customers, we are coming together to define a clear future and drive forward that ambition.”","The move is the latest sign that Coinbase is trying to put down deeper roots outside of the U.S. amid a crackdown by regulators in the region. The company <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/227253\/coinbase-bermuda-offshore-derivatives-exchange\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">recently secured a license<\/a> to operate an international exchange out of Bermuda, where it plans to offer derivatives trading while also <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/231030\/coinbase-singapore-services\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">expanding its offering<\/a> in Singapore.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Lukas Enzersdorfer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bermuda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Vienna","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Konrad","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Raiffeisenlandesbank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitpanda Technology Solutions","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lydia","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bitpanda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Coinbase Prime","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"United States","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Ryan Weeks","The Block"]}