{"summary":"Binance Japan is studying the issuance of a stablecoin with MUFG as it re-enters the market.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/252894\/binance-looks-to-issue-stablecoins-in-japan-with-mufg-unit-by-end-of-2024","publishDate":"2023-09-26T03:05:40","id":4631,"type":null,"title":"Binance looks to issue stablecoins in Japan with MUFG unit by end of 2024","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance has partnered with a unit of Japanese bank MUFG to study the issuance of a new stablecoin pegged to fiat currencies, as the world’s largest cryptocurrency exchange re-enters the Japanese market.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance said today in a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.prnewswire.co.uk\/news-releases\/mitsubishi-ufj-trust-and-banking-corporation-and-binance-japan-commence-joint-study-to-explore-new-stablecoin-issuance-using-progmat-platform-to-accelerate-web3-adoption-301938333.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">statement<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that Binance Japan Inc. and Mitsubishi UFJ Trust and Banking Corporation (MUTB) are conducting a joint study with the aim of issuing a stablecoin tied to fiat currency, including the Japanese Yen and other foreign currencies.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">MUTB is exploring the possibility of using its platform, dubbed “Progmat Coin,” as infrastructure for stablecoin issuance, according to the statement. Both companies plan to commence stablecoin operations by the end of next year upon obtaining applicable regulatory approvals, they added.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The news comes after Japan’s parliament in June 2022 <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/150032\/japan-passes-stablecoin-bill-ensuring-redemption-at-face-value-bloomberg-says\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">introduced a legal framework for stablecoins,<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> guaranteeing that they are linked to the yen or another fiat currency and that holders have the right to redeem them at face value. The legal framework took effect this June.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Stablecoins have important use cases across the broader financial ecosystem – from a lower-cost and instantaneous cross border trade settlement for business clients, to the facilitation of trading other cryptocurrencies seamlessly for retail investors — stablecoins fill an important financial services need and are crucial for the success of Web 3.0 adoption,\" Takeshi Chino, general manager of Binance Japan, said in the statement.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Tatsuya Saito, vice president of product of MUTB, said: \"We believe that the new stablecoin from this collaboration will be a step forward in advancing the Web 3.0.\"<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In November 2022, Binance acquired 100% of Sakura Exchange BitCoin — paving the way for it to be regulated by the Japan Financial Services Agency. Its re-entry into the market came after the <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/109623\/japan-fsa-another-warning-binance-unregistered-operations\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">JFSA issued warnings in 2021 against Binance<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, stating that the exchange was operating in the country without registration.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance Japan, which fully <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/242410\/binance-plans-to-first-list-34-tokens-in-japan-as-it-re-enters-the-market-report\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">launched services last month<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, said that it <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/248057\/binance-japan-plans-to-triple-number-of-listed-tokens-to-100-bloomberg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">aims to offer at least 100 tokens<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on its platform in the short term.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"June 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tatsuya Saito","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"JFSA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Takeshi Chino","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"today","content":"DATE"},{"type":"the Japan Financial Services Agency","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mitsubishi UFJ Trust","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Japan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Binance Japan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sakura Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"100%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"June","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Binance Japan Inc.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"November 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Binance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MUTB","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["ASIAN REGULATION","TRADFI BANKS"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}