{"summary":"The chief financial officer of bankrupt crypto lender Voyager is set to depart the company, according to a Friday announcement.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/172550\/bankrupt-crypto-lender-voyagers-cfo-resigns","publishDate":"2022-09-23T17:18:44","id":4642,"type":null,"title":"Bankrupt crypto lender Voyager&#x27;s CFO resigns","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["The chief financial officer of bankrupt crypto lender Voyager is expected to leave the company, a Friday announcement said.","<span class=\"xn-person\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ashwin Prithipaul \"is resigning to pursue other opportunities,\" Voyager said in a statement. Prithipaul has served as CFO of the company since May, according to his LinkedIn profile.&nbsp;<\/span>","\"Mr. Prithipaul will depart from the company after a transition period, and Chief Executive Officer <span class=\"xn-person\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stephen Ehrlich<\/span> will assume Mr. Prithipaul's duties in the interim,\" the company said.","Voyager <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/155990\/crypto-broker-voyager-digital-files-for-chapter-11-bankruptcy\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection<\/a> in July. The firm held <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/168264\/bankrupt-voyager-digital-to-hold-asset-auction-on-september-13\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">a bankruptcy auction<\/a> earlier this month, and a hearing is scheduled for Sept. 29 to approve the results of that process. Crypto firms <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/171533\/binance-and-ftx-lead-voyager-auction-wsj\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance and FTX<\/a> are among the firms said to be bidding on the company's assets.&nbsp;&nbsp;","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"earlier this month","content":"DATE"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"\" Voyager","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Prithipaul","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sept. 29","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ashwin Prithipaul \"","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Voyager","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Stephen Ehrlich","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE","FTX"],"authors":["Michael McSweeney","The Block"]}