{"summary":"The crypto exchange said the decision was based on its most recent review of the stablecoin.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/215435\/coinbase-to-halt-trading-of-binances-busd-for-not-meeting-listing-standards","publishDate":"2023-02-27T11:44:36","id":4652,"type":null,"title":"Coinbase to halt trading of Binance USD for not meeting listing standards","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Coinbase will suspend trading of Binance USD (BUSD) on March 13 at around noon EST.","The crypto exchange said the decision was based on its most recent review of the stablecoin, which Paxos recently <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/210919\/sec-to-sue-paxos-for-listing-binance-usd-stablecoin-wsj\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">stopped issuing<\/a> following an order from a New York regulator.","\"Our determination to suspend trading for BUSD is based on our own internal monitoring and review processes,\" a Coinbase spokesperson told The Block. \"When reviewing BUSD, we determined that it no longer met our listing standards and will be suspended.\"","Customers will still have access to and be able to withdraw BUSD funds. However, trading will be suspended on Coinbase.com (Simple and Advanced Trade), Coinbase Pro, Coinbase Exchange, and Coinbase Prime, the exchange said.","Paxos <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/210919\/sec-to-sue-paxos-for-listing-binance-usd-stablecoin-wsj\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">got a Wells notice from<\/a> the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) earlier this month alleging that it listed BUSD as an unregistered security. The stablecoin issuer said it <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/211242\/paxos-categorically-disagrees-with-sec-in-calling-busd-a-security\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"categorically disagrees<\/a>\" with the SEC's categorization but is in <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/213663\/paxos-in-constructive-discussions-with-the-sec-ends-relationship-with-binance\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"constructive discussions<\/a>\" with the regulator. It also cut ties with Binance.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BUSD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance USD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coinbase Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coinbase Prime","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"March 13","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE","COINBASE"],"authors":["Catarina Moura","The Block"]}