{"summary":"The proposed legal defense fund would cover fees for Sushi&#x27;s core contributors.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/221723\/sushi-hit-with-sec-subpoena-seeking-3-million-usdt-legal-defense-fund","publishDate":"2023-03-21T13:26:48","id":4655,"type":null,"title":"Sushi hit with SEC subpoena, seeking $3 million USDT legal defense fund","category":["DEFI"],"content":["The Securities and Exchange Commission recently served Sushi and \"head chef\" Jared Grey with a subpoena, the decentralized finance company said on Tuesday.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","Grey asked Sushi DAO to fund a $3 million USDT legal defense fund to cover costs related to the SEC’s inquiry. Sushi sought to establish a legal entity to reduce liability for contributors and the DAO last year.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","“We’re cooperating with the SEC,” Grey said in a <a href=\"https:\/\/forum.sushi.com\/t\/establish-sushi-legal-defense-fund\/11813\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">blog post<\/span><\/a>. “It has become evident funds must be available to handle legal needs for operational continuity and to protect core contributors.”<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","The SEC did not immediately respond to a request for comment, and Grey said Sushi does not “intend to comment publicly on ongoing investigations or other legal matters.”","The Sushi DAO Legal Defense Fund would cover “reasonable” attorney fees and costs for core contributors who have been active since the ratification of Sushi 2.0 last year. The funds will come from a combination of Kanpai fees, grants and Sushi. If the money runs out before the legal issues conclude, the DAO will make $1 million USDT available as needed.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$3 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$1 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Grey","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Grey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"DAO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jared Grey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sushi DAO Legal Defense Fund","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sushi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sushi DAO","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["SEC"],"authors":["Stephanie Murray","The Block"]}