{"summary":"FTX&#x27;s most prominent investors, including the largest asset manager in the world and one of the most significant pension funds, by The Block Research.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/184625\/softbank-and-blackrock-among-ftx-investors-in-the-dark-over-binance-deal","publishDate":"2022-11-09T06:05:40","id":4685,"type":null,"title":"SoftBank and BlackRock among FTX investors in the dark over Binance deal","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["Binance's agreement to acquire FTX.com has left some of the world's largest investors in the dark.","Beleaguered FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried wrote to investors <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/184542\/bankman-fried-apologizes-to-ftx-investors-for-lack-of-communication-over-binance-deal\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">on Tuesday<\/a>, apologizing for his lack of communication, adding that the details of a non-binding agreement for Binance to buy FTX.com haven't been finalized.","\"I wish I had more details for you guys right now; I don't yet,\" he said, adding that he would be \"quite swamped\" over the coming days, and that Ramnik Arora, FTX head of product, would answer any questions.&nbsp;&nbsp;","Backers of the exchange up to now have included: BlackRock, Ontario Teachers Pension Plan, Sequoia, Paradigm, Tiger Global, SoftBank, Circle, Ribbit Capital, Alan Howard, Multicoin Capital, VanEck and Temasek, among others, according to The Block Research.&nbsp;","&nbsp;","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Source: The Block Research<\/span><\/em>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Ontario Teachers Pension Plan","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BlackRock","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tiger Global","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Paradigm","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SoftBank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Temasek","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ribbit Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"VanEck","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Multicoin Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Circle","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alan Howard","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ramnik Arora","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sequoia","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE","FTX"],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}