{"summary":"MiamiWeb3, the must-attend institutional Web3 summit from November 28th to 30th at the InterContinental Miami Hotel, has already announced an incredible mix of speakers, including the likes of Mayor Francis Suarez and Tim Draper.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/181704\/miamiweb3-reveals-packed-agenda-going-beyond-crypto-and-embracing-web3","publishDate":"2022-11-01T08:50:52","id":4708,"type":null,"title":"MiamiWeb3 reveals packed agenda going beyond crypto and embracing Web3","category":["SPONSORED"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">MiamiWeb3, the must-attend institutional Web3 summit from November 28th to 30th at the InterContinental Miami Hotel, has already announced an<\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.miamiweb3.com\/event\/13f05fee-1e91-4663-9745-27b22640bf6a\/websitePage:4b7c5fb6-6bea-4d92-866b-9cfed7bea14c\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">incredible mix of speakers<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, including the likes of Mayor Francis Suarez and Tim Draper. <\/span><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Now, to drive the long wait to a close, the team behind MiamiWeb3 have now announced the full agenda!<\/b><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Co-organized by the City of Miami, Atlas, and CTH Group, participants will be treated to a gathering of masterclass speakers, panelists, and industry leaders, shedding light on the state of the industry and its future.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">For the full agenda, visit<\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.miamiweb3.com\/event\/13f05fee-1e91-4663-9745-27b22640bf6a\/websitePage:0f39e992-ef06-492d-9927-9592839c4a4d\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">MiamiWeb3 agenda<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">!<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Keynote speeches, panel discussions and fireside chats across the three-day event tie together four key themes to help institutions get involved in this emerging asset class and create a platform for industry leaders to drive meaningful discussions on trends and pressing topics concerning Web3. After kicking off the event with a welcome reception on the evening of November 28th, guests are led straight into action with the jam-packed agenda.<\/span>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Global &amp; Macro Takes<\/b><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> (Nov 29th, morning) — speakers from government, traditional finance, Web3 and the world’s leading think tanks discuss their views on the state of the industry and where they see opportunities for future growth. With diverse perspectives from speakers such as <\/span><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Francis Suarez, Mayor of Miami<\/b><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, <\/span><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Cynthia Lummis, U.S. Senator of Wyoming, Derek Devens, Managing Director, Senior Portfolio Manager at Neuberger Berman, Jared Favole, Senior Director, Communications and Policy at Circle, Nicole Valentine, FinTech Director, Center for Financial Markets, Milken Institute <\/b><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">and many more covering the regulation, CBDCs, financial and technological aspects. Participants get a 360-degree birdseye view on everything that matters now and looking ahead to 2023.<\/span>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">DeFi: Beyond Crypto<\/b><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> (Nov 29th, afternoon) — there's much more to Web3 than crypto: there is an entire world of new financial primitives and applications waiting to be explored through DeFi. While DeFi is accessible to individuals, institutions often struggle with custody, compliance, taxation, mining, and unlocking the yields made possible through this technology. Join experts such as<\/span><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Anthony Bassili, Head of Asset Allocators at Coinbase Institutional<\/b><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, <\/span><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Joel Edgerton, Head of Americas Enterprise at Ledger, James Putra, Vice President, Product Strategy, TradeStation Crypto, Inc., <\/b><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">and <\/span><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Alex McDougall, CEO of Stablecorp<\/b><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on a journey across the institutional DeFi landscape, and how to access this market.<\/span>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Web2 to Web3<\/b><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> (Nov 30th, morning) — the transition from Web2 to Web3 is well-underway. Beginning at the infrastructure level, discussing the potential of unlocking Bitcoin layers to L2s &amp; scaling solutions post-merge to investing in Web3 ecosystems as the new platforms, participants are led through emerging Web3 technologies and the industries that are being built around them. Don't miss out on industry leaders, including <\/span><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Tim Draper, Founding Partner of Draper Associates,<\/b> <b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Trevor Owens, Managing Partner at Stacks Ventures,<\/b><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> and <\/span><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Angela Dalton, Founder &amp; CEO, Signum Growth Capital,<\/b> <b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Anthony Avedissianl, Investor, Seed Club Ventures, <\/b><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">breaking down what matters!<\/span>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Embracing Web3 <\/b><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">(Nov 30th, afternoon) — finally, we look towards the future to \"go beyond crypto and embrace Web3\". Speakers discuss their outlook on Web3’s role and impact on gaming, entertainment, organizations (DAOs), identity &amp; on-chain reputations, philanthropy, sports, and the future of money. Don't miss out on <\/span><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Salim Ismail, Founding Executive Director, Singularity University, Sandy Carter, SVP &amp; Channel Chief at Unstoppable Domains,&nbsp; Elana Dickman, Investor, Red Beard Ventures, David S. Bennahum, CEO of Ready Games,<\/b><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> and many more fantastic speakers and panelists!<\/span>","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.miamiweb3.com\/?utm_source=theblock&amp;utm_medium=article&amp;utm_campaign=oct2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">GET YOUR TICKETS TO MIAMIWEB3 TODAY<\/b><\/a>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The three-day in-person event is expected to attract attendees from across the globe with its packed agenda. With MiamiWeb3, Atlas and CTH Group are creating a platform with globally relevant participation to drive meaningful outcomes for the Web3 industry: from building out the ecosystem across all verticals to unleashing Web3’s full potential with new business models to contributing to a better foundation for fair, equitable, and clean growth for the world. MiamiWeb3 has it all.<\/span>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This post is commissioned by CTH Group and does not serve as a testimonial or endorsement by The Block. This post is for informational purposes only and should not be relied upon as a basis for investment, tax, legal or other advice. You should conduct your own research and consult independent counsel and advisors on the matters discussed within this post. Past performance of any asset is not indicative of future results.<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Head of Americas Enterprise","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"James Putra","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Anthony Bassili","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Miami","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Communications","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nicole Valentine","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Signum Growth Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jared Favole","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Seed Club Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Singularity University","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"David S. Bennahum","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Atlas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Atlas","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Milken Institute","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Francis Suarez","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tim Draper","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Trevor Owens","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sandy Carter","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"November 28th","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Cynthia Lummis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Anthony Avedissianl","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"InterContinental Miami Hotel","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Center for Financial Markets","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FinTech","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SVP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"TradeStation Crypto, Inc.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Derek Devens","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Red Beard Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Elana Dickman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"evening","content":"TIME"},{"type":"Wyoming","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Angela Dalton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Coinbase Institutional","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Joel Edgerton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Circle","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CTH Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Neuberger Berman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Founding Partner of Draper Associates","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Macro Takes<\/b><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> (Nov 29th","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alex McDougall","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Stacks Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sponsored","The Block"]}