{"summary":"A group of lawmakers pressed SEC Chair Gary Gensler to urgently allow the listing of a spot bitcoin ETF on Tuesday.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253093\/lawmakers-urge-sec-chair-gensler-to-allow-spot-bitcoin-etfs-immediately","publishDate":"2023-09-26T15:44:03","id":4730,"type":null,"title":"Lawmakers urge Gensler to allow spot bitcoin ETFs &#x27;immediately&#x27;","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A group of Republican and Democratic lawmakers pressed Securities and Exchange Commission Chair Gary Gensler to urgently allow the listing of a spot bitcoin <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/252790\/latest-bitwise-bitcoin-etf-filing-takes-sec-to-task-over-academic-literature\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">exchange-traded fund<\/a> following a significant court ruling.&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Reps. Mike Flood, R-Neb., Tom Emmer, R-Minn., Ritchie Torres, D-N.Y. and Wiley Nickel, D-N.C., urged Gensler to allow those listings, arguing a regulated spot bitcoin ETF would increase investor protection by making access to bitcoin more transparent and safer, according to a <a href=\"https:\/\/flood.house.gov\/sites\/evo-subsites\/flood.house.gov\/files\/evo-media-document\/sec-bitcoin-spot-etf-letter-signature-check.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">letter<\/span><\/a> sent Tuesday.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Congress has a duty to ensure the SEC approves investment products that meet the requirements set out by Congress,\" they said. \"To that end, we urge you to approve the listing of spot-bitcoin ETPs immediately.\"<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Last month, Grayscale Investments <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/247947\/bitcoin-price-soars-after-grayscale-win-in-dispute-with-sec\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">secured a win<\/a> when three judges in the U.S. Court of Appeals for the D.C. Circuit ruled that the SEC had to re-review its bid for a spot bitcoin ETF. This came after Grayscale sued the agency last year after its proposal for spot bitcoin ETF was rejected.<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The court specifically addressed the SEC's differential treatment of spot bitcoin ETFs and similar funds based on futures contracts, which the regulator has approved.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"The Court’s finding underscores the fundamental point,\" the lawmakers said. \"A spot bitcoin ETP is indistinguishable from a bitcoin futures ETP. Thus, the SEC’s current posture is untenable moving forward.\"<\/span>","Gensler will respond to members of Congress directly, not through the media, an SEC spokesperson said.&nbsp;","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The SEC has not yet greenlit a spot bitcoin ETF, although big name players including BlackRock and Fidelity have submitted applications for funds over the past several months.&nbsp;<\/span>","Separately on Tuesday, Rep. Blaine Luetkemeyer, R-Mo., sent a letter to Gensler and Financial Industry Regulatory Authority President Robert Cook over concerns that both agencies allow registered broker-dealers with ownership ties to the Chinese Community Party to operate in the U.S.&nbsp;","Luetkemeyer argued guidance was too narrow and insufficient to address concerns regarding non-China based U.S. firms with ties to the CCP, citing broker-dealers, including Prometheum Inc, Webull Financial, LLC and Moomoo, Inc.&nbsp;","\"The SEC's limited effort in this regard is particularly troubling given the important role registered broker-dealers play in our financial markets, including the fact that many of these firms provide (or intend to provide) products and services directly to retail investors, which requires the collection of substantial amounts of customers' personal information,\" the lawmaker said.&nbsp;","Luetkemeyer posed questions asking Gensler about the agency's data security concerns on ties to the CCP, among others. The deadline for Cook and Gensler to respond is Oct. 26.&nbsp;","The SEC, Moomoo and Webull did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&nbsp;","FINRA said it planned to respond to the letter. Prometheum declined to comment on this specific letter. In the past, the firm's Co-Chief Executive Officer Aaron Kaplan has said <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/238718\/republican-lawmakers-ask-justice-department-sec-to-investigate-prometheum\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">concerns<\/a> over Prometheum's ties to China were \"unfounded and without merit.\"&nbsp;","Luetkemeyer sits on the House Financial Services Committee, which will <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253102\/sec-chair-gensler-calls-for-crypto-compliance-ahead-of-wednesday-hearing\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">hear<\/a> from Gensler on Wednesday.&nbsp;","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Updated at 6:45 p.m. to add letter from Luetkemeyer and a response from the SEC<\/em>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Updated at 9:20 a.m. with comments about FINRA and Prometheum&nbsp;<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Webull","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Grayscale","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Blaine Luetkemeyer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"CCP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Moomoo, Inc.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Grayscale Investments","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wiley Nickel","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Prometheum","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"6:45 p.m.","content":"TIME"},{"type":"Gary Gensler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gensler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gensler and Financial Industry Regulatory Authority","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"9:20 a.m.","content":"TIME"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Aaron Kaplan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Webull Financial","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Oct. 26","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FINRA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"House Financial Services Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Moomoo","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Cook","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"N.Y.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"BlackRock","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tom Emmer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Mo.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"LLC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Chinese Community Party","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Congress","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fidelity","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Robert Cook","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Neb.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Minn.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ritchie Torres","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Luetkemeyer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Prometheum Inc","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"D.C.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"China","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Mike Flood","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["SEC"],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}