{"summary":"Rep. Tom Emmer, R-Minn., who had won nomination for the U.S. House Speaker on Tuesday, dropped out of the race just hours later.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/259252\/crypto-king-emmer-selected-as-nominee-for-u-s-speaker-heads-to-house-floor-vote","publishDate":"2023-10-24T13:07:55","id":4737,"type":null,"title":"&#x27;Crypto king&#x27; Emmer drops out of House Speaker race: reports","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto-friendly Rep. Tom Emmer, R-Minn., who had won nomination for the U.S. House Speaker on Tuesday morning but still needed to secure votes on the House floor, dropped out of the race just hours later.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Emmer had come out on top on Tuesday after he and eight other candidates, including Rep. Byron Donalds, R-Fla., and Pete Sessions, R-Texas, announced their bids for the position over the weekend. However, by Tuesday afternoon he was out, according to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.washingtonpost.com\/politics\/2023\/10\/24\/house-speaker-vote\/#link-JENOZ4BQSZGR7E2O3LRWM73RHE\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">news reports<\/a>.<\/span>","<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">After multiple rounds of voting on earlier in the day, House Republicans had pushed Emmer forward. Emmer's try for speaker came after bids from <\/span><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Rep. Jim Jordan, R-Ohio, and Steve Scalise, R-La., failed to get the needed votes over the past few weeks.&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">House Majority Whip Emmer, who the Minnesota Reformer has <a href=\"https:\/\/minnesotareformer.com\/2022\/09\/21\/u-s-rep-tom-emmer-has-become-a-powerful-washington-ally-to-cryptocurrency\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">dubbed<\/a> the \"crypto king of Congress,\"&nbsp; has introduced bills over the past few years including one to create a new definition for tokens and another that would ban the Federal Reserve from issuing a direct CBDC. He has also been supportive of a bill that takes a comprehensive approach at a regulatory framework for crypto, while <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253305\/gensler-takes-heat-from-lawmakers-over-his-approach-to-regulating-crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">slamming<\/span><\/a> Securities and Exchange Commission Chair Gary Gensler for taking a \"regulation by harassment approach\" toward digital assets.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Emmer also leads the Congressional Blockchain Caucus, which is favorable toward crypto and believes in a light touch regulatory approach.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> The House has been without a speaker for the past few weeks after former House Speaker Kevin McCarthy, R-Calif., was ousted following a power struggle with lawmakers including Rep. Matt Gaetz, R-Fla.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">McCarthy reportedly nominated Emmer, telling NBC's \"Meet the Press\" on <a href=\"https:\/\/www.nbcnews.com\/meet-the-press\/meet-press-october-22-2023-n1307654\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sunday<\/span><\/a> that the Minnesota Republican needed to get elected this week.<\/span>","<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">(Updates story throughout to show that Emmer dropped out of race just hours after being selected as latest nominee.)<\/i><\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Federal Reserve","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Emmer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Pete Sessions","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kevin McCarthy","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S. House Speaker","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Congressional Blockchain Caucus","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Minnesota","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Gary Gensler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"La.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"afternoon","content":"TIME"},{"type":"Sunday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Fla.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Tom Emmer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jim Jordan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NBC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Byron Donalds","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Congress","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ohio","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Texas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"House","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Steve Scalise","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Minn.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"morning","content":"TIME"},{"type":"Calif.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Matt Gaetz","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["HOUSE AGRICULTURE COMMITTEE","HOUSE FINANCIAL SERVICES COMMITTEE"],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}