{"summary":"Another FTX-like situation is possible, said CFTC Chair Rostin Behnam on Wednesday during a conference hosted by Georgetown University.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/263174\/nothing-has-changed-in-the-past-year-opening-the-door-for-another-ftx-like-situation-cftc-chair","publishDate":"2023-11-15T11:04:50","id":4748,"type":null,"title":"&#x27;Nothing has changed,&#x27; door open for another FTX-like situation: CFTC Chair","category":["U.S. POLICYMAKING"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Another FTX-like situation is possible, said Commodity Futures Trading Commission Chair Rostin Behnam.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Behnam urged the Senate Banking Committee in December 2022 that lawmakers needed to move <a href=\"https:\/\/www.cftc.gov\/PressRoom\/SpeechesTestimony\/opabehnam29\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">quickly<\/span><\/a> on a regulatory approach to create guardrails and prevent risk — and, if not, said crypto would be unsafe for investors and could bring with it greater risks. Now, almost a year later, Behnam was asked by a CNBC reporter at a conference at Georgetown University whether anything has changed since then.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Ultimately, the answer to that question is, no, nothing has changed and we could be in a position where another FTX type event happens,\" Behnam said on Wednesday morning.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried, who was found <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/261240\/sam-bankman-fried-convicted-on-all-counts-report\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">guilty<\/span><\/a> on all counts for defrauding investors just a few weeks ago, caused customers to lose billions. The collapse led to major distrust in crypto from some in Congress while others pitched legislation to regulate crypto in the U.S.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Meanwhile, Behnam said crypto markets have changed dramatically since an uptick at the beginning of the pandemic and even just a year ago. <\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"So could an FTX type event happen?\" Behnam said. \"I don't want to ever say never, but certainly the market dynamics and the market environment is much different today than it was a year ago let alone two or three.\"<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Congress needs to create a roadmap, Behnam said on Wednesday, echoing previous comments in last year's Senate Banking <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/191407\/cftc-chair-behnam-walks-fine-line-during-congress-first-ftx-hearing\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">hearing<\/span><\/a>.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"We lacked the authority to comprehensively regulate the digital commodity market,” Behnam said in December 2022. “To prevent this from happening again, we must be provided appropriate authority by Congress.\"<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Two bills advanced out of the House Financial Services Committee during the summer, and would still need a full vote by the House before going onto the Senate. <\/span><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">One bill would regulate stablecoins, while the other takes a comprehensive approach at creating a regulatory framework for crypto. Even with an eventual House vote, they would still need to garner support in the Senate, which could prove to be tough. Other lawmakers have pushed for <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/259559\/senator-elizabeth-warren-finds-support-in-us-house-for-effort-to-tackle-crypto-financed-terrorism\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">legislation<\/a> to crack down on the use of crypto for money laundering and evading sanctions.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Behnam said bills, though not commenting on which specific ones, seem to be caught in a \"holding pattern.\"&nbsp;<\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Congress","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CNBC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"House","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Senate Banking","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"morning","content":"TIME"},{"type":"December 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Georgetown University","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Commodity Futures Trading Commission Chair Rostin Behnam","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Senate Banking Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Behnam","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"House Financial Services Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"summer","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Senate","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["CFTC","FTX","SENATE BANKING COMMITTEE"],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}