{"summary":"The world’s largest cryptocurrency exchange can now offer authorized crypto services to institutional and qualified retail investors in Dubai, the company said today.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/242127\/binance-obtains-license-to-operate-as-virtual-asset-exchange-in-dubai","publishDate":"2023-07-31T02:35:54","id":4783,"type":null,"title":"Binance obtains license to operate as virtual asset exchange in Dubai","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance, the world’s largest cryptocurrency exchange, has obtained an Operational Minimum Viable Product license to operate virtual asset exchange services in Dubai, the company said today.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The license allows Binance FZE, the exchange’s Dubai subsidiary, to offer services in the country initially to institutional and qualified retail investors, Binance said in a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.binance.com\/en\/blog\/ecosystem\/binance-is-the-first-virtual-asset-exchange-to-receive-an-operational-mvp-license-in-dubai-7342057061995039467\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">statement<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The news follows Binance’s earlier efforts to obtain a provisional MVP license in March 2022 and a preparatory MVP license in September 2022. Eligible users in Dubai will now be able to access authorized services, “knowing they’re under investor protection and market assurance standards tailored specifically for the virtual asset sector,” the exchange said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We are honored to be the first exchange to be granted an operational Minimum Viable Product License by VARA,” Richard Teng, head of regional markets of Binance, said in the statement. “Our priority is to be able to operate this first fully regulated exchange in, and from Dubai, in a FATF-compliant ecosystem, setting the stage for global scalability with uncompromised user assurance.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Even as Binance secures licenses in Dubai and <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.binance.com\/en\/legal\/licenses\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">a number of other jurisdictions<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, it faces mounting scrutiny other global markets. Last week, the exchange said it had <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/241489\/binance-germany-license\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">withdrawn an application<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> for a license from German financial regulator BaFin.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Earlier in July, Binance’s office in Australia was searched by local regulators as part of an ongoing probe into the cryptocurrency exchange, Bloomberg <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2023-07-05\/binance-australia-offices-searched-by-regulator-as-part-of-derivatives-probe?utm_source=website&amp;utm_medium=share&amp;utm_campaign=twitter#xj4y7vzkg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In the U.S., Binance currently finds itself in the crosshairs of multiple regulators, with the Commodities Futures Trading Commission first <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/223015\/cftc-sues-binance\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filing a lawsuit<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> against it in March. The Securities and Exchange Commission also <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/233154\/sec-files-suit-against-binance\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">sued<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> the exchange and Zhao last month for allegedly violating securities laws.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Zhao last month","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"today","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Commodities Futures Trading Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FATF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"March 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Dubai","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Binance’s","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Richard Teng","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Australia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"VARA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance FZE","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"September 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"BaFin","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Binance","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}