{"summary":"Binance CEO Changpeng Zhao announced on Twitter that exchange would convert approximately $1 billion of BUSD to bitcoin, ether and BNB.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/219165\/binance-converting-1-billion-in-busd-to-bitcoin-ether-and-bnb","publishDate":"2023-03-13T03:00:39","id":4797,"type":null,"title":"Binance converting $1 billion in BUSD to bitcoin, ether and BNB","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Binance CEO Changpeng Zhao <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/cz_binance\/status\/1635131601884700674\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/a> on Twitter that the foremost crypto exchange would convert the approximately $1 billion remaining from its Industry Recovery Initiative funds to native crypto assets — precisely, bitcoin, ether and BNB.","The cryptocurrencies will be purchased using the exchange's dollar-pegged stablecoin, BUSD.","Zhao — who is widely known by his initials, CZ — shared that, for transparency, some of the transactions will <a href=\"https:\/\/etherscan.io\/address\/0x043a80999cee3711d372fb878768909fbe7f71e6#tokentxns\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">occur<\/a> on-chain.","The $1 billion conversions to native crypto assets come amid a banking crisis that captured the United States' attention over the weekend.","Last night, the New York Department of Financial Services <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/219119\/state-regulator-takes-control-of-signature-bank-federal-regulators-guarantee-deposits\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">seized<\/a> what was widely considered the last crypto-friendly bank, Signature Bank, citing systematic risks — effectively cutting the crypto industry off from banks in the country.&nbsp;","The move coincides with the Federal Reserve's creation of a Bank Term Funding Program, which — on fears of a broader economic impact — will lend money to Silicon Valley Bank and ensure deposits beyond $250,000 are accessible.&nbsp;Silicon Valley Bank's collapse is the second-largest in the country's history.","\"Took 15 seconds and costs $1.29,\" CZ tweeted, citing a movement of funds worth over $980 million. \"Imagine moving $980 million through a bank before banking hours on a Monday.\"","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Federal Reserve","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$250,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"New York Department of Financial Services","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Changpeng Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Signature Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bank Term Funding Program","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$980 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$1.29","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"United States","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Silicon Valley Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE","BUSD","CZ","FEDERAL RESERVE"],"authors":["Adam James","The Block"]}