{"summary":"Matic, a native token of blockchain scalability project Matic Network, plunged by around 70% from $0.042 to $0.013 in under 35 minutes on Monday. Matic Network held its token sale via Binance Launchpad earlier this year and raised around $5 million.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/49898\/how-a-misleading-tweet-drove-binance-listed-matic-token-tank-by-70","publishDate":"2019-12-10T08:10:07","id":4800,"type":null,"title":"Matic token tanks by 70%; company claims was &#x27;a coordinated attack&#x27;","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["Matic, a native token of blockchain scalability project Matic Network, plunged by around 70% from $0.042 to $0.013 in under 35 minutes on Monday.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nMatic Network, in its <a href=\"https:\/\/blog.matic.network\/foundation-token-movement-accounting\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">blog post<\/a> published Tuesday, said that a misleading tweet by Samuel Gosling, founder of cryptocurrency evaluation platform Validity Crypto, “created the FUD” (fear, uncertainty, and doubt) among crypto Twitter.","Gosling <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/xGozzy\/status\/1204274673548173312?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1204274673548173312&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.matic.network%2Ffoundation-token-movement-accounting%2F\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweeted<\/a> Monday at around 4:15 am CET that the Matic Network Foundation transferred around 1.50 billion Matic tokens (15% of the supply, worth about $67 million) in the past 50 days, adding that some of which seem to have been sent for liquidation at Binance. However, the dump of Matic tokens took place hours before the tweet at around 1:50 am CET and lasted until 2:25 am CET, meaning that the tweet had nothing to do with the crash.&nbsp; He later <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/xGozzy\/status\/1204274673548173312?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1204274673548173312&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.matic.network%2Ffoundation-token-movement-accounting%2F\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweeted: <\/a>\"I just want to deeply apologize for providing an inaccurate claim, it turns out it was only 381,903,830 $MATIC (3% of the supply) that 'seems' has been liquidated.”<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n","","Matic Network went on to say in its blog post: “We want to strongly state that the allegations of token movement from our Foundation account, made by a FUD account against Matic team are completely baseless.\"<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nEarlier today, Sandeep Nailwal, Matic Network's co-founder and COO, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.youtube.com\/watch?v=13KM8rn5-Aw&amp;feature=youtu.be\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">held<\/a> an ask-me-anything (AMA) session to further explain the price crash and said: \"What we believe is that after our meteoric rise, these people (market manipulators) thought that [MATIC] would be an ideal project to short. I think the timing of this manipulative shorting was chosen in a way that our whole team was asleep because it was night time in India. It seems to be a coordinated attack.”<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nBinance CEO Changpeng “CZ” Zhao also <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/cz_binance\/status\/1204261531015188480?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1204261531015188480&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fblog.matic.network%2Ffoundation-token-movement-accounting%2F\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweeted<\/a> earlier today that the exchange is investigating the matter but it is “already clear that the MATIC team has nothing to do with it. A number of big traders panicked, causing a cycle.”<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nMatic Network <a href=\"https:\/\/www.binance.com\/en\/blog\/319412873974988800\/Binance-Launchpad-Announces-Matic-Network-as-Next-Project-Under-its-New-Token-Launch-Format\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">held<\/a> its token sale via Binance Launchpad earlier this year and raised around $5 million. \"Matic has been relatively illiquid, and Binance also allows users to margin trade the token. Both of these factors likely contributed to the sharp fall,\" said Larry Cermak, research director at The Block.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Correction: We have updated the story with the timings of the price crash and changed the headline.<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Binance Launchpad","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"70%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"1.50 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Samuel Gosling","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"MATIC","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"AMA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"15%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$0.013","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Matic Network Foundation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$5 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Matic","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"3%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"earlier today","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$0.042","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Validity Crypto","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$67 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Sandeep Nailwal","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Matic Network","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Larry Cermak","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"India","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$MATIC","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Binance","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE","TOKENS"],"authors":["Yogita Khatri","The Block"]}