{"summary":"VanEck portfolio manager Pranav Kanade analyzes some of the trends and opportunities that he sees playing out during the current crypto bear market.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/258083\/vaneck-portfolio-manager","publishDate":"2023-10-18T08:01:05","id":482,"type":null,"title":"VanEck portfolio manager lays out themes defining this crypto bear market","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 92<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 5 of The Scoop was recorded with <b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro and VanEck Portfolio Manager Pranav Kanade.<\/b><\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on <a href=\"https:\/\/www.youtube.com\/channel\/UCqjFueYMJ78eF6G0lGLzzpQ\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Youtube<\/a>, <\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a>,<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Please send feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"dbabb4bfb8baa8af9bafb3beb9b7b4b8b0f5b8b4\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm\/?e=BLOCK8608585729\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Pranav Kanade is a portfolio manager at VanEck.","In this episode, Kanade analyzes some of the trends and opportunities that he sees playing out during the current crypto bear market.","Kanade says that crypto builders should be focusing on building products that help onboard new users into the ecosystem:","\"If I were to criticize this space for something, it's that a lot of people are too focused on building things for the existing user base rather than building things for people that are not current users... I'd love to see more of that.","The VanEck Ethereum Strategy ETF launched in early October as one of the first ETFs ever to launch based on ether futures.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"VanEck Ethereum Strategy ETF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Pranav Kanade","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kanade","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"VanEck","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"October","content":"DATE"},{"type":"VanEck Portfolio","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}