{"summary":"The Block’s Frank Chaparro sits down with Ian Sigalow, cofounder and partner at Greycroft.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/67828\/greycroft-cofounder-social-trading-venture-covid","publishDate":"2020-06-09T18:29:15","id":4824,"type":null,"title":"Greycroft&#x27;s cofounder talks social stock trading and how COVID-19 has impacted the venture landscape","category":["PODCASTS"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 22 of Season 2 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block’s Frank Chaparro and Ian Sigalow, cofounder and partner at Greycroft.<\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"e5958a8186849691a5918d8087898a868e86979c95918acb868a88\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode of The Scoop is brought to you by Bitstamp, the original global cryptocurrency exchange. Since 2011, Bitstamp has been a cornerstone of the industry, earning the trust of over four million individuals and top financial institutions looking for a reliable trading venue. <\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Whether you’re trading on our web platform, mobile app or industry-leading APIs, Bitstamp gives you the professional-grade tools you need to execute your strategy.&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/bitstamp.net\/app?r=pro%E2%80%93&amp;utm_source=Website&amp;utm_medium=podcast&amp;utm_campaign=theblock&amp;utm_content=ctaapp\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Download the Bitstamp app<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or visit&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.bitstamp.net\/pro\/?utm_source=Website&amp;utm_medium=podcast&amp;utm_campaign=theblock&amp;utm_content=ctaweb\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitstamp.net\/Pro<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;to learn more and start trading today!<\/i>","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK8355200825\" width=\"100%\" height=\"200\" frameborder=\"0\" scrolling=\"no\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Ian Sigalow has been in the venture capital (VC) space for over a decade, launching his firm Greycroft in 2006.","Since then, he's taken some big swings in the fintech space, many of which have paid off. Greycroft manages about $2 billion today.&nbsp;","He was an angel investor in Venmo at a time when people told him that PayPal had already won the race of free peer-to-peer service. On this week's episode of The Scoop, Sigalow discussed how one of the firm's latest investments — Public.com — could build a similar business by combining social elements with trading.&nbsp;","Sigalow sits on the board of Public, which recently garnered Series B investments from the likes of Will Smith and Adobe chief product officer Scott Belsky. It's a social network for traders, allowing users to trade stocks as well as grow their information networks.&nbsp;","\"So we believe at Greycroft that there is an opportunity, just like there was when Venmo was founded, to create a multiplayer game inside of a stock brokerage around a feed, and to build the first socially native brokerage application in the world,\" he said.","In this episode of The Scoop, Sigalow and The Block's Frank Chaparro explored Public's business as well as the VC landscape in the midst of COVID-19. The two also discussed:","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2006","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Will Smith","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Adobe","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2011","content":"DATE"},{"type":"19","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"PayPal","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Venmo","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Venmo","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Greycroft","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Scott Belsky","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bitstamp","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ian Sigalow","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$2 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","Aislinn Keely","The Block"]}