{"summary":"On December 15th The Block&#x27;s Asia editor Wolfie Zhao was joined by leaders from Amber Group, BlockFi, FTX, and Poolin Finance to explore the inner workings of crypto lending in Asia Pacific.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/88468\/crypto-lending-under-the-hood-full-webinar","publishDate":"2020-12-20T12:16:40","id":4826,"type":null,"title":"Crypto Lending Under the Hood | Full Webinar","category":["SPONSORED"],"content":["On December 15th The Block’s Asia editor Wolfie Zhao was joined by leaders from Amber Group, BlockFi, FTX, and Poolin Finance to explore the inner workings of crypto lending in Asia Pacific.","You can learn more about our panelists and watch the event in full below:&nbsp;","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Our Panelists:<\/strong><\/span>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Michael Wu<\/strong> – Founder &amp; CEO, Amber Group","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sam Bankman-Fried<\/strong> – CEO, FTX &amp; Alameda Research","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Rishi Ramchandani<\/strong> – Director of Business Development, Asia, BlockFi","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Qian Xiong<\/strong> – COO, Poolin Finance","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto Lending Under the Hood<\/strong>","<iframe src=\"https:\/\/www.youtube.com\/embed\/wMV9Iagz7v8\" width=\"560\" height=\"315\" frameborder=\"0\" allowfullscreen=\"allowfullscreen\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","This event is brought to you by BlockFi. BlockFi is building a bridge between cryptocurrencies and traditional financial and wealth management products to advance the overall digital asset ecosystem for individual and institutional investors. BlockFi’s platform manages more than $2 billion in assets and has generated tens of millions in interest for clients. The company continues to expand its presence in the US and across international markets, with offices in New Jersey, London, Singapore,Argentina and Poland. <a href=\"https:\/\/try.blockfi.com\/institutions\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"nofollow noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Learn more about BlockFi here<\/a>.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Wolfie Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Amber Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"New Jersey","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Poolin Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Michael Wu<\/strong> – Founder &amp; CEO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Asia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Argentina","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Hood","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX &amp; Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"London","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Poland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"December 15th","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Asia Pacific","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Rishi Ramchandani","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Business Development","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$2 billion","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sponsored","The Block"]}