{"summary":"Cardano Founder and CEO of Input-Output Global Charles Hoskinson chats with The Block&#x27;s Frank Chaparro.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/131070\/inside-the-cardano-ecosystem-with-charles-hoskinson","publishDate":"2022-01-21T11:31:16","id":4948,"type":null,"title":"Inside the Cardano ecosystem with Charles Hoskinson","category":["PODCASTS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">3<\/strong><\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> <\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 4 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block’s Frank Chaparro and Charles Hoskinson, founder of Cardano and CEO of Input-Output Global.<\/i><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on <\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, <\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, <\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, <\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"f2829d9691938186b2869a97909e9d919991808b82869ddc919d9f\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors <a href=\"http:\/\/www.fireblocks.com\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Fireblocks<\/a>, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.kraken.com\/scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kraken<\/a> &amp; <a href=\"http:\/\/Chainalysis.com\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Chainalysis<\/a><\/b><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Fireblocks is an enterprise-grade platform delivering a secure infrastructure for moving, storing, and issuing digital assets. Fireblocks enables exchanges, lending desks, custodians, banks, trading desks, and hedge funds to securely scale digital asset operations through the Fireblocks Network and MPC-based Wallet Infrastructure. Fireblocks serves over 725 financial institutions, has secured the transfer of over $1.5 trillion in digital assets, and has a unique insurance policy that covers assets in storage &amp; transit. For more information, please visit <a href=\"http:\/\/www.fireblocks.com\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">www.fireblocks.com<\/a>.<\/em><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Kraken<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Whether you’re an experienced crypto trader or just starting out, Kraken has the tools to help you achieve financial freedom. With 50+ cryptocurrencies to choose from, industry-leading security and a wide variety of features to suit any investing strategy, Kraken puts the power in your hands to buy, sell and trade digital assets. Visit <\/i><a href=\"http:\/\/kraken.com\/scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kraken.com<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to get started today.<\/i><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Chainalysis<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/b><\/span><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Chainalysis is the blockchain data platform. We provide data, software, services, and research to government agencies, exchanges, financial institutions, and insurance and cybersecurity companies in over 60 countries. Our data powers investigation, compliance, and market intelligence software that has been used to solve some of the world’s most high-profile criminal cases and grow consumer access to cryptocurrency safely. Backed by Accel, Addition, Benchmark, Coatue, Paradigm, Ribbit, and other leading firms in venture capital, Chainalysis builds trust in blockchains to promote more financial freedom with less risk. For more information, visit <a href=\"http:\/\/www.chainalysis.com\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">www.chainalysis.com<\/a>.<\/span><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><iframe loading=\"lazy\" frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK7074073410\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em>","ADA — the native cryptocurrency of the Cardano network — is among the myriad of cryptocurrencies that saw their price soar in 2021.","On this episode of The Scoop, The Block's Frank Chaparro sat down with Charles Hoskinson, founder of Cardano and CEO of Input-Output Global, to unpack the ecosystem underpinning the price headlines.","While Cardano's ADA has surged over the course of 2021, the blockchain that underpins the token is yet to play host to a large decentralized exchange, of the kind that has sprung up on networks like Ethereum and Solana. Questions have also arisen about the number of successful decentralized applications or 'DApps' in the ecosystem when compared to networks.","Hoskinson says that this sentiment reflects a misunderstanding about what is being developed on Cardano.","\"There's almost 200 DApps that are under construction right now,\" he noted. \"SundaeSwap is one of the most prominent, it's launching tomorrow,\" referring to the DEX that launched Thursday — albeit with congestion issues that resulted in some transactions taking longer than expected to <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/InputOutputHK\/status\/1484301683303800843?s=20\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">complete<\/a>.","\"There are several already running on the ecosystem,\" Hoskinson clarified. \"And, you know, smart contract support technically started just in September of last year.\"","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Looking to the future, Hoskinson believes that Cardano can continue to become more decentralized as it grows over time, noting that if its valuation ever hit bitcoin's it would have \"tens of thousands, if not hundreds of thousands of stake pools running the system or complemented by tons of validators inside the system.\"<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In the future, Cardano could even continue to exist without the participation of the Wyoming resident. \"T<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">he founders are important because they get the party started and they set the initial state of the system.\" <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">He went on to add:<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"I think that you have to plan for obsolescence, you have to plan to fire yourself. And that's what Satoshi did.\"<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In this episode, Chaparro and Hoskinson also discuss:<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"September of last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Hoskinson","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coatue","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kraken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Benchmark","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Charles Hoskinson","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$1.5 trillion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Cardano","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Paradigm","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Chainalysis<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/b><\/span><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Chainalysis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Wyoming","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Satoshi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kraken<\/a> &amp; <a href=\"http:\/\/Chainalysis.com\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Chainalysis","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Accel","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ribbit","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"DEX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fireblocks Network","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MPC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ADA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["CARDANO"],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}