{"summary":"Bakkt, the cryptocurrency platform run by Intercontinental Exchange, has rolled out a career portal and it appears the firm is looking to make a number of","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/8208\/bakkt-is-looking-to-make-a-slew-of-hires-to-build-out-its-digital-asset-ecosystem-mobile-app","publishDate":"2019-01-22T10:47:09","id":4952,"type":null,"title":"Bakkt is looking to make a slew of hires to build out its digital asset ecosystem, mobile app","category":["INSTITUTIONAL INVESTORS"],"content":["Bakkt, the cryptocurrency platform run by Intercontinental Exchange, has rolled out a career portal and it appears the firm is looking to make a number of key hires.&nbsp;","As The Block previously reported, the firm has brought on new talent to build out its crypto platform including Adam White, COO of Bakkt, who joined from Coinbase. Now, the firm is looking to hire for the following positions:","The latter position, Mobile Developer, will work on building a mobile app for the \"Bakkt product suite\" which the firm hopes will be used by millions of people, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bakkt.com\/careers\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">according to the job ad<\/a>.&nbsp;","Bakkt has lofty goals to build out a ecosystem for digital assets with the help of brands like Starbucks and Microsoft. Recently the firm announced its first acquisition and that it had closed a $182 million fundraise.&nbsp;","Bakkt &nbsp;is aiming to launch a new market for bitcoin futures this year, but the specific launch date is unclear. Originally, it was planning to have the product trading at the end of 2018. A number of regulatory pressures, including the partial U.S. Government shutdown, have stalled its plans, according to sources.","Still, CEO Kelly Loeffler has tried to remedy market observers' concerns that the firm might be sitting on its hands, saying, \"we’re not standing still as we await regulatory approval by the CFTC for the launch of regulated trading in our crypto markets.\"","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Mobile Developer","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Intercontinental Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$182 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"CFTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Microsoft","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kelly Loeffler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Starbucks","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Adam White","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}