{"summary":"Ether&#x27;s price has broken through the $2,000 mark, rallying amidst news that BlackRock may have taken steps to offer a spot Ethereum ETF.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/262372\/ether-surpasses-2000-for-first-time-since-july-as-blackrock-registers-ishares-ethereum-trust-entity-in-delaware","publishDate":"2023-11-09T13:28:20","id":4966,"type":null,"title":"Ether surpasses $2,000 for first time since July as BlackRock registers iShares Ethereum Trust entity in Delaware","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ether's price broke through the $2,000 mark for the first time since July, rallying amidst news that BlackRock <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/262407\/blackrock-ishares-ethereum-trust-entity-filing-delaware\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">appeared<\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to take an initial step in the possible offering of a spot <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ethereum <\/span><span class=\"articleTooltip\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"\/price\/248349\/ethereum-eth-usd\" class=\"articleTooltip__link\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"><img src=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2023\/10\/ethereum.png\" alt=\"\" title=\"\" class=\"articleTooltip__tokenImage\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">ETH<\/span> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText articleTooltip__tokenText_price articleTooltip__tokenText_negative\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">\n      -0.91%\n    <\/span><\/a> <!----><\/span><\/span> ETF with a<\/span><\/span><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span><a class=\"editor-rtfLink\" href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/262407\/blackrock-ishares-ethereum-trust-entity-filing-delaware\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filing<\/span><\/a><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to register a new iShares Ethereum Trust entity in Delaware<\/span>","<a class=\"editor-rtfLink\" href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/price?range=1D\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ether's price jumped over 7%<\/span><\/a><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on Thursday to $2,040, at 12:15 p.m. ET, according to <\/span><a class=\"editor-rtfLink\" href=\"https:\/\/www.coingecko.com\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CoinGecko<\/span><\/a><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. Bitcoin also made notable gains, reaching a daily high of $37,925 before falling back in a swathe of long liquidations to $36,311.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Thursday's market uptick is part of a multi-faceted event-led rally, according to analysts at Bitfinex. \"<\/span><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">We believe that we are in an accumulation phase for the next cycle and the bottom could very well be in place,\" Bitfinex analysts told The Block.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CoinShares Head of Research James Butterfill said Thursday's price spike was also triggered by spot ETF-related remarks made by Bloomberg Intelligence analysts Eric Balchunas and James Seyffart. On Thursday, a window opened for the SEC to \"theoretically issue approval orders\" for a spot bitcoin ETF, they wrote.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"A brief window opens on November 9 for the SEC to potentially approve all 12 U.S. spot bitcoin ETF applicants, including Grayscale's GBTC. Even if approvals don't arrive this month, we still believe there's a 90% chance of approval by January 10,\" the Bloomberg analysts noted.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">However, speaking to The Block, Butterfill cautioned against predicting whether approvals will materialize within this window. The CoinShares analyst added that markets are extremely sensitive to the spot ETF topic.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"This sensitivity was evident in our recent investor survey, where nearly 60% of investor concerns were centered on government regulation. Therefore, any positive news in this area is likely to be, and has been, eagerly seized upon by investors,\" he added.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Analysts see more factors involved in bitcoin's recent price spike. Apart from anticipation over the possible approval of a spot bitcoin ETF, these include bullish movements in the macroeconomic environment, such as major U.S. indices clocking their longest winning streaks in two years, and a shift in the bitcoin market share from short-term holders to long-term holders.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"This bullish attitude is caused by the synergy of ETF approval expectations and optimism in the U.S. stock market. I think we have a great chance to see a $40,000 level for bitcoin in the near future,\" YouHodler Chief of Markets Ruslan Lienkha told The Block.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Lienkha added Thursday's rally looks like it will sustain, \"as interest rates for stablecoins are skyrocketing in the crypto world right now.\"<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Risk assets are catching tailwinds in the wider economy. On Wednesday, the S&amp;P 500 logged its eighth straight session in the green, and the Nasdaq clocked its ninth straight day of gains, its longest winning streak in two years.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Yet, James Butterfill does not perceive today's market rally as a response to broader market events. \"Bitcoin has been gradually decoupling from equities since the beginning of 2023, so the correlation between bitcoin and equities has significantly dropped from 72% to just 20% as of now,\" he said.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">FRNT Financial Head of Data Strahinja Savic highlighted blockchain data revealing a decline in bitcoin short-term holder supply, with the trend contributing to an upward price trajectory during a phase of increased demand. \"For instance, 69% of bitcoin has moved for over a year, suggesting the majority of investors hodling,\" he noted.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"90%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Delaware","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ruslan Lienkha","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$2,040","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"20%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"S&amp;P","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"CoinShares Head of Research James Butterfill","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"January 10","content":"DATE"},{"type":"72%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"60%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"-0.91%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Butterfill","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"69%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$2,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$36,311","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$37,925","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Eric Balchunas","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"7%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"November 9","content":"DATE"},{"type":"James Seyffart","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BlackRock","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitfinex","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ethereum Trust","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"James Butterfill","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"12:15 p.m. ET","content":"TIME"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg Intelligence","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ETF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FRNT Financial Head of Data Strahinja Savic","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CoinGecko","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$40,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Nasdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["ANALYST REPORTS","CRYPTO MOVERS","ECONOMIC INDICATORS"],"authors":["Brian McGleenon","The Block"]}