{"summary":"The committee&#x27;s leaders, Debbie Stabenow, D-Mich., and John Boozman, R-Ark., have worked on legislation that would build a CFTC-centered regulatory regime around digital commodities, primarily bitcoin.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/188842\/senate-committee-to-hold-ftx-related-hearing-in-december","publishDate":"2022-11-21T14:23:45","id":5031,"type":null,"title":"Senate committee to hold FTX-related hearing in December","category":["POLICY"],"content":["The Senate Agriculture Committee has scheduled a hearing on the recent high-profile collapse of crypto exchange FTX.&nbsp;","Titled \"Why Congress Needs to Act: Lessons Learned from the FTX Collapse,\" the hearing will take place on December 1 and feature testimony from Commodity Futures Trading Commission Chair Rostin Behnam.","The committee's leaders, Debbie Stabenow, D-Mich., and John Boozman, R-Ark., have <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/185746\/senators-moving-forward-with-sbf-backed-bill-after-ftx-collapse\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">worked on legislation<\/a><\/span> that would build a CFTC-centered regulatory regime around digital commodities, primarily bitcoin. Behnam actively supported the bill, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/170439\/cftc-chair-asks-senators-for-more-authority-in-crypto-markets\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">testifying<\/a> before the committee in September on the subject, while Stabenow and Boozman both pledged to move forward with legislation. The bill drew criticism from members of the decentralized finance community, and had a prominent industry champion in former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried.&nbsp;","Last week the House Financial Services Committee was <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/187617\/u-s-house-committee-to-hold-hearing-on-ftx-collapse-and-crypto-fall-out\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">first to announce a hearing<\/a> on the high-profile exchange's implosion, which sent reverberations across the industry. The Senate Banking Committee is also <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/187758\/senate-banking-committee-eyes-hearing-on-sam-bankman-frieds-ftx-collapse\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">weighing<\/a> a potential hearing on the topic.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"John Boozman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Congress Needs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Debbie Stabenow","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Mich.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"December 1","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Stabenow","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"CFTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Commodity Futures Trading Commission Chair Rostin Behnam","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Senate Banking Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ark.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Boozman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"House Financial Services Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Senate Agriculture Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["SENATE AGRICULTURE COMMITTEE"],"authors":["Kollen Post","The Block"]}