{"summary":"An NYDFS spokesperson said Signature Bank did not provide the regulator enough assurances that it could maintain normal operations in the midst of a bank run and disputed that the takeover had anything to do with the bank&#x27;s digital asset business.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/219837\/nydfs-pushes-back-against-claim-that-signature-bank-takeover-was-crypto-related","publishDate":"2023-03-14T15:47:41","id":5033,"type":null,"title":"NYDFS pushes back against claim that Signature Bank takeover was crypto related","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A New York regulator rebuffed criticism from former congressman Barney Frank and said its decision to take over Signature Bank was not related to the bank's work with digital asset businesses. &nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“The decision to take possession of the bank and hand it over to the FDIC was based on the current status of the bank and its ability to do business in a safe and sound manner on Monday,” a spokesperson said in an emailed statement.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The NYDFS spokesperson said it worked with executives at Signature Bank to evaluate its financial position, the ability to meet withdrawal requests and whether it could continue normal operations on Monday. The bank did not provide “reliable and consistent data, <span class=\"s5\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">creating a significant crisis of confidence in the bank’s leadership,” according to the spokesperson.&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/span><\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Barney Frank, a member of the Signature Bank board and an architect of the Dodd-Frank financial regulatory law, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/219391\/barney-frank-regulators-shuttered-signature-bank-to-show-crypto-is-toxic\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">told The Block<\/span><\/a> on Monday that he thought regulators had closed the bank because “they <\/span><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">wanted to show that banks shouldn't be involved in crypto.”&nbsp;<\/span>","NYDFS characterized Signature as a bank with much more significant operations than just its digital asset business, which was a fraction of the bank's overall activity.&nbsp;","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Signature was a traditional commercial bank with a wide range of activities and customers, including small businesses like food vendors at Hunt’s Point, residential mortgage banking, commercial real estate, to name a few,\" the spokesperson said.&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The NYDFS took control of Signature Bank on Sunday after it experienced a withdrawal frenzy similar to the one that occurred with the tech-friendly Silicon Valley Bank two days before. SVB was the second-largest bank failure by asset total in the U.S.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Last week, <\/span><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Silvergate Bank, which counted FTX and other digital asset firms among its clients, said it would wind down operations “i<\/span><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">n light of recent industry and regulatory developments,” fueling concerns that appear to have contributed the run on Silicon Valley.&nbsp; &nbsp;<\/span>","NYDFS Superintendent Adrienne Harris canceled her scheduled appearance at the SXSW conference in Austin, Texas on Tuesday.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Sunday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Silvergate Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Austin","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"SXSW","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dodd","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Texas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Signature Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"FDIC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Barney Frank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SVB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Adrienne Harris","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Silicon Valley","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Silicon Valley Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["CONGRESS","CRYPTO BANKS AND LENDERS","FDIC","FEDERAL RESERVE","TRADFI BANKS","TREASURY DEPARTMENT"],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}