{"summary":"Conflux Network token jumped 38% following the announcement on Thursday.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/205827\/conflux-token-soars-following-nft-partnership-with-chinese-version-of-instagram","publishDate":"2023-01-26T08:13:57","id":5057,"type":null,"title":"Conflux token soars following NFT partnership with Chinese version of Instagram","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["Conflux token will integrate with Little Red Book, the Chinese version of Instagram, to let users display their NFTs on the platform. The Conflux Network's official Twitter page <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/Conflux_Network\/status\/1618567448067997696?s=20&amp;t=Wa3tLStFL1JO9GzOJufdUQ\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweeted<\/a> the news today.","The conflux token was trading at $0.042 by 7:37 a.m. EST, up about 38% over the past 24 hours, according to TradingView data.","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/symbols\/CFXUSD\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CFXUSD chart by TradingView<\/span><\/a>","Little Red Book has around 200 million monthly active users, according to Conflux Network and Qiangua's 2022 XiaoHongshu Active User Portrait Trend <a href=\"https:\/\/www.cbndata.com\/report\/2891\/detail?isReading=report&amp;page=1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Report.<\/a>&nbsp;","Conflux is becoming the \"major bridge\" for connecting \"prominent internet industry players\" in China, who have initiated efforts to embrace web3, said Ming Wu, CTO of Conflux.","Last year, Instagram <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/182451\/instagram-to-support-polygon-powered-nft-marketplace\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/a> it would host a marketplace for NFTs, starting with support for Polygon.&nbsp;MATIC <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/182516\/polygon-token-bucks-fed-fueled-downturn-after-instagram-announcement\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">surged<\/a> around 13% following the announcement.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Instagram","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"TradingView","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Conflux Network","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$0.042","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ming Wu","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"7:37 a.m. EST","content":"TIME"},{"type":"13%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"38%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Qiangua","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CTO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"XiaoHongshu Active User Portrait Trend <a href=\"https:\/\/www.cbndata.com\/report\/2891\/detail?isReading=report&amp;page=1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Report","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"China","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["POLYGON"],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}