{"summary":"In this episode of The Scoop, Bakkt’s Chief Product Officer Dan O&#x27;Prey lays out Bakkt’s ambitions for the future, and breaks down his company’s strategy to help banks increase their client-facing crypto offerings.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/169745\/inside-bakkts-mission-to-help-banks-offer-crypto-services-to-retail","publishDate":"2022-09-14T05:00:17","id":5082,"type":null,"title":"Inside Bakkt&#x27;s mission to help banks offer crypto services to retail","category":["PODCASTS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 86<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 4 of The Scoop was recorded live with <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro<\/strong>&nbsp;and <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bakkt Chief Product Officer Dan O'Prey<\/strong>.<\/i><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"5929363d3a382a2d192d313c3b35363a323a2b20292d36773a3634\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i><\/span>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK5048785258\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Since going public last October, the digital asset management platform Bakkt has been working towards enabling more businesses to provide crypto services to their customers.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">For example, in April of this year, Bakkt closed a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/140813\/bakkt-inks-deal-to-offer-bitcoin-ether-buys-and-sells-to-american-bank-customers\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">deal<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> with American Bank which allows the bank’s customers to buy and sell both bitcoin and ether.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In this episode of The Scoop, Bakkt’s Chief Product Officer Dan O'Prey lays out Bakkt’s ambitions for the future and breaks down his company’s strategy to help banks grow their client-facing crypto offerings.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">According to O'Prey, Bakkt hopes to position itself as the underlying infrastructure layer that enables access to a variety of crypto services:<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Bakkt is aiming to be that infrastructure platform — those services under the hood — that can enable non-crypto companies to offer crypto to their consumers in a variety of different fashions.”<\/span>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">During this episode, Chaparro and O'Prey also discuss:<\/span><\/i>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors <a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Tron<\/em><\/a>, <em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.chainalysis.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Chainalysis<\/a>&nbsp;&amp; <\/em><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.iwc.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC Schaffhausen<\/a><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em><\/b>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Tron<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nOn August 1st, 2022, Poloniex launched a faster and more stable trading system along with a <\/em><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">brand new user interface. Poloniex was founded in January 2014 as a global cryptocurrency trading platform. With its world-class service and security, it received funding in 2019 from renowned investors, including H.E. Justin Sun, Founder of TRON. Poloniex supports spot and margin trading as well as leveraged tokens. Its services are available to users in nearly 100 countries and regions with various languages available. For more information visit <a href=\"https:\/\/poloniex.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Poloniex.com<\/a>.<\/em><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/b>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Chainalysis<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nChainalysis is the leading blockchain data platform. We provide data, software, services, and research to government agencies, exchanges, financial institutions, and insurance and cybersecurity companies in over 60 countries. Backed by Accel, Addition, Benchmark, Coatue, Paradigm, Ribbit, and other leading firms in venture capital, Chainalysis builds trust in blockchains to promote more financial freedom with less risk. For more information, visit <a href=\"https:\/\/www.chainalysis.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">www.chainalysis.com<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About IWC Schaffhausen<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC Schaffhausen is a Swiss luxury watch manufacturer based in Schaffhausen, Switzerland. Known for its unique engineering approach to watchmaking, IWC combines the best of human craftsmanship and creativity with cutting-edge technology and processes. With collections like the Portugieser and the Pilot’s Watches, the brand covers the whole spectrum from elegant timepieces to sports watches. For more information, visit <a href=\"https:\/\/www.iwc.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC.com<\/a>.<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Switzerland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Dan O'Prey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coatue","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"American Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Chainalysis<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nChainalysis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Benchmark","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"IWC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April of this year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Schaffhausen","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"IWC Schaffhausen<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC Schaffhausen","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"H.E. Justin Sun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bakkt","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Paradigm","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"January 2014","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Chainalysis<\/a>&nbsp;&amp; <\/em><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.iwc.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC Schaffhausen","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Accel","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"August 1st, 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ribbit","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"October","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN","CRYPTO","FINTECH"],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}