{"summary":"On this episode of The Scoop, Sky Mavis Games Co-Founder Jeff ‘Jiho’ Zirlin chats with host Frank Chaparro about the growth of their game Axie Infinity.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/119188\/heres-how-axie-infinity-is-bridging-the-divide-between-blockchain-gaming-and-defi","publishDate":"2021-10-01T14:27:02","id":5097,"type":null,"title":"Here’s how Axie Infinity is bridging the divide between blockchain gaming and DeFi","category":["NFTS"],"content":["Episode <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">61&nbsp;<\/strong>of Season 3 of The Scoop was recorded at the 2021 Mainnet Conference with The Block’s Frank Chaparro and Jeff Zirlin, co-founder &amp; growth lead at Sky Mavis.","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"62120d060103111622160a07000e0d010901101b12160d4c010d0f\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors <a href=\"http:\/\/Bakkt.com\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bakkt<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"http:\/\/kraken.com\/scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kraken<\/a>, and&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.exodus.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Exodus<\/a><\/strong>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bakkt® unlocks the $1.2+ trillion of digital assets that is currently held in cryptocurrencies, rewards and loyalty points, gaming assets and merchant stored value. We began in 2018 with the vision to bring trust and transparency to digital assets. Through the Bakkt Warehouse and Bakkt Bitcoin Futures and Options contracts, we serve institutional clients in an end-to-end regulated market with true price transparency. For consumers, Bakkt aggregates digital assets to enable instant liquidity and to empower users to trade, transfer and pay however they want. Visit <a href=\"http:\/\/Bakkt.com\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bakkt.com<\/a> for more information<\/span><\/em>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Kraken<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Whether you’re an experienced crypto trader or just starting out, Kraken has the tools to help you achieve financial freedom. With 50+ cryptocurrencies to choose from, industry-leading security and a wide variety of features to suit any investing strategy, Kraken puts the power in your hands to buy, sell and trade digital assets. Visit&nbsp;<\/em><a href=\"http:\/\/kraken.com\/scoop\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kraken.com<\/em><\/a><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;to get started today.<\/em>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Exodus<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Exodus is leading the world out of traditional finance by building beautiful and user-friendly crypto products. Forget having to learn the nuances of different cryptocurrencies. Exodus is designed for everyone and hides the complex details behind a beautiful and intuitive interface.<\/em>","<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nOn this episode of The Scoop, Sky Mavis Games Co-Founder and Growth Lead Jeff ‘Jiho’ Zirlin joined Frank Chaparro at the 2021 Mainnet Conference to discuss their game Axie Infinity.","Chaparro and Zirlin cover Axie’s recent growth in popularity, kicking off the ‘Play-To-Earn’ trend in gaming, and how Axie Infinity players in the Philippines and other emerging economies are playing the game to supplement their incomes.","To be sure, the project's concentration in the Philippines speaks to how much work the project has ahead of it in making it truly global. Zirlin told Chaparro that Axie's user base has grown from some 38K active users in April to around 1.7 Million active users in August.","Interest in the project has since waned given a wider drawdown in the gaming NFT market, down roughly 45% as per data from The Block, with a weekly volume declining from the peak of $220M to around $130M. ","","Like the emerging markets Axie is popular in, Zirlin noted that the game also shows characteristics of an emerging market economy where \"you have hot inflows of money and then also withdrawals.\"","\"Axie Infinity is competing over mind share from a wide-range of blockchain gaming projects, including Cryptokitties, from which Axie initially drew its inspiration. Zirlin announced on The Scoop that Axie is creating their own DEX for the game. Instead of moving funds to wallets and then to an exchange to convert cryptocurrency, players will be able to convert their funds directly to the currency of their choosing through the DEX. <br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n\"We're also working on an in-house decentralized exchange or a Dex which will be native to our Ethereum-side chain called Ronin.\" Zirlin said, adding, \"I think we really saw the future of the gaming industry and rightly, we've kind of seen the emergence of this metaverse emerging market worker.\"","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$1.2+ trillion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Sky Mavis","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Kraken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Philippines","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mainnet Conference","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Zirlin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Axie","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$220M","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Jeff ‘Jiho’ Zirlin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jeff Zirlin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bakkt Warehouse","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"45%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"the Philippines","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$130M","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"DEX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dex","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Infinity","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}