{"summary":"California Governor Gavin Newsom vetoed a crypto license bill to support transactions.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/172676\/california-gov-newsom-nixes-crypto-license-bill","publishDate":"2022-09-24T19:12:36","id":5128,"type":null,"title":"California Gov. Newsom nixes crypto license bill","category":["BITCOIN"],"content":["California Governor Gavin Newsom <a href=\"https:\/\/www.gov.ca.gov\/wp-content\/uploads\/2022\/09\/AB-2269-VETO.pdf?emrc=bb881d\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">vetoed<\/a>&nbsp;a bill that would have created a BitLicense-like framework for The Golden State.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nSponsored by Democrat Assemblyman Tim Grayson, <a href=\"https:\/\/leginfo.legislature.ca.gov\/faces\/billTextClient.xhtml?bill_id=202120220AB2269\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Assembly Bill 2269<\/a> passed in the state senate and assembly late last month. The Digital Financial Assets Law proposed a framework for companies in the digital asset space to apply for a license to operate.&nbsp;<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n“It is premature to lock a licensing structure,” Newsom wrote in a Sept. 23 letter to the California State Assembly. “A more flexible approach is needed to ensure regulatory oversight can keep up with rapidly evolving technology and use cases, and is tailored with the proper tools to address trends and mitigate consumer harm.”<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nNew York already issues licenses for “<a href=\"https:\/\/www.dfs.ny.gov\/virtual_currency_businesses\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">virtual currency business<\/a>,\" known as the BitLicense. Companies, including <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coinbase.com\/blog\/coinbase-obtains-the-bitlicense\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Coinbase<\/a> and&nbsp; <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/markets\/2018\/06\/18\/payments-firm-square-receives-bitlicense-from-new-york\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Square<\/a> operate in the state via the license, which has had a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/40602\/a-lawsuit-against-nydfs-to-abolish-bitlicense-moves-to-the-states-highest-court\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">controversial histor<\/a>y.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nA new regulatory program is “a costly undertaking, and this bill would require a loan from the general fund in the tens of millions of dollars for the first several years,” Newsom wrote. “Such a significant commitment of general fund resources should be considered and accounted for in the annual budget process.”","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"California State Assembly","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"tens of millions of dollars","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Gavin Newsom","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Newsom","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Golden State","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tim Grayson","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"California","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sept. 23","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Digital Financial","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Assembly Bill 2269","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["CRYPTO"],"authors":["Christiana Loureiro","The Block"]}