{"summary":"Falling inflation figures and potential bitcoin spot ETF approvals could add fuel to a potential crypto rally going into 2024.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/263460\/ether-undervalued-bitcoin-targeting-45000","publishDate":"2023-11-17T09:55:13","id":5142,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin averts sell-off after stopgap bill avoids government shutdown, analyst says","category":["MARKET UPDATES"],"content":["Continued near-term sell-off risk was averted in the crypto market after U.S. President Joe Biden <a href=\"https:\/\/www.reuters.com\/world\/us\/uss-biden-signs-stopgap-spending-bill-white-house-says-2023-11-17\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">signed<\/a> a stopgap spending bill to avoid a potential government shutdown yesterday, according to investment firm Matrixport's Head of Crypto Research and Strategy Markus Thielen.","If a shutdown had gone ahead, non-essential government work would have halted, including the Securities and Exchange Commission’s progress on potential bitcoin spot ETF approvals, even by January 2024, resulting in more profit-taking and bitcoin potentially dropping 10%, Thielen argued.","A narrow window to approve all current bitcoin spot ETF applications at the same time ends today, Nov. 17. Once the window passes, all current filings can no longer be accepted simultaneously this year — as it's unlikely a filing would be accepted during its comment window — shifting emphasis to the next deadline on Jan. 10, K33 Research analysts <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/263127\/bitcoin-etp-exposure-hits-all-time-highs-approval-window-spot-etfs-nears-end\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a> earlier this week.","With the bill approved, momentum for a potential bitcoin spot ETF approval is maintained, keeping alive Matrixport’s year-end price target of $45,000, Thielen added. This was initially set in February when bitcoin was trading at $22,500.","With the latest inflation data on Nov. 14 revealing a fall in the U.S. CPI from 3.7% to 3.2%, lower than expected, Matrixport forecasts a further decline to 1.6% in 2024. Such a drop could lead to significant interest rate cuts by the U.S. Federal Reserve (150-200 basis points), fueling a continued rally in risk-on assets like tech stocks and cryptocurrencies, Thielen said.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Thielen also reiterated expectations that this “fifth bitcoin bull market” would last until December 2024, roughly six months after <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitcoin <\/span><span class=\"articleTooltip\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"\/price\/248348\/bitcoin-btc-usd\" class=\"articleTooltip__link\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"><img src=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2023\/10\/bitcoin.png\" alt=\"\" title=\"\" class=\"articleTooltip__tokenImage\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">BTC<\/span> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText articleTooltip__tokenText_price articleTooltip__tokenText_negative\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">\n      -0.86%\n    <\/span><\/a> <!----><\/span><\/span>’s next expected halving event in April — when the block reward gets cut in half — with a price target of $125,000.<\/span>","Matrixport projects Ethereum's revenues to reach $171 million this month — the highest since May — hinting at a period of potential outperformance relative to bitcoin. The boost is a positive sign not just for ether but for the broader altcoin market, with fees and revenue on the rise across various chains and bitcoin’s market dominance peaking, Thielen wrote.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ethereum monthly revenues. Image: <a href=\"https:\/\/www.matrixport.com\/institutions\/research\/matrix-on-target\/766\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Matrixport<\/a>.<\/span>","U.S. trading hours continue to be the most important, especially following BlackRock's Ethereum Trust <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/262407\/blackrock-ishares-ethereum-trust-entity-filing-delaware\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">registration<\/a> in Delaware last week, Nasdaq’s subsequent 19b-4 <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/262514\/nasdaq-files-for-blackrocks-proposed-ishares-ethereum-trust-etf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filing<\/a> for BlackRock's proposed iShares Ethereum Trust ETF and BlackRock’s S-1 <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/263299\/blackrock-ethereum-etf-sec\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filing<\/a> for an ether spot ETF with the SEC yesterday, Thielen added.","Bitcoin mining stocks, including Hive Blockchain, Marathon Digital and Iris Energy, could also be set for a period of outperformance against bitcoin, according to Matrixport.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Regression Model of Bitcoin-related stocks. Image: <a href=\"https:\/\/www.matrixport.com\/institutions\/research\/matrix-on-target\/766\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Matrixport<\/a>.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"earlier this week","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Matrixport","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Delaware","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Matrixport","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$125,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"January 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"10%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Jan. 10","content":"DATE"},{"type":"1.6%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Markus Thielen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"3.2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Matrixport's Head of Crypto Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitcoin <\/span><span class=\"articleTooltip\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"\/price\/248348\/bitcoin-btc-usd\" class=\"articleTooltip__link\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"><img src=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2023\/10\/bitcoin.png\" alt=\"\" title=\"\" class=\"articleTooltip__tokenImage\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$171 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Joe Biden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nov. 14","content":"DATE"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Iris Energy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hive Blockchain","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nov. 17","content":"DATE"},{"type":"BlackRock","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$22,500","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"3.7%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Ethereum Trust","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Thielen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"February","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$45,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"U.S. Federal Reserve","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"December 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"-0.86%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Marathon Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nasdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN","ETHEREUM","INVESTMENT FIRMS"],"authors":["James Hunt","The Block"]}