{"summary":"Ken Griffin&#x27;s Citadel Securities has taken a stake in crypto-friendly bank Silvergate.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/211495\/citadel-securities-takes-5-5-stake-in-crypto-friendly-bank-silvergate-capital-shares-rise","publishDate":"2023-02-14T09:44:17","id":5183,"type":null,"title":"Citadel Securities takes 5.5% stake in crypto-friendly bank Silvergate Capital; shares rise","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Shares in Silvergate Capital jumped after market maker Citadel Securities reported a 5.5% stake in the crypto-friendly bank.","Ken Griffin's firm now <a href=\"https:\/\/www.sec.gov\/Archives\/edgar\/data\/1312109\/000110465923020887\/tm234672d4_sc13g.htm\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">owns<\/a> over 1.7 million shares in the La Jolla-based bank, worth over $25 million based on the price at close on Monday. Shares in the bank soared 7% at the open, trading above $15, according to TradingView data.&nbsp;","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/symbols\/NYSE-SI\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">SI chart by TradingView<\/span><\/a>","The bank has faced increasing scrutiny over the past few months since the collapse of FTX. Silvergate <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/202744\/silvergate-bank-loss\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a> a more than $1 billion net loss for the fourth quarter as the sector suffered a \"crisis of confidence.\"&nbsp;","Fears over increased regulatory oversight in the U.S. on banks that interact with cryptocurrency have also weighed heavily on the stock. SI was the most shorted stock on Wall Street as of Jan. 31, according to a recent <a href=\"https:\/\/www.marketwatch.com\/tools\/screener\/short-interest\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">report<\/a>&nbsp;from MarketWatch.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"7%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"TradingView","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"5.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Silvergate Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"La Jolla","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Jan. 31","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$15","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"MarketWatch","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Citadel Securities","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"fourth quarter","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$25 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Ken Griffin","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["CITADEL","INVESTMENT FIRMS"],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}