{"summary":"Singh asked SBF not to use FTX money for a deal with &quot;super networkers&quot; Michael Kives and Bryan Baum and their company K5 Global.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/257696\/sbf-trial-hears-testimony-that-ftx-deals-with-celebrities-and-influencers-climbed-to-over-1-billion-inner-city-press","publishDate":"2023-10-16T13:06:39","id":5207,"type":null,"title":"SBF trial hears testimony that FTX deals with celebrities and influencers climbed to over $1 billion: Inner City Press","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["FTX's former engineering director Nishad Singh read out a list of deals from a spreadsheet in court at Sam Bankman-Fried's criminal trial on Monday that showed funds given to celebrities and influencers climbed well over $1 billion, Inner City Press <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/innercitypress\/status\/1713914408877916250\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a>.","Such deals included the $135 million FTX spent to rename a famous entertainment complex in Miami to the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/100858\/ftx-miami-heat-partnership-is-official\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">FTX Arena<\/a> (now <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/232139\/shaq-served-ftx-again\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kaseya Center<\/a>). Also on the list were $28 million paid to basketball player Steph Curry, $14 million to Canadian businessman Kevin O'Leary and undisclosed amounts to football quarterback Tom Brady, model Gisele Bundchen and actor Larry David.&nbsp;","These deals amassed to $1.3 billion, Singh was reported as <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/innercitypress\/status\/1713934442585112679\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">saying<\/a>.&nbsp;","Singh also touched on a conversation he had with Sam Bankman-Fried and Gary Wang concerning an investment in Michael Kive's and Bryan Baum's company K5 Global.","\"Sam sent Gary and me a term sheet to give millions in bonus to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/240707\/ftx-administrators-file-to-recover-71m-from-its-philanthropic-and-life-science-arms\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Michael Kives<\/a> and Bryan Baum, and a billion investment in their VC firm,\" Singh reportedly <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/innercitypress\/status\/1713933605150318799\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a>. \"I asked that it be done with Sam's money and not FTX's money.\"","Bankman-Friend entered a hasty deal with Kives and Baum, known as \"super networkers,\" for <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/236049\/alameda-seeks-to-claw-back-700-million-sbf-paid-super-networkers\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$700 million<\/a>, The Block previously reported.&nbsp;","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$1 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Miami","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$14 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$28 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Tom Brady","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Michael Kive","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sam","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$700 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Steph Curry","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kives","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Michael Kives","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Inner City Press","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1.3 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Kevin O'Leary","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Larry David","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nishad Singh","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bryan Baum","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$135 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gisele Bundchen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sam sent Gary","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Baum","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gary Wang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Singh","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kaseya Center<\/a>)","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["FTX","LAWSUITS","SBF TRIAL"],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}