{"summary":"The crypto exchange serving institutional clients was launched last year with much fanfare – and $10 billion in funding.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/155859\/bullish-com-cuts-jobs-crypto-exchange","publishDate":"2022-07-05T12:41:38","id":5249,"type":null,"title":"Bullish becomes the latest crypto exchange to cut jobs","category":["HIRING"],"content":["<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bullish, a crypto exchange serving institutional clients, has joined rivals in making layoffs as the market struggles with an ongoing period of weakness.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Fewer than 30 staff members have lost their jobs at Bullish — which <a href=\"https:\/\/www.sec.gov\/Archives\/edgar\/data\/1872195\/000119312522185182\/d180840df4a.htm\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">employs<\/a> around 390 people — a source familiar with the situation told The Block.<\/span><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A company spokesperson confirmed the layoffs on Tuesday, while adding that \"Bullish continues to actively hire for product, engineering and other strategic roles as we continue to evolve our business strategy.\"<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bullish was&nbsp;<\/span><a class=\"editor-rtfLink\" href=\"https:\/\/bullish.com\/news\/press-releases\/launch-of-new-cryptocurrency-exchange-bullish\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">launched last year<\/span><\/a><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to much fanfare as a <\/span><a class=\"editor-rtfLink\" href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/112630\/an-inside-look-at-bullish-the-billion-dollar-crypto-exchange-thats-just-begun-its-test-pilot\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">subsidiary of Block.one<\/span><\/a><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, the software company behind the EOSIO blockchain protocol. Block.one and other investors — including Peter Thiel's Thiel Capital, British hedge fund billionaire Alan Howard, Galaxy Digital and Nomura — provided an initial $10 billion in funding.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">By cutting jobs, Bullish joins other crypto firms that have been struggling due to a significant market downturn. In recent weeks, Coinbase, Gemini, BitMEX, OSL and Abra have all trimmed their workforces, <\/span><a class=\"editor-rtfLink\" href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/155209\/abra-becomes-latest-crypto-firm-to-cut-jobs\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">as The Block previously reported<\/span><\/a><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bullish is based in the Cayman Islands and regulated by the Gibraltar Financial Services Commission. The company has employees across the globe, with a large presence in Hong Kong.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Last year, Bullish said it plans to go public via a deal with Far Peak Acquisition Corporation, a special purpose acquisition company (SPAC). That deal is yet to close and Bullish last week <\/span><a class=\"editor-rtfLink\" href=\"https:\/\/bullish.com\/news\/press-releases\/bullish-and-far-peak-acquisition-corp-announce-extension-of-outside-date-for-business-combination-june-2022\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">agreed<\/span><\/a><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to extend the outside termination date from July 8 to December 31 to give it more time to complete.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">As part of the extension, Bullish said it also paid Far Peak a $2.5 million fee, which Far Peak will use for working capital.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">If the SPAC deal goes through, Bullish will become a publicly traded company on the New York Stock Exchange. The company expects the deal to close in the third quarter of this year.<\/span>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Corrects name of company to Bullish from Bullish.com in headline and first paragraph.&nbsp;<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Cayman Islands","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Gemini","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Peter Thiel","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Galaxy Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July 8","content":"DATE"},{"type":"December 31","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nomura","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$2.5 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Far Peak Acquisition Corporation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York Stock Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$10 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"SPAC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gibraltar Financial Services Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alan Howard","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"third quarter","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Thiel Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["LAYOFFS"],"authors":["Yogita Khatri","The Block"]}