{"summary":"Lawyers of the disgraced FTX founder reiterated the necessity of his temporary release in a filing on Monday.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/252900\/sam-bankman-frieds-counsel-again-asks-for-jail-release-ahead-of-trial","publishDate":"2023-09-26T03:37:13","id":5276,"type":null,"title":"Sam Bankman-Fried’s counsel again asks for jail release ahead of trial","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Attorneys for Sam Bankman-Fried, founder of failed crypto exchange FTX, once again asked a district court to temporarily release him from jail ahead of his <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/251312\/prosecutors-dont-like-juror-questions-proposed-by-sbfs-lawyers\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">upcoming trial next month<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bankman-Fried’s lawyers submitted a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.courtlistener.com\/docket\/66631291\/288\/united-states-v-bankman-fried\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">letter<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on Monday to Judge Lewis Kaplan, arguing that the temporary release of Bankman-Fried is “necessary for the preparation of [his] defense.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“The Court has previously noted that it understands the difficulties of preparing a complex case for trial,” his lawyers said. “We submit that we are finding it exceedingly difficult as a practical matter to adequately prepare for trial with the restrictions on access currently in place. This is not a point we make lightly but it is the reality of the nature of this case.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bankman-Fried’s defense counsel added that they will only have access to him in the cellblock for a very limited amount of time in the morning before the trial day begins. “When the trial day ends, he will be taken back to the MDC and will arrive well past the time when visiting hours are over,” the lawyers said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“​​We believe that temporary release is the only way for defense counsel to have sufficient access to Mr. Bankman-Fried to properly represent him at trial,” they added.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The disgraced founder <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/236735\/judge-denies-motion-to-dismiss-most-charges-against-sam-bankman-fried\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">could face over 100 years in prison<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> if convicted on an array of charges including fraud.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Over the past few weeks, Bankman-Fried's attorneys have&nbsp;<\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/247689\/sam-bankman-frieds-lawyers-ask-for-temporary-release-from-jail\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">urged the district court to grant the former FTX CEO's temporary release<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> from jail to review documents ahead of his trial.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In August, his lawyers claimed that the Department of Justice’s request to revoke his bond — after he shared private diaries belonging to Caroline Ellison with the press — was based on “thin” factual ground and said such a move would <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/242689\/sam-bankman-fried-claims-dojs-request-to-revoke-bail-raises-free-speech-concern\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">violate his right to free speech<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The DOJ, however, previously <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.courtlistener.com\/docket\/66631291\/253\/united-states-v-bankman-fried\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that Bankman-Fried, who is detained at the Metropolitan Detention Center, has sufficient access to a laptop to review necessary documents.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Last week, Judge Kaplan <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/252429\/judge-blocks-certain-witnesses-from-sam-bankman-frieds-upcoming-trial\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">blocked certain witnesses from Bankman-Fried’s trial<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. The judge ordered that a British barrister, a professor at the University of Michigan and some others will not be testifying at the trial.<\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Department of Justice","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Caroline Ellison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"University of Michigan","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kaplan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"MDC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Court","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Metropolitan Detention Center","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"DOJ","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lewis Kaplan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["FTX","SAM BANKMAN-FRIED","SBF TRIAL"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}