{"summary":"Taproots Wizards has raised $7.5 million in a seed round with crypto-focused venture capitalist Standard Crypto leading the round.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/263343\/bitcoin-ordinals-startup-taproot-wizards-raises-7-5-million-in-seed-round","publishDate":"2023-11-16T11:09:19","id":528,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin Ordinals startup Taproot Wizards raises $7.5 million in seed round","category":["DEALS"],"content":["Hoping to re-infuse the Bitcoin community with \"magic,\" quirky startup Taproots Wizards has raised $7.5 million in seed round financing with crypto-focused venture capitalist Standard Crypto leading the round.","\"We heard about bitcoin 10 years ago. And we're here to fix it,\" Taproot Wizards <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/taprootwizards\/status\/1725163116059627761\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">posted to X<\/a> on Thursday. \"Our mission is to repopulate Bitcoin’s 10-year-old wizard village.\"&nbsp;","The organization is a \"Bitcoin-focused Ordinals project,\" according to TechCrunch, which <a href=\"https:\/\/techcrunch.com\/2023\/11\/16\/taproot-wizards-bitcoin-ordinals\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">broke the news<\/a> of the seed round. \"Taproot Wizards has a limited mint of 2,121 wizards, the specific number paying homage to the total supply of bitcoin: 21 million,\" the report said. \"To date, less than 1% — 20 Taproot Wizards’ Ordinals — have been inscribed so far.\"","Ordinals, which enable the indexing and tracking of every satoshi (Bitcoin’s smallest unit) across the network, were introduced in January. The process called \"inscription\" allocates image or other data to individual satoshis. Ordinals can serve as either individual NFTs or fungible BRC-20 tokens.&nbsp;","In February, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/207986\/luxor-mines-largest-bitcoin-block-ever-contains-taproot-wizard-nft\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block reported<\/a> that crypto developer Udi Wertheimer and Bitcoin mining company Luxor had teamed up in a wizard-themed NFT collection. The first Taproot Wizard NFT was mined in a block at the time.","Taproot Wizards are awarding Ordinals to active community members who have participated in the outfit's “wizard school” or proven that they are Bitcoin fanatics, according to TechCrunch. Last month, Taproot Wizards <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/TaprootWizards\/status\/1710380380736385123\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">held a party<\/a> in Amsterdam where attendees with the best wizard costume could win one of the community's Ordinals.","The organization also said they received backing from other investors including StarkWare and Bitcoin Frontier Fund. \"Zero Ordinals have been sold to investors in this round. If our investors want any, they should take a wizard shower!\" Taproot Wizards said in a <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/TaprootWizards\/status\/1725163127086432641\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">post to X<\/a>.","Transactions on the Bitcoin network hit an <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/255659\/bitcoin-transactions-see-sharp-decline-following-ordinals-peak-hype\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">all-time high<\/a> in September thanks in part to the hype surrounding Ordinals.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Amsterdam","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Taproot Wizard NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Taproots Wizards","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"February","content":"DATE"},{"type":"20","content":"DATE"},{"type":"\" Taproot Wizards","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BRC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Udi Wertheimer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Standard Crypto","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$7.5 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Taproot Wizards","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Luxor","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["SEED &AMP; PRE-SEED"],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}