{"summary":"The Federal Reserve is readying its new instant payments service for launch between May and July of next year. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/166327\/federal-reserves-fednow-payments-system-will-be-live-within-a-year-says-brainard","publishDate":"2022-08-29T15:12:41","id":5299,"type":null,"title":"Federal Reserve&#x27;s FedNow payments system will be live within a year, says Brainard","category":["POLICY"],"content":["The Federal Reserve is getting closer to delivering its much-anticipated instant payments system, FedNow.&nbsp;","In a virtual <a href=\"https:\/\/www.federalreserve.gov\/newsevents\/speech\/brainard20220829a.htm\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">speech<\/a> on August 29, Fed Vice Chair Lael Brainard announced: \"We will be ready to launch the FedNow Service between May and July of 2023, bringing this innovative core instant payment infrastructure to financial institutions of every size across America.\"","As currently envisioned, the FedNow service will provide real-time, 24\/7 access to payments for financial insitutions of any size.&nbsp;","","","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Source: <a href=\"https:\/\/www.frbservices.org\/financial-services\/fednow\/about.html#:~:text=The%20FedNow%20Service%20is%20a,every%20day%20of%20the%20year.\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Federal Reserve<\/a><\/em><\/span>","FedNow appears in many conversations alongside a potential Fed central bank digital currency or CBDC. A Fed governor recently came out in support of <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/164085\/federal-reserve-governor-pumps-the-brakes-on-us-cbdc-in-favor-of-fednow\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">FedNow as opposed to a US-centric CBDC<\/a>.","In her first appearance before Congress, Brainard herself fielded a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/149040\/fed-vice-chair-brainard-defends-cbdcs-against-republican-attacks-in-first-hearing-since-confirmation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">barrage of questions<\/a> about a potential CBDC from concerned Republicans looking to establish that the Fed lacked statutory authority to issue a digital dollar without congressional approval. It's a subject about which several agencies, including the Fed, the Treasury, and the Department of Justice are <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/166075\/most-of-the-responses-to-joe-bidens-crypto-executive-order-are-due-next-week\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">supposed to report to President Biden<\/a> by next week, per the executive order earlier this year.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Federal Reserve","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July of 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Department of Justice","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fed","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Lael Brainard","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Congress","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"America","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"August 29","content":"DATE"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FedNow","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Brainard","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Biden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FedNow Service","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["FEDERAL RESERVE","PAYMENTS"],"authors":["Kollen Post","The Block"]}