{"summary":"Coinbase&#x27;s chief legal officer Paul Grewal said the crypto industry is ready to put legal troubles behind it and focus on innovation.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/239646\/coinbase-sees-crypto-winter-thawing-after-ripples-partial-legal-victory","publishDate":"2023-07-14T10:09:32","id":5304,"type":null,"title":"Coinbase sees crypto winter &#x27;thawing&#x27; after Ripple’s partial legal victory","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Coinbase Chief Legal Officer Paul Grewal thinks crypto winter might be starting to thaw.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We’re seeing green shoots,” Grewal told CNBC in a televised interview, commenting on a partial <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/239559\/sec-faces-wake-up-call-after-ripple-ruling-though-appeal-likely\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">legal victory<\/a> for Ripple Labs in a long-running dispute with the Securities and Exchange Commission that sent its native XRP <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/239608\/xrp-daily-volume-surges-court-ruling-exchange-relistings\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">soaring<\/a>.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“People are eager to return to focusing on innovation and new ideas, new technologies rather than hearing from lawyers like me and judges in court cases,” Grewal said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Shortly after the ruling on Thursday, Coinbase, along with Crypto.com and Kraken Pro, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/239573\/rival-exchanges-join-coinbase-in-reopening-xrp-trading-after-court-ruling\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reopened trading<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> for XRP which at one point jumped by more than 80% amid massive trading volume.&nbsp;<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","\"Yesterday's ruling on XRP is a big win for the crypto industry,\" Coinbase said in a <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/coinbase\/status\/1679853585821999104\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweet<\/a> on Friday.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"80%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"” Grewal","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"CNBC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"XRP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Grewal","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Paul Grewal","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["COINBASE"],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}