{"summary":"Maryland Democrat Glenn Ivey, who calls for “even-handed” crypto regulation, won a congressional primary on Tuesday.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/158755\/maryland-house-primary-winner-promises-even-handed-crypto-regulation","publishDate":"2022-07-20T12:50:07","id":5326,"type":null,"title":"Maryland House primary winner promises ‘even-handed’ crypto regulation","category":["POLICY"],"content":["Maryland Democrat Glenn Ivey, who calls for “even-handed” crypto regulation, won a congressional primary on Tuesday.","Ivey is very likely to win the November election in the heavily Democratic district.","The crypto industry is one step closer to landing a new <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/158220\/crypto-curious-dem-on-the-ballot-in-hot-maryland-primary\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">potential ally<\/a> in Congress after Maryland Democrat Glenn Ivey <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/AP_Politics\/status\/1549616594887888899?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">won<\/span><\/a> a congressional primary on Tuesday night.","Ivey defeated former Rep. Donna Edwards in a crowded primary in the state’s 4th Congressional District. Ivey was a state attorney for Prince George’s County and previously worked on Capitol Hill. The winner of the primary is likely to win the November general election in the deep-blue district.","Although the primary did not hinge on crypto regulation, Ivey dedicated a piece of his campaign platform to digital asset regulation. He cautioned against over-regulation of crypto, saying “this innovation should not be stifled before it has a chance to mature and add value to the U.S. economy.”","“I will work closely with industry experts and other leaders to make sure that regulation is thoughtful and even-handed,” Ivey wrote on his campaign website.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","Web3 Forward, a super PAC that supports crypto candidates and is funded by industry executives, reported spending $109,000 to boost Ivey’s primary campaign. He also nabbed a pre-primary endorsement from Rep. Maxine Waters, who chairs the House Committee on Financial Services.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Prince George’s County","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Maxine Waters","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$109,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Maryland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"4th Congressional District","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Congress","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"night","content":"TIME"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ivey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ivey","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Glenn Ivey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Donna Edwards","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"House Committee on Financial Services","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["CONGRESS","MAXINE WATERS"],"authors":["Stephanie Murray","The Block"]}