{"summary":"In this episode of The Scoop Mining Report, The Block Research&#x27;s mining analyst Wolfie Zhao and host Frank Chaparro take a further look at the pressures facing miners in today&#x27;s market environment and how recent heatwaves have affected mining operations today.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/159459\/the-mining-report-with-wolfie-zhao-when-miner-capitulation","publishDate":"2022-07-27T05:01:20","id":5344,"type":null,"title":"The Mining Report with Wolfie Zhao: When miner capitulation?","category":["THE BLOCK"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">69<\/strong><\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 4 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block's Frank Chaparro and The Block Research Mining Research Analyst Wolfie Zhao.<\/i><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"14647b707775676054607c7176787b777f77666d64607b3a777b79\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK4553074687\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/i><\/span>","Following the crypto market crash in May and June, several institutional bitcoin mining companies have liquidated large portions of their bitcoin reserves, adding more fuel to the selling pressure.","In this episode, we discussed the impact of the shrinking hash price and the profitability of bitcoin mining at the moment. The network's hash price has reached the lowest point since late 2020 due to bitcoin's price decline and only moderate difficulty correction. Even though the network has had three difficulty declines in a row over the past month, the competition level is still up by about 10% year-to-date.","Meanwhile, the global energy price surge and inflation are pushing mining firms' production costs even higher – not to mention that a lot of them also have growing interest expenses on outstanding loans they took since last year. If bitcoin's price drops below the critical $15,000 level, we may start to see miner capitulation. Listen to more of our discussions below.","In this episode of The Scoop Mining Report, The Block Research's mining analyst Wolfie Zhao and host Frank Chaparro take a further look at the pressures facing miners in today's market environment and how recent heatwaves have affected mining operations today.","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors <em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.chainalysis.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Chainalysis<\/a>&nbsp;&amp;<\/em>&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.iwc.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC Schaffhausen<\/a><\/em><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/b>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Chainalysis<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nChainalysis is the leading blockchain data platform. We provide data, software, services, and research to government agencies, exchanges, financial institutions, and insurance and cybersecurity companies in over 60 countries. Backed by Accel, Addition, Benchmark, Coatue, Paradigm, Ribbit, and other leading firms in venture capital, Chainalysis builds trust in blockchains to promote more financial freedom with less risk. For more information, visit <a href=\"https:\/\/www.chainalysis.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">www.chainalysis.com<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About IWC Schaffhausen<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC Schaffhausen is a Swiss luxury watch manufacturer based in Schaffhausen, Switzerland. Known for its unique engineering approach to watchmaking, IWC combines the best of human craftsmanship and creativity with cutting-edge technology and processes. With collections like the Portugieser and the Pilot’s Watches, the brand covers the whole spectrum from elegant timepieces to sports watches. For more information, visit <a href=\"https:\/\/www.iwc.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC.com<\/a><\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Wolfie Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Switzerland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Paradigm","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"10%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Coatue","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$15,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Chainalysis<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nChainalysis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Accel","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Benchmark","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ribbit","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"IWC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block Research Mining Research Analyst Wolfie Zhao","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"June","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Schaffhausen","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"IWC Schaffhausen<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC Schaffhausen","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chainalysis<\/a>&nbsp;&amp;<\/em>&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.iwc.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC Schaffhausen","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN","MINING"],"authors":["The Scoop","The Block"]}