{"summary":"Crypto exchange giant FTX&#x27;s head of over-the-counter and institutional sales, Jon Cheesman, quietly left the company last month.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/174513\/ftxs-head-of-otc-and-institutional-sales-has-quietly-left-the-firm","publishDate":"2022-10-03T16:19:01","id":5364,"type":null,"title":"FTX&#x27;s head of OTC and institutional sales has quietly left the firm","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto exchange giant FTX's head of over-the-counter and institutional sales, Jonathan Cheesman, is no longer working for the company, two sources with knowledge of the matter told The Block.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Cheesman <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/103602\/crypto-exchange-ftx-hsbc-jonathan-cheesman-traditional-financial-institutions\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">joined<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> FTX in May 2021 and was tasked with <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">bringing traditional financial institutions into crypto markets, having <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">previously worked at HSBC, Goldman Sachs and Barclays. He began trading crypto in 2017, with a prior partnership at crypto investment company Distributed Global. He told The Block last year after he joined FTX that he would be \"a bridge between traditional finance and crypto natives\" at the exchange operator.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Cheesman also headed Access, FTX's investor advisory services unit. An<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> FTX-related account on Twitter that he set up hasn't been active since August.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The exchange said through a spokesperson that it won't be hiring a replacement for Cheesman, saying it has a full team in place to handle the role<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Cheesman has returned to his own&nbsp; firm&nbsp; <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/suite.endole.co.uk\/insight\/company\/13338359-jci-advisory-ltd?page=overview\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">JCi Advisory Ltd<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> , which he <a href=\"https:\/\/suite.endole.co.uk\/insight\/company\/13338359-jci-advisory-ltd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">set up<\/a> last year before joining FTX, one of the two sources said. The source said that FTX is also a client of the advisory firm, among others.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In the 16 months Cheesman served as FTX head OTC and institutional sales, the exchange averaged $64.08 billion in volume with a peak in November 2021 of $92.51 billion based on data from <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockresearch.com\/data\/crypto-markets\/spot\/fiat-exchange-volume\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block Research<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/crypto-markets\/spot\/fiat-exchange-volume\/embed\" title=\"Fiat Exchange Volume\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The industry has seen a share of departures in recent months. Last month, FTX US president Brett Harrison <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/172744\/ftx-us-president-harrison-is-stepping-down\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">stepped<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> back to an advisory role. In the same month, Celsius Network CEO Alex Mashinsky <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/173098\/celsius-network-ceo-mashinsky-resigns\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">resigned<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, a move that was followed by a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/173103\/celsius-tokens-price-tumbles-after-ceo-mashinsky-resigns\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">sharp decline<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in the price of the network’s token, CEL. In addition, former CEO of Kraken, Jesse Powell, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/171847\/krakens-jesse-powell-stepping-down-as-ceo-of-crypto-exchange\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">stepped down<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to make way for <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/172575\/new-kraken-ceo-ripley-seeks-growth-not-a-clash-of-crypto-titans\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">incoming<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> CEO David Ripley. Earlier today, bitcoin investment services firm NYDIG’s CEO Robert Gutmann and president Yan Zhao <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/174421\/nydigs-ceo-and-president-to-step-down-as-crypto-changing-of-the-guard-continues\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">left roles<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> at the company.<\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"HSBC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Barclays","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cheesman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$64.08 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Kraken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jonathan Cheesman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"David Ripley","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"November 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Yan Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"May 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alex Mashinsky","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Robert Gutmann","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"JCi Advisory Ltd","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jesse Powell","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Goldman Sachs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Brett Harrison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$92.51 billion","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Yogita Khatri","Jeremy Nation","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}