{"summary":"In this episode of The Scoop, Scottie Pippen and Orange Comet CEO Dave Broome discuss how Web3 is creating new ways for celebrities and fans to connect, and share the story behind Pippen&#x27;s upcoming ‘SP33’ NFT collection.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/194742\/scottie-pippen-unpacks-the-power-of-flexing-in-the-metaverse","publishDate":"2022-12-14T05:00:17","id":5398,"type":null,"title":"Scottie Pippen unpacks the power of flexing in the metaverse","category":["NFT COLLECTIONS"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 124<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 4 of The Scoop was recorded live with <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro and NBA legend Scottie Pippen and Orange Comet CEO Dave Broome.<\/strong><\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts.&nbsp;Email feedback and revision requests can be sent to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"3c4c53585f5d4f487c4854595e50535f575f4e454c4853125f5351\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK3847585141\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/i>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Six-time NBA champion Scottie Pippen is making his mark on the metaverse with a digital sneaker <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/orangecomet.com\/collection\/scottie-pippen\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">collection<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> featuring 1,000 unique ‘SP33’ NFTs.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">For the launch, Pippen partnered with Orange Comet — the company that recently helped Sir Anthony Hopkins launch his own NFT <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/176922\/fancy-a-zoom-call-with-hannibal-lecter-theres-an-nft-for-that\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">collection<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In this episode of The Scoop, Scottie Pippen and Orange Comet CEO Dave Broome discuss how Web3 is creating new ways for celebrities and fans to connect, and share the story behind the upcoming ‘SP33’ NFT collection.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">According to Pippen, launching a digital sneaker collection is a way to bring his brand into the digital era.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“I was a big sneakerhead growing up in the NBA world, so this is my opportunity to really resurface back into the sneaker world, but do it from a digital standpoint.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Not only will holders be able to wear their SP33 shoes around the metaverse, but 33 of the 1,000 NFTs will also come with a real-world sneaker prototype.<\/span>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">During this conversation, Chaparro, Pippen, and Broome also discuss:<\/span><\/i>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Tron,&nbsp;<\/em><\/a><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.ledn.io\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ledn,<\/a> <a href=\"https:\/\/nordvpn.com\/thescoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">NordVPN<\/a><\/em><\/b><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Tron<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Founded in 2013, Huobi Global is one of the largest virtual asset exchanges in the world. Huobi Global serves millions of users across international markets. Since its establishment, Huobi Global has committed to providing first class virtual asset investment services. Huobi Global's robust infrastructure, product innovation and capital strength provides a truly customer-centric and secure trading environment to help our international users to achieve their investment objectives. Please refer to Huobi's official website for more information: <a href=\"http:\/\/www.huobi.com\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">huobi.com<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Ledn<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong>Ledn was founded on the unshakeable conviction that digital assets have the power to democratize access to the global economy. We help you to experience the real life benefits of your Bitcoin without having to sell it. Start a savings account, take out a loan, or double your Bitcoin. For more information visit&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.ledn.io\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ledn.io<\/a><\/em>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><b data-stringify-type=\"bold\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About NordVPN<\/strong><\/b><\/em><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">NordVPN is essential for keeping crypto transactions secure, hiding your IP address and protecting your devices from hackers and data theft. Get premium cyber-security on up to 6 devices for the price of a cup of coffee a month. Get your exclusive NordVPN Deal and try it risk-free now with a 30-day money-back guarantee: Visit <a class=\"c-link\" tabindex=\"-1\" href=\"https:\/\/nordvpn.com\/thescoop\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-stringify-link=\"https:\/\/nordvpn.com\/thescoop\" data-sk=\"tooltip_parent\" data-remove-tab-index=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">https:\/\/nordvpn.com\/thescoop<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"NBA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Orange Comet","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Huobi Global","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Broome","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2013","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ledn","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Huobi","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Anthony Hopkins","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Pippen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ledn<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong>Ledn","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dave Broome","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Scottie Pippen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}