{"summary":"Crypto prices remained mostly flat after the market opened on Wednesday, as traders await the Fed’s interest rate decision and comments from the press conference this afternoon.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/207535\/market-trades-flat-ahead-of-feds-interest-rate-decision","publishDate":"2023-02-01T10:10:07","id":540,"type":null,"title":"Market trades flat ahead of Fed&#x27;s interest rate decision","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Crypto prices remained mostly flat after the market opened on Wednesday, as traders await the Federal Reserve’s interest rate decision and comments from the subsequent press conference this afternoon.","Bitcoin fell 0.1% to $23,136 around 9:50 a.m. EST, according to TradingView data.","","","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/chart\/xAJYa739\/?symbol=COINBASE%3ABTCUSD\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BTCUSD chart by TradingView<\/a><\/span>","Ether also declined 0.1% to around $1,588. BNB declined 0.8%, while Cardano's ADA rose 1.2%. Polygon's MATIC was down 1.5% in the past 24 hours after rising yesterday.","Dog-themed meme coins declined slightly, with Dogecoin and Shiba Inu down 1.8% and 1%, respectively.&nbsp;","Silvergate shares rose 1.8% to around $14 by 9:50 a.m., according to Nasdaq data, rising alongside most other crypto stocks.","Jack Dorsey's Block declined 0.1% to trade around $81, while MicroStrategy declined 0.1%. Coinbase was also down, falling by 0.1%.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Federal Reserve","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"this afternoon","content":"TIME"},{"type":"9:50 a.m.","content":"TIME"},{"type":"TradingView","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1.8%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$14","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"1.2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"0.1%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$23,136","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$81","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Shiba Inu","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cardano","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Dogecoin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"0.8%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"1.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"9:50 a.m. EST","content":"TIME"},{"type":"$1,588","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Jack Dorsey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"ADA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MicroStrategy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nasdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["ANALYST REPORTS","BNB","COINBASE","DOGECOIN","EARNINGS","ECONOMIC INDICATORS","ETHEREUM","RATE DECISIONS","SHIBA INU"],"authors":["Sam Venis","The Block"]}