{"summary":"Huobi said it will be the first exchange to support the launch of the PYUSD stablecoin and provide fee-free PYUSD\/USDT trading pairs.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/243686\/huobi-paypal-stablecoin","publishDate":"2023-08-08T05:33:47","id":5409,"type":null,"title":"Huobi plans to list PayPal stablecoin &#x27;soon&#x27;","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Huobi said today that it will soon list <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">PYUSD<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, a stablecoin <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/243569\/paypal-launches-stablecoin\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">launched<\/a> Monday by PayPal.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The crypto exchange said in a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.huobi.com\/support\/en-us\/detail\/44945804382445\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">statement<\/a> that it will be “the first exchange to support the launch of PYUSD stablecoin, and will provide PYUSD\/USDT trading pairs with zero trading fee permanently.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Huobi, however, did not specify when it will list PayPal's stablecoin. “When the market circulation and liquidity conditions are ripe, Huobi will open trading at the first time,” the company said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Its announcement came just a day after Huobi advisor and Tron founder Justin Sun <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/justinsuntron\/status\/1688573051179552768\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweeted<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;that he hoped to invite PayPal to consider issuing PYUSD on Tron. “Mutual benefits await in the digital payment landscape,” Sun wrote in the tweet.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">PayPal launched&nbsp;its <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">own U.S. dollar stablecoin in collaboration with Paxos, and said in a <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">release<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that the token will be gradually made available to users in the United States.&nbsp;<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The payments giant said U.S. dollar deposits, short-term treasuries and similar cash equivalents would fully back PYUSD.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Huobi’s announcement on potentially listing PYUSD came as the exchange still faces what it claimed were rumors surrounding the supposed arrests of its executives in China, reported by a Hong Kong media outlet.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Huobi advisor Justin Sun <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/justinsuntron\/status\/1688026465387044864\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweeted<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> “4” on Sunday, a commonly-used phrase in the crypto community — coined by Binance boss Changpeng Zhao — when faced with so-called FUD (fear, uncertainty and doubt).&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Jiayin Xie, Huobi’s head of social media, told The Block today that Huobi’s operation remains normal.&nbsp;<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“The FUD surrounding the executive arrests did have some impact on us but not much,” Xie, who’s based in Singapore, said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sun also <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/xiejiayinHuobi\/status\/1688056497618800642\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">retweeted<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> an earlier post of Xie refusing the rumor.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Sunday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"USDT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"today","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Paxos","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"PayPal","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Justin Sun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"” Xie","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jiayin Xie","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Tron","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Huobi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"United States","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"China","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Changpeng Zhao —","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["FINTECH","HTX","JUSTIN SUN"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}