{"summary":"Robert Greifeld led Nasdaq as its CEO from 2003 to 2016, driving its evolution as a fledgling listening venue for many tiny tech companies into a diversified global financial technology company. He now sits on the board of two financial high frequency trading firms, including Virtu Financial, where he serves as Chairman. In this conversation we discuss his new book, Market Movers, and dig into his storied career and examine some of the market structure debates shaping today&#x27;s capital markets. I hope you enjoy the episode.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/45714\/bob-greifeld-former-ceo-of-nasdaq-examines-some-market-structure-debates","publishDate":"2019-11-05T16:30:15","id":5434,"type":null,"title":"Bob Greifeld, former CEO of Nasdaq examines market structure debates, crypto, and the IPO market","category":["PODCASTS"],"content":["<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Robert Greifeld led Nasdaq as its CEO from 2003 to 2016, driving its evolution as a fledgling listing venue for many tiny tech companies into a diversified global financial technology company. He now sits on the board of two financial high frequency trading firms, including Virtu Financial, where he serves as Chairman. In this conversation we discuss his new book, Market Movers, and dig into his storied career and examine some of the market structure debates shaping today's capital markets. I hope you enjoy the episode.<\/em>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The following transcript is taken from episode twenty seven of The Scoop, The Block’s flagship podcast. Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on <a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/a>, or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to&nbsp;<a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection#8dfde2e9eeecfef9cdf9e5e8efe1e2eee6eefff4fdf9e2a3eee2e0\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"2d5d42494e4c5e596d5945484f41424e464e5f545d5942034e4240\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/span><\/a>.<\/em>","<iframe src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK5536898722\" width=\"100%\" height=\"200\" frameborder=\"0\" scrolling=\"no\" data-mce-fragment=\"1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","In this episode of The Scoop, Greifeld explored several topics with Chaparro, including:","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2003","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2016","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Robert Greifeld","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Greifeld","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Virtu Financial","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nasdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}