{"summary":"Rarible now sells assets from one of the most popular protocols for blockchain-based gaming on its platform.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/169458\/nft-marketplace-rarible-partners-with-immutable-to-sell-gaming-nfts","publishDate":"2022-09-13T09:00:42","id":5456,"type":null,"title":"NFT marketplace Rarible partners with Immutable","category":["METAVERSE & NFT"],"content":["<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The NFT marketplace Rarible tapped the Ethereum L2 scaling protocol Immutable X to allow users to buy and sell NFTs from Gods Unchained, Guild of Guardians, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/150291\/nft-game-illuvium-raises-72-million-in-digital-land-sales\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Illuvium <\/a>and other popular blockchain-based games built on Immutable X.<\/span>","This is not Rarible's first entry into selling gaming NFTs, Rarible co-founder Alex Salnikov told The Block, as gaming assets on Polygon and Solana have been previously available on the platform. However, Rarible's integration with Immutable X adds assets from one of the most popular protocols for blockchain-based games, as well as assets from some of the longest running blockchain-based games like Gods Unchained, onto the NFT platform.&nbsp;","While Gods Unchained never gained the popularity of other blockchain-based games like Axie Infinity or Sorare, the competitive card game saw a peak trading volume of $6.32 million in January of this year, The Block's data dashboard shows.&nbsp;","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/nft-non-fungible-tokens\/gaming\/gaming-nft-trade-volume\/embed\" title=\"Gaming NFT Trade Volume\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Immutable X, created by the blockchain gaming firm Immutable, allows NFTs to be sold quickly and with a nominal transaction fee. Immutable X has a particular focus on blockchain-based gaming assets, with the video game distribution giant GameStop opting to use the protocol for its <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/132903\/gamestop-immutable-x-nft-marketplace-ethereum-layer-2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">NFT marketplace<\/span><\/a>.","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Rarible is now a more robust competitor to the likes of <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/128189\/gaming-nft-platform-fractal-launches\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Fractal<\/a>, launched by Twitch co-founder Justin Kan, and other gaming-focused NFT marketplaces.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Rarible","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Guild of Guardians","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Justin Kan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Infinity","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$6.32 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alex Salnikov","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"GameStop","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["RARIBLE"],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}