{"summary":"Bitcoin plummets below $21,000, ether losses ground ahead of The Merge and traders are increasingly expecting a harsh response from the Fed next week. Bitcoin plummets below $21,000, ether losses ground ahead of The Merge and traders are increasingly expecting a harsh response from the Fed next week.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/169679\/bitcoin-drops-below-21000-ether-under-1600-following-hot-u-s-inflation","publishDate":"2022-09-13T12:39:36","id":5469,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin drops below $21,000, ether under $1,600 following hot U.S. inflation","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["Hotter than expected U.S. inflation pushed bitcoin below $21,000 while the price of ether dipped under $1,600 as crypto tracked traditional financial markets lower.","Bitcoin was trading at $20,888 on Coinbase, down about 5.9% over the past 24 hours, per <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coinbase.com\/price\/bitcoin\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">data<\/a>&nbsp;from the exchange.","","","Tuesday's losses followed higher-than-expected inflation <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/169220\/u-s-inflation-comes-in-above-estimates-8-3-year-on-year-and-0-1-month-on-month\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">figures<\/a> from the U.S., up 8.3% year-on-year, while headline inflation was up 0.1% month-on-month and core inflation rose 0.6% month-on-month.","Ether's losses over the past 24 hours are even greater than bitcoin's, dropping more than 6% to $1,598, per Coinbase <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coinbase.com\/price\/ethereum\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">data<\/a>.","","","A higher inflation <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bls.gov\/cpi\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">figure<\/a> would most likely result in further selloffs in the equity and crypto market, according to 21.co research associate Adrian Fritz. \"Since this would lead to an even more hawkish Fed, that is expected to announce another interest rate hike next week,\" he said.","The S&amp;P 500 was down almost 3% at the time of writing, while the Nasdaq composite shed a little over 4%, with markets digesting the the surprise data with just eight days to go to the Fed's next decision on interest rates.&nbsp;","Ahead of the inflation news traders had been factoring in a hike of 75 basis points, however, according to the CME's FedWatch dashboard the market is now predicting an 20% probability of a 100-basis-point hike at next week's meeting.&nbsp;","","","Elsewhere, the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/symbols\/TVC-DXY\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">DXY index<\/a>, which measures the U.S. dollar relative to a basket of other foreign currencies, was back up, gaining 1.3%. FTX's Sam Bankman-Fried <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/169287\/macro-matters-the-merge-and-bitcoin-back-above-22000-this-week-in-markets\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a>&nbsp;that the dollar dominance and inflation has affected crypto markets this year, and today's price movements appear to reinforce that assumption.","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"8.3%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$20,888","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"6%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Fed","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"4%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"20%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"S&amp;P","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"0.1%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$1,598","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$21,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"CME","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1,600","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"5.9%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"3%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"DXY","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"0.6%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Adrian Fritz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"1.3%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Fried","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Nasdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN","ETHEREUM","FTX"],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}