{"summary":"Mashinsky reportedly used the funds to pay back state and federal taxes accrued from his income from his Celsius assets. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/174332\/ex-ceo-mashinsky-withdrew-10-million-before-celsius-bankruptcy-ft","publishDate":"2022-10-02T15:50:06","id":5482,"type":null,"title":"Celsius’s former CEO withdrew $10 million before the firm’s bankruptcy: FT","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Celsius Network founder and ex-CEO Alex Mashinsky withdrew $10 million before the company froze customer withdrawals and ultimately declared bankruptcy, the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.ft.com\/content\/5f7c9eab-ca5f-4425-91be-5781313c9723\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Financial Times<\/a> reports.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Citing people familiar with the matter, the FT reported that Mashinsky withdrew the $10 million in May. Withdrawals were frozen on June 12 due to customer concerns about the crypto bear market and the crypto lender’s financial stability.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Mashinsky and his family had $44 million worth of crypto assets frozen in the crypto lender following his withdrawal, a spokesperson told FT. Mashinsky <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/173098\/celsius-network-ceo-mashinsky-resigns\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">resigned<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> as CEO on Sept. 27, 2022.&nbsp;<\/span>","“In mid to late May 2022, Mr Mashinsky withdrew a percentage of cryptocurrency in his account, much of which was used to pay state and federal taxes. In the nine months leading up to that withdrawal, he consistently deposited cryptocurrency in amounts that totalled what he withdrew in May,” the spokesperson was quoted as saying.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Mashinsky co-founded Celsius in 2017, and the firm reached a $3 billion valuation by the end of 2021. The firm filed for <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/157491\/crypto-lender-celsius-declares-chapter-11-bankruptcy-in-new-york\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Chapter 11 bankruptcy<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on July 18 and has been embroiled in legal proceedings since.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Vermont Department of Financial Regulation even alleged that the firm ran a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/168369\/celsius-ran-a-ponzi-like-scheme-states-allege\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ponzi-like scheme<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> and that client funds were not safe – despite the firm assuring users that they were. <\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"FT. Mashinsky","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sept. 27, 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$3 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"May 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$44 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Alex Mashinsky","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Vermont Department of Financial Regulation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mr Mashinsky","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"July 18","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Financial Times","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$10 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Mashinsky","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ponzi","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"June 12","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}