{"summary":"Entertainment driven blockchain Theta Labs partners with Pogs, the milk-game from the 1990s.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/240354\/theta-labs-partners-with-90s-milk-caps-game-pogs-as-it-eyes-digital-resurgence","publishDate":"2023-07-18T12:03:09","id":5527,"type":null,"title":"Theta Labs partners with &#x27;90s milk-caps game Pogs as it eyes digital resurgence","category":["GAMING"],"content":["Entertainment focused blockchain company Theta Labs is partnering with 1990s milk cap game company Pogs as it pursues web3 ambitions.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Rebranded as <a href=\"https:\/\/www.pogdigital.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Pog Digital<\/a>, the company said that the 165 million millennials and Gen Zers who collected its product \"will want to own a modern iteration that integrates digital and physical experiences.\"<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">During more than 30 years of existence, Pogs has worked with top brands like Disney, Barbie and Pokemon, it said in a statement.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"By partnering with Theta Labs, we are able to scale a dedicated ecosystem while connecting our collections across multiple blockchains such as Solana, Ethereum and Bitcoin,\" Pog Digital CEO Kyler Frisbee said in the statement.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">With a team made up of former employees from Netflix, Samsung, Amazon and Vimeo, Theta hopes to become \"the leading blockchain for media and entertainment.\" The company has raised more than $100 million, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.crunchbase.com\/organization\/theta\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">according to Crunchbase<\/a>.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Kyler Frisbee","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Samsung","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Theta Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Amazon","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$100 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Pog Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Netflix","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Barbie","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1990s","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Solana","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Disney","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}