{"summary":"In an AMA on Twitter, Ethereum co-founder Vitalik Buterin reflects on when Ethereum was first launched in 2015.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/116413\/vitalik-buterin-reveals-his-biggest-regret-about-ethereum","publishDate":"2021-09-02T04:22:34","id":5626,"type":null,"title":"Vitalik Buterin reveals his biggest regret about Ethereum","category":["ETHEREUM"],"content":["In six years, Ethereum has gone from a newly launched project to a global settlement platform <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/data\/on-chain-metrics\/ethereum\/ethereums-adjusted-on-chain-volume-daily\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">moving $9 billion in value<\/a> per day — with applications ranging from DeFi to NFTs.&nbsp;","But what’s the one thing that Ethereum co-founder Vitalik Buterin regrets the most?","“The whole '8 cofounders' thing (and choosing them so quickly and nondiscriminately),” he <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/VitalikButerin\/status\/1433245736641040384\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">revealed today<\/a> in a Twitter AMA.","These eight co-founders are Buterin himself, poker coach Mihai Alisie, Canadian entrepreneur Anthony Di Iorio, programmer Jeffrey Wilcke, mathematician Charles Hoskinson, Amir Chetrit who was working on Colored Coins, SyNerG Music CEO Joseph Lubin, and computer scientist Gavin Wood (based on their jobs at the time).","Hoskinson is now the founder of Cardano, which is introducing smart contracts this month, while Gavin Wood is building Polkadot. Both are <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coingecko.com\/en\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">top 10<\/a> blockchain platforms by market cap.","At the time, there was a big debate over whether Ethereum should be a for-profit corporation or a non-profit. It was almost incubated as a company but the paper was never signed. This issue was divisive and even led to the ousting of Hoskinson from the group.","“People are harder to tightly coordinate in small groups than I expected. You can't just get everyone to sit around in a circle, see each other's inherent goodness and get along, especially when huge incentive conflicts are at play,” Buterin <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/VitalikButerin\/status\/1433199904713678855\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">added<\/a> in response to a similar question.","In terms of the design of the Ethereum Virtual Machine itself, Buterin <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/VitalikButerin\/status\/1433255593683259398\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a> it was a bad idea to make it 256 bit, whereas it should have been “64 bit with an arbitrary-size bigint feature.” This refers to processing power, with 64 bits systems able to process data more quickly.","Buterin speculated that if he wasn’t into crypto, he <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/VitalikButerin\/status\/1433240431588872194\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">would probably<\/a> be working on designing a kind of social media platform.&nbsp;","He also <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/VitalikButerin\/status\/1433229704765394946\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">discussed<\/a> that he still remains somewhat of a digital nomad, although he moves around more slowly now, living in places for months at a time.&nbsp;","“I feel like my huge span of time in Singapore last year changed me quite a bit. It was interesting to just... be by myself and with my own thoughts for the first time in nearly a decade,” he <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/VitalikButerin\/status\/1433238556839841794\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a>.","Tesla CEO Elon Musk also weighed in, <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/elonmusk\/status\/1433231578189107203\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">asking<\/a> Buterin what love is. He replied, \"<span class=\"css-901oao css-16my406 r-poiln3 r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">X AE A-12 don't hurt me...\"<\/span>","<i data-stringify-type=\"italic\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">For more stories like this, make sure to subscribe to The Block on <\/i><i data-stringify-type=\"italic\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a class=\"c-link\" href=\"https:\/\/t.me\/the_block_crypto\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-sk=\"tooltip_parent\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Telegram<\/a><\/i><i data-stringify-type=\"italic\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/i>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Hoskinson","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Anthony Di Iorio","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Mihai Alisie","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Colored Coins","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Vitalik Buterin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ethereum Virtual Machine","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jeffrey Wilcke","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Buterin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Elon Musk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Joseph Lubin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cardano","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"AMA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$9 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Gavin Wood","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Amir Chetrit","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Charles Hoskinson","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gavin Wood (","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["CARDANO","ETHEREUM","VITALIK BUTERIN"],"authors":["Tim Copeland","The Block"]}