{"summary":"Sam Trabucco has resigned as co-CEO of Alameda Research. He will continue on as an advisor.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/165564\/alameda-research-co-ceo-trabucco-resigns","publishDate":"2022-08-24T16:05:55","id":5627,"type":null,"title":"Alameda Research co-CEO Trabucco resigns","category":["HIRING"],"content":["Alameda Research co-CEO Sam Trabucco has resigned from his role at the crypto trading firm.","He will stay on as an adviser and Caroline Ellison will continue as sole CEO, Trabucco <a href=\"https:\/\/mobile.twitter.com\/AlamedaTrabucco\/status\/1562519118741323778\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said in a Tweet<\/a>. The company declined to comment further other than to confirm his exit.","\"I can't personally continue to justify the time investment of being a central part of Alameda,\" Trabucco said. \"Everyone works really hard here, and spending a 'normal' amount of time at work is tricky — especially when you're trying to be a leader.\"","Trabucco has been gradually scaling down his role at the company and doesn't currently have any projects lined up, he also said. He joined as a trader in 2019.","FTX founder Sam Bankman-Fried also founded Alameda, in 2017. Trabucco and Ellison took over as co-CEOs last year.","Although Alameda did not comment on the reason for Trabucco's departure, he suggested in a tweet that he's leaving for personal reasons.","\"I've reached a point in life where I have to prioritize other things,\" Trabucco said. \"Lately I've been really happy, spending a lot of time traveling, visiting friends and family, working on \"myself\" and whatnot. Also I bought a boat, that's been cool. I needed to relax, and I'm really, really happy.\"","Bon voyage.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Madhu Unnikrishnan contributed to this report<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Ellison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Trabucco","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Caroline Ellison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Trabucco","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Trabucco","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Catarina Moura","The Block"]}