{"summary":"Gemini said it currently has no money deposited at Signature Bank. All customer funds are held at JPMorgan, Goldman Sachs and State Street Bank.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/219292\/gemini-had-no-customer-funds-gusd-at-signature-bank","publishDate":"2023-03-13T10:04:58","id":5659,"type":null,"title":"Gemini had no customer funds, GUSD at Signature Bank","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["Crypto exchange Gemini said it held no customer funds or Gemini dollars (GUSD) at Signature in the wake of the bank's <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/219119\/state-regulator-takes-control-of-signature-bank-federal-regulators-guarantee-deposits\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">closure by regulators on Sunday<\/a>.","While it used to partner with Signature, all of its customer funds are now at JPMorgan, Goldman Sachs and State Street Bank, Gemini <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/Gemini\/status\/1635272598228721676?s=20\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a> on Twitter. Some GUSD reserves are also at Fidelity.","\"It’s very sad to hear the news about Signature Bank. They have been incredible partners to Gemini and our industry for the better part of a decade,\" the company said. \"We continue to actively monitor counterparty risk due to banking partnerships to prevent any impact to Gemini customers.\"","Regulators shut down Signature Bank on Sunday but said that all deposits would be safe. That was two days after Silicon Valley Bank was similarly seized by regulators in California. Last week, Silvergate announced that it was winding down and liquidating.","Signature Bank and Silvergate were the two most popular banks used by crypto companies, leaving many scrambling to find new banking partners.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Sunday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Silvergate","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gemini","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Goldman Sachs and State Street Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gemini","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"California","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Gemini dollars","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gemini","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Fidelity","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Signature Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Silicon Valley Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["GEMINI"],"authors":["Catarina Moura","The Block"]}