{"summary":"The Australian Treasury said that it plans to require platforms that hold a certain threshold of crypto assets to obtain a license.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/256585\/australia-proposes-crypto-exchange-regulation-with-existing-laws","publishDate":"2023-10-16T01:17:31","id":5678,"type":null,"title":"Australia proposes crypto exchange regulation with existing laws","category":["REGULATION"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Australia today released a proposal to regulate digital-asset services platforms as the country steps up efforts to “provide clarity” and “protect customers.” <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Australian Treasury said in a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/treasury.gov.au\/consultation\/c2023-427004\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">consultation paper<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that failures and vulnerabilities of these platforms have “increased the need to regulate to protect consumers.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The government plans to leverage existing Australian financial services laws. It intends to require platforms with a certain threshold of assets — AU$1,500 ($948) for an individual or AU$5 million ($3.2 million) in aggregate — to obtain an Australian Financial Services Licence.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Specifically, the regulators also seek to apply certain obligations, including setting up standards for custody software and requirements when transacting in tokens. The proposal would also apply additional obligations for activities, including trading, staking, tokenization and fundraising.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The consultation for the document closes on Dec. 1, 2023.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“The Treasury has today released a consultation process, which is pleasing to see,” Jonathon Miller, managing director of Kraken Australia, told The Block. “Australia is now in the unfortunate situation where our regulation has taken a very long time, so we’re taking the approach of shoehorning crypto into existing financial services regulation. We’re behind our global peers when it comes to implementing a crypto framework, so I appreciate the need to have something in place locally to provide certainty to platforms like ours.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Miller said that the approach, however, creates ample opportunities for the regulation to ignore the nuances of the technology. “I’m hopeful that we can work collaboratively with the Government to make sure we don’t snuff out the benefits of future innovations in crypto that might fall outside the conventional ‘financial services’ box,” he added.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Angela Ang, senior policy advisor at blockchain intelligence firm TRM Labs and a former regulator at the Monetary Authority of Singapore, said in a social media <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.linkedin.com\/posts\/angelaajl_crypto-digitalassets-australia-activity-7119486237677146112-w6Xv?utm_source=share&amp;utm_medium=member_desktop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">post<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that the Australian government’s proposal is “a thoughtful way to apply existing legal and regulatory constructs to crypto assets that take into account their unique characteristics, as well as alignment to international standards.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Some banks in Australia have become increasingly cautious about the risks of potential crypto scams. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In July, National Australia Bank said it had <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/239890\/national-australia-bank-blocks-payments-to-high-risk-crypto-exchanges\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">blocked some payments to “high-risk” cryptocurrency exchanges<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to protect its customers. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In June, <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">the Commonwealth Bank of Australia also <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/233713\/australia-bank-crypto-limits-scams\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">took measures to limit its customers' ability<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to send money to crypto exchanges due to crypto-related scams. <\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Australian Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"TRM Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"AU$5 million ($3.2 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Dec. 1, 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Kraken Australia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$948","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Miller","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Angela Ang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jonathon Miller","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Commonwealth Bank of Australia","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Australian Financial Services Licence","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"National Australia Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Government","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Monetary Authority","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Australia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"June","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["PAYMENTS"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}