{"summary":"Altcoins took the brunt of Tuesday&#x27;s market retrace as investor caution increased ahead of the release of Federal reserve minutes.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/263999\/altcoins-lead-market-retrace-ahead-of-release-of-fed-minutes","publishDate":"2023-11-21T11:57:11","id":5687,"type":null,"title":"Altcoins lead market retrace ahead of release of Fed minutes","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["Altcoins took the brunt of Tuesday's market retrace as investor caution increased ahead of the release of minutes from the U.S. Federal Reserve's November meeting.","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitcoin fell 0.8% over the past 24 hours to $36,976 at 11:40 a.m. ET, according to <\/span><a class=\"editor-rtfLink\" href=\"https:\/\/www.coingecko.com\/en\/coins\/bitcoin\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CoinGecko<\/span><\/a><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The decrease in value of the world's largest digital asset by market capitalization was overshadowed by the decline experienced by altcoins, such as <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/learn\/249535\/what-is-solana-and-how-does-it-work-a-beginners-guide-to-sol-cryptocurrency\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Solana<\/a> and ether. In the past 24 hours, <a href=\"https:\/\/wp.theblock.co\/data\/crypto-markets\/futures\/top-5-ether-futures-open-interest-exchanges\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ether<\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> slipped below the $2,000 mark to $1,990, a fall of over 3%. <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Solana <\/span><span class=\"articleTooltip\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"\/price\/33827\/solana-sol-usd\" class=\"articleTooltip__link\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"><img src=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2023\/10\/solana.png\" alt=\"\" title=\"\" class=\"articleTooltip__tokenImage\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">SOL<\/span> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText articleTooltip__tokenText_price articleTooltip__tokenText_negative\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">\n      -0.61%\n    <\/span><\/a> <!----><\/span><\/span> fell further in the same period, dropping by almost 7% to now change hands at $55.35.<\/span><\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Bitcoin has not sold off as much as other coins because when it is compared to other assets, like Solana and ether, it is considered far safer, less volatile, and a lower beta asset,\" Bitfinex analysts told The Block.<\/span>","According to CoinShares Head of Research James Butterfill, Solana's recent rally was primarily driven by speculation. \"In contrast, we continue to see much greater growth in total value locked on the Ethereum network and much greater growth of Layer 2 solutions such as Abritrum and Optimism relative to Solana, while the Ethereum developer count is five times the size of Solana's,\" Butterfill told The Block.","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In contrast to the sliding value of Solana and other blue-chip altcoins was BNB's rally. The token that is used to pay transaction fees on the Binance cryptocurrency exchange increased by 6.3% in the past 24 hours. <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/263858\/bnb-price-spikes-amid-report-of-possible-binance-deal-with-doj\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BNB's rally<\/a> comes after a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2023-11-20\/us-seeks-more-than-4-billion-from-binance-to-end-criminal-case\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">report<\/a> that the U.S. Department of Justice is seeking $4 billion from Binance as part of a proposed resolution of a years-long investigation into the world’s largest cryptocurrency exchange.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Analysts at Bitfinex characterized the current market conditions as being influenced by heightened volatility and uncertainty. <\/span><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"We expect traders will view bitcoin as a safe haven in times of uncertainty, rather than completely switching to the dollar. A lot of the new money which has entered the market is more hopeful and optimistic about crypto as a whole and will maintain exposure to the market, even when there is a correction, by holding bitcoin,” the analysts added.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">On Tuesday, the Federal Reserve will release the minutes of the last Federal Open Market Committee <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/263335\/bitcoin-could-see-significant-capital-inflow-next-year-as-investors-anticipate-fed-pivot-say-analysts\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">meeting<\/a>. Due to be released at 2 p.m. ET, t<\/span><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">he minutes will be closely watched by investors for clues about the direction of monetary policy and its potential impact on the cryptocurrency market.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">At the last FOMC meeting, the U.S. central bank paused the benchmark interest rate in the 5.25% to 5.5% range. The move was interpreted as somewhat dovish by markets. However, Fed Chair Jerome Powell added nuance in a press conference after the rate announcement.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"We're not confident that we haven't, we're not confident that we have reached that sufficiently restrictive plateau,\" Powell told reporters. His words sowed enough uncertainty to keep global markets cautious.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Federal Reserve","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Fed","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"6.3%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$4 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1,990","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"CoinShares Head of Research James Butterfill","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Powell","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$36,976","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"U.S. Department of Justice","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Butterfill","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$2,000 mark","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"-0.61%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Solana","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"11:40 a.m. ET","content":"TIME"},{"type":"7%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"3%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2 p.m. ET","content":"TIME"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"0.8%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"5.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Federal Open Market Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"5.25%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jerome Powell","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S. Federal Reserve","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$55.35","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"FOMC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CoinGecko","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Solana","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["CRYPTO MOVERS","ECONOMIC INDICATORS","FEDERAL RESERVE","RATE DECISIONS"],"authors":["Brian McGleenon","The Block"]}