{"summary":"On this episode of The Scoop, The Block&#x27;s Frank Chaparro and Biber explore: Anchorage&#x27;s review process in determining whether or not to list an asset The importance of transitioning from state by state regulatory framework to a unified federal framework. Why the absence of enforcement action has made it harder for companies understand what law is, or is not and more.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/56017\/understanding-the-regulatory-hurdles-in-crypto-with-anchorage-general-counsel-katie-biber","publishDate":"2020-02-14T12:11:42","id":5733,"type":null,"title":"Understanding the regulatory hurdles in crypto with Katie Biber","category":["CRYPTOCURRENCY"],"content":["<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 6 of Season 2 of The Scoop was recorded on January 21 at&nbsp; The Block offices with Frank Chaparro and Katie Biber, General Counsel at Anchorage. Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on <a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/a>, or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to&nbsp;<a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection#98e8f7fcfbf9ebecd8ecf0fdfaf4f7fbf3fbeae1e8ecf7b6fbf7f5\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"2858474c4b495b5c685c404d4a44474b434b5a51585c47064b4745\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/span><\/a><\/em>","<iframe src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK5250932042\" width=\"100%\" height=\"200\" frameborder=\"0\" scrolling=\"no\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Crypto custodian Anchorage emerged&nbsp;from stealth in January 2018, unveiling a new type of custody solution aimed at toppling incumbents like BitGo and Coinbase.","Backed by Andreessen Horowitz and Blockchain Capital, the firm has locked down $57 million in venture capital to build out a faster alternative to cold storage solutions. Leading the firm's regulatory and policy efforts is Katie Biber, a legal professional who once served as the GC for Romney's presidential campaign.","On this episode of The Scoop, The Block's Frank Chaparro and Biber explore:","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$57 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Anchorage","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"January 21","content":"DATE"},{"type":"January 2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Romney","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Andreessen Horowitz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Biber","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Blockchain Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Katie Biber","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"General Counsel","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}