{"summary":"The statement comes after a report said Binance transferred more than $400 million from its U.S. affiliate to another firm controlled by CEO Changpeng Zhao.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/212756\/merit-peak-firm-at-heart-of-reuters-report-operated-on-binance-us-exchange-admits","publishDate":"2023-02-16T20:17:15","id":5766,"type":null,"title":"Merit Peak, firm at heart of Reuters report, operated on Binance.US, exchange admits","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Binance.US, the U.S. affiliate of the world’s largest crypto exchange, acknowledged that a market making firm called Merit Peak, which is alleged to have secretly received $400 million from the exchange, operated on its platform.&nbsp;","“While there was a market making firm named Merit Peak that operated on the Binance.US platform, it stopped all activity on the platform in 2021,” the company <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/BinanceUS\/status\/1626370268045225984?s=20\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweeted<\/a> in response to a bombshell Reuters report earlier in the day that said the funds were withdrawn from the bank account of the exchange's U.S. affiliate during the first three months of 2021.&nbsp;","“Binance.US has never — and will never — trade nor lend out customer funds,” the statement adds.“Only Binance.US employees have access to Binance.US bank accounts. Period.”","The <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/212658\/binance-transferred-400-million-from-u-s-partner-to-zhao-run-firm-reuters-says\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Reuters<\/a> report said parent company Binance secretly transferred hundreds of millions in funds from a Binance.US account at California-based Silvergate Bank to Merit Peak, an investment firm also controlled by Binance CEO Changpeng Zhao.","Binance, which is not authorized to operate in the U.S., insists that Binance.US operates as a wholly independent affiliate.","“Our leadership team is staffed with former DOJ, SEC, FBI, and NYFed employees who are committed to operating a platform that is safe and abides by U.S. laws and regulations,” Binance.US said in its statement. The statement also claims that Binance.US fully reserves its assets, and is subject to “regular audits”.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"the first three months of 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FBI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Reuters","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"California","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$400 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Silvergate Bank to Merit Peak","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DOJ","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Binance CEO Changpeng Zhao","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE","CZ"],"authors":["Colin Wilhelm","The Block"]}