{"summary":"Despite the bear market, BAYC maintained the highest floor price among NFT projects for nearly the whole year.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/198625\/bored-ape-yacht-club-ends-2022-with-69-eth-floor-price","publishDate":"2022-12-31T18:02:25","id":5775,"type":null,"title":"Bored Ape Yacht Club ends 2022 at $83,000 floor price","category":["METAVERSE & NFT"],"content":["Yuga Labs backed NFT project Bored Ape Yacht Club (BAYC) ended the year with a floor price around 69 ETH, or $82,740, according to The Block's Data Dashboard.&nbsp;","","","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Source: NFT Price Floor<\/em>","BAYC held the highest floor price among all NFT projects this year, only dipping below its fellow Yuga Labs collection CryptoPunks briefly in November before rising above once more. At its peak, BAYC's floor price reached 144.9 ETH, worth $409, 720 in May.&nbsp;","Yuga Labs NFT projects nabbed some of the most expensive sales of 2022. Of the 12 <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/196988\/yuga-labs-dominates-most-expensive-nft-sales-of-2022\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">highest NFT transactions<\/a> this year, eight were from Yuga Labs's CryptoPunks, BAYC or Mutant Ape Yacht Club collections, The Block previously reported. Larva Labs had originally launched CryptoPunks in 2017, but Yuga Labs <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/137631\/bored-apes-creator-yuga-labs-acquires-ip-for-cryptopunks-and-meebits\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">bought<\/a> the intellectual property in March.&nbsp;","To be sure, Yuga Labs faced some headwinds in 2022. Along with dozens of other people and companies, Yuga Labs was named in a California <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/193746\/yuga-labs-moonpay-named-in-celebrity-nft-endorsement-lawsuit\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">class action lawsuit<\/a> pertaining to undisclosed celebrity endorsements on Dec. 9.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"BAYC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Yuga Labs","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"NFT Price Floor","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Yuga Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bored Ape Yacht Club","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mutant Ape Yacht Club","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$82,740","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$409","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block's Data Dashboard","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"California","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Dec. 9","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["BAYC","YUGA LABS"],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}