{"summary":"Brian Beccafico, an NFT art collector who goes by Arthemort online, will be on Sotheby&#x27;s team as an NFT specialist.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/165301\/sothebys-hires-nft-specialist-to-join-digital-art-team","publishDate":"2022-08-23T16:05:03","id":5777,"type":null,"title":"Art auction house Sotheby’s hires an NFT specialist","category":["NFTS"],"content":["<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The historic art auction house Sotheby’s has hired an NFT specialist to join its digital art team.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Brian Beccafico, who goes by Arthemort online, <\/span><span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced his new position at Sotheby’s through a <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/Arthemort\/status\/1561966205296074754\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">meme<\/a>. The auction house confirmed in a call that he has joined the company.<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sotheby’s has steadily increased its involvement in NFTs since it auctioned its first NFT, one by digital creator Pak for nearly <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/101958\/auction-house-sothebys-pak-nft-sale-yields-nearly-17m\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$17 million,<\/span><\/a><span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span><span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">in April 2021. The auction house launched its own NFT platform called Sotheby’s <a href=\"https:\/\/metaverse.sothebys.com\/matsuyama-harmless-charm\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Metaverse<\/a> in October.&nbsp;<\/span>","Sotheby's offers NFTs through multiple sale formats, including auction, buy-now and generative drops, and has a team of specialists in New York, London, Paris and Hong Kong. Sotheby’s marquee sales for NFTs and digital art – Natively Digital - are held three times a year. Last year, when such things were searingly hot, the most expensive Bored Ape Yacht Club ever sold went for $3.4 million, and the second most expensive Cryptopunk ever sold reached $11.7 million.&nbsp;","<span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Beccafico, who comes from a family of art collectors, is an NFT art collector himself who has purchased works from the top names in crypto including Beeple, Pak, Fewocious and XCOPY, Beccafico said in a prior <a href=\"https:\/\/artfromfuture.medium.com\/interview-with-brian-beccafico-a-young-art-collector-fd81721ea6d9\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">interview<\/a>. He recently received a master's degree in art business from Sotheby's.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Sotheby’s","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sotheby’s <a href=\"https:\/\/metaverse.sothebys.com\/matsuyama-harmless-charm\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Metaverse","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$11.7 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Paris","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$3.4 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"April 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Beccafico","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Brian Beccafico","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sotheby's","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"London","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Natively Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$17 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"October","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}