{"summary":"The NFTs will appear in a hexagon with a cloud of particles moving around the image.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/152214\/tag-heuer-rolls-out-nft-feature-for-some-smartwatch-models","publishDate":"2022-06-15T10:28:05","id":5825,"type":null,"title":"Tag Heuer rolls out NFT feature for some smartwatch models","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Tag Heuer, the Swiss luxury watchmaker owned by fashion powerhouse LVMH, will now let customers display non-fungible tokens (NFTs) on the face of certain smartwatch models, in a new feature announced on Wednesday morning.","The move comes in partnership with Ledger for owners of the Tag Heuer Connected Calibre E4 smartwatch. Watches will also be compatible with Metamask.","The NFTs will appear in a hexagon with a cloud of particles moving around the image. The new update will be available free for smartwatch owners through the Apple App Store or Google’s Play store.","The company said it worked with blue chip NFT collections such as Bored Ape Yacht Club, CryptoPunk, Clone-X, and World of Women to develop the idea.","\"I have had a deep interest in the NFT space, and this feature fits with TAG Heuer’s tradition of being avant-garde and innovative in technology,\" Frédéric Arnault, CEO of TAG Heuer, said in a statement. The company was one of the first major luxury brands to experiment with smartwatches back in 2015.&nbsp;","Despite NFT floor prices <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/151754\/nft-floor-prices-are-falling-along-with-the-broader-crypto-market\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">dropping<\/a> this week, many fashion and luxury fashion brands have enthusiastically moved ahead with crypto payments offers or NFTs. Just yesterday, French apparel brand Lacoste <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/151851\/french-fashion-brand-lacoste-wades-into-web3-with-nft-launch\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/a> the launch of its own NFT collection. Gucci, Off White, and Farfetch also announced that they would accept crypto payments earlier this year.","Alongside these, LVMH competitor Kering's chief client and digital officer Grégory Boutté said in a conference last week that he wants the conglomerate to be a pioneer in the web3 and NFT space.","Last month, Tag Heuer began <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/147849\/luxury-watchmaker-tag-heuer-inks-deal-with-bitpay-to-accept-crypto-online-in-the-us\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">accepting<\/a> crypto payments in the US. Arnault also purchased a Bored Ape last month, showing enthusiasm for the space on his Twitter.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2015","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Grégory Boutté","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bored Ape Yacht Club","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"LVMH","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lacoste","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kering","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Farfetch","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tag Heuer Connected Calibre E4 smartwatch","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"morning","content":"TIME"},{"type":"Frédéric Arnault","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Clone","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Metamask","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gucci","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Anushree Dave","The Block"]}