{"summary":"GSR has secured in-principle approval from the Monetary Authority of Singapore (MAS) for a Major Payment Institution license. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253851\/gsr-in-principle-approval-singapore-payment-institution-license","publishDate":"2023-10-02T08:00:47","id":5839,"type":null,"title":"GSR secures in-principle approval for Singapore payment institution license","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["One of crypto’s oldest market makers, GSR, has secured in-principle approval from the Monetary Authority of Singapore (MAS) for a Major Payment Institution license.&nbsp;","The decision will help GSR to deepen its roots in the Singapore market and leverage it as a hub to invest in the region and encourage adoption of web3 technology, according to a statement.","The global cryptocurrency trading firm and liquidity provider said it was proud to have met MAS’s admission requirements and is working toward being granted a full license in Singapore.","\"We are immensely grateful to MAS for their constructive oversight, which helps shape a growing digital asset ecosystem that we feel proud to be a substantial part of,” GSR Group CEO Jakob Palmstierna said.&nbsp;","“We are delighted to be recognised as one of the first firms of our type to be granted this in-principle approval from an internationally respected regulator such as MAS,” GSR Group COO Xin Song added. “MAS has led the way providing a clear framework for digital asset utility, enabling us to deepen our local client partnerships, and continue in our critical role as a liquidity provider within the ecosystem.”","Earlier today, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253755\/coinbase-granted-full-license-in-singapore\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Coinbase was granted a full Major Payment Institution license<\/a> by MAS, nearly a year after it received <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/176064\/crypto-exchange-coinbase-gets-license-in-singapore\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">in-principal approval<\/a>.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Jakob Palmstierna","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"GSR","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"GSR Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Monetary Authority of Singapore (MAS","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MAS","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"GSR Group COO","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["James Hunt","The Block"]}