{"summary":"Sam Bankman-Fried, the former CEO of the collapsed FTX crypto exchange, will depart the Bahamas on Wednesday evening to be extradited to the U.S., the Office of the Attorney General said in an emailed statement. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/197300\/bahamas-government-says-bankman-fried-will-depart-wednesday","publishDate":"2022-12-21T18:17:44","id":5849,"type":null,"title":"Bahamas government says Bankman-Fried will depart Wednesday","category":["CRYPTO INFRASTRUCTURE"],"content":["Sam Bankman-Fried, the former CEO of the collapsed FTX crypto exchange, will depart the Bahamas on Wednesday evening to be extradited to the U.S., the Office of the Attorney General said in an emailed statement.&nbsp;","Bankman-Fried was <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/186393\/sam-bankman-fried-arrested-in-the-bahamas\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">arrested<\/a> on Dec. 12 and subsequently waved his right to challenge the extradition request from the U.S., where authorities have accused him of committing or conspiring to commit fraud on FTX's customers and lenders, money laundering and conspiracy to defraud the U.S. and violate campaign finance disclosure laws.","\"The Bahamas has determined that the provisional arrest, and subsequent written consent by SBF to be extradited without formal extradition proceedings satisfies the requirements of the Treaty and our nation’s Extradition Act.,\" Attorney General Sen. Ryan Pinder KC said in the statement.","","The Bahamas foreign minister signed the warrant of surrender for Bankman-Fried today, the ministry said in a separate statement.&nbsp;","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"evening","content":"TIME"},{"type":"Dec. 12","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Bahamas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Attorney General","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bahamas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ryan Pinder KC","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Nathan Crooks","The Block"]}