{"summary":"The US-based company, which specialises in building self-custody wallets, has also announced a new API.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/146031\/bitcoin-self-custody-company-casa-raises-21-million-in-series-a-launches-new-api","publishDate":"2022-05-10T10:16:49","id":5857,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin self-custody company Casa raises $21 million in Series A, launches new API","category":["WALLETS"],"content":["Bitcoin self-custody company Casa raised $21 million in its Series A round, the company announced today.","The round was led by Acrew Capital, with participation from previous investors Avon Ventures, Stillmark, Tioga Capital, Castle Island Ventures and Lerer Hippeau. New investors also joined the round, including Positive Sum Ventures, AngelList CEO Naval Ravikant and Adobe Chief Product Officer Scott Belsky.","The US-based company, which specializes in building self-custody wallets, has also announced a new&nbsp;Application Programming Interface (API), a tool that allows a piece of software to more easily communicate with the outside world. The API will enable businesses to integrate multisig wallets into their products and allow users to authenticate using their personal wallets for third-party services while still maintaining control of their keys.","The company said in a statement that this “unlocks a wide range of capabilities”. Among them are confirming financial information for things like loan approval, managing retirement investments, and automatically depositing Bitcoin into users’ Casa accounts.","“With the launch of the Casa API, we will be able to go the next step and give our customers even more visibility into the bitcoin they hold as part of their long-term financial plan,” Ryan Radloff, CEO at Choice, a bitcoin-focused retirement account service and Casa partner, said in the statement.","“We're excited to leverage the API to make the process seamless, from generating a new keyset to viewing your multi-sig wallet balance in real-time, from within your retirement account — this will be a bold leap forward for managing bitcoin as part of your long-term portfolio.”","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Acrew Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Adobe","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Castle Island Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"AngelList CEO Naval Ravikant","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$21 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Casa","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ryan Radloff","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Casa API","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Stillmark","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tioga Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Scott Belsky","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Avon Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Lerer Hippeau","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["SERIES A"],"authors":["Callan Quinn","The Block"]}