{"summary":"The firm&#x27;s valuation sits at less than $7 billion following a $14 billion valuation in March 2022, Bloomberg reported.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/263079\/blockchain-com-raises-110-million-in-series-e-funding","publishDate":"2023-11-14T16:10:49","id":5862,"type":null,"title":"Blockchain.com raises $110 million in Series E funding","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Crypto exchange Blockchain.com has secured a $110 million raise in Series E financing.","Kingsway Capital, an investment management firm based in the UK, led the new funding round, according to a company <a href=\"https:\/\/www.blockchain.com\/blog\/posts\/blockchaincom-announces-strategic-growth-series-e-round-led-by-kingsway-capital\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">release<\/a>. Additional participants include Baillie Gifford, Lakestar, Lightspeed Venture Partners, Coinbase Ventures and others.","Blockchain.com's valuation sits at \"less than half of\" $14 billion, Bloomberg <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2023-11-14\/crypto-exchange-blockchain-com-raises-110-million-at-fraction-of-prior-value#xj4y7vzkg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a> citing sources familiar with the matter. The firm <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/140070\/blockchain-com-raises-series-d-at-a-14-billion-valuation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reached<\/a> its $14 billion valuation in March of 2022 after an undisclosed amount raised in a Series D financing round.&nbsp;","Manny Stotz, Kingsway Capital founder and CEO, and Nicolas Brand, partner at Lakestar, have joined Blockchain.com's board of investors following the round.","Kingsway Capital had also led <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/177306\/blockchain-com-raises-fresh-capital-in-round-led-by-kingsway-capital-bloomberg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">another<\/a> undisclosed funding round for Blockchain.com that closed in the third quarter of last year, The Block previously reported in October of 2022.&nbsp;","Blockchain.com was left with a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/156585\/blockchain-com-stands-to-lose-270-million-on-three-arrows-capital-loans\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$270 million hole<\/a> after the 2021 <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/193649\/three-arrows-capital-co-founder-says-it-wasnt-luna-that-took-it-out-but-ftx\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">collapse<\/a> of the crypto lender Three Arrows Capital, which the company had lent funds to.","The firm <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/158920\/blockchain-com-cuts-a-quarter-of-staff-closes-argentina-offices-coindesk\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">laid off<\/a> 150, or 25%, of its staff, closed its Argentinian office and reduced CEO compensation in July 2022.&nbsp;","Blockchain.com did not immediately respond to The Block's request for comment.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Lakestar","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"October of 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Baillie Gifford","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"third quarter of last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Kingsway Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$14 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Manny Stotz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"25%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Lightspeed Venture Partners","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coinbase Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nicolas Brand","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$270 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"July 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"March of 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$110 million","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["SERIES C &AMP; BEYOND"],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}