{"summary":"Crypto prices have run into headwinds, stalling and then dipping after rallying over the weekend.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/220183\/bitcoin-crypto-prices-trade-lower-while-some-suggest-stocks-might-be-overvalued","publishDate":"2023-03-15T12:50:35","id":5872,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin, crypto prices trade lower, while some suggest stocks might be overvalued","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["Crypto prices slipped on Wednesday as banking worries persisted and some analysts suggested stocks could be overvalued.&nbsp;","Bitcoin was trading at around $24,400 by 12:30 p.m. EDT, down about 1.3% over the past few hours, according to TradingView data. Ether dipped about 2% to $1,650.&nbsp;","","","\"U.S. markets are beginning to price a higher probability of a Fed pause as sentiment deteriorates,\" the GSR analysts said, adding that \"lower-than-expected retail sales and PPI releases provide increased flexibility for the Fed to potentially pause at next week's FOMC.\"","The Fed will announce its latest interest rate decision a week from today, with the market now pricing in a near 58% probability of a pause.&nbsp;","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.cmegroup.com\/markets\/interest-rates\/cme-fedwatch-tool.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">FedWatch target rate probabilities<\/span><\/a>","FedWatch, the CME's tool, analyzes the probability of changes to the Fed rate using 30-Day Fed Funds futures pricing data, now shows a 57.9% probability of a pause — up from about 30% yesterday.&nbsp;","Charles Schwab's chief investment strategist, Liz Ann Sonders, <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/LizAnnSonders\/status\/1635945336882511873?s=20\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">says<\/a> the Rule of 20 suggests stocks might be overvalued.","<a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/LizAnnSonders\/status\/1635945336882511873\/photo\/1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">S&amp;P 500 P\/E + US CPI YoY<\/span><\/a>","The rule says if the S&amp;P 500 price-earnings ratio and CPI year-on-year equal 20, markets may be fairly valued.","The S&amp;P 500 P\/E is currently around 20.65, according to Multpl data, while year-on-year inflation came in at 6% in February — suggesting markets are overvalued.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"6%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"GSR","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fed","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$24,400","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"February","content":"DATE"},{"type":"1.3%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"S&amp;P","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1,650","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Liz Ann Sonders","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"30%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"PPI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Charles Schwab","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Day Fed","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"58%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FOMC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"57.9%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"12:30 p.m. EDT","content":"TIME"},{"type":"CME","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}