{"summary":"Part II of the Digital Asset Data and Infrastructure series will take place on Thursday, June 11, 12pm ET \/ 9am PT. Frank Chaparro will be joined by Blockset CTO Samuel Sutch and Unbound Director of Product Management Rebecca Aspler, who will be exploring Security and Scale for Enterprise Blockchain Solutions.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/67040\/digital-asset-data-and-infrastructure-webinar-part-ii","publishDate":"2020-06-01T16:40:12","id":5873,"type":null,"title":"Digital Asset Data and Infrastructure Webinar, Part II: Top 5 Security and Scalability Issues in the Digital Asset Sector","category":["WEBINAR"],"content":["Part II of the Digital Asset Data and Infrastructure series will take place on Thursday, June 11, 12pm ET \/ 9am PT.","This installation of the series <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">drills into the nuances of properly implementing highly secure and scalable solutions for building blockchain-based products. Guest speakers <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Samuel Sutch, CTO of <a href=\"https:\/\/blockset.com\/?utm_source=webinartheblock&amp;utm_campaign=webinarii&amp;utm_term=theblockwebinar&amp;utm_content=20200604-webinarii\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BRD<\/a><\/strong>, and <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Rebecca Aspler, Director of Product Management at <a href=\"https:\/\/www.unboundtech.com\/?utm_campaign=casp_for_custody&amp;utm_source=BRD_webinar_Apr_2020\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Unbound Tech<\/a><\/strong> will paint a clear picture of what security and scalability mean while providing real-world examples of customer anecdotes. The Block’s <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Frank Chaparro&nbsp;<\/strong>will be moderating conversation for the event.&nbsp;<\/span>","You can register for the webinar below:","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" title=\"The Block Presents: Digital Asset Data and Infrastructure Part II (Security) | The Block\" src=\"https:\/\/app.livestorm.co\/p\/a413eb3e-d643-4c67-a7d8-a468cb633d4a\/form\" width=\"100%\" height=\"360\" frameborder=\"0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About the Guests:<\/strong><\/span>","Samuel Sutch is the CTO of BRD and the creator of <a href=\"https:\/\/blockset.com\/?utm_source=webinartheblock&amp;utm_campaign=webinarii&amp;utm_term=theblockwebinar&amp;utm_content=20200604-webinarii\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"nofollow noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Blockset<\/a>. He is a serial entrepreneur who has exited two companies as a founder, Lightt, Inc. and Making Friends, Inc, and was the creator of Yammer’s early mobile experience. Samuel also has a vast history of bringing technology solutions at scale to enterprises like Intel and Google. Today, he is an advocate of distributed financial technology and is a key component in helping BRD enable both consumers and institutions to integrate with the digital asset ecosystem.","Leading the blockchain product line at <a href=\"https:\/\/www.unboundtech.com\/?utm_campaign=casp_for_custody&amp;utm_source=BRD_webinar_Apr_2020\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"nofollow noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Unbound Tech<\/a>, Rebecca is driving innovation all the way from prototyping, market-fit validation, roadmap planning to periodical features-prioritization and specification. Staying informed of the market landscape, Rebecca is also analyzing the digital assets and enterprise blockchain ecosystem, products and constantly evolving regulations. Prior to this role and specializing in product management for large scale cloud-based (SaaS) enterprise software applications, Rebecca has led product management groups and operations at companies such as SAP and Teoco, growing new products from inception point to profitable product lines; serving successfully various Fortune 1,000 companies","<a href=\"https:\/\/blockset.com\/?utm_source=webinartheblock&amp;utm_campaign=webinarii&amp;utm_term=theblockwebinar&amp;utm_content=20200604-webinarii\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Blockset by BRD<\/a> offers highly reliable blockchain infrastructure. With enterprise-grade uptime, massive scalability, and multi-chain data from a single source, Blockset is the only solution for institutions around the globe to deliver real-time, blockchain-based applications to millions of users. Using the services provided by Blockset, businesses can build professional custody solutions, auditing platforms, and much more with its multi-chain API and professional services. It is the industry-leading B2B solution that is propelling crypto adoption at scale.&nbsp;","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.unboundtech.com\/?utm_campaign=casp_for_custody&amp;utm_source=BRD_webinar_Apr_2020\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Unbound Tech<\/a> creates cryptographic and blockchain key management solutions designed for enterprise banks, institutional-grade custodians, and premier exchanges. Unbound’s blockchain and tokenized asset management platforms utilize the latest in cutting-edge multiparty computation (MPC) technology to provide greater interoperability, rigid and reliable security, and enhanced operational efficiency for its clients.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Lightt, Inc.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Samuel Sutch","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Rebecca Aspler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Digital Asset Data","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CTO of BRD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SAP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Intel","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Director of Product Management","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BRD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Unbound Tech","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Blockset","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"MPC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CTO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Inc","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"June 11","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Rebecca","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sponsored","The Block"]}