{"summary":"Ahead of its hotly anticipated IPO, Coinbase has hired an investor relations executive from Facebook to serve as its face to Wall Street.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/89553\/coinbase-facebook-investor-relations-ipo","publishDate":"2020-12-29T13:46:37","id":5895,"type":null,"title":"Coinbase nabs Facebook investor relations director ahead of IPO","category":["THE BLOCK"],"content":["Ahead of its hotly anticipated initial public offering, crypto exchange operator Coinbase has hired an investor relations executive from <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/16832\/facebook-is-on-the-look-out-for-a-lawyer-with-blockchain-experience\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Facebook<\/a> to serve as its face to Wall Street.","Anil Gupta, previously a director of investor relations at the social media giant, announced Monday on LinkedIn that he is joining the crypto exchange to \"lead their Investor Relations efforts.\"","\"Today is my last day at Facebook. The past 8+ years (that’s 33 earnings calls!) have been nothing short of spectacular. I have learned, grown, and accomplished more than I could have ever imagined,\" Gupta wrote in a LinkedIn status.","Gupta joined <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/16859\/report-facebook-stored-200-600-million-user-passwords-in-plain-text-for-years\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Facebook<\/a> in 2012 — the year the company had its own market debut. He previously held positions in equity research at Imperial Capital and Oppenheimer.","In his new role at Coinbase, Gupta will likely be tasked with engaging with the sell-side and shaping the way Coinbase is pitched as a public investment to big pension funds and asset managers. When Coinbase goes public, he will likely lead a team that works hand-in-hand with the CFO on presenting quarterly results.","The firm filed a confidential S1 ahead of its IPO and is expecting to tap the public markets in the first quarter of the new year. The firm has already enlisted Goldman Sachs as an investment banking adviser for its IPO.","After publication, Coinbase CFO Alesia Haas told The Block: “We are beyond delighted to have Anil join Coinbase and lead our IR efforts as we embark on the next stage of Coinbase’s journey.”","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Gupta","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"the first quarter","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2012","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Imperial Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Facebook","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Oppenheimer","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coinbase CFO Alesia Haas","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Anil Gupta","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Goldman Sachs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"S1","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["COINBASE"],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}