{"summary":"H.E. Justin Sun, Ambassador, Permanent Representative of Grenada to the WTO &amp; Founder of TRON, announced the launch of the APENFT Marketplace Mainnet on April 15th at 12:00 pm UTC during his Livestream.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/142391\/apenft-marketplace-launches-mainnet-the-first-nft-marketplace-on-tron","publishDate":"2022-04-19T09:00:48","id":5914,"type":null,"title":"APENFT Marketplace Launches Mainnet - The First NFT Marketplace on TRON","category":["SPONSORED"],"content":["<a href=\"https:\/\/www.hejustinsun.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">H.E. Justin Sun<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, Ambassador, Permanent Representative of Grenada to the WTO &amp; Founder of TRON, announced the launch of the <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/apenft.io\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">APENFT Marketplace<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Mainnet on April 15th at 12:00 pm UTC during his <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.youtube.com\/watch?v=evf_uHPDaeA&amp;t=1s\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Livestream<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. As the first official NFT marketplace on TRON, the launch marks a historic moment in the continued evolution of the <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/tron.network\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TRON<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> NFT ecosystem. The Marketplace features zero initial transaction fees &amp; minimal gas fees to encourage NFT artists and developers to launch on the platform.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">APENFT is an essential art foundation in the TRON ecosystem whose goal is to achieve a cross-field worldwide collection and provide a bridge for top traditional artists to make inroads into the NFT market. It’s backed by the TRON network's underlying technology with support from the world's most extensive distributed storage system, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.bittorrent.com\/token\/bittorrent-file-system\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BitTorrent File System (BTFS)<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, to provide secure, reliable, efficient, and decentralized services to NFT art lovers across the globe. Like how blockchain democratizes finance, APENFT turns prominent art pieces into NFTs. It upgrades the way artworks are hosted and transforms them from elite-exclusive items to something that truly belongs to the people. APENFT believes in art for everyone.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In partnership with APENFT, Sun has listed the Monkey Head NFT from the \"Twelve Digital Zodiac Heads\" collection as the first NFT collectible for sale following the Mainnet launch. Sun purchased the complete set of “Twelve Digital Zodiac Heads,” the one-of-a-kind NFT art collection, on March 31 for over $1.5 million at the Special Auction hosted by Metapoly XM, under Poly Auction (Xiamen).<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">APENFT plans to set the starting price at 666 WTRX. The highest bidder will take home the valuable Monkey Head NFT.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">During the auction, APENFT Marketplace will also reward the top three highest bidders each day with a Regular Genesis NFT. In addition, bidders stand a chance to receive extra bonuses offered by APENFT Marketplace. The highest bidder will be awarded a Legendary Genesis NFT; the second-highest bidder will receive an exclusive Monkey Head-themed Epic Genesis NFT; the third-highest bidder will earn a WIN NFT HORSE NFT-themed Zodiac Animal Head.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Monkey Head NFT has significant symbolic value in Chinese culture, as monkeys represent intelligence and rebellion. The combination of the Monkey Head NFT and APENFT Marketplace marks the debut of ancient artworks in the decentralized world.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In addition, Sun has also donated several well-known artworks, including Le Nez by Giacometti and Femme nue couchée au collier (Marie-Thérèse) by Pablo Picasso, to organizations such as the APENFT Foundation to support the development of NFT art.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">APENFT Marketplace's mechanism better represents inclusiveness and equality, which are the future trends of Web 3.0. In addition, APENFT Marketplace attracts NFT projects of trending topics in the market, allowing users to get in on the act from day one. Finally, by reducing handling fees in the initial stage and offering creators more flexibility to allocate their royalties, APENFT Marketplace lowers the cost for general users to enter the NFT market. <\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"BitTorrent","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Marie","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$1.5 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"TRON<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"April 15th","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Regular Genesis NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Metapoly XM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"APENFT Marketplace","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Giacometti","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Pablo Picasso","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"March 31","content":"DATE"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Grenada","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Legendary Genesis NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Poly Auction (Xiamen)","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"WTO &amp; Founder of TRON","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Monkey Head NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Twelve Digital Zodiac Heads","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"H.E. Justin Sun","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sponsored","The Block"]}