{"summary":"In the “Treehouse of Horror XXXIV” episode titled “Wild Bart Can’t Be Token,” which aired on Sunday in the U.S., Bart was accidentally “digitized” into an NFT.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/261606\/nfts-get-the-simpsons-treatment-in-latest-episode","publishDate":"2023-11-06T01:49:22","id":5918,"type":null,"title":"NFTs get the Simpsons treatment in latest episode","category":["METAVERSE & NFT"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Blockchain and <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/learn\/251483\/what-is-a-nft-and-why-do-they-have-value\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">non-fungible tokens<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> (NFTs) took center stage in the latest episode of The Simpsons, as the show writers took another stab at parodying the crypto space <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/56762\/the-simpsons-latest-episode-explains-blockchain-and-crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">following a 2020 episode<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In the “Treehouse of Horror XXXIV” episode titled “Wild Barts Can’t Be Token” that aired on Sunday in the U.S., Bart was accidentally “digitized” into an NFT with Marge embarking on an adventure in a blockchain-powered realm to save him.<\/span>","Simpsons just made a crypto &amp; NFT episode <a href=\"https:\/\/t.co\/pgsKgu3KB7\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">pic.twitter.com\/pgsKgu3KB7<\/a>","<script async=\"async\" src=\"https:\/\/platform.twitter.com\/widgets.js\" charset=\"utf-8\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/script>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The special episode featured references to many iconic NFTs and artists, including the Bored Ape Yacht Club and Beeple. The show also poked fun at the speculative nature of certain NFTs, with Homer initially devastated by Bart's digitization but later ecstatic over the $1.5 million value of the Bart NFT.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The floor price of BAYC edged up 1.59% over the past 24 hours, according to <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/nftpricefloor.com\/bored-ape-yacht-club\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">data<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> from NFT Price Floor, but it remains a long way off peak prices. The Mutant Ape Yacht Club’s floor price rose 1.83%.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In 2020, the Simpsons <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/56762\/the-simpsons-latest-episode-explains-blockchain-and-crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">explained<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in the episode <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.justwatch.com\/us\/tv-show\/the-simpsons\/season-31\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Frinkcoin\" (S31, E13)<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> how blockchain and cryptocurrencies work. In the episode, Professor Frink introduces cryptocurrency to Lisa Simpson via \"TV's most beloved scientist, Mr. Jim Parsons\" — who played Sheldon Cooper in The Big Bang Theory.<\/span>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/nft-non-fungible-tokens\/art-collectibles\/floor-price-of-art-and-collectibles-nfts\/embed\" title=\"Floor Price of Popular NFTs\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Sunday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$1.5 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sheldon Cooper","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"NFT Price Floor","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bored Ape Yacht Club","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jim Parsons","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Mutant Ape Yacht Club","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"crypto &amp; NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frink","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Lisa Simpson","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Marge","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bart NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1.59%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Bart","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"1.83%","content":"PERCENT"}],"hashtag":["BAYC"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}