{"summary":"Former FTX CEO SBF reportedly wanted to acquire the parent company of Snapchat, former Alameda Research CEO Caroline Ellison said.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/256017\/caroline-ellison-tells-court-that-sam-bankman-fried-wanted-to-buy-snapchat-reports","publishDate":"2023-10-11T13:28:44","id":599,"type":null,"title":"Caroline Ellison tells court that Sam Bankman-Fried wanted to buy Snapchat: reports","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried reportedly wanted to acquire the parent company of Snapchat, former Alameda Research CEO Caroline Ellison told the court on Wednesday.&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ellison kept a list of “things Sam is freaking out about,” which she regularly updated, including “buying SNAP,” the parent company of Snapchat, according to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.cnn.com\/2023\/10\/11\/business\/sbf-fraud-trial-witnesses\/index.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CNN<\/span><\/a>. Also on that list was “raising funds from MBS,” from the Saudi Arabia crown prince Mohammed bin Salman and “to trade Japanese government bonds,” according to <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/innercitypress\/status\/1712100664841539775\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Inner City Press<\/span><\/a>.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ellison also added to the list “getting regulators to crack down on binance,” according to those reports. Bankman-Fried and Binance CEO Changpeng Zhao had a long public rivalry, with Binance <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/227557\/sbf-rumors-cz-binance-ftx-patrick-hillman-tweet\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">accusing<\/span><\/a> the former FTX CEO of spreading rumors ahead of FTX’s collapse.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ellison is on her second day of testifying in front of a New York district court against Bankman-Fried. Earlier in the day, she said Bankman-Fried told her to come up with different ways to hide <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/255938\/caroline-ellison-prepared-7-different-balance-sheets-to-present-to-genesis-months-before-bankruptcy-inner-city-press\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">billions<\/span><\/a> in loans to Alameda Research’s balance sheets, according to reporting from Inner City Press.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ellison described what she and Bankman-Fried did before meeting with Matt Ballensweig, co-head of trading and lending at the crypto lender Genesis, who had asked for updated information on Alameda's balance sheet.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"He told me to come up with alternative ways to present the information. He wanted me to conceal things on our balance sheet. So I prepared seven different balance sheets. I did not want to be dishonest but I presented the alternatives to Sam and let him decide,\" Ellison said.&nbsp;<\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Saudi Arabia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ellison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Inner City Press","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Caroline Ellison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"CNN","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Changpeng Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sam","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Matt Ballensweig","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["FTX","SBF TRIAL"],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}