{"summary":"The tool helps improve the visibility of intellectual property for NFT projects — a long running issue in the space. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/181859\/new-protocol-aims-to-improve-on-chain-nft-intellectual-property-rights","publishDate":"2022-11-02T03:30:21","id":6014,"type":null,"title":"New V-Art Protocol improves on-chain NFT intellectual property rights ","category":["NFTS"],"content":["V-Art's new tool, called the V-Art Protocol, is aimed to help protect IP rights and improve NFT project licensing and will go live on Nov. 2, the blockchain-based digital content monetization platform said.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Projects can verify, protect and manage their IP rights on <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/179605\/near-foundation-spends-40-million-to-replace-usn-stablecoins-collateral-gap\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">NEAR<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> and <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/181349\/vitalik-buterin-shares-the-kind-of-defi-regulation-he-would-like-to-see\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ethereum<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> blockchains, and V-Art aims to add Aurora and Polygon this year and Solana next year, V-Art CEO Anastasiia Gliebova told The Block at the web3 Summit in Lisbon. The firm raised $1.4 million in seed funding thus far.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">NFT IP rights, particularly when it touches upon copyright, have led to skirmishes between NFT project leaders and holders in the past. Case in point was CryptoPunks created by Larva Labs. The NFT project did not have any public guidelines for IP or copyright for years — until users attempted to monetize their NFT, then LarvaLabs sought legal action against such holders.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Partly stemming from unclear NFT IP rights came projects who eschewed copyright altogether such as Nouns, The Block previously <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/news+\/142696\/how-a-disillusioned-former-cryptopunk-owner-is-trying-to-change-the-nft-copyright-game\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.&nbsp;<\/span>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">With additional reporting by Lucy Harley-McKeown<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Aurora","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lucy Harley","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Anastasiia Gliebova","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Nov. 2","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Larva Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"McKeown","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$1.4 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Lisbon","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}