{"summary":"Deribit, the leading crypto options exchange, said that it does not have any &quot;large and risky&quot; positions with Alameda Research or assets on FTX.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/184714\/crypto-options-exchange-deribit-says-it-is-unaffected-by-ftx-and-alameda-collapse","publishDate":"2022-11-09T07:56:30","id":606,"type":null,"title":"Crypto options exchange Deribit says it is unaffected by FTX and Alameda collapse","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["Deribit, the leading crypto options exchange, said it does not have any \"large and risky\" positions with Alameda Research, the sister firm of embattled crypto exchange FTX.","The crypto exchange also noted that it neither has assets with FTX — which has frozen withdrawals and may be <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/184423\/ftxs-bankman-fried-gets-binance-bailout-in-stunning-reversal-of-fortune\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">acquired<\/a> by Binance — nor exposure to its exchange token, FTT, or Solana's SOL, which is closely linked with FTX and Alameda Research.","\"Deribit does not have any special terms for Alameda or large &amp; risky positions,\" it <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/DeribitExchange\/status\/1590315930588184578\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweeted<\/a>, adding: \"Nor do we rely on their liquidity provision in any of our products. Furthermore Deribit or group companies do not have assets with FTX or other exposure to e.g. FTT or SOL.\"&nbsp;Both FTX's FTT token and Solana's coin are <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/184619\/solana-ftt-and-serum-prices-plummet-on-back-of-ftx-collapse\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">down<\/a> 72% and 30%, respectively, notably worse than the rest of the crypto market.","Furthermore, Deribit also <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/DeribitExchange\/status\/1590316691426316293\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reiterated<\/a> that it does not have a trading desk or group company that clears markets or trades on its behalf.","Deribit also promised to publish a Merkle Tree proof-of-reserve for its reserve assets — something other crypto exchanges have also promised to do.","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"crypto exchange FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"72%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Deribit","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"30%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE","FTX"],"authors":["Adam James","The Block"]}