{"summary":"The Luna Foundation Guard now holds $3 billion worth of bitcoin as reserve backing for the TerraUsD (UST) stablecoin.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/145289\/luna-foundation-guard-buys-additional-1-5-billion-in-bitcoin-backing-for-ust","publishDate":"2022-05-05T13:12:36","id":6065,"type":null,"title":"Luna Foundation Guard buys additional $1.5 billion in bitcoin backing for UST","category":["BITCOIN"],"content":["The Luna Foundation Guard (LFG), a nonprofit created to support the Terra ecosystem, <a href=\"https:\/\/mobile.twitter.com\/LFG_org\/status\/1522234947070689280\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/a> the purchase of $1.5 billion worth of bitcoin (BTC) for its stablecoin reserves on Thursday.","According to its announcement, LFG bought 37,863 BTC ($1.5 billion) via over-the-counter swaps with Genesis Trading and Three Arrows Capital. Of the $1.5 billion, $1 billion was an OTC swap with Genesis while the other $500 million was acquired from Three Arrows Capital.","Thursday's announcement means that LFG’s bitcoin reserves have grown to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/138892\/do-kwon-reveals-plan-to-increase-usts-bitcoin-reserve-to-3-billion\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$3.5 billion<\/a>, 30% of the way to the stated goal of $10 billion. The purchase also saw LFG’s wallet become the seventh-largest single BTC holder, according to <a href=\"https:\/\/bitinfocharts.com\/top-100-richest-bitcoin-addresses.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">data<\/a> from BitInfoChart’s “Bitcoin Rich List.”","As previously reported by The Block, these bitcoin acquisitions are part of efforts by the LFG to build up reserves for the TerraUSD (UST) stablecoin. Terraform Labs CEO Do Kwon has contributed funds to enable the organization to proceed with its bulk BTC purchases.","Apart from bitcoin, the LFG has also bought <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/141136\/luna-foundation-guard-buys-100-million-in-avax-tokens-for-stablecoin-reserve\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$100 million in avalanche (AVAX) tokens<\/a> for its stablecoin reserves.","The LFG’s play is part of an <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/news+\/144858\/very-stable-geniuses-the-race-to-build-regulation-proof-stablecoins\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">emerging trend<\/a> of algorithmic stablecoins acquiring crypto assets as part of their collateral reserve. <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/142867\/justin-sun-to-launch-algorithmic-stablecoin-usdd-on-tron-will-use-10-billion-of-crypto-as-collateral\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Tron’s USDD stablecoin<\/a> is also about to launch with plans for a collateral reserve that may go as high as $10 billion.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Luna Foundation Guard","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$1 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$100 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kwon","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"LFG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$10 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$1.5 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"30%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"AVAX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Genesis Trading and Three Arrows Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$500 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Three Arrows Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$3.5 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"UST","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN","DO KWON"],"authors":["Osato Avan-Nomayo","The Block"]}