{"summary":"CCP Games raised $40 million in a seed round led by a16z. The company is building a new game set in the Eve Universe using blockchain technology. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/221574\/a16z-blockchain-game-eve","publishDate":"2023-03-21T11:40:11","id":6105,"type":null,"title":"A16z leads $40 million round for blockchain game set in Eve universe","category":["GAMING"],"content":["Iceland-based CCP Games raised $40 million to build a new blockchain-based game set in the Eve Universe.","The seed round was led by a16z, with other participants including Makers Fund, Bitkraft, Kingsway Capital, Hashed and Nexon, the company <a href=\"https:\/\/www.ccpgames.com\/news\/2023\/ccp-games-has-secured-usd40m-led-by-andreessen-horowitz-for-an-innovative\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a> in a press release.","\"Years before the first blockchain was created, the sci-fi space MMO EVE Online proved out many of the core principles that define web3 today,\" a16z said in a blog post.","While the AAA title will use smart-contract technology, its production will be separate from any of CCP's projects, including the original Eve Online, the company said.","The popular game is a virtual world where players interact in a digital economy and build their corporations.","\"Since its inception, CCP Games’ vision has been to create virtual worlds more meaningful than real life,\" said CCP Games CEO Hilmar Veigar Pétursson.\"Now, with advancements made within blockchain, we can forge a new universe deeply imbued with our expertise in player agency and autonomy, empowering players to engage in new ways.\"","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Eve Universe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bitkraft","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Hilmar Veigar Pétursson","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Iceland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$40 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"AAA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CCP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nexon","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kingsway Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["SEED &AMP; PRE-SEED"],"authors":["Catarina Moura","The Block"]}