{"summary":"Bitcoin enthusiasts, tech innovators, and industry leaders from around the world will come together to discuss the latest advancements in the Bitcoin industry at the Bitcoin 2023 Conference. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/230352\/bitcoin-2023-conference-to-host-political-leaders-from-around-the-world","publishDate":"2023-05-11T09:00:52","id":6106,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin 2023 Conference to Host Political Leaders from Around the World","category":["SPONSORED"],"content":["Bitcoin enthusiasts, tech innovators, and industry leaders from around the world will come together to discuss the latest advancements in the Bitcoin industry at the Bitcoin 2023 Conference.&nbsp;","\"Bringing political speakers to the Bitcoin 2023 conference is not just about highlighting the increasing acceptance of Bitcoin in the political sphere, but also about providing a platform for diverse perspectives and ideas. We believe that by engaging with politicians who are open to the idea of Bitcoin, and furthering their understanding of Bitcoin at the conference, we can create champions for the industry in Washington and beyond.\"","Brandon Green, Director of Events at BTC Media","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About The Bitcoin Conference<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong>Since 2012 Bitcoin Magazine has been the most trusted source of news, information, and expert commentary on Bitcoin. Providing analysis, research, education, and thought leadership at the intersection of finance, technology, and culture. They are also the organizer of the cryptocurrency industry's largest annual event –&nbsp;<a title=\"\" href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/TheBitcoinConf?s=20&amp;t=p_2Vl-T3CYHriYubpIXnPg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Bitcoin Conference<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nThis annual global Bitcoin Conference has grown tremendously since it began in San Francisco in 2019. April 2022 in Miami the team hosted over 26,000 attendees and 400+ companies and went global in October of 2022 with&nbsp;<a title=\"\" href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/BitcoinConfEUR?s=20&amp;t=p_2Vl-T3CYHriYubpIXnPg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitcoin Amsterdam&nbsp;<\/a>– the largest European bitcoin conference. This years events have been scheduled&nbsp;<a title=\"\" href=\"http:\/\/b.tc\/conference\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitcoin 2023<\/a>&nbsp;on May 18-20 2023 in Miami and Bitcoin Amsterdam on October 12-13 2023.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This post is commissioned by The Bitcoin Conference<\/i><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;and does not serve as a testimonial or endorsement by The Block. This post is for informational purposes only and should not be relied upon as a basis for investment, tax, legal or other advice. You should conduct your own research and consult independent counsel and advisors on the matters discussed within this post. Past performance of any asset is not indicative of future results.<\/i><\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"San Francisco","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"20 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"BTC Media","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"October of 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"May 18","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Washington","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"April 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Miami","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bitcoin 2023 Conference","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitcoin Conference<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong>Since 2012 Bitcoin Magazine","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Brandon Green","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"October 12","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bitcoin Amsterdam&nbsp;<\/a>–","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitcoin Amsterdam","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bitcoin Conference","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Bitcoin Conference","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"13 2023","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sponsored","The Block"]}