{"summary":"Elon Musk said Sam Bankman-Fried owns no private shares of Twitter, refuting a report from SBF-owned news organization, Semafor.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/189627\/elon-musk-criticizes-semafor-report-of-bankman-frieds-twitter-shares","publishDate":"2022-11-23T16:20:22","id":6126,"type":null,"title":"Elon Musk criticizes Semafor report of Bankman-Fried’s Twitter shares","category":["PEOPLE"],"content":["Elon Musk criticized a Semafor report on former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried’s ownership of private shares of Twitter, calling the article a lie.","Bankman-Fried invested in Semafor, which Musk said represents a conflict of interest in terms of unbiased coverage.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A spat between Elon Musk and a Sam Bankman-Fried-funded global news organization unfolded over Twitter as Musk branded Semafor’s reporting as lies.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“As I said, neither I nor Twitter have taken any investment from SBF\/FTX. Your article is a lie,” Musk said, in response to Semafor Editor-in-Chief Ben Smith in a <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/elonmusk\/status\/1595342985931411456?s=20&amp;t=smicyCkvkY-0TWVQz9Yt0A\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Twitter thread<\/a>.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Prompting the criticism from Musk is a Semafor <a href=\"https:\/\/www.semafor.com\/article\/11\/22\/2022\/sam-bankman-fried-elon-and-a-secret-text\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">report<\/a> that said Bankman-Fried “contributed $100 million in stock towards the now-private Twitter,” citing previously unreported texts between the two.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Musk openly criticized Semafor over the coverage and said Semafor is owned by Bankman-Fried, which he called “a massive conflict of interest.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Prior to Musk’s $44 billion <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/180725\/musk-at-last-takes-over-twitter-reports\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">purchase<\/a> of the social media giant, texts between Musk and Bankman-Fried on May 5 revealed what might have been a joint investment, according to Semafor, with Bankman-Fried potentially rolling a previously acquired $100 million stake of the company into Musk’s buyout.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Despite that, the deal was <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/180780\/sam-bankman-fried-set-to-make-up-to-100-million-from-musk-twitter-purchase\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">not to be<\/span><\/a>,<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> as Bankman-Fried ultimately decided not to participate in the Twitter acquisition, a source with knowledge previously told The Block.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Musk refuted any claims that Bankman-Fried owns shares in Twitter. “<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">No. He may have owned shares in Twitter as a public company, but he certainly does not own shares in Twitter as a private company,” Musk said.<\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"May 5","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$100 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Semafor","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Twitter","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"SBF\/FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Elon Musk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$44 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Musk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ben Smith","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["ELON MUSK","PRIVATE COMPANY M&AMP;A","SAM BANKMAN-FRIED"],"authors":["Jeremy Nation","The Block"]}