{"summary":"Managers behind three crypto ETFs in Australia plan to delist the products.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/182247\/australian-crypto-etfs-to-be-delisted","publishDate":"2022-11-02T13:07:04","id":6135,"type":null,"title":"Australian crypto ETFs to be delisted","category":["CAPITAL MARKETS"],"content":["Cosmos Asset Management plans to delist the Cosmos Purpose Bitcoin Access ETF (CBTC) and Cosmos Purpose Ethereum Access ETF (CPET) funds, according to a Nov. 2 letter posted to the securities and derivatives exchange Cboe Australia. In a separate letter, One Managed Investment Funds Limited also <a href=\"https:\/\/www.cboe.com.au\/disclosures\/DIG021122001.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">informed<\/a> the Cboe that it will request to revoke the quotation for the Cosmos Global Digital Miners Access ETF.","The three Cosmos funds soon to be delisted each have net asset values under A$1 million.&nbsp;","Cosmos had <a href=\"https:\/\/www.cboe.com.au\/disclosures\/CBT311022001.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filed a letter<\/a> with the Cboe on Oct. 31 requesting that trading related to the CBTC and CPET ETFs be halted. One Managed Investment Funds Limited also requested a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.cboe.com.au\/disclosures\/DIG311022001.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">trading halt<\/a> on the Cosmos Global Digital Miners Access ETF (DIGA) in a separate letter.","Spot crypto ETFs are relatively new in Australia, where the first of these products <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/146958\/australias-first-bitcoin-and-ethereum-etfs-launched-by-cboe-australia-and-etf-securities\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">launched<\/a> in May just around the time crypto asset prices started sliding.. The Cosmos Purpose Bitcoin Access ETF was one of the first to launch on Cboe Australia, along with bitcoin and ethereum ETFs from Zurich-based 21Shares. Cosmos' Purpose Ethereum Access ETF <a href=\"https:\/\/www.ft.com\/content\/b534fb11-a716-49e3-835d-5d9e81f57fb7\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">launched<\/a> in June.","The DIGA ETF first <a href=\"https:\/\/www.financialstandard.com.au\/news\/crypto-mining-etf-launches-179790273?q=%22Cosmos%20Global%20Digital%20Miners%22\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">launched<\/a> in Oct. 2021 when Cboe Australia was known as Chi-X.","Cosmos' intent to delist the funds was first reported by Bloomberg.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Cosmos Global Digital Miners Access ETF (DIGA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"A$1 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Chi","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Cosmos Asset Management","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cosmos Global Digital Miners Access ETF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cosmos Purpose Bitcoin Access ETF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Oct. 31","content":"DATE"},{"type":"X.","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Australia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Cboe","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Zurich","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"June","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Purpose Ethereum Access ETF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nov. 2","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Oct. 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Cboe Australia","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["COSMOS"],"authors":["Kristin Majcher","The Block"]}