{"summary":"The Financial Stability Board (FSB), which coordinates rules for the Group of 20 (G20) economies, has issued recommendations for regulating “global stablecoins” such as the Facebook-led Libra project.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/61743\/g20-watchdog-issues-recommendations-for-regulating-global-stablecoins","publishDate":"2020-04-14T06:40:44","id":6137,"type":null,"title":"G20 watchdog issues recommendations for regulating ‘global stablecoins’","category":["STABLECOINS"],"content":["The Financial Stability Board (FSB), which coordinates rules for the Group of 20 (G20) economies, has issued recommendations for regulating “global stablecoins” such as the Facebook-led Libra project.","The ten “high-level” recommendations, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.fsb.org\/wp-content\/uploads\/P140420-1.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">published<\/a> Tuesday in a 67-page report, seek to promote “consistent” and “effective” regulation of global stablecoins.","“The recommendations aim to mitigate the potential risks with the use of GSCs [global stablecoins] as means of payment and\/or store of value, both at the domestic and international level, while supporting responsible innovation and providing sufficient flexibility for jurisdictions to implement domestic approaches,” said the FSB.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n​​​​​​​​​​​​The <a href=\"https:\/\/g20.org\/en\/about\/Pages\/Participants.aspx\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">G20 members<\/a> are Argentina, Australia, Brazil, Canada, China, France, Germany, India, Indonesia, Italy, Japan, Mexico, ​South Korea​,​ Russia, Saudi Arabia, South Africa, ​​​Turkey, the U.K., the U.S. and the European Union (EU)​.","The FSB said it aims to bring in regulations that are “proportionate to the risks” posed by global stablecoins - but also taking into consideration how those risks may change over time.","The recommendations apply the principle of “same business – same risks – same rules,” independent of the underlying technology of stablecoins.","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ten “high-level” recommendations<\/strong>","The recommendations follow on from calls by the G20 in <a href=\"https:\/\/www.fsb.org\/2019\/06\/progress-in-implementation-of-g20-financial-regulatory-reforms\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">June 2019<\/a> for the FSB to address regulatory issues. <br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nThe FSB’s recommendations are open for public feedback until July 15. The final recommendations, factoring in feedback, will be published in October 2020.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Saudi Arabia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Canada","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"South Korea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Turkey","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"France","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Indonesia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"South Africa","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.K.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"October 2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Argentina","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FSB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Australia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Germany","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Financial Stability Board (FSB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Russia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Italy","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"June 2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"G20","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July 15","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Brazil","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Mexico","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"European Union (EU","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Japan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"India","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"the Group of 20 (G20","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"China","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Yogita Khatri","The Block"]}