{"summary":"Republican Rep. Kevin Hern donated a $5,000 contribution from an FTX executive after the company filed for bankruptcy protection.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/186918\/gop-lawmaker-donates-ftx-execs-campaign-contribution","publishDate":"2022-11-14T17:25:27","id":6143,"type":null,"title":"GOP lawmaker donates FTX exec’s campaign contribution ","category":["POLICY"],"content":["Rep. Kevin Hern, R-Okla., donated a $5,000 campaign contribution from an FTX executive after the company filed for bankruptcy protection.&nbsp;","Hern is the second lawmaker to distance himself from FTX after Rep. Jesus “Chuy” Garcia, D-Ill.","Rep. Kevin Hern, R-Okla., is the latest member of Congress to donate political funds he received from an FTX executive, distancing himself after the troubled crypto exchange filed for bankruptcy protection.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","FTX Digital Markets Co-CEO Ryan Salame gave $5,000 to Hern Victory Fund, a joint fundraising committee with ties to Hern’s campaign, the Help Elect Republicans Now leadership PAC and the National Republican Congressional Committee.","“Rep. Hern has donated the money from FTX,” Hern’s campaign said. The $5,000 donation will go to Food On The Move, a charity in Oklahoma.&nbsp;","FTX filed for bankruptcy protection last week after a run on its utility token. The firm was once valued at $32 billion.","Salame was a major political donor during the 2022 midterm cycle. He spent millions to support more than a dozen Republicans with his American Dream Federal Action super PAC. Salame also gave individual contributions to many lawmakers and candidates.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","Hern is the second lawmaker to distance himself from FTX executives. Rep. Jesus “Chuy” Garcia, D-Ill., <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/184820\/sam-bankman-fried-goes-from-toast-of-washington-to-political-pariah\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">donated<\/a> a $2,900 contribution from former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried to a Chicago charity last week.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$32 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$5,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Ryan Salame","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ill","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Congress","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"American Dream Federal Action super PAC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Okla.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ill.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hern Victory Fund","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"National Republican Congressional Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kevin Hern","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jesus “Chuy” Garcia","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"last week","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Hern","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$2,900","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Chicago","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Oklahoma","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Stephanie Murray","The Block"]}