{"summary":"Gap is collaborating with Brandon Sines, the artist behind Frank Ape to launch their first collectible NFT experience. Gap launches first collectible NFT experience.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/130087\/clothing-retailer-gap-launches-nft-collection-on-tezos","publishDate":"2022-01-12T11:28:12","id":6158,"type":null,"title":"Clothing retailer Gap launches NFT collection on Tezos","category":["NFTS"],"content":["Fashion brand Gap has released its first collection of NFTs in collaboration with Brandon Sines, the artist behind <a href=\"https:\/\/frankape.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Frank Ape<\/a>.","Through the gamified digital experience, customers can unlock the opportunity to buy digital art by Sines and a limited edition, physical Gap hoodie.","“Gap has always been at the intersection of music, art and culture, so we are excited about this growth opportunity in the digital space with artists like Brandon Sines,” said Chris Goble, chief product<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nofficer and general manager of Gap North America, in a statement.","The NFT collection was deployed on the proof-of-stake Tezos blockchain, which has recently been involved in collections from other consumer-facing brands, including <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/126668\/gaming-giant-ubisoft-is-testing-in-game-nfts-through-a-new-platform\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ubisoft<\/a>, Pantone, and Red Bull. Gap’s collectible experience is built in partnership with InterPop, a production studio that uses Tezos.","The collection will feature four levels, available on a first-come, first-serve basis with limited editions at the Rare and Epic levels. Additional digital experiences are planned for the future.","With this new project, the company said it hopes to obtain insights into how customers want to engage in a digital world.","\"As part of our mission to create enduring customer relationships, our teams are constantly innovating,” John Strain, Gap's chief digital and technology officer, said in a statement. “We are excited about the possibilities that a more planet-friendly blockchain technology can unlock for us and all the new ways it will enable us to connect with our customers.”&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chris Goble","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ubisoft","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Brandon Sines","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gap North America","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"John Strain","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sines","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Frank Ape","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Pantone","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Anushree Dave","The Block"]}