{"summary":"The bitcoin mining firm intends to raise $80 million for its first-phase mining construction project in Bhutan, Wu Blockchain reported.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/241891\/jihan-wus-bitdeer-launches-fund-to-mine-bitcoin-in-bhutan-report","publishDate":"2023-07-28T11:56:21","id":6225,"type":null,"title":"Jihan Wu’s Bitdeer launches fund to mine bitcoin in Bhutan: report","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Singapore-headquartered bitcoin mining firm Bitdeer Technologies founded by Jihan Wu has launched a closed-end fund dedicated to mining bitcoin in Bhutan, as the company steps up operations in the South Asian nation, crypto news outlet Wu Blockchain <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/WuBlockchain\/status\/1684861352521990144\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Friday.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitdeer has started to raise capital for the Bitdeer Green Bitcoin Fund, which aims to gain returns from bitcoin mining operations in Bhutan. With a duration of six years, the fund plans to raise $80 million for its first-phase construction project with a minimum investment threshold of $5 million from investors, according to the report.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">With the fund, Bitdeer targets to build mining projects in Bhutan with total hashrate amounting to nearly 20 EH\/s.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitdeer confirmed the report when contacted by The Block for comment.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitdeer, a spinoff from Chinese mining rig maker Bitmain cofounded by Jihan Wu, has been expanding its presence in the Himalayan kingdom.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In May, Bitdeer announced a partnership with Bhutan’s state-owned investment company Druk Holding and Investments to <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/229192\/bhutan-bitcoin-mining-fund-bitdeer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">raise up to $500 million<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> for a crypto mining fund.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We are excited to be working alongside DHI in accessing Bhutan’s zero-emissions power to sustainably enable the blockchain technologies that will eventually form an immutable bedrock for a global store of value,” Jihan Wu, chairman of Bitdeer, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.globenewswire.com\/news-release\/2023\/05\/03\/2659973\/0\/en\/Bitdeer-and-Druk-Holding-Investments-to-Jointly-Develop-Green-Digital-Asset-Mining-Operations-in-the-Kingdom-of-Bhutan.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> at the time.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitdeer <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/app.quotemedia.com\/data\/downloadFiling?webmasterId=90423&amp;ref=317400428&amp;type=HTML&amp;symbol=BSGAU&amp;cdn=6944e8b91081b876f64f2ffa790ece8a&amp;companyName=Blue+Safari+Group+Acquisition+Corp.+Unit&amp;formType=425&amp;formDescription=Prospectuses+and+communications%2C+business+combinations&amp;dateFiled=2023-04-11\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">went public<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on Nasdaq in April via a special purpose acquisition company merger, with a valuation of US$1.18 billion. Its stock price climbed 1.96% in after-hours trading on Thursday.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$80 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"US$1.18 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Jihan Wu","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitmain","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Druk Holding and Investments","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Himalayan kingdom","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$500 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Bitdeer Technologies","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bhutan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"1.96%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Jihan Wu","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bitdeer","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Wu Blockchain","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$5 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Nasdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}