{"summary":"Decentralized derivatives exchange MCDEX is now live on Arbitrum Rollup, the Ethereum layer-2 scaling solution, and will go public after testing for a couple of weeks. MCDEX is the first fully permissionless decentralised perpetual swap which is live on mainnet where anyone can create any perpetual market. Decentralized derivatives exchange MCDEX is now live on Arbitrum Rollup, the Ethereum layer-2 scaling solution, and will go public after testing for a couple of weeks. MCDEX is the first fully permissionless decentralised perpetual swap which is live on mainnet where anyone can create any perpetual market.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/106161\/mcdex-mcb-goes-live-on-arbitrum","publishDate":"2021-06-03T09:23:31","id":6248,"type":null,"title":"MCDEX (MCB) Goes Live on Arbitrum","category":["SPONSORED"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Decentralized derivatives exchange MCDEX is now live on Arbitrum Rollup, the Ethereum layer-2 scaling solution, and will go public after testing for a couple of weeks. MCDEX is the first fully permissionless decentralised perpetual swap which is live on mainnet where anyone can create any perpetual market. Permissionless is the key feature of this protocol, which can empower the whole community to contribute to the MCDEX ecosystem — anyone can create any perpetual market of on-chain or off-chain synthetic assets. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">MCDEX V3 has an automated market maker (AMM) with 1000 times higher efficiency than that of the AMM that relies on the constant product formula. Built on Arbitrum, MCDEX V3 has the following key features: <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Though Arbitrum mainnet is only open to developers on 28 May, MCDEX has been testing on the Arbitrum testnet since <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">February<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. So far, the feedback from users has been positive and one common feedback is that the platform runs “fast and smooth”.<\/span>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“The ground-breaking features of MCDEX V3 help to solve the pain points for traders on Ethereum layer 1. We believe that this will elevate user trading experience on DEXes after deploying on Arbitrum.” – MCDEX&nbsp;<\/span><\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“MCDEX V3’s advanced and innovative design is going to be game-changing for perpetual swaps, and Arbitrum’s low cost and fast response times will mean faster oracle updates, greater capital efficiency and an unparalleled user experience for MCDEX users. As one of our earliest partners, we’ve gotten to know the stellar team at MCDEX quite well, and we’re excited to reach this launch milestone together.” – Arbitrum Co-Founder, Steven Goldfeder<\/span><\/i>","<img decoding=\"async\" loading=\"lazy\" class=\"alignnone size-medium wp-image-106189\" src=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2021\/05\/Picture1-1-800x434.png\" alt=\"\" width=\"800\" height=\"434\" srcset=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2021\/05\/Picture1-1-800x434.png 800w, https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2021\/05\/Picture1-1-768x416.png 768w, https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2021\/05\/Picture1-1.png 882w\" sizes=\"(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">MCDEX recently just <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/mcdex.medium.com\/mcdex-closes-7m-investment-962512f40c97\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">secured a funding<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> of $7M led by Delphi Digital and Alamada Research.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Other participants in the round includes: <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/multicoincap?s=20\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Multicoin<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Capital, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/fenbushi?s=20\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Fenbushi Capital<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/DeFianceCapital?s=20\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">DeFiance<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Capital, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/Incuba_Alpha?s=20\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Incuba Alpha<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/d1ventures?s=20\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">D1 Ventures<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/defialliance?s=20\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Defi Alliance<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/NGC_Ventures?s=20\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">NGC<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/IOSGVC?s=20\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IOSG<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, Zeuth, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/okex_ventures\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">OKEx Blockdream Ventures<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, Horizon Capital, Bixin Ventures, Digital Renaissance Foundation, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/realmaskbook?s=20\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Mask Network<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, Shata Capital, Finlink, <\/span><a href=\"http:\/\/plutus.vc\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Plutus.vc<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, Magic Ventures, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/ZBScapital?s=20\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ZBS Capital<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, and <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/Melt_Dem?s=20\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Meltem Demirors<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> (angel investor).<\/span>","<img decoding=\"async\" loading=\"lazy\" class=\"alignnone size-medium wp-image-106164\" src=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2021\/05\/Picture1-800x419.png\" alt=\"\" width=\"800\" height=\"419\" srcset=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2021\/05\/Picture1-800x419.png 800w, https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2021\/05\/Picture1-768x403.png 768w, https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2021\/05\/Picture1.png 904w\" sizes=\"(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">"],"entity":[{"type":"NGC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bixin Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Horizon Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ZBS Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Incuba Alpha","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"February","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Steven Goldfeder","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"DeFiance<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Zeuth","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Shata Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Arbitrum Rollup","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Digital Renaissance Foundation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mask Network","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Blockdream Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fenbushi Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Defi Alliance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Magic Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$7M","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Alamada Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Delphi Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sponsored","The Block"]}