{"summary":"Crypto.com’s Crypto Earn has launched in the United States. Since rolling out last month, Crypto Earn has grown rapidly and now, is available to users in","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/28585\/crypto-com-earn-up-to-8-annually-on-btc-eth-ltc-xrp-more-now-in-the-us-2","publishDate":"2019-06-26T00:30:30","id":6274,"type":null,"title":"Crypto.com: Earn up to 8% annually on BTC, ETH, LTC, XRP &amp; more - now in the US","category":["STARTUPS"],"content":["Crypto.com’s <a href=\"https:\/\/crypto.com\/en\/earn.html\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto Earn<\/a> has launched in the United States. Since rolling out last month, Crypto Earn has grown rapidly and now, is <a href=\"https:\/\/help.crypto.com\/articles\/2692288-which-u-s-states-are-the-crypto-com-wallet-card-app-available\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">available to users in 36 states<\/a> in the US.","Crypto Earn allows users to deposit their cryptocurrency and earn up to 8% annually on BTC, ETH, XRP, LTC, TUSD, PAX, USDC, and now also Crypto.com’s MCO. Users can choose a 1-month, 3-month, and\/or flexible term. The interest accrues daily and is paid out weekly. Earnings are immediately available to spend. By staking MCO (Crypto.com) tokens, users are able to earn preferential rates (~2% more).","Since launch, the team has expanded the crypto options from 3 (BTC, TUSD, and PAX) to 8 (added ETH, LTC, USDC, XRP and MCO); enabled flexible term, as well as, multiple active deposits; and implemented a 7-day payout. More cryptocurrencies will be progressively added.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nCrypto Earn’s interest earned rates can be found in the table below:","\n<style type=\"text\/css\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\ntable.crypto-chart, table.crypto-chart th, table.crypto-chart td{\nborder-collapse: collapse;\nborder: 1px solid #efefef;\n}\ntable.crypto-chart{\nwidth: 100%;\nmax-width: 650px;\nmargin: 10px auto;\nborder-spacing: 1px;\nbackground-color: #ffffff;\n}\ntable.crypto-chart td{\npadding: 5px 10px;\ntext-align: center;\nwidth: 33.33%;\n}\ntable.crypto-chart tr.catHeader td{\nbackground-color: #efefef;\n}\n#post-28585 .entry-content .list-social {\ndisplay:none !important;\n}\n<\/style>\n","<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nCrypto Earn’s terms are industry-leading and very favorable to customers:","To get started and earn interest on your cryptocurrency, sign up for Crypto Earn <a href=\"https:\/\/crypto.com\/en\/earn.html\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">here<\/a>!","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">*Crypto Earn Eligibility - Crypto.com Wallet &amp; Card App approved users except citizens or residents of Hong Kong SAR, Switzerland, or Malta. We are working to make the product available to these jurisdictions.<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"8%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Crypto Earn Eligibility","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Switzerland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"33.33%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Crypto Earn","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SAR","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Crypto.com Wallet &amp; Card App","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MCO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"100%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"USDC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Malta","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"United States","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"LTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sponsored","The Block"]}