{"summary":"The criminal case against former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried was reassigned to U.S. Judge Lewis Kaplan after Judge Ronnie Abrams recused herself on Friday.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/198066\/sam-bankman-fried-criminal-case-assigned-to-new-judge-reuters","publishDate":"2022-12-27T12:02:01","id":6277,"type":null,"title":"Sam Bankman-Fried criminal case assigned to new judge: Reuters","category":["POLICY"],"content":["The criminal case against former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried was reassigned to U.S. Judge Lewis Kaplan after U.S. District Judge Ronnie Abrams <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/197814\/judge-withdraws-sbf-case-conflict\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">recused<\/a> herself on Friday, Reuters <a href=\"https:\/\/www.reuters.com\/legal\/bankman-frieds-criminal-case-assigned-judge-lewis-kaplan-court-filing-2022-12-27\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a>, citing a court filing.","Kaplan is also overseeing high-profile defamation lawsuits against former President Donald Trump, Reuters said. Abrams withdrew from the case because her husband is a partner at the law firm Davis Polk &amp; Wardwell, which advised FTX in 2021.","\"My husband has had no involvement in any of these representations,\" Abrams said in <a href=\"https:\/\/www.documentcloud.org\/documents\/23531804-order-in-ftx-case-judge-abrams-recuses-herself-after-delayed-transcripts-unsealed-recusal-order-here-whos-next-innercitypresscom-is-on-it\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">a Friday filing<\/a>. \"Nonetheless, to avoid any possible conflict, or the appearance of one, the Court hereby recuses itself from this action.\"","Bankman-Fried was arrested on Dec. 12 in the Bahamas and is accused by U.S. authorities of committing or conspiring to commit fraud, money laundering and conspiracy to defraud the U.S. and violate campaign finance disclosure laws. He was extradited to the U.S. last week and <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/197573\/ellison-and-wang-guilty-pleas-unsealed-as-bankman-fried-granted-bail\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">released on bail<\/a> while he awaits trial.&nbsp;","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Abrams","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ronnie Abrams","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Dec. 12","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Donald Trump","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Reuters","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bahamas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"last week","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Davis Polk &amp; Wardwell","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Lewis Kaplan","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["CRIME","FTX","SAM BANKMAN-FRIED"],"authors":["Nathan Crooks","The Block"]}