{"summary":"The woman behind crypto scam OneCoin is now on Europe&#x27;s most wanted list.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/146251\/ruja-ignatova-europes-most-wanted-cryptoqueen-crime-scam-ponzi","publishDate":"2022-05-11T07:42:52","id":6304,"type":null,"title":"Ruja Ignatova added to Europe&#x27;s most wanted list as search for missing &#x27;Cryptoqueen&#x27; widens","category":["THE BLOCK"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ruja Ignatova, the founder of Ponzi scheme OneCoin, has been added to Europe's list of most wanted fugitives as of Wednesday.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ignatova is known for being the head of OneCoin, one of the biggest scams in the history of crypto, and the basis of the BBC podcast series, “The Missing Cryptoqueen.”<\/span>","She has now been added to Europol’s <a href=\"https:\/\/eumostwanted.eu\/#\/ignatova-ruja\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">most wanted list<\/a>, with officials saying she's <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">suspected of being the “driving force and intellectual inventor” of OneCoin, which \"induced investors all over the world to invest in this actually worthless currency.”&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">OneCoin’s business was built on selling educational cryptocurrency trading packages to its members, who were incentivized with commissions to sell to yet more new members. OneCoin claimed its membership was as large as 3 million people during the peak of the scheme, including victims across the globe.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">As a result, US prosecutors in the Southern District of New York <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/61610\/court-unseal-indictment-onecoin-pyramid-scam-cofounder\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">charged<\/a> the leaders of OneCoin with wire fraud, securities fraud and money laundering in 2019. This included Ruja Ignatova and Konstantin Ignatov, her brother, as well as Mark Scott.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Konstantin Ignatov was arrested in March 2019 while Scott was arrested in September 2018, however Ruga Ignatova remains at large.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The addition of Ignatova to Europe’s most wanted list and the cash reward of €5,000 (about $5,250) for information on her head widens the scope of the search and increases the likelihood that she will be brought to justice.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Scott was found guilty by a federal jury in Manhattan in 2019 while Ignatov signed a plea deal in the same year which meant he would not face further criminal charges.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$5,250","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Mark Scott","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ruga Ignatova","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BBC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Europol","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Scott","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"March 2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ignatova","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Southern District of New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ruja Ignatova","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Manhattan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Konstantin Ignatov","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"September 2018","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}