{"summary":"Rep. McHenry’s shift to temporarily be House Speaker could waste precious time that is needed to move crypto bills across the finish line.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/254816\/us-crypto-legislation-could-stall-amid-republican-leadership-drama","publishDate":"2023-10-04T15:06:32","id":6326,"type":null,"title":"US crypto legislation could stall amid Republican leadership drama","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Rep. Patrick T. McHenry's shift to temporarily cover one of the most powerful U.S. leadership seats could waste precious time needed to move cryptocurrency bills closer across the finish line.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">McHenry, who took over the position of Speaker of the House on <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/254607\/crypto-friendly-rep-patrick-mchenry-becomes-speaker-pro-temp-following-house-speaker-oust\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Tuesday<\/a> with a deafening gavel bang, could hold the spot for a week — or much longer. He doesn't seem to have even wanted the post to begin with,<\/span><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> preferring to lead the House Financial Services Committee in getting bills, including crypto, out the gate. <\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">His focus will now likely be shifted after former Speaker Kevin McCarthy, R-Calif, was ousted on Tuesday <\/span><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">following a power struggle with far-right lawmakers including Rep. Matt Gaetz, R-Fla.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Of course he has gotten dragged into this fight whether he likes it or not,\" said Ron Hammond, director of government relations at the Blockchain Association.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Two bills just advanced out of his committee in July and are awaiting a full House vote before being passed to the Senate. One bill would regulate stablecoins, while the other takes a comprehensive approach at creating a regulatory framework for crypto; even with an eventual<\/span><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> House vote, they would still need to garner support in the Senate, which could prove to be tough.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Those bills are just sitting there and we really can’t do anything to move the needle here, we just have to wait for the general politics to play out and then get back to legislating, which is the unfortunate situation,” Hammond said.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The House was supposed to be out of session this week and next, but Hammond pointed out that no new hearings have been scheduled.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"We’re kind of in a standstill now,\" he said.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span><\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Behind the scenes, lawmakers are now jockeying for support to become the next Speaker of the House. A closed door call or conversation with the Republican party is expected to happen on Oct. 10, with a possible general floor vote the next day.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"A lot can mess that up, but right now that's the plan, is that in a week from now we will have a new speaker,” Hammond said, noting the process could drag on if a vote doesn't occur.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Basically, until a House member is chosen as Speaker, the House's work activity comes to a screeching halt<\/span><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,\" said John Aughenbaugh, <\/span><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">associate professor at Virginia Commonwealth University. That means typically no subcommittee committee hearings or votes, he added.<\/span>","<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">McHenry won't lose his position as House Financial Services chair, but he won't be doing much, including work on crypto bills, until a permanent Speaker is chosen, Aughenbaugh said.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Rep. Steve Scalise, R-La., is the current frontrunner for the speakership, though his health could come into question, the Blockchain Association's Hammond said. Scalise was reportedly diagnosed with blood cancer in August.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Everyone thinks he is going to make a full recovery, but of course the speaker job is no easy job,\" Hammond said.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Scalise hasn't really dipped his toes into crypto, Hammond added.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto friendly House Majority Whip Rep. Tom Emmer, R-Minn., is the second runner-up. Rep. Gaetz, who had a heavy hand in knocking McCarthy out, reportedly said Emmer would \"make a great speaker.\"<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"At the end of the day, we want to make sure we just get the House together so we can move these bills along because we're just wasting floor time here,\" Hammond said.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Blockchain Association","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Emmer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kevin McCarthy","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gaetz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Hammond","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ron Hammond","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"La.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"House Financial Services","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"House Financial Services Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Fla.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Tom Emmer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"McCarthy","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Calif","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Virginia Commonwealth University","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"House","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Patrick T. McHenry","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Steve Scalise","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Minn.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Oct. 10","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Scalise","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"John Aughenbaugh","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Aughenbaugh","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Matt Gaetz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Senate","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["CONGRESS","HOUSE AGRICULTURE COMMITTEE","HOUSE FINANCIAL SERVICES COMMITTEE"],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}