{"summary":"ABN AMRO Clearing Bank N.V., a futures and securities clearing firm serving the Americas, Europe and Asia Pacific, cleared the trade. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/263882\/wintermute-asia-executes-first-options-block-trade-through-cme-group","publishDate":"2023-11-21T09:00:06","id":6440,"type":null,"title":"Wintermute Asia executes first options block trade through CME Group","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Wintermute Asia, a crypto derivatives trading arm of the algorithmic trading firm Wintermute Group, said Tuesday that it executed its first options block trade through CME Group.","The BTC\/USD block was traded between Wintermute Asia and TP ICAP and was cleared by ABN AMRO Clearing Bank, Wintermute said in a statement.&nbsp;","\"In such a fast-growing and exciting market, it is fantastic to see crypto-native firms such as Wintermute accessing traditional products and services, solidifying our belief that the maturation of this market is building momentum,\" Sam Newman, TP ICAP's digital assets head of broking, said in the statement.&nbsp;","CME Group is a derivatives exchange headquartered in Chicago. In mid-August, the firm <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/245823\/cme-cf-benchmarks-apac-bitcoin-ether\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/a> a collaboration with the crypto indexing firm CF Benchmarks to provide APAC-specific reference rates for ether and bitcoin, The Block previously reported.&nbsp;","\"We are pleased to provide <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/242003\/wintermute-staff-singapore\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Wintermute<\/a> and its counterparties with access to our highly liquid, regulated suite of benchmark cryptocurrency futures and options on bitcoin and ether,\" said Giovanni Vicioso, global head of cryptocurrency products at CME Group.","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Disclaimer: Evgeny Gaevoy, the founder and CEO of Wintermute, previously sat on The Block's board of directors from April 2023 to early November 2023 and remains a minority shareholder.<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Wintermute","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"April 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"ABN AMRO Clearing Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"November 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Wintermute Asia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Wintermute","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sam Newman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Wintermute Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CME Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wintermute","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"APAC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ICAP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Giovanni Vicioso","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"TP ICAP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Evgeny Gaevoy","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"mid-August","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Chicago","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["PAYMENTS"],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}