{"summary":"Coinbase deals with the node set-up process and other technical details, making staking more accessible to everyday retail users.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/154960\/coinbase-adds-support-for-staking-solana","publishDate":"2022-06-29T18:28:08","id":6452,"type":null,"title":"Coinbase adds support for staking Solana","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto exchange firm Coinbase has expanded its staking reward offerings to include Solana.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The minimum starting balance a user needs to start staking Solana is $1. Payouts occur every seven days.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Previously, tokens that could be staked on Coinbase included Ethereum, Algorand, Cosmos, Tezos, Dai and Cardano. Adding Solana means users can streamline how they stake their tokens and earn rewards using Coinbase’s platform, according to a Wednesday blog post.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In order to stake Solana, a Coinbase user must have their identity validated on the platform and reside in a location in which staking is allowed, as stipulated in the firm’s <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/help.coinbase.com\/en\/coinbase\/trading-and-funding\/staking-rewards\/staking-inflation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">support page.<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tezos","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Dai","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Cosmos","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Cardano","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Algorand","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$1","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["COINBASE","SOLANA","STAKING"],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}