{"summary":"“All customers who had deposits with these banks can rest assured that they’ll be protected and will have access to their money as of today,&quot; Biden said in an attempt to assuage Americans during the midst of a digital age bank run.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/219229\/biden-reassures-americans-that-banking-system-is-safe-in-wake-of-collapses","publishDate":"2023-03-13T09:40:10","id":6458,"type":null,"title":"Biden reassures Americans that banking system is safe in wake of collapses","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">U.S. President Joe Biden assured American citizens that the banking system is safe following the collapses of Signature Bank and Silicon Valley Bank.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Americans can have confidence that the banking system is safe,” Biden said. “All customers who had deposits with these banks can rest assured that they’ll be protected and will have access to their money as of today.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Biden's address, and the maneuvering announced by regulators over the weekend, is an attempt to halt further bank runs. U.S. financial authorities <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/219119\/state-regulator-takes-control-of-signature-bank-federal-regulators-guarantee-deposits\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">assured<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> full return of Silicon Valley and Signature Bank customer deposits on Sunday.<\/span>","Biden <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">repeated a statement <a href=\"https:\/\/www.whitehouse.gov\/briefing-room\/statements-releases\/2023\/03\/12\/statement-from-president-joe-biden-on-actions-to-strengthen-confidence-in-the-banking-system\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">released<\/a> over the weekend that “no losses will be borne on the taxpayer.” Deposits will be available for employers and small businesses affected, while investors and bondholders will not receive a similar government backstop.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“The actions that we took today were designed to limit the consequences of the depositor outflows from Silicon Valley and from Signature and to reduce any spillover effects,\" the Federal Reserve Board, the Treasury Department and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/219119\/state-regulator-takes-control-of-signature-bank-federal-regulators-guarantee-deposits\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in a joint statement.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Silicon Valley Bank was closed down by a California regulator after it failed to meet a surge in outflows on Friday. On Sunday, a New York regulator <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/219119\/state-regulator-takes-control-of-signature-bank-federal-regulators-guarantee-deposits\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">seized<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Signature Bank \"to protect depositors.\"&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Both financial institutions intersect with crypto, as Signature Bank works with stablecoin companies and Silicon Valley Bank works with tech startups and venture capital firms. <\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Sunday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"weekend","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Treasury Department","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Signature Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Federal Reserve Board","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Silicon Valley and Signature Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"California","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Joe Biden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Silicon Valley","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Biden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Silicon Valley Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}