{"summary":"XRP, which is up 9.2% in the last day, has taken over Bitcoin&#x27;s lead in the broader crypto over the past month.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/223709\/ripple-xrp-tokens-dominate-crypto-rally","publishDate":"2023-03-29T14:17:11","id":6461,"type":null,"title":"XRP takes lead in crypto rally over bitcoin","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["While bitcoin has <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/220829\/bitcoin-hovers-around-27000-leading-crypto-rally\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">outperformed other cryptocurrencies<\/a> since the onset of the banking crisis earlier this month, XRP has taken the lead in recent days.","The token has been trading up in the past week and saw a sharp uptick over the weekend. It is currently trading at around $0.60, up 9.2% over the past 24 hours and 16.9% in the last week.","XRP's performance could signal how investors are feeling about a pending lawsuit brought by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission against payments firm Ripple, which initially launched the token in 2012.","\"Google Trends data confirms that users searching for 'XRP' are highly interested in the case's outcome,\" said Strahinja Savic, head of data and analytics at FRNT Financial. \"It's unclear what specifically is causing the optimism around XRP right now. However, there is significant focus on crypto regulation. The SEC's case against Ripple may be gaining increased attention as a result, amplifying optimism from [Ripple CEO Brad] Garlingouse and figures close to the case.\"","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/crypto-markets\/prices\/bitcoin-vs-top-20-marketcap-price-performance-1d\/embed\" title=\"Bitcoin vs Top 20 Marketcap Price Performance (1D)\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Bitcoin, meanwhile, is trading at around $28,329 — up 5.4% in the last day. It has mostly been trading between $27,000 and $28,000 over the past two weeks, at times <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/222028\/bitcoin-trading-up-close-to-29000-ahead-of-fed-decision\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">briefly coming close to $29,000<\/a>.","\"To the topside, 28.5\/29.0k remains critical resistance to the continuation of this rally, so we can expect plenty of stops and fast moves higher through there,\" crypto trading firm B2C2 said in a newsletter.","&nbsp;","","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/chart\/h7wYKiIo\/?symbol=BINANCE%3AXRPUSD\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">XRP\/USD chart by TradingView<\/a>","","","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/chart\/h7wYKiIo\/?symbol=BINANCE%3ABTCUSD\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BTC\/USD chart by TradingView<\/a>","Galaxy Digital shares were up by 11.2%, a day after the company announced <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/223206\/michael-novogratz-calls-2022-a-formative-year-as-galaxy-digital-reports-1-billion-loss\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">a net loss of $1 billion<\/a> for its fiscal year 2022. Coinbase and MicroStrategy saw shares rise by 2.6% and 9.8%, respectively.","In traditional financial markets, the Nasdaq 100 was up by 1.5% and the S&amp;P 500 by 1.1%.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"9.2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Galaxy Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"16.9%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"5.4%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"TradingView","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2012","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FRNT Financial","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Strahinja Savic","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$0.60","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"S&amp;P","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"11.2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Brad] Garlingouse","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"XRP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$29,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Google Trends","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"earlier this month","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$28,329","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2.6%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"1.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"1.1%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$28,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"9.8%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"MicroStrategy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$27,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Nasdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Catarina Moura","The Block"]}