{"summary":"Sam Bankman-Fried considered closing Alameda Research in September because it wasn&#x27;t making enough money to justify its existence.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/194604\/we-came-we-saw-we-researched-bankman-fried-considered-closing-alameda-in-september","publishDate":"2022-12-13T11:10:45","id":6463,"type":null,"title":"&#x27;We came, we saw, we researched&#x27;: Bankman-Fried considered closing Alameda in September","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Sam Bankman-Fried contemplated closing Alameda Research in September, according to charges filed by the Commodity Futures Trading Commission.&nbsp;","The disgraced former CEO reportedly drafted and shared a document titled \"'We came, we saw, we researched,\" which questioned whether Alameda should be permanently shut down.","<span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“I only started thinking about this today, and so haven’t vetted it <\/span><span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">much yet,\" wrote Bankman-Fried. \"But: I think it might be time for Alameda Research to shut down.<\/span> <span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Honestly, it was <\/span><span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">probably time to do that a year ago.”<\/span>","Bankman-Fried was arrested last night by authorities in the Bahamas and this morning slapped with numerous charges of fraud and other wrongdoing by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission and the CFTC over the collapse of FTX and Alameda.","Bankman-Fried listed a number of reasons for closing the trading shop, including that Alameda doesn't justify the current cost of capital, which is \"really expensive\" in this environment and that Alameda was not making enough money to justify its existence.","\"[T]<span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">he fact that we didn’t hedge as much as we should have alone cost <\/span><span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">more in EV [expected value] than all the money Alameda has ever made or ever will make,\" Bankman-Fried wrote.<\/span>","He also listed downsides for closing the shop, noting that there would be \"less liquidity on FTX,\" according to CFTC complaint. The <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/194526\/for-sbf-and-ftx-the-fraud-started-from-day-one-that-and-other-revelations-from-the-sec\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">SEC charges<\/a> from earlier in the day note that Alameda was one of FTX's largest customer and received special privileges.","Bankman-Fried went so far as to draft a Twitter thread about Alameda's closure, according to the filing.&nbsp;","<span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The former CEO concluded the document with: “I feel really uncertain what’s right! So I guess my plan is <\/span><span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">that, this coming weekend, we should just make a call, and enact it before next Monday, one way <\/span><span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">or another. Thoughts?”<\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"this morning","content":"TIME"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"today","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Commodity Futures Trading Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bahamas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"CFTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["FTX","SAM BANKMAN-FRIED"],"authors":["Kari McMahon","The Block"]}