{"summary":"The state-owned bank has partnered with China Telecom and China Unicom to test SIM card payments linked to e-CNY, China&#x27;s in trial CBDC.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/239063\/bank-of-china-tests-sim-card-nfc-payments-for-digital-yuan","publishDate":"2023-07-11T21:55:20","id":6465,"type":null,"title":"Bank of China tests SIM card NFC payments for digital yuan","category":["THE BLOCK"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bank of China, one of China's largest state-owned banks, is testing a new offline payment method linked to SIM cards for digital yuan, or the e-CNY, the country’s in trial central bank digital currency (CBDC).<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bank of China has partnered with telecommunication operators China Telecom and China Unicom to start testing the new feature on Tuesday, the bank said Monday in a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/mp.weixin.qq.com\/s\/Il2p2rKE116xMh97Ml0wQg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">social media post<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The bank intends to allow users to make payments with their phones by connecting its e-CNY app with what it calls “super SIM cards” that are equipped with a near-field communication function. Users would only need to bring their mobile phones close to point of sales terminals to pay. That means payments can be processed even with a phone turned off.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Such SIM card payment features, however, will only be available on certain Android phones in some pilot areas in China, the bank said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The People’s Bank of China (PBOC), the central bank, has been testing a so-called CBDC and rolled out a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/129081\/chinas-digital-yuan-wallet-goes-live-on-app-stores-in-pilot-mode\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">pilot e-CNY app<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in January last year.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The PBOC has expanded its digital yuan pilot to at least 26 locations in 17 provincial-level cities and regions, including Beijing, Shanghai, Shenzhen and Suzhou, state media Xinhua <\/span><a href=\"http:\/\/www.news.cn\/fortune\/2023-04\/08\/c_1129503697.htm\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in April.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Meanwhile, Hong Kong in May <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.hkma.gov.hk\/eng\/news-and-media\/press-releases\/2023\/05\/20230518-4\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">launched an e-HKD pilot program<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> after the Hong Kong Monetary Authority released a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.hkma.gov.hk\/eng\/news-and-media\/press-releases\/2021\/10\/20211004-3\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">whitepaper<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in October 2021 on a potential retail CBDC.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The HKMA, Hong Kong’s de facto central bank, said in a September <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.hkma.gov.hk\/media\/eng\/doc\/key-information\/press-release\/2022\/20220920e4a1.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">consultation paper<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that it will explore the possibility of cross-border payments linking e-CNY and e-HKD.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Beijing","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Hong Kong Monetary Authority","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Shenzhen","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"PBOC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"China Unicom","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Suzhou","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bank of China","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"October 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"January last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Xinhua","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"People’s Bank of China (PBOC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"SIM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Shanghai","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"HKMA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"China","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"China Telecom","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["CBDCS"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}