{"summary":"House lawmakers could release a draft stablecoin bill as early as this week, after plans to release a full piece of legislation fell apart.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/159569\/lawmakers-race-to-release-draft-of-stablecoin-bill-ahead-of-august-recess","publishDate":"2022-07-25T18:17:21","id":6490,"type":null,"title":"Lawmakers race to release draft of stablecoin bill ahead of August recess","category":["CONGRESS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">US House of Representatives lawmakers could introduce draft text of a stablecoin bill as early as this week, a last-ditch effort to keep regulation front-of-mind ahead of the August recess.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Lawmakers are working on a discussion draft of the legislation, according to four people familiar with the plan. The move comes as a stablecoin regulation deal between House Financial Services Committee Chair Maxine Waters, D-Calif., and ranking Republican Rep. Patrick McHenry, R-N.C., has stalled on Capitol Hill.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The bill came as a surprise to many in DC last week, though Waters and committee Democrats were said to be working on a broader crypto package.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">House lawmakers had <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/158767\/house-lawmakers-prep-bipartisan-stablecoin-bill-to-unveil-next-week\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">initially planned<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to release a full stablecoin regulation bill this week, but negotiations have seemingly stalled. Those involved apparently had hashed out standards for acceptable reserves to back fiat-pegged stablecoins. Sources familiar with the negotiations noted that it was a Treasury-brokered deal that would allow non-banks to issue stablecoins — which would go against its <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/122890\/us-treasury-releases-long-awaited-report-on-stablecoin-risk-features-request-for-new-laws\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">earlier push to limit issuance<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to FDIC-insured financial institutions.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The move displeased committee progressives. Meanwhile, several Republicans were unhappy with McHenry’s team cutting them out of negotiations, as well as broader concerns about federal preemption of state regulatory authorities.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">If a draft is not released in the coming days, those involved fear stablecoin regulation efforts will lose momentum by the time lawmakers return to the Capitol in September, one source said. Lawmakers had not settled on the final text of a discussion draft as of Monday afternoon.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Representatives for Waters and McHenry did not reply to requests for comment.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The end-of-summer recess, a time when lawmakers head back to their districts and often campaign ahead of the midterm elections, begins August 1 and lasts through Labor Day. When the House returns this fall, lawmakers will still be in a race against the clock to pass legislation before the November election.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">If the stablecoin push is unsuccessful, it won’t be the only crypto-related bill to stall in Congress this year. Sens. Kirsten Gillibrand, D-N.Y., and Cynthia Lummis, R-Wyo., <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/158484\/crypto-market-crash-gives-regulation-more-urgency-sen-gillibrand-says\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">acknowledged<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> last week that their sweeping crypto regulation bill is unlikely to get a vote ahead of the midterms.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"N.Y.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"fiat","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"fall","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"US House of Representatives","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wyo.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Congress","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Patrick McHenry","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"August 1","content":"DATE"},{"type":"House","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"},{"type":"House Financial Services Committee Chair Maxine Waters","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FDIC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Kirsten Gillibrand","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Calif.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cynthia Lummis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"summer","content":"DATE"},{"type":"afternoon","content":"TIME"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"},{"type":"McHenry","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["MAXINE WATERS","PATRICK MCHENRY"],"authors":["Kollen Post","Stephanie Murray","The Block"]}