{"summary":"Layer 1 blockchain Canto is migrating to become an Ethereum Layer 2 that uses zero-knowledge proofs, according to a statement.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/251566\/canto-to-migrate-into-a-zk-powered-layer-2-on-ethereum","publishDate":"2023-09-18T14:10:42","id":6500,"type":null,"title":"Canto to migrate into a ZK-powered Layer 2 on Ethereum","category":["CRYPTO ECOSYSTEMS"],"content":["The Layer 1 blockchain Canto is set to migrate to Ethereum.&nbsp;","The Layer 1 blockchain is migrating to become an Ethereum Layer 2 that uses zero-knowledge proofs, according to a <a href=\"https:\/\/polygon.technology\/blog\/canto-to-migrate-to-a-zk-l2-powered-by-polygon-chain-development-kit?utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_content=canto-blog\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">statement<\/a>. Canto is working with the Ethereum scaling developer Polygon to do so, leveraging the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/247873\/polygon-labs-chain-development-kit\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Polygon Chain Development Kit (CDK)<\/a> to undergird the new design as it puts a focus on real-world assets.","\"After assessing several routes, it quickly became clear that Polygon CDK offers a powerful suite to enable Canto to deliver a ZK L2 that extends the community's defining ethos of permissionless sovereignty, security, and liquidity as a public good,\" Canto <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/CantoPublic\/status\/1703809950290718871?s=20\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">added<\/a> on X. Polygon CDK is an open-source codebase for creating ZK-powered Ethereum Layer 2s.&nbsp;","Canto originally launched in 2022 as a general-purpose Layer 1 blockchain offering an Ethereum Virtual Machine-compatible execution layer.&nbsp;","Canto follows other Layer 1 blockchains looking to Ethereum this year. In July, the development firm behind <a href=\"https:\/\/docs.google.com\/presentation\/d\/1tIEch0hRenBkPbBQLQEwaxhL0JelAfHkNwYL579Q9CE\/edit#slide=id.g222f2c0afe7_1_1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Celo<\/a> announced that it would turn the Layer 1 into a Layer 2 built on Ethereum, using Optimism's OP Stack to carry out the transition.&nbsp;","A month later, co-founder and architect of the Fantom Foundation Andre Cronje said that the team was considering what would effectively make the Layer 1 <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/243220\/fantom-optimistic-rollups-ethereum\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Fantom<\/a> into an Ethereum Layer 2 via optimistic rollups. (Although he decries the label.)","Additionally, Canto joins Astar, Immutable, IDEX and Palm Network as ZK-based Layer 2s built by Polygon.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"IDEX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Palm Network","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ethereum Virtual Machine","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Canto","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Polygon CDK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"X. Polygon CDK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fantom","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Polygon Chain Development","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fantom Foundation Andre Cronje","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["OPTIMISM"],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}