{"summary":"Brad Garlinghouse said today in Singapore that the crypto community needs to agree on certain basic regulations.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/250742\/ripple-ceo-says-the-crypto-community-cant-pretend-regulation-doesnt-matter","publishDate":"2023-09-13T08:24:00","id":6566,"type":null,"title":"Ripple CEO says the crypto community ‘can’t pretend regulation doesn’t matter’","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ripple CEO Brad Garlinghouse said there needs to be proper regulation in place for the cryptocurrency industry to thrive.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“There is an underlying segment of the crypto world that is so anti-regulation and all about anonymity,” Garlinghouse said today at a panel at Token 2049 in Singapore. “In my judgment, if we want this industry to thrive and achieve what it can fundamentally rewire how financial infrastructure works, we can't pretend like government regulation doesn't matter.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">He added that there are some basic things the crypto community has to agree on. “I still do find categories of the crypto community fighting on some of these basic regulatory frameworks.”&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“AML is going to matter, KYC is going to matter,” Garlinghouse, whose company has been <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/250024\/sec-snaps-back-against-ripple-in-push-for-an-interlocutory-appeal\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">caught up in a legal fight with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, continued. “If you're taking the point of view that we're going to circumvent those things, that's not the industry I see out 5 to 10 years from now that really is thriving and growing.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Commenting on the U.S. business environment for the crypto industry, Garlinghouse said that crypto entrepreneurs should avoid launching a company in the U.S.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“The only country I would not encourage people to start a company right now is the US. There's probably some others, but the U.S. is a big one to call out,” he said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Last week, the SEC <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/250024\/sec-snaps-back-against-ripple-in-push-for-an-interlocutory-appeal\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">snapped back against Ripple’s assertion<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that a New York court should not allow the agency to appeal part of a high-profile ruling. The regulator said on Friday that Ripple was trying to delay a resolution “so that they may continue freely selling <span class=\"articleTooltip\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"\/price\/248352\/xrp-xrp-usd\" class=\"articleTooltip__link\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"><img src=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2023\/10\/xrp-symbol-white-128.png\" alt=\"\" title=\"\" class=\"articleTooltip__tokenImage\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">XRP<\/span> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText articleTooltip__tokenText_price articleTooltip__tokenText_negative\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">\n      -1.60%\n    <\/span><\/a> <!----><\/span> into public markets without the disclosures that come with registration.”<\/span><\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"-1.60%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2049","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"today","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"” Garlinghouse","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Garlinghouse","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Brad Garlinghouse","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"AML","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["ASIAN REGULATION","LAWSUITS","SEC"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}