{"summary":"CJ Rinaldi formerly worked at Blockchain.com as Chief Compliance Officer (CCO), and the CCO to Deutsche Bank before that.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/204809\/kraken-hires-blockchain-coms-former-chief-compliance-officer","publishDate":"2023-01-24T08:00:25","id":6582,"type":null,"title":"Blockchain.com&#x27;s Chief Compliance Officer joins crypto exchange Kraken","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Crypto exchange giant Kraken has hired C.J. Rinaldi as its chief compliance officer.&nbsp;","Rinaldi joins Kraken after working at the crypto services firm Blockchain.com as its chief compliance officer from October 2021 until December 2022. Rinaldi helped mitigate Blockchain.com's risk and expand its global compliance framework. Before Blockchain.com, Rinaldi worked at Deutsche Bank as chief compliance officer, and prior to that as senior counsel in the Enforcement Division of the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission.","Jesse Powell, Kraken's CEO of over 11 years, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/171847\/krakens-jesse-powell-stepping-down-as-ceo-of-crypto-exchange\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">stepped down<\/a> on Sept. 21, 2022, and the firm's COO David Ripley assumed the CEO role. Kraken laid off <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/191023\/kraken-cuts-30-of-staff-to-weather-crypto-winter\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">30%<\/a> of its workforce on Nov. 30, 2022 to help \"weather the crypto storm,\" joining <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/190758\/bitso-cuts-more-staff-in-fresh-round-of-layoffs\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitso<\/a>, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/149813\/crypto-exchange-gemini-slashes-about-10-of-its-work-force\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Gemini<\/a>, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/159786\/gods-unchained-developer-immutable-lays-off-around-8-of-staff\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Immutable<\/a> and a myriad of other crypto firms to downsize their workforce amid depressed market conditions last year, The Block previously reported.&nbsp;","Kraken saw $13.8 billion in monthly crypto exchange volume in December, comprising 2.95% of all crypto exchange volume for the month, according to The Block's Data Dashboard.","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/crypto-markets\/spot\/cryptocurrency-exchange-volume-monthly\/embed\" title=\"Cryptocurrency Monthly Exchange Volume\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Deutsche Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sept. 21, 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"C.J. Rinaldi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gemini","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Enforcement Division","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2.95%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"December","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Kraken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jesse Powell","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"30%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"October 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Rinaldi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block's Data Dashboard","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"December 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$13.8 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Nov. 30, 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"David Ripley","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["ANTI-MONEY LAUNDERING","HIRING","KRAKEN"],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}