{"summary":"Anthony Scaramucci talks crypto game plans with host Frank Chaparro in the latest episode of The Scoop.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/109976\/inside-anthony-scaramuccis-bitcoin-and-ether-etf-game-plan","publishDate":"2021-06-29T15:26:57","id":6649,"type":null,"title":"Inside Anthony Scaramucci&#x27;s bitcoin and ether ETF game plan","category":["INSTITUTIONAL INVESTORS"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode <\/i><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">36<\/strong><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> of Season 3 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block’s Frank Chaparro and SkyBridge Capital’s Anthony Scaramucci.<\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"760619121517050236021e13141a19151d15040f0602195815191b\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors <a href=\"http:\/\/eventussystems.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Eventus<\/a>, <a href=\"http:\/\/kraken.com\/scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kraken<\/a>, and Exodus<\/strong><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Eventus is the leading global provider of multi-asset class trade surveillance, transaction monitoring and market risk solutions. Eventus offers a powerful, award-winning trade surveillance platform that is easy to deploy, customize and operate. Eventus is proven in the most complex, high-volume and real-time environments and supports many of the industry’s leading crypto exchanges including Coinbase, Gemini, ErisX and OSL. The company’s rapidly growing client base relies on Eventus’ responsive support and product development teams to overcome its most pressing regulatory challenges.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Kraken<\/strong><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Whether you’re an experienced crypto trader or just starting out, Kraken has the tools to help you achieve financial freedom. With 50+ cryptocurrencies to choose from, industry-leading security and a wide variety of features to suit any investing strategy, Kraken puts the power in your hands to buy, sell and trade digital assets. Visit&nbsp;<\/em><a href=\"http:\/\/kraken.com\/scoop\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kraken.com<\/em><\/a><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;to get started&nbsp;today.<\/em><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Exodus<\/strong><\/span>","","Anthony Scaramucci — the New York financier and former White House official — first jumped into the crypto fray at the end of last year.&nbsp;","Now, Scaramucci is going all in.&nbsp;","During the latest episode of The Scoop, the Skybridge Capital founder walks listeners through his journey to bitcoin. Skybridge first began investing in BTC at the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/89533\/anthony-scaramuccis-skybridge-has-invested-182-million-into-bitcoin-according-to-deck\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">end of last year<\/a>.&nbsp;","\"We have a full commitment to crypto,\" he remarked.","Since then, Skybridge has <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/98910\/first-advisors-skybridge-bitcoin-etf\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">thrown its hat in the bitcoin exchange-traded product ring<\/a> and also plans to launch an ETF that has exposure to publicly traded cryptocurrency companies.","Indeed, Skybridge is one of a number of U.S. companies vying to go to market with a bitcoin ETF. But the Securities and Exchange Commission has yet to give the nod to such a product, and the proposed ETF that's furthest along in the process — put forward by asset management company VanEck — is now the subject of an <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/108643\/sec-more-comment-bitcoin-etf-vaneck\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">additional<\/a> comment period. Other companies, like NYDIG, Fidelity and Cathie Wood's ARK Invest, are among those pursuing bitcoin ETF launches.","Skybridge also has plans to launch a private Ethereum fund.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"July 1st, we're launching a private Ethereum fund. We’ll then file for an ETF for Ethereum. Again, it is anybody's guess when those things will be going,\" he said. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Scaramucci went on to say:<\/span>","\"<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">I can say — which is public information — that we did file for an ETF related to Bitcoin. We also have a UIT with a company out of Wheaton, Illinois, called First Trust… as we're speaking, we're making an announcement on an ETF for a digital innovation fund that has some great publicly traded assets that we think are geared related to [Ethereum], related to Bitcoin, but also the other coins.\"<\/span>","Scaramucci believes he can lean on his Wall Street chops for product adoption. He cited Morgan Stanley’s buy-in to SkyBridge’s digital asset portfolio as another example of Wall Street’s appetite for Bitcoin. “Morgan Stanley is a very big part of our business.\"","Remaining firm on his bullish stance on Bitcoin’s valuation, Scaramucci told The Scoop:","“Here's what I think. I think that we'll be sitting here a year from now, there'll still be skeptics, still be people that are fence-sitters, but there will be slightly more people in the pool with us and, as a result of which, the prices will be higher. And I just think this is one of those weird assets where the higher the prices go, the more people are going to be drawn into the pool.”","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"VanEck —","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Anthony Scaramucci","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"White House","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July 1st","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Kraken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"OSL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Illinois","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Skybridge","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cathie Wood","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"SkyBridge","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Morgan Stanley","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"SkyBridge Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gemini","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Fidelity","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"First Trust","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UIT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Scaramucci","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Wheaton","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Skybridge Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN","CRYPTO","ETHEREUM"],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}