{"summary":"On the morning of Friday, July 17th 2020, The Block presented its Central Bank Digital Currencies - Design, Policy &amp; Implementation webinar before a live audience.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/72061\/central-bank-digital-currencies-design-policy-implementation-full-webinar","publishDate":"2020-07-19T12:52:56","id":6651,"type":null,"title":"Central Bank Digital Currencies — Design, Policy &amp; Implementation | Full Webinar","category":["TECHNOLOGY"],"content":["On July 17th, The Block presented its <i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Central Bank Digital Currencies - Design, Policy &amp; Implementation<\/i> webinar before a live audience. This webinar served as a prelude to The Block's central bank digital currencies (CBDCs) whitepaper, set for release in the coming weeks.","The webinar began with a brief presentation on the main concepts of central bank digital currencies (CBDCs) by The Block research analyst Ryan Todd. Todd walked the audience through the data collection methodology, stating: \"We've conducted a number of interviews across central banks, policymakers, researchers, tech vendors and financial institutions.\" He also shared a statistic showing that 80% of central banks worldwide are \"engaged\" with CBDC research and development.","Next, Todd handed the presentation over to The Block research analyst Mike Rogers. Rogers moderated the CBDC expert panel, which featured:","These practitioners answered questions relating to their area of CBDC specialization.","Sheila Warren focused on the policy side of CBDC, sharing her experiences at the WEF — these included creating both <a href=\"https:\/\/www.weforum.org\/press\/2020\/01\/governing-the-coin-world-economic-forum-announces-global-consortium-for-digital-currency-governance\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Global Consortium for Digital Currency Governance<\/a> and <a href=\"https:\/\/www.weforum.org\/whitepapers\/central-bank-digital-currency-policy-maker-toolkit\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The WEF's CBDC Policy-Maker Toolkit<\/a>.&nbsp;","John Kiff discussed the finer points of CBDC standardization, economic theory and other findings from the IMF's <a href=\"https:\/\/www.imf.org\/en\/Publications\/WP\/Issues\/2020\/06\/26\/A-Survey-of-Research-on-Retail-Central-Bank-Digital-Currency-49517\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A Survey of Research on Retail Central Bank Digital Currency<\/a> paper.","As a service provider for the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.centralbankbahamas.com\/download\/022598600.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bahamas' Project Sand Dollar<\/a>,&nbsp;Carmelle Cadet focused on CBDC implementation. Carmelle noted the importance of information technology (IT) infrastructure, application programming interface (API) transformation and regulatory sandboxes for smoothing CBDC execution.&nbsp;","Robert Bench shared his insights regarding CBDC in North America, particularly the importance of aligning stakeholders across the CBDC spectrum. He also briefly commented on the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.digitaldollarproject.org\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Digital Dollar Project<\/a>.","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">You can view the webinar in its entirety along with the accompanying slides below:<\/em>","<iframe src=\"https:\/\/www.youtube.com\/embed\/In0aFE7euYg\" width=\"560\" height=\"315\" frameborder=\"0\" allowfullscreen=\"allowfullscreen\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<iframe id=\"doc_87981\" class=\"scribd_iframe_embed\" title=\"The Block CBDC - Europe and Americas\" src=\"https:\/\/www.scribd.com\/embeds\/469506950\/content?start_page=1&amp;view_mode=scroll&amp;access_key=key-yJRLj87A3bUbKcmx4mFv\" width=\"100%\" height=\"600\" frameborder=\"0\" scrolling=\"no\" data-auto-height=\"false\" data-aspect-ratio=\"1.7790927021696252\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Central Bank Digital Currencies","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ryan Todd","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Digital Dollar Project","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"80%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Survey of Research on Retail Central Bank Digital Currency","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Todd","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Mike Rogers","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sheila Warren","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"North America","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"IMF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Policy &amp; Implementation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bahamas","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July 17th","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Global Consortium for Digital Currency Governance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Carmelle Cadet","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"John Kiff","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"WEF","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["The Block","The Block"]}