{"summary":"Michael Lewis said the founder of failed crypto exchange FTX had looked into paying Donald Trump not to run for president.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253764\/sam-bankman-fried-considered-paying-trump-5-billion-not-to-run-for-office-michael-lewis-claims","publishDate":"2023-10-02T00:11:53","id":6681,"type":null,"title":"Sam Bankman-Fried considered paying Trump $5 billion not to run for office, Michael Lewis claims","category":["PEOPLE"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sam Bankman-Fried, founder of the failed crypto exchange FTX, looked into paying Donald Trump $5 billion not to run for the presidency, Michael Lewis claimed.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Lewis, acclaimed author of \"The Big Short\" and \"Flash Boys,\" made the claim in a CBS <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.cbsnews.com\/news\/ftx-founder-sam-bankman-fried-michael-lewis-book-60-minutes-transcript\/?ftag=CNM-00-10aab7d&amp;linkId=238697261\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">interview<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;that aired Sunday.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"So he did get an answer… There was a number that was kicking around. And the number that was kicking around when I was talking to Sam about this was $5 billion,\" Lewis said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Lewis added that Bankman-Fried was also investigating whether such a payment would be legal. “The question Sam had was not just, ‘Is $5 billion enough to pay Trump not to run,’ but ‘Was it legal?’” he said.<\/span>","Mark Botnick, a spokesperson for Bankman-Fried, declined to comment on the potential payment.&nbsp;","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Prior to FTX's collapse, Bankman-Fried was as an active political donor. Federal prosecutors have reportedly <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/195992\/us-prosecutors-probing-bankman-frieds-political-donations-ny-times\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">probed his donations to both Democrat and Republican lawmakers<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bankman-Fried <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/236735\/judge-denies-motion-to-dismiss-most-charges-against-sam-bankman-fried\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">could face over 100 years in prison<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> if convicted on an array of charges including fraud in his upcoming trial, which is <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253627\/sam-bankman-frieds-trial-is-about-to-start-will-it-help-crypto-finally-move-on\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">set to begin on Tuesday<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Sunday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Mark Botnick","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$5 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Lewis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Donald Trump","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"CBS","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sam","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Michael Lewis","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["FTX","SAM BANKMAN-FRIED"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}