{"summary":"The SEC is seeking details on investors due diligence into FTX, the collapsed exchange which raised over $1.8 billion from more than 90 investors.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/199688\/sec-probes-ftx-investors-on-due-diligence-procedures-reuters","publishDate":"2023-01-06T04:07:53","id":6683,"type":null,"title":"SEC probes FTX investors on due diligence procedures: Reuters","category":["POLICY"],"content":["The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) wants to understand the due diligence process investors followed when&nbsp;it came to investing in collapsed crypto exchange FTX, according to a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.reuters.com\/technology\/us-securities-regulator-probes-ftx-investors-due-diligence-sources-2023-01-05\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Reuters report.<\/a>","The regulator is looking to understand the due diligence policies and procedures FTX investors had in place at the time and whether they followed them when they invested in the exchange, the report said, citing&nbsp;two sources familiar with the matter.","The SEC have already brought charges against three FTX executives for allegedly defrauding investors: Sam Bankman-Fried, the CEO and co-founder of FTX; Gary Wang, the CTO and co-founder of FTX and Caroline Ellison, the CEO of Alameda Research. Both Wang and Ellison have already pleaded guilty and are <a href=\"https:\/\/www.sec.gov\/news\/press-release\/2022-234\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">cooperating<\/a> with the SEC's investigation.","The Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) and the U.S. Attorney’s Office for the Southern District of New York have also brought charges against Bankman-Fried, who <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/198982\/bankman-fried-pleads-not-guilty-to-criminal-charges\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">pleaded<\/a> not guilty to fraud charges on Tuesday.","A spokesperson for the SEC declined Reuters' request for comment on the probe into investors' due diligence.","Investors could face scrutiny over whether they met their fiduciary duty to their own investors, one source said in the report.","The publication was unable to determine the number of firms that were receiving inquiries from the regulator. FTX <a href=\"https:\/\/www.crunchbase.com\/organization\/ftx-exchange\/investor_financials\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">raised<\/a> over $1.8 billion from more than 90 investors over the course of five years.","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Ellison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Caroline Ellison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wang","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1.8 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Reuters","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gary Wang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"the Southern District of New York","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CTO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["CFTC","FTX","SEC"],"authors":["Kari McMahon","The Block"]}