{"summary":"The index token, JPEGz, is based on the market capitalization of 10 popular NFT collections, according to Cryptex Finance.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/209167\/nft-index-token-launched-by-cryptex-finance","publishDate":"2023-02-07T11:00:07","id":6695,"type":null,"title":"NFT index token launched by Cryptex Finance","category":["TOKEN PROJECTS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Cross-chain DeFi provider Cryptex Finance today will launch its JPEGz token, an index token based on the market capitalization of some of the hottest NFT collections, the company said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The index comprises 10 notable NFT collections including Yuga Labs’ Bored Ape Yacht Club and CryptoPunks, and others such as CloneX, Cool Cats, Doodles, Vee Friends and World of Women, Cryptex said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The token will be directly available on the Cryptex Finance decentralized application, and may be swapped across Uniswap and Slingshot via the Layer 2 scaling network Arbitrum, Cryptex added.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Each collection’s floor prices are fed into the index via Chainlink’s NFT Floor Price Feeds oracle architecture featuring Coinbase Cloud’s aggregation algorithm.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“For the first time, users can mint price exposure to track 10 popular NFT collections using ETH or DAI without the need to hold the underlying NFT’s themselves,” said Cryptex Finance co-founder Joe Sticco.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Cryptex Finance launched its <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/90641\/defi-project-offers-new-way-to-trade-the-entire-1-trillion-crypto-market\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TCAP<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> token, an index token based on over 2,000 cryptocurrencies, in 2021.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Joe Sticco","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Cryptex Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Vee Friends and World of Women","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bored Ape Yacht Club","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT Floor Price Feeds oracle","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coinbase Cloud","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DAI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cryptex","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["ARBITRUM","BAYC","CRYPTOPUNKS","DOODLES"],"authors":["Jeremy Nation","The Block"]}