{"summary":"Most recently general counsel at Pantera, Joseph Cisewski has previously worked at both the CFTC and SEC. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/159742\/panteras-general-counsel-joins-cftc-staff-as-commission-work-recenters-around-crypto","publishDate":"2022-07-26T16:39:18","id":6705,"type":null,"title":"Pantera&#x27;s general counsel joins CFTC staff as commission work recenters around crypto","category":["THE BLOCK"],"content":["A former legal leader from the crypto world is joining the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC).&nbsp;","On July 26, CFTC Commissioner Christy Goldsmith Romero <a href=\"https:\/\/www.cftc.gov\/PressRoom\/PressReleases\/8564-22?utm_source=govdelivery\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/a> that she has hired Joseph Cisewski as chief of staff and senior counsel.&nbsp;","Cisewski most recently served as general counsel for Pantera Capital, a crypto-focused venture capital and hedge fund that <a href=\"https:\/\/panteracapital.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reports<\/a> it has over $5.1 billion in assets under management. In a statement, Goldsmith Romero highlighted these credentials.“His fluency on digital-asset and other issues will be valuable as the Technology Advisory Committee embarks on its agenda later this year,” she said.","A former employee of the CFTC, he worked under then-Commissioner Mark Wetjen, who now <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/123003\/ftx-us-hires-gensler-era-cftc-commissioner-to-spearhead-lobbying\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">heads crypto exchange FTX's<\/a> government relations.&nbsp;","Just yesterday, CFTC Chair Rostin Behnam announced that the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/159563\/cftc-will-evolve-labcftc-hub-into-office-of-technology-innovation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">commission was expanding<\/a> its long-standing fintech wing, LabCFTC, into the Office of Technology Innovation. The CFTC has spent much of 2022 <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/133644\/before-senate-cftc-cites-crypto-as-basis-for-biggest-expansion-since-dodd-frank\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">arguing for a bigger role<\/a> in crypto regulation, alongside a corresponding budget and staffing expansion. The crypto industry, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/159545\/led-by-exchanges-crypto-industry-lobbying-grew-17-in-q2-despite-bear-market\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">especially the major exchanges<\/a>, have become increasingly supportive.","Pantera, meanwhile, recently <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/147668\/terra-pantera-capital-cashed-out-80-investment-before-ust-crash\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">lost significant holdings<\/a> in Luna and Terra, as the stablecoin and associated token collapsed.&nbsp;","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Technology Advisory Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Goldsmith Romero","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"July 26","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Luna","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$5.1 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Christy Goldsmith Romero","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Pantera Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"CFTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Joseph Cisewski","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Terra","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"crypto exchange FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Office of Technology Innovation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mark Wetjen","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["CFTC","FTX"],"authors":["Kollen Post","The Block"]}