{"summary":"Binance says it hired an executive with compliance experience to serve as its UK director.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/185614\/binance-hires-uk-director-invokes-need-to-comply-with-regulators","publishDate":"2022-11-10T15:28:00","id":6751,"type":null,"title":"Binance hires UK director, invokes need to comply with regulators","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">While flagging efforts to remain above board in the United Kingdom, Binance announced it hired a new director. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In a LinkedIn post, Binance Regional Manager of Europe and the UK Ilir Laro said his company picked Nish Patel to be a director.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n\"Our main focus will be to register and comply with the UK's Financial Conduct Authority to operate a regulated crypto-asset business in the UK,\" Laro wrote.&nbsp;<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In the wake of crypto exchange FTX’s seismic collapse, regulating the trading of digital assets has quickly become a central topic among the crypto industry. At one point Binance, the world’s largest crypto currency exchange, intended to take over the flailing FTX but then walked away.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nPatel previously worked in compliance for both the cryptocurrency platform Rain and Hamilton Capital Holding, according to his LinkedIn profile.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Binance Regional Manager of Europe","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UK's Financial Conduct Authority","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ilir Laro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nish Patel","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Laro","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hamilton Capital Holding","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"United Kingdom","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["COINBASE"],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}