{"summary":"FTX sought assistance from a U.S. bankruptcy court in an ongoing fight over ownership of about $450 million in Robinhood Markets stock.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/197657\/ftx-bankruptcy-robinhood-shares","publishDate":"2022-12-23T04:44:35","id":6752,"type":null,"title":"FTX asks court for help in battle over $450 million in Robinhood shares","category":["BANKRUPTCY"],"content":["Defunct crypto exchange FTX has sought assistance from a U.S. bankruptcy court in an ongoing fight over ownership of about $450 million in Robinhood Markets stock.","Specifically, 56 million shares are owned by Emergent Fidelity Technologies, an entity 90% owned by disgraced FTX founder and former CEO Sam Bankman-Fried and organized in Antigua and Barbuda, according to <a href=\"https:\/\/storage.courtlistener.com\/recap\/gov.uscourts.deb.188450\/gov.uscourts.deb.188450.291.0.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">a court filing<\/a>.","The parties trying to gain control of the Robinhood shares — frozen on brokerage ED&amp;F Man Capital Markets in November — are failed crypto lender BlockFi, FTX creditor Yonathan Ben Shimon and Bankman-Fried.","\"The fact that multiple prepetition creditors of different Debtors and Mr. Bankman-Fried are all seeking to obtain possession of the Robinhood Shares demonstrates that the asset should be frozen until this Court can resolve the issues in a manner that is fair to all creditors of the Debtors,\" FTX said.","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"90%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$450 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Robinhood Markets","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Antigua","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Robinhood","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Emergent Fidelity Technologies","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Yonathan Ben Shimon","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Robinhood Shares","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Barbuda","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["BANKRUPTCY FILINGS","FTX","ROBINHOOD"],"authors":["Adam James","The Block"]}