{"summary":"The cryptocurrency market kicked off October in the green, with bitcoin rising above the $28,000 mark and ether nearing the $1,700 mark.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253787\/bitcoin-sees-early-october-gains-as-it-rises-above-28000","publishDate":"2023-10-02T14:24:09","id":6795,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin sees early October gains as it rises above $28,000","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["The cryptocurrency market kicked off October in the green, with bitcoin rising above the $28,000 mark and ether briefly breaking above the $1,700 mark, for the first time since late August.","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitcoin <\/span><span class=\"articleTooltip\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"\/price\/248348\/bitcoin-btc-usd\" class=\"articleTooltip__link\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"><img src=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2023\/10\/bitcoin.png\" alt=\"\" title=\"\" class=\"articleTooltip__tokenImage\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">BTC<\/span> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText articleTooltip__tokenText_price articleTooltip__tokenText_negative\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">\n      -0.71%\n    <\/span><\/a> <!----><\/span><\/span> climbed around 3% to hover around $28,000 at 1:00 p.m. ET, according to <\/span><\/span><a class=\"editor-rtfLink\" href=\"https:\/\/www.coingecko.com\/en\/coins\/bitcoin\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CoinGecko<\/span><\/a><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. The world's largest digital asset by market capitalization seemed at first glance to be correlating with rising tech stocks. <\/span>The tech-heavy Nasdaq and the S&amp;P 500 gained on Monday, as investors digested the news of a last-minute deal that averted a partial U.S. government shutdown.","However, data from The Block showed that since September 18, bitcoin's correlation metric has not exceeded 0.2 or -0.2, indicating essentially no correlation between the digital asset and major equity indices.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BTC Pearson Correlation (The Block's Data Dashboard)<\/span>","Ether gained 0.2% in the past 24 hours <span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">to change hands at $1,684<\/span><\/span>, <span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">at 1:00 p.m. ET. The second largest digital asset by market capitalization was <\/span>spurred on by investor anticipation following the introduction of several ether futures ETFs. Products offered by <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253947\/ether-futures-etfs-from-proshares-vaneck-and-others-go-live\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">VanEck<\/a>, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/243372\/valkyrie-btf-bitcoin-ether-etf-convert\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Valkyrie<\/a>, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/243157\/proshares-bitwise-bitcoin-ether-etf-applications\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ProShares<\/a>, and <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253643\/bitwise-intends-to-begin-trading-ether-futures-etfs-on-monday\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitwise<\/a> became available to investors on Monday. These are the first ETFs to be established based on ether futures, arriving nearly two years after the debut of the first bitcoin futures ETF.","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Haven1 Foundation Director Akash Mahendra <\/span>forecasted that the Security &amp; Exchange Commission's approval will usher in \"a new era where Ethereum becomes increasingly mainstream.\"","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"This landmark decision by the SEC not only showcases Ethereum’s rising prominence but also signals a profound shift in the regulatory landscape,\" he added in a note sent to The Block.<\/span>","Yield App CIO Lucas Kiely said that October is typically a good month for the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/244938\/crypto-asset-risk-banking-system-fdic\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">cryptocurrency<\/a> market.","\"It is dubbed 'uptober' by market insiders, and only twice since 2013 has bitcoin closed at a loss in October,\" Kiely added in a note sent to The Block. But he added, \"It is likely a little too early to get excited by these current price movements, it is unlikely to be the beginning of a significant rally without any other catalysts to drive it.\"","Additionally, he pointed out that investors will be reminded of crypto's vulnerabilities as the \"Sam Bankman-Fried trial will soon make its way into mainstream headlines.\"","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bitwise","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2013","content":"DATE"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"S&amp;P","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1:00 p.m. ET","content":"TIME"},{"type":"-0.71%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"VanEck","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Lucas Kiely","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$1,700","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Foundation Director Akash Mahendra","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"3%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$1,684","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Security &amp; Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"0.2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Kiely","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Valkyrie","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$28,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"September 18","content":"DATE"},{"type":"CoinGecko","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"October","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Nasdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BTC Pearson Correlation (The Block's Data Dashboard)","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["ANALYST REPORTS","CRYPTO MOVERS","ECONOMIC INDICATORS","EQUITY MOVERS","FTX"],"authors":["Brian McGleenon","The Block"]}