{"summary":"The launch means users and developers can now access Evmos as a Layer 1 blockchain on Cosmos.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/143771\/evmos-launches-blockchain-to-bring-ethereum-virtual-machine-to-cosmos","publishDate":"2022-04-28T07:58:19","id":6844,"type":null,"title":"Evmos launches blockchain to bring Ethereum Virtual Machine to Cosmos","category":["LAYER 1S"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">After years of development, <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Evmos <\/span><span class=\"articleTooltip\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"\/price\/257160\/evmos-evmos-usd\" class=\"articleTooltip__link\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"><img src=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2023\/10\/evmos.png\" alt=\"\" title=\"\" class=\"articleTooltip__tokenImage\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">EVMOS<\/span> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText articleTooltip__tokenText_price articleTooltip__tokenText_negative\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">\n      -4.66%\n    <\/span><\/a> <!----><\/span><\/span> (formerly called Ethermint) went live on the Cosmos network, its developers <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/EvmosOrg\/status\/1519373707134877697\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/a> Wednesday. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The launch means users and developers can now access Evmos as a Layer 1 blockchain on Cosmos — an interoperability protocol whose <a href=\"https:\/\/cosmos.network\/ecosystem\/apps\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ecosystem<\/a> contains more than 250 apps and services. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In particular, the Evmos launch allows users to deploy smart contracts and assets from Ethereum and use them in the Cosmos ecosystem.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The newly-launched <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/133926\/airdrop-for-ethereum-cosmos-power-users-set-to-take-place-next-week\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Evmos<\/a> was first conceptualized in 2016 as Ethermint. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">What’s different about Evmos is that unlike most other Cosmos chains, it is fully compatible with the Ethereum Virtual Machine. This is a computing environment used by developers on the Ethereum blockchain. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">By integrating the EVM mechanism, the team hopes to make it more appealing to Ethereum developers. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Over the last year, EVM has become the most widely adopted standard for smart contracts, and is now found across a number of blockchains trying to replicate Ethereum's success. These include <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/141911\/ava-labs-avalanche-raising-350-million-5-25-billion-valuation-report\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Avalanche<\/a>, Polygon, BNB Chain, Fantom and Moonbeam.<\/span>","To kick-start its ambitions, the Evmos developers plan to first achieve interoperability with Ethereum through <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockresearch.com\/an-overview-of-cross-chain-bridges-in-defi-106959\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">bridges<\/a>. The team is working with bridge applications including <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/142663\/connext-unveils-token-next-airdrop-blockchain-interoperability\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Connext<\/a>, Celer, Nomad and others so token transfers can be made between the two chains.","“Through these bridges, crypto users will be able to move assets to Evmos and use them within is applications,” Federico Kunze Küllmer, the co-founder of Evmos, told The Block.&nbsp;","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">There are plans to expand within the Cosmos ecosystem as well. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Using a protocol called Inter-Blockchain Communication (IBC), this <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">blockchain has the ability to share data and assets with other Cosmos-enabled chains. <\/span>","There are also applications set to launch on Evmos — decentralized exchanges, money markets and NFTs, including QuantumSwap, Diffusion Finance, Nomad, Coslend and others.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Connext","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2016","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Polygon","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Nomad","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ethereum Virtual Machine","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Moonbeam","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"IBC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fantom","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cosmos","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"-4.66%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"EVM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Diffusion Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Federico Kunze Küllmer","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["COSMOS","ETHEREUM","SMART CONTRACTS"],"authors":["Vishal Chawla","The Block"]}