{"summary":"Potentially impacted parties are listed in an FTX filing in the defunct crypto exchange&#x27;s ongoing Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection filings.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/188140\/jpmorgan-chase-wells-fargo-among-potentially-exposed-ftx-parties","publishDate":"2022-11-17T15:44:03","id":6865,"type":null,"title":"JPMorgan Chase, Wells Fargo among potentially exposed FTX parties","category":["LEGAL"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">FTX&nbsp; has named Kroll Restructuring Administration as its agent as it navigates the federal bankruptcy process and cited dozens of companies and people affected by its collapse, a petition filed by the exchange shows.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kroll is to act as a claims and noticing agent, often assigned to cases where creditors are in excess of 1,000 parties. As claims agent, Kroll will liaise between entities in the legal proceedings, managing documentation and preparing and serving related notices. FTX filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection on Nov. 11 in the U.S. Bankruptcy Court for the District of Delaware.&nbsp;<\/span>","Following the filing, FTX Group announced over Twitter that it established Kroll as its claims agent, and provided <a href=\"https:\/\/cases.ra.kroll.com\/FTX\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">a link<\/a> to where related documents filed to the U.S. Bankruptcy Court may be accessed.","The documents provide a preliminary list of claims depicting outstanding millions owed to parties such as Bankhaus Scheich Wertpapierspezialist, Blockchainfonds, Ethereal Tech, as well as entities whose names remain “on file.”","","","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The filing would also appear to be a preliminary attempt to establish a list of creditors exposed to the collapse of FTX, although it remains unclear as to the specific extent of each party’s involvement with the fallen exchange.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The list “is based on the Debtors’ currently available information of creditors and does not include any information regarding the Debtors’ customers,” a footnote in the document reads, continuing, “Additionally, the Debtors’ professionals have not yet had the opportunity to independently verify certain of the roles, titles and affiliate relationships with respect to the parties listed herein and will supplement as necessary.”<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The document names individuals and organizations ranging from equity holders of 5% or more, bankruptcy judges, professionals, banks lenders and administrative agents, contract counterparties and debtors. Also named are directors, officers, known affiliates, ordinary course professionals and landlords, as well as parties related to insurance, litigation, and finally governmental regulatory and tax agencies.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Currently it remains unclear as to the extent of the named organizations role in the collapse beyond the categorization.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A small selection of persons of interest includes:<\/span>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Disclaimer: The Block Crypto is listed as a vendor of FTX<\/em>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Update: This story has been updated to include financial entities other than banks in the subheading above.<\/em>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S. Bankruptcy Court","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kroll","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kroll Restructuring Administration","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ethereal Tech","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block Crypto","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kroll","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nov. 11","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bankhaus Scheich Wertpapierspezialist","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"the District of Delaware","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Blockchainfonds","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["COURT HEARINGS","FTX"],"authors":["Jeremy Nation","The Block"]}