{"summary":"Haun Ventures announced that it led a $10 million seed round for San Francisco-based Argus Labs, a crypto game developer and publisher.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/233252\/haun-ventures-argus-labs","publishDate":"2023-06-06T12:00:47","id":6880,"type":null,"title":"Haun Ventures leads $10 million investment in Argus Labs","category":["VENTURE CAPITAL"],"content":["Haun Ventures today announced that it led a $10 million seed round for San Francisco-based Argus Labs, a crypto game developer and publisher.","Concurrently, Argus launched its World Engine, a new blockchain-based software development kit designed to help other developers build and customize interoperable game worlds.","In a blog post published today, Argus Labs founder Scott Sunarto, who previously created the game Dark Forest as a teenager, said that while “online games were born from the internet, they are siloed, cut off from the vast potential of a connected universe.”&nbsp;He views World Engine — an “open-source, connected layer 2 of sharded blockchains that will serve as the backbone for the Internet of Games” — as a solution, according to today’s announcement.","Haun Ventures, the venture capital firm founded by former Andreessen Horowitz general partner Katie Haun, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/138836\/katie-haun-crypto-vc-fundraise\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">raised $1.5 billion for two crypto investment funds<\/a> in early 2022 —&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/221441\/sam-rosenblum-haun-ventures-profile-billion-dollar-crypto-vc-machine\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">much of which it is yet to deploy<\/a>.","Other angel investors in tech and gaming — including Elad Gil, Balaji Srinivasan and Siqi Chen, Kevin Aluwi, Sunny Agarwal, Calvin Liu and Scott Moore — also participated in the round, alongside Robot Ventures, Anagram and Dispersion Capital.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"San Francisco","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Argus","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kevin Aluwi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Katie Haun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sunny Agarwal","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Scott Sunarto","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Argus Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Balaji Srinivasan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$1.5 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Scott Moore","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Haun Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Andreessen Horowitz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Siqi Chen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Calvin Liu","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$10 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Elad Gil","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dispersion Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["SEED &AMP; PRE-SEED"],"authors":["Ryan Weeks","The Block"]}