{"summary":"Upbit, South Korea’s largest crypto exchange, received the initial nod from the MAS to offer a wider range of Digital Payment Token services.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/256581\/upbit-initial-approval-digital-asset-license-singapore","publishDate":"2023-10-16T00:33:26","id":6882,"type":null,"title":"Upbit obtains initial approval for digital asset license in Singapore","category":["REGULATION"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Upbit, a South Korean crypto exchange owned by Dunamu, has obtained in-principle approval from the Monetary Authority of Singapore through a local entity, the company said today.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">It said in a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.prnewswire.com\/apac\/news-releases\/upbit-singapore-secures-in-principle-approval-from-the-mas-301954702.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">statement<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that the initial approval for a Major Payment Institution license to Upbit Singapore Pte. Ltd. allows it to continue providing relevant services while awaiting the grant of the full license.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Since 2018, we have been building solid foundations for a robust digital asset business in Singapore, the leading financial hub in Asia,” Alex Kim, founder and CEO of Upbit Singapore, said in the statement. “This approval from MAS is a strategic milestone for us to deepen our presence in Singapore, which is at the forefront of digital asset innovation. Singapore, as our global powerhouse, unlocks new capabilities for retail, institutional, and infrastructure-focused businesses.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Earlier this month, Coinbase was <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253755\/coinbase-granted-full-license-in-singapore\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">granted the full MPI license<\/span><\/a> —<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;nearly a year after it <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/176064\/crypto-exchange-coinbase-gets-license-in-singapore\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">obtained in-principle approval<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In June, Circle also <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/233409\/circle-mpi-singapore\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">received an MPI license<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, allowing its affiliate, Circle Internet Singapore, to offer digital payment token services, and cross-border and domestic money transfer services in the city-state.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"MPI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"today","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Asia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Monetary Authority","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alex Kim","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"June","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Circle","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Upbit Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"MAS","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dunamu","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Upbit Singapore Pte. Ltd.","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["ASIAN REGULATION"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}