{"summary":"Federal Reserve Chair Jerome Powell stated that he will not push forward a U.S. central bank digital currency for the time being. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/173111\/the-fed-has-not-decided-to-proceed-with-a-digital-dollar-says-powell","publishDate":"2022-09-27T11:57:54","id":6885,"type":null,"title":"The Fed has &#x27;not decided to proceed&#x27; with a digital dollar, says Powell","category":["REGULATION"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Jerome Powell, chair of the Federal Reserve, shut down expectations for <\/span>a U.S. central bank digital currency (CBDC) to be issued in the near future.&nbsp;","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The central bank leader said that the U.S. has “not decided to proceed” with the issuance of a CBDC for the time being. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"We do not see ourselves making that decision for some time,\" <\/span>he said Tuesday, speaking remotely on a panel about the role of central banks in digital markets during a conference in Paris.","Instead, the U.S. central bank will be working in collaboration with Congress and the executive branch to evaluate the policy and the technological issues.&nbsp;","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Powell went on to outline a multi-year period during which the Fed would focus on \"building public confidence in our analysis and ultimate conclusions, which we certainly haven’t reached yet.” <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Powell did elaborate that, if adopted, a U.S. CBDC would have several key characteristics: intermediated, privacy-protected, identity-verified, and interoperable.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"We would be looking to balance privacy protection with identity verification, which has to be done in today’s traditional banking system as well,\" <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Powell said referring to the <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.federalreserve.gov\/publications\/files\/money-and-payments-20220120.pdf\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">discussion paper<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> issued in January this year, where the Federal Reserve took the first step towards a CBDC.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Earlier this month, Federal Reserve Vice Chair Lael Brainard <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/168366\/fed-needs-to-answer-key-questions-around-digital-dollar-brainard\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that the central bank was seeking answers to questions that would determine the need for a CBDC.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">At a New York conference hosted by the Bank Policy Institute, Brainard emphasized that the Fed’s investigation will determine the future financial system infrastructure, but said that a digital dollar&nbsp; is not \"particularly relevant today.\"<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Federal Reserve","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Fed","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Paris","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Lael Brainard","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Congress","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Earlier this month","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Powell","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"January this year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Jerome Powell","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Brainard","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bank Policy Institute","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["FEDERAL RESERVE","JEROME POWELL"],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}