{"summary":"Binance has resumed processing withdrawals requests of the USD Coin (USDC) stablecoin after pausing them for several hours.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/194511\/binance-resumes-usdc-stablecoin-withdrawals-after-temporary-pause","publishDate":"2022-12-13T12:15:10","id":6899,"type":null,"title":"Binance resumes USDC stablecoin withdrawals after temporary pause","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance has resumed processing withdrawal requests of the USD Coin (USDC) stablecoin after pausing them for several hours.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance, the world's largest cryptocurrency exchange platform by daily volume, temporarily stopped processing USDC withdrawals due to inadequate USDC reserves on the platform, <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/cz_binance\/status\/1602579499903852544\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">according<\/a> to <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance CEO Changpeng Zhao<\/span>.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance holds a large majority of its stablecoin holdings, more than $11.5 billion in Paxos-issued BUSD, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/portfolio.nansen.ai\/dashboard\/binance\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">according<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to Nansen data.&nbsp;<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">To increase its USDC reserves, it made efforts to swap its BUSD holdings with USDC. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">However, any token swaps into USDC required routing funds through a New York bank which was not yet open, Zhao said. This hindered the exchange's ability to process these transactions, so the exchange temporarily<\/span> <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/binance\/status\/1602579775721283584\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">paused<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> USDC withdrawals while it conducted a token swap.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Users have been withdrawing large amounts of funds from Binance, including USDC and other stablecoins. Since yesterday, Binance has seen a net outflow of over $2 billion in various crypto assets, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/Merkle3_\/status\/1602620827924631552\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">according to<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> estimates from Simon Cousaert, director of data at The Block.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance claims to hold more than<\/span> <a href=\"https:\/\/portfolio.nansen.ai\/dashboard\/binance\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$60 billion<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> worth of assets across all of its wallets.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$11.5 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Binance","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Paxos","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Changpeng Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nansen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Simon Cousaert","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"USDC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$60 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"USD Coin (USDC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$2 billion","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE"],"authors":["Vishal Chawla","The Block"]}