{"summary":"Agencies are looking into whether FTX&#x27;s U.S. subsidiary violated exchange law, and its connections with other organizations.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/185129\/justice-department-joins-sec-in-ftx-probe-wsj","publishDate":"2022-11-09T21:10:58","id":6913,"type":null,"title":"Justice Department joins SEC in FTX probe: WSJ","category":["LEGAL"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">For collapsed cryptocurrency exchange FTX, legal troubles are mounting. <\/span>","The Department of Justice (DoJ) and the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) are working together to investigate FTX’s U.S. subsidiary, <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Wall Street Journal reported, citing an unnamed person familiar with the matter.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">FTX, now facing <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/185068\/ftx-tells-investors-bankruptcy-is-likely-without-fresh-cash-bloomberg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">potential bankruptcy<\/a>, has garnered the attention of multiple regulators. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Amid the expansion of the SEC’s months-long probe into whether assets on FTX.us may be considered securities, the agency is in close contact with the DoJ, the newspaper reported. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">If the SEC determines the assets in question to be securities, it would mean FTX may have violated U.S. exchange laws.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Regulators also are turning their attention to the relationship between FTX.us and its Caribbean parent company, as well as the nature of its connections to trading firm Alameda Research.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Caribbean","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DoJ","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Department of Justice (DoJ","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Jeremy Nation","The Block"]}