{"summary":"Music stars Diplo, DJ Khaled, Martin Garrix and Future have bought Bored Ape Yacht Club NFTs via MoonPay’s ‘concierge service’. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/126088\/nft-moonpay","publishDate":"2021-12-02T09:49:30","id":6940,"type":null,"title":"Diplo, DJ Khaled, Future and Martin Garrix buy NFTs through MoonPay","category":["NFTS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Music stars Diplo, DJ Khaled, Martin Garrix and Future have bought NFTs from the Bored Ape Yacht Club collection via MoonPay’s ‘concierge service’.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In the last week, all four musicians have changed their profile pictures on either Twitter or Instagram to flaunt their purchases.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Yesterday, alongside changing his profile picture to Bored Ape #5384, producer Diplo tweeted <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/diplo\/status\/1466157259252240395\/photo\/1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">a Spotify Wrapped image featuring the item.<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> On November 28, rapper <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/1future\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Future posted #4672 with the caption ‘gm’.&nbsp;<\/span><\/a>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">All of these items from the Bored Ape Yacht Club can be traced back to <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/opensea.io\/0xd75233704795206de38cc58b77a1f660b5c60896?tab=activity\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">MoonPay’s OpenSea account.<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> The account page shows that each of the pieces was bought by MoonPay and later transferred to another address.&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Of the four stars, only Diplo has a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/opensea.io\/diplo\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">named OpenSea address,<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;but a person close to the situation confirmed that the other addresses are affiliated with the other stars and that MoonPay facilitated the purchases.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Last week, The Block revealed that MoonPay had quietly launched a ‘concierge’ service targeting&nbsp;<\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/125483\/moonpay-concierge-celebrities-nft\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">high-net individuals interested in buying digital collectables and crypto.<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Its first customers included rappers Lil Baby, Post Malone and talk show host Jimmy Fallon.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Yet aside from transferring the NFTs to clients and invoicing them, the exact mechanics of how concierge deals are negotiated remain unclear.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The nature of the deals has drawn scepticism from crypto Twitter, with <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/RyanJamesWeeks\/status\/1463988549234085894\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">users questioning the relationship<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> between the artists and MoonPay.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CEO and co-founder Ivan Soto-Wright recently confirmed that he first met Fallon at NFT.NYC, and it was during this meeting that the host agreed to shout out the payments company on his show, according to Soto-Wright. A MoonPay spokesperson confirmed last week that the company has no commercial relationship with Fallon.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The addition of four more celebrities to MoonPay's client roster suggests the service is gaining traction in the wake of the company’s <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/125483\/moonpay-concierge-celebrities-nft\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$555 million Series A round,<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;which was led by Tiger Global and Coatue.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Soto","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tiger Global","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"4672","content":"DATE"},{"type":"MoonPay spokesperson","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bored Ape Yacht Club","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coatue","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$555 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"November 28","content":"DATE"},{"type":"MoonPay’s OpenSea","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ivan Soto","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Diplo","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jimmy Fallon","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"last week","content":"DATE"},{"type":"5384","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Wright","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"MoonPay","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Martin Garrix","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Post Malone","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Fallon","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["PAYMENTS"],"authors":["Tom Matsuda","Ryan Weeks","The Block"]}