{"summary":"It is the one thing the entire cryptocurrency market is anticipating: the bitcoin halving. In this episode of The Scoop. we welcome GSR Trading cofounder Rich Rosenblum to dig into the halving.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/62613\/gsrs-rich-rosenblum-digs-into-bitcoins-upcoming-halving","publishDate":"2020-04-22T17:56:20","id":6980,"type":null,"title":"GSR&#x27;s Rich Rosenblum digs into bitcoin&#x27;s upcoming halving","category":["BITCOIN"],"content":["<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 14 of Season 2 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with Frank Chaparro and Rich Rosenblum, co-founder of GSR Trading.&nbsp;<\/em>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/a>, or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to&nbsp;<a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection#90e0fff4f3f1e3e4d0e4f8f5f2fcfff3fbf3e2e9e0e4ffbef3fffd\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"3e4e515a5d5f4d4a7e4a565b5c52515d555d4c474e4a51105d5153\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/span><\/a><\/em>","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK4053958076\" width=\"100%\" height=\"200\" frameborder=\"0\" scrolling=\"no\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","It is the one thing the entire cryptocurrency space is anticipating: the bitcoin block reward halving.","In 19 days, the number of bitcoin released with each block reward will drop from 12.5 to 6.25, a 50% cut in supply.","This will be the third halving in bitcoin's lifetime and it has market participants across crypto speculating about the potential ramifications. Namely, whether it will result in a pop in bitcoin's price or whether it is priced in.","In this episode of The Scoop, we welcome GSR Trading co-founder Rich Rosenblum to dig into the halving. Rosenblum, who spent ten years at Goldman Sachs trading oil, kicked things off with the firm's transition from a programmatic trading firm in a retail driven market into a broker offering bespoke products to help miners hedge their risks.","We also discuss:&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"GSR","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Rich Rosenblum","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Goldman Sachs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Rosenblum","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"50%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN","MINING"],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}