{"summary":"Tracing bitcoin records, which was used to pay for fraud website services, allowed the Metropolitan Police unit to narrow down suspects. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/189816\/uks-biggest-ever-scam-leads-to-100-arrests-after-police-track-bitcoin-records","publishDate":"2022-11-24T12:21:40","id":6990,"type":null,"title":"UK’s &#x27;biggest ever&#x27; scam leads to 100 arrests after police track bitcoin records","category":["LEGAL"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">More than 100 people were arrested in what the London’s Metropolitan Police <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/news.met.police.uk\/news\/more-than-100-arrests-in-uks-biggest-ever-fraud-operation-457840\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">calls<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> “the UK’s biggest ever fraud operation” after taking down a fraud website called iSpoof used on 200,000 potential victims in Britain alone.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">iSpoof allowed scammers to pose as officials from banks such as Barclays, Santander, HSBC, Lloyds, Halifax, First Direct, Natwest, Nationwide and TSB. Criminals paid for the service in bitcoin, according to the police report.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Scotland Yard’s Cyber Crime Unit worked in cross-national cooperation, including authorities in the U.S. and Ukraine, to take down the site this week. In a 20-month period, the Met police claims the operation earned the criminals almost £3.2 million ($3.9 million).<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Cyber Crime Unit began investigating iSpoof in June 2021, and were able to trace bitcoin records. With almost 60,000 users on iSpoof, the investigation team narrowed suspects down to UK users who spent at least £100 worth of bitcoin on the site.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“The exploitation of technology by organized criminals is one of the greatest challenges for law enforcement in the 21<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">st<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> century,” said Commissioner Mark Rowley in the police statement.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The UK arrests may be followed up in other countries as a list of suspects was handed over to authorities in the Netherlands, Australia, France and Ireland.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"June 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"HSBC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"France","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"the Netherlands","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Britain","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"TSB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Scotland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Halifax","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Australia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Lloyds","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"London","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"First Direct","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$3.9 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Mark Rowley","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ireland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Barclays","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Natwest, Nationwide","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ukraine","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["CRIME"],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}