{"summary":"Coinbase has hired a big voice from the market structure world to lead its capital markets division ahead of the company&#x27;s much-anticipated direct listing on Nasdaq. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/99865\/coinbase-hires-former-sec-director-brett-redfearn-as-capital-markets-lead","publishDate":"2021-03-30T15:01:24","id":7082,"type":null,"title":"Coinbase hires former SEC director Brett Redfearn as capital markets lead","category":["CAPITAL MARKETS"],"content":["<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockresearch.com\/analysis-a-majority-of-coinbases-volume-is-still-dominated-by-four-assets-despite-the-exchange-adding-over-a-dozen-new-tokens-35448\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Coinbase<\/a> has hired a big voice from the market structure world to lead its capital markets division ahead of the company's much-anticipated direct listing on Nasdaq.&nbsp;","Former Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) director Brett Redfearn—who is best known for his contributions to policy proposals within market structure oversight—is <a href=\"https:\/\/blog.coinbase.com\/coinbase-hires-brett-redfearn-as-vp-capital-markets-41df20c7a934\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">taking on the role<\/a> of VP of capital markets at <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockresearch.com\/mapping-out-coinbases-acquisitions-and-investments-7878\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Coinbase<\/a> this week.","Redfearn, who left the SEC in December, previously was the global head of market structure at JPMorgan. As director of its division of trading and markets, Redfearn oversaw exchanges, high-frequency trading firms, and other brokers. He has sided against exchanges in US equities on issues like rising market data costs.","During his time with the agency, the SEC adopted new rules that aimed at <a href=\"https:\/\/www.thetradenews.com\/us-to-decentralise-sip-model-and-add-depth-of-book-data-in-major-overhaul\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">increasing competition<\/a> in the market data ecosystem.&nbsp;","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockresearch.com\/analyzing-coinbases-asset-exploration-announcements-40733\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Coinbase<\/a> is set to go public next month. Along with the broader market for cryptocurrencies, the firm has seen its assets on the platform cross $90 billion by the end of the year.&nbsp;","Redfearn will report to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockresearch.com\/mapping-out-the-coinbase-mafia-5252\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Coinbase<\/a> chief product officer Surojit Chatterjee.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Brett Redfearn","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Former Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"this week","content":"DATE"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$90 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Redfearn","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"December","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Surojit Chatterjee","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nasdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["COINBASE","SEC"],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}