{"summary":"Bitcoin 2022 is the LARGEST Bitcoin event ever that takes place April 6th - 9th in Miami Beach, Florida. All four days will be packed with exclusive content, exciting announcements and an incredible lineup of expert bitcoin speakers and leaders.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/138400\/bitcoin-2022-is-quickly-approaching-tickets-increase-march-18","publishDate":"2022-03-18T07:09:22","id":7099,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin 2022 is Quickly Approaching, Tickets Increase March 18","category":["SPONSORED"],"content":["Bitcoin 2022 is the LARGEST Bitcoin event ever that takes place April 6th - 9th in Miami Beach, Florida. All four days will be packed with exclusive content, exciting announcements and an incredible lineup of expert bitcoin speakers and leaders.","Day 1 is Industry day for those who are looking to build a bitcoin business or career. Days 2 and 3 are general conference days featuring speakers like El Salvador President Nayib Bukele, who has promised a BIG SURPRISE, U.S. Senator Cynthia Lummis of Wyoming, thought leaders like Jordan Peterson, as well as CEOs like Michael Saylor, Elizabeth Stark, Jack Mallers, Adam Back and hundreds more.","The conference caps off with the world's first and largest Bitcoin Music Festival - Sound Money Fest headlined by rapper and fellow bitcoiner Logic, Steve Aoki, CL, Run the Jewels, San Holo, Deadmau5 and many more! Last year’s conference SOLD OUT and this year’s is on pace to be 3x larger so make sure you grab your tickets before it's too late. Visit&nbsp;<a href=\"http:\/\/b.tc\/conference\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-saferedirecturl=\"https:\/\/www.google.com\/url?q=http:\/\/b.tc\/conference&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1647646708522000&amp;usg=AOvVaw1giOXua2JMsylR0twzHkSL\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">b.tc\/conference<\/a>&nbsp;to learn more. Pay in Bitcoin to save and use promo code&nbsp;<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“MOON22”<\/b>&nbsp;for 10% off and I will see you in Miami<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">! Ticket prices increase on March 18th!<\/b>","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.b.tc\/conference\/?utm_source=Website&amp;utm_medium=cpc&amp;utm_term=theblock&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_campaign=all-tickets\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Website<\/a>","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.b.tc\/conference\/registration?utm_source=Website&amp;utm_medium=cpc&amp;utm_term=theblock&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_campaign=all-tickets\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Registration Page<\/a>","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.b.tc\/conference\/agenda?utm_source=Website&amp;utm_medium=cpc&amp;utm_term=theblock&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_campaign=all-tickets\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Agenda<\/a>","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.b.tc\/conference\/speakers?utm_source=Website&amp;utm_medium=cpc&amp;utm_term=theblock&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_campaign=all-tickets\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Speakers<\/a>","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.b.tc\/conference\/whale-pass?utm_source=Website&amp;utm_medium=cpc&amp;utm_term=theblock&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_campaign=all-tickets\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Whale Pass<\/a>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"San Holo","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Florida","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"March 18th!","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Miami","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"10%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Wyoming","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Elizabeth Stark","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bitcoin Music Festival","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jordan Peterson","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jack Mallers","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Adam Back","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nayib Bukele","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Cynthia Lummis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Steve Aoki","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Miami Beach","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Michael Saylor","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sponsored","The Block"]}