{"summary":"Anatoly Yakovenko Founder &amp; CEO of Solana Labs joins host Frank Chaparro for a deep dive into Solana.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/117205\/anatoly-yakovenko-unpacks-solanas-rise-memes-and-nft-snafus","publishDate":"2021-09-10T12:46:01","id":7100,"type":null,"title":"Anatoly Yakovenko unpacks Solana&#x27;s rise, memes, and NFT snafus","category":["PODCASTS"],"content":["Episode <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">55<\/strong> of Season 3 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block’s Frank Chaparro and Anatoly Yakovenko, Founder &amp; CEO at Solana Labs.","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"64140b000705171024100c0106080b070f07161d14100b4a070b09\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors <a href=\"http:\/\/Bakkt.com\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bakkt<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"http:\/\/kraken.com\/scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kraken<\/a>, and&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.exodus.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Exodus<\/a><\/strong>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bakkt® unlocks the $1.2+ trillion of digital assets that is currently held in cryptocurrencies, rewards and loyalty points, gaming assets and merchant stored value. We began in 2018 with the vision to bring trust and transparency to digital assets. Through the Bakkt Warehouse and Bakkt Bitcoin Futures and Options contracts, we serve institutional clients in an end-to-end regulated market with true price transparency. For consumers, Bakkt aggregates digital assets to enable instant liquidity and to empower users to trade, transfer and pay however they want. Visit <a href=\"http:\/\/Bakkt.com\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bakkt.com<\/a> for more information<\/span><\/em>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Kraken<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Whether you’re an experienced crypto trader or just starting out, Kraken has the tools to help you achieve financial freedom. With 50+ cryptocurrencies to choose from, industry-leading security and a wide variety of features to suit any investing strategy, Kraken puts the power in your hands to buy, sell and trade digital assets. Visit&nbsp;<\/em><a href=\"http:\/\/kraken.com\/scoop\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kraken.com<\/em><\/a><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;to get started today.<\/em>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Exodus<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Exodus is leading the world out of traditional finance by building beautiful and user-friendly crypto products. Forget having to learn the nuances of different cryptocurrencies. Exodus is designed for everyone and hides the complex details behind a beautiful and intuitive interface.<\/em>","&nbsp;","It has been a wild summer for blockchain project Solana.&nbsp;","From the meteoric rise in the price of its native token to technical problems facing NFTs launched on the blockchain, the project has entered the forefront.&nbsp;<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">On this episode of The Scoop, Anatoly Yakovenko Founder &amp; CEO of Solana Labs joins host Frank Chaparro for a deep dive into Solana, which some believe can compete with Ethereum despite being less decentralized.&nbsp;<\/span>","As for price specifically, <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Yakovenko admitted it doesn't always make sense.&nbsp;<\/span>","\"This is just mind-boggling that if the price of Solana doesn't make any sense, then I have no clue why Ethereum has anything in terms of its value,\" he said, adding:","\"I don't pay attention to the price so much because I have no control over it and I'm an engineer. So, like, if I can't change it, then it's just like one of these variables.\"","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Solana Labs completed a $314.2 million fundraise back in June 2021 (that amount raised is a play on the number Pi). Investors included Andreessen Horowitz, Polychain Capital, FTX via Alameda Research and CoinShares. But as of yet, Yakovenko said much of their capital raise has not been deployed. It is also known for powering Serum, the decentralized exchange launched by Sam Bankman-Fried of FTX. Solana recently launched its Metaplex NFT marketplace, which Yakovenko acknowledged experienced server issues.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Still, DeFi comes to the top of Yakovenko's mind as a core use case. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“I've really felt that finance was a place where blockchain makes sense,\" he said.<\/span>","In Yakovenko's view, users could even one day use their own hardware to tap into the network in order to access financial market data as quickly as professional trading firms with access to exchange data.","\"The network guarantees as close as possible to an impossible problem, which is that information propagates equally to everybody at the same speed,\" he said.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$1.2+ trillion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Yakovenko","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Kraken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$314.2 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Andreessen Horowitz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Anatoly Yakovenko","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Metaplex NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"June 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bakkt Warehouse","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Yakovenko","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Solana Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Anatoly Yakovenko Founder &amp; CEO of Solana Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Polychain Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"summer","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Solana","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["ETHEREUM","SOLANA"],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}