{"summary":"Crypto price soared after the market opened on Thursday, as traders responded to the Federal Reserve’s interest rate decision yesterday with a bullish sentiment.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/208068\/crypto-market-jumps-following-fed-rate-decision","publishDate":"2023-02-02T10:30:21","id":7108,"type":null,"title":"Crypto market jumps following Fed rate decision","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["Crypto prices soared after the market opened on Thursday, as traders responded to the Federal Reserve’s interest rate decision yesterday with a bullish sentiment.","Bitcoin rose 3.5% to $23,730 around 9:50 a.m. EST, according to TradingView data, pushing toward the upper bound of the $15,000-$25,000 range within which it has traded for around eight months.","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/chart\/q0HITX89\/?symbol=COINBASE%3ABTCUSD\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BTCUSD chart by TradingView<\/a>","Ether also climbed significantly by 6.4% to around $1,685. Polygon's MATIC rose 13%, Avalanche's AVAX was up 17.9%, Uniswap's UNI was up 9%, and Cardano's ADA rose 6%. BNB was also up 6%.","Dog-themed meme coins rose less dramatically, with Dogecoin and Shiba Inu up 2.4% and 4.2%, respectively.&nbsp;","\"We are seeing some positive correlation in crypto with the rally in risk assets,\" says Stephane Oullette, CEO of FRNT Financial.","Because the FOMC decision was \"incrementally dovish,\" Oullette said, it has partially validated the thesis, among some speculators, that \"bitcoin has bottomed.\"","Crypto-related stocks also rose significantly after the market opened.","Silvergate shares rose 21.6% to around $19 by 10 a.m., according to Nasdaq data, rising alongside most other crypto stocks.","Jack Dorsey's Block increased 4.2% to trade around $87, while MicroStrategy increased 4.6%. Coinbase was up significantly, increasing by 10%.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Federal Reserve","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"6%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"TradingView","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FRNT Financial","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"10%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Oullette","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$15,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$19","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"13%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$23,730","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$25,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Shiba Inu","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"9%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"3.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"6.4%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"17.9%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Cardano","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Dogecoin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$87","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"4.6%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2.4%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"10 a.m.","content":"TIME"},{"type":"Uniswap","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"4.2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$1,685","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"9:50 a.m. EST","content":"TIME"},{"type":"AVAX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Stephane Oullette","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jack Dorsey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FOMC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ADA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"21.6%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"MicroStrategy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nasdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["EQUITY MOVERS"],"authors":["Sam Venis","The Block"]}