{"summary":"On this week&#x27;s episode of The Scoop, CEO of Pantera Capital Dan Morehead says crypto is at an inflection point with so many institutions looking to bitcoin.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/92617\/pantera-capital-ceo-bitcoins-institutional-adoption","publishDate":"2021-01-26T14:35:48","id":7131,"type":null,"title":"Pantera Capital CEO says bitcoin adoption is changing the crypto narrative","category":["PODCASTS"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 5 of Season 3 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block’s Frank Chaparro and Dan Morehead, CEO of Pantera Capital.&nbsp;<\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"31415e555250424571455954535d5e525a52434841455e1f525e5c\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode of The Scoop is brought to you by Blockset. With&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/newsletter.theblockcrypto.com\/l\/7ongM1BS4pW2oMzRHwneMw\/V1Ujzkd447eIMGZOacS39Q\/r7uLQEbKLnxHG2n9jmci4Q\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Blockset<\/a>, companies gain access to tools such as:<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">1. A highly scalable API that supports Bitcoin, Ethereum, Ripple, and other top chains<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n2. AML\/KYC data expediting time to market by complying with legal requirements<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n3. Leading custody solutions using modern multi-party compute (MPC) technology&nbsp;<\/i>","<a href=\"https:\/\/blockset.com\/?utm_source=theblocknewsletter&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=theblocknlhomepage&amp;utm_term=newsletthomepage&amp;utm_content=20201125-feed-theblock\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Learn more and start building&nbsp;<span class=\"sh-date\" tabindex=\"0\" data-date-isostring=\"2021-01-11T20:00:00.000Z\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">today<\/span><\/a>.&nbsp;","&nbsp;","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK3933280354\" width=\"100%\" height=\"200\" frameborder=\"0\" scrolling=\"no\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Pantera Capital's CEO Dan Morehead says initial coin offerings (ICO) aren't dead, but the investment world is shifting toward a narrative dominated by Bitcoina nd Ethereum.","\"Crypto as a market is so volatile that the narrative changes,\" said Morehead on this week's episode of The Scoop.&nbsp;","That narrative lately has been all about bitcoin's growing adoption. From <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/92111\/microstrategy-buys-additional-bitcoin-10-million-btc\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Microstrategy<\/a> to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/80711\/stone-ridge-treasury-bitcoin\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stone Ridge Holdings<\/a> — and maybe soon the city of <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/91405\/miami-mayor-bitcoin-btc-investment-plan-city-treasury-reserves\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Miami<\/a> — big players are allocating to the top cryptocurrency.","But as the money flows towards bitcoin adoption, ICO's aren't over, according to Morehead. Pantera is still pitched one every two to four months, and the firm's initial coin offering (ICO) fund <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/91272\/panteras-ico-fund-ends-2020-up-more-than-500-bitcoin-fund-up-nearly-300\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ended 2020<\/a> up more than 500%.&nbsp;","Still, that's a sharp decline from the 50 pitches a week Pantera sifted through in 2017, and its bitcoin fund closed 2020 up nearly 300%. The crypto narrative for investors is trending towards Bitcoin amid institutional adoption, Morehead told The Scoop.","\"We’re really seeing an inflection point with more coming into the market over the last couple of months.... I think the reality is they’re looking for managers that manage multiasset funds sometimes both tokens and venture and they ultimately want that all to be within a handful of managers,\" he said.","Lately, Morehead is fielding calls from endowments, putting the industry at an intriguing inflection point. Driving the interest in bitcoin is the current macro backdrop as well as bitcoin's block reward halving last year—which the firm <a href=\"http:\/\/prod-latest-alb-2062789233.us-east-1.elb.amazonaws.com\/linked\/91272\/panteras-ico-fund-ends-2020-up-more-than-500-bitcoin-fund-up-nearly-300\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a> could play a role in bringing its price to $115,000.&nbsp;","Morehead broke down what that means for the coming year on this week's episode, along with:","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Disclosure: Pantera was an investor in a past funding round for The Block.<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Miami","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"300%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$115,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"500%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Pantera Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Morehead","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Stone Ridge Holdings","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ICO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dan Morehead","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitcoina nd Ethereum","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Microstrategy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Pantera","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"AML","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MPC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN"],"authors":["Aislinn Keely","The Block"]}