{"summary":"FTX Ventures Head Amy Wu has resigned, The Information reported, citing the executive who joined in January to launch a $2 billion fund.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/186084\/ftx-ventures-head-amy-wu-resigns-the-information","publishDate":"2022-11-11T14:19:22","id":7140,"type":null,"title":"FTX Ventures Head Amy Wu Resigns: The Information","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["FTX Ventures Head <a href=\"https:\/\/www.linkedin.com\/in\/amytongwu\/?originalSubdomain=bs\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Amy Wu<\/a> has resigned, The Information <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theinformation.com\/briefings\/ftx-ventures-head-amy-wu-resigns\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a>, citing the executive.","Wu <a href=\"https:\/\/blog.ftx.com\/blog\/launching-ftx-ventures\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">joined<\/a> in January to launch what was expected to have been a $2 billion fund. She was an early advocate of web3 startups, invested in Ethereum startup Offchain Labs and blockchain gaming company Faraway during her previous role as a partner at Lightspeed Venture Partners, The Information said. FTX Ventures and sister firm Alameda Research invested in more than 250 crypto industry startups, according to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/186058\/alameda-research-ftx-ventures-invested-in-more-than-250-crypto-startups\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">data collected<\/a> by The Block Research.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nNews of the resignation came after more than 100 corporate entities affiliated with the FTX crypto exchange filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection.&nbsp;<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nSpeaking at Breakpoint in Lisbon last week, Wu <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/183452\/ftx-ventures-amy-wu-vc-deals-during-bull-market-lacked-proper-due-diligence\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a> that VC deals were rushed and went forward without proper due diligence during the last crypto bull market.&nbsp;","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"The Block Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FTX Ventures Head <a href=\"https:\/\/www.linkedin.com\/in\/amytongwu\/?originalSubdomain=bs\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Amy Wu","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Lightspeed Venture Partners","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"last week","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lisbon","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$2 billion","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Nathan Crooks","The Block"]}