{"summary":"GameStop will carry FTX gift cards in its stores as part of a new partnership, the companies announced on Sept. 7.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/168445\/gamestop-announces-ftx-partnership","publishDate":"2022-09-07T16:36:52","id":7142,"type":null,"title":"GameStop announces FTX partnership","category":["GAMING AND METAVERSE"],"content":["FTX US and GameStop formed a new partnership, the companies announced today. The companies plan to collaborate on new e-commerce and online marketing initiatives.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","The partnership is aimed at introducing more GameStop “customers to FTX’s community and its marketplaces for digital assets,” the companies said in a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.businesswire.com\/news\/home\/20220907006127\/en\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">press release<\/a>. GameStop will be FTX’s preferred retail partner in the U.S. and will carry FTX gift cards in some stores. Financial terms of the partnership were not disclosed.","GameStop is no stranger to the digital asset space. The company launched an <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/156986\/gamestop-goes-live-with-public-beta-of-nft-marketplace\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">NFT marketplace<\/span><\/a> in July.","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"GameStop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Stephanie Murray","The Block"]}