{"summary":"Binance Japan added that it plans to work with other local crypto exchanges to ensure better liquidity, local media reported.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/248057\/binance-japan-plans-to-triple-number-of-listed-tokens-to-100-bloomberg","publishDate":"2023-08-30T05:13:50","id":7158,"type":null,"title":"Binance Japan plans to triple number of listed tokens to 100: Bloomberg","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance Japan, which <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/242410\/binance-plans-to-first-list-34-tokens-in-japan-as-it-re-enters-the-market-report\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">launched full services earlier this month<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, said today that it aims to offer at least 100 tokens on its platform in the short term — about three times the current offering — according to a Bloomberg <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.co.jp\/\/news\/articles\/2023-08-30\/S06NY5T1UM0W01\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">report<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance Japan’s representative said today in an online briefing that it plans to work with other local crypto exchanges in the country to ensure better liquidity in the market, Japanese crypto media outlet <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/coinpost.jp\/?p=479791\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Coinpost reported<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. Changpeng Zhao, founder and CEO of Binance, retweeted the Coinpost article.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Japanese arm of Binance, the world’s largest crypto exchange, currently lists 34 tokens. It has previously said that customers in Japan can gain access to services including spot trading, Earn products and its NFT marketplace.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In November 2022, Binance acquired 100% of Sakura Exchange BitCoin — paving the way for it to be regulated by the Japan Financial Services Agency.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The re-entry came after the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/109623\/japan-fsa-another-warning-binance-unregistered-operations\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">JFSA issued warnings in 2021 against Binance<\/a>, saying that the exchange was operating in the country without registration.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"JFSA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"today","content":"DATE"},{"type":"the Japan Financial Services Agency","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Japan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sakura Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"100%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"November 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Binance","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}