{"summary":"In this episode of The Scoop, Algorand Foundation CEO Staci Warden provides insight into some exciting developments in the Algorand ecosystem that she hopes will harness the power of Algorand&#x27;s technology for global good. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/158015\/algorand-foundation-ceo-staci-warden-says-algorand-is-ready-to-change-the-world","publishDate":"2022-07-18T10:37:36","id":7163,"type":null,"title":"Algorand Foundation CEO Staci Warden on how Algorand is going to distinguish itself in the bear market","category":["THE BLOCK"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">65<\/strong><\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 4 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block's Frank Chaparro and Staci Warden, CEO of The Algorand Foundation.<\/i><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"d2a2bdb6b1b3a1a692a6bab7b0bebdb1b9b1a0aba2a6bdfcb1bdbf\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i><\/span>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK6209078406\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Although Algorand may not be the most popular blockchain ecosystem, its underlying technology is arguably among the most cutting edge.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Founded in 2017 by Silvio Micali, MIT professor and Turing Award <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/web.archive.org\/web\/20130316052703\/http:\/\/www.acm.org\/press-room\/news-releases\/2013\/turing-award-12\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">recipient<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> for his pioneering work in the fields of cryptography and computer science, Algorand uses a highly efficient consensus mechanism it calls <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.algorand.com\/technology\/pure-proof-of-stake\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">pure proof of stake<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, and is one of the most <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/algorand.foundation\/news\/carbon-neutral\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">energy-efficient<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> blockchains in the industry.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">While Silvio Micali oversees the research and development of Algorand's technology, the Algorand Foundation is responsible for helping the surrounding community flourish.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In this episode of The Scoop, Algorand Foundation CEO Staci Warden detailed recent developments in the Algorand ecosystem that she hopes will harness the power of Algorand's technology for global good.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"We have the best tech in crypto, and I think a lot of people would acknowledge that,\" Warden says. She cites Algorand's roughly 1,000 transactions per second and 4.5 second settlement time — which the development team hopes to increase to 10,000 transactions per second and 2.5 second settlement time by the end of the year.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Given these performance indicators, Warden believes Algorand is equipped to handle problems at scale. As she explains,<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"When you've got a machine like that, of course you start thinking big — and so we think in terms of very big global problems.\"<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">One of these problems is financial inclusion, which the Algorand Foundation is looking to address through an upcoming partnership with an organization that is planning to make 4G mobile phones preloaded with Algorand's tech available to people in Africa who might otherwise be unable to access traditional financial services.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Algorand also has a growing decentralized finance ecosystem, largely due to an ecosystem <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/117308\/algorand-sets-up-330-million-fund-thats-focused-on-defi\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">fund<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> launched last September that today is worth approximately $50 million.<\/span>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">During this episode, Chaparro and Warden also discuss:<\/span><\/i>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors <em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.chainalysis.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Chainalysis<\/a>&nbsp;&amp;<\/em>&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.iwc.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC Schauffhausen<\/a><\/em><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/b>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Chainalysis<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nChainalysis is the leading blockchain data platform. We provide data, software, services, and research to government agencies, exchanges, financial institutions, and insurance and cybersecurity companies in over 60 countries. Backed by Accel, Addition, Benchmark, Coatue, Paradigm, Ribbit, and other leading firms in venture capital, Chainalysis builds trust in blockchains to promote more financial freedom with less risk. For more information, visit <a href=\"https:\/\/www.chainalysis.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">www.chainalysis.com<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About IWC Schaffhausen<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC Schaffhausen is a Swiss luxury watch manufacturer based in Schaffhausen, Switzerland. Known for its unique engineering approach to watchmaking, IWC combines the best of human craftsmanship and creativity with cutting-edge technology and processes. With collections like the Portugieser and the Pilot’s Watches, the brand covers the whole spectrum from elegant timepieces to sports watches. For more information, visit <a href=\"https:\/\/www.iwc.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC.com<\/a><\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"The Algorand Foundation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Silvio Micali","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Algorand Foundation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Switzerland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coatue","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chainalysis<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nChainalysis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Staci Warden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Benchmark","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"IWC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Chainalysis<\/a>&nbsp;&amp;<\/em>&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.iwc.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Schaffhausen","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Algorand","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"IWC Schaffhausen<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC Schaffhausen","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Paradigm","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Warden","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Accel","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MIT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ribbit","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Algorand Foundation CEO Staci Warden","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Africa","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Algorand","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$50 million","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["CRYPTO","FINTECH"],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}