{"summary":"Binance NFT will stop supporting Polygon NFTs on Sept. 26. Afterward, users won&#x27;t be able to buy or list Polygon NFTs on the platform.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/249937\/binance-to-remove-support-for-polygon-nfts","publishDate":"2023-09-08T10:29:30","id":7173,"type":null,"title":"Binance to remove support for Polygon NFTs","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto exchange Binance's NFT marketplace is ending support for the <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Polygon <\/span><span class=\"articleTooltip\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"\/price\/248360\/polygon-matic-usd\" class=\"articleTooltip__link\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"><img src=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2023\/10\/matic-token-icon.png\" alt=\"\" title=\"\" class=\"articleTooltip__tokenImage\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">MATIC<\/span> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText articleTooltip__tokenText_price articleTooltip__tokenText_negative\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">\n      -0.83%\n    <\/span><\/a> <!----><\/span><\/span> Network.<\/span>","Binance NFT will stop supporting Polygon NFTs on Sept. 26 at 6:00 UTC. Afterward, users won't be able to buy or list Polygon NFTs on the platform, and all affected listings will be canceled, Binance wrote in a Friday <a href=\"https:\/\/www.binance.com\/en\/support\/announcement\/binance-nft-important-updates-on-the-sandbox-nft-staking-program-and-polygon-network-support-accd8386f2b64a27a880894437c76089\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">release<\/a>.&nbsp;","\"Users should withdraw their NFTs via the Polygon Network from Binance NFT Marketplace by Dec. 31, 2024 at 23:59 UTC,\" Binance wrote.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance is also ending its NFT staking program for <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Sandbox <\/span><span class=\"articleTooltip\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"\/price\/248403\/the-sandbox-sand-usd\" class=\"articleTooltip__link\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"><img src=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2023\/10\/sandbox_logo.jpg\" alt=\"\" title=\"\" class=\"articleTooltip__tokenImage\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">SAND<\/span> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText articleTooltip__tokenText_price articleTooltip__tokenText_negative\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">\n      -0.19%\n    <\/span><\/a> <!----><\/span><\/span>, and users won't be able to stake LAND NFTs on Polygon to earn rewards after Sept. 26.<\/span>","\"This decision was made after careful consideration and evaluation, and it is part of our ongoing efforts to streamline product offerings on Binance NFT Marketplace,\" Binance noted.&nbsp;","The Sandbox NFT collection is the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.binance.com\/en\/nft\/home\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">second<\/a> most traded Polygon NFT collection on Binance's NFT marketplace. It has a floor price of 899.15 MATIC ($494) and all-time trading volume of 20.2 million MATIC ($11.1 million).","After removing Polygon, Binance NFT will support three blockchains including BNB Chain, Ethereum and Bitcoin.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"-0.19%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Binance NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Polygon Network","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"UTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sandbox NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$11.1 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"-0.83%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Sept. 26","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Dec. 31, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$494","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Polygon NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Binance NFT Marketplace","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Binance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE"],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}