{"summary":"Sam Bankman-Fried agreed to stay off Signal, but his bail term proposal would allow him to use other messaging platforms.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/209392\/judge-denies-bankman-frieds-bail-modification-ahead-of-thursday-hearing","publishDate":"2023-02-07T11:12:18","id":7175,"type":null,"title":"Judge denies Bankman-Fried’s bail modification ahead of Thursday hearing","category":["LEGAL"],"content":["A U.S. District judge rejected Sam Bankman-Fried’s request to modify his bail terms and cancel a Thursday hearing on the issue, according to court documents filed on Tuesday.","Bankman-Fried agreed this week to stop using encrypted or ephemeral messaging apps like Signal after prosecutors accused him of using the technology to contact a potential witness in his criminal case and sought modifications to his bail terms.","Judge Lewis Kaplan denied Bankman-Fried’s motion to amend his bail and cancel oral arguments on the matter later this week. A Thursday hearing will go forward, according to the judge’s order.","The former FTX boss said in a court filing that he would stay off encrypted or ephemeral messaging apps, but Bankman-Fried's proposal would have allowed him to use most other messaging platforms, including phone calls, iMessage, FaceTime, Facebook Messenger and WhatsApp, with some restrictions.","Bankman-Fried is facing a litany of criminal charges tied to his alleged mishandling of customer funds at his crypto exchange FTX and trading firm Alameda Research.&nbsp;","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FaceTime","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lewis Kaplan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["COURT HEARINGS","FTX"],"authors":["Stephanie Murray","The Block"]}