{"summary":"In this episode of The Scoop, Chief Strategy Officer and Head of Global Policy at Circle, Dante Disparte, joins host Frank Chaparro to share what a responsible approach to stablecoin regulation might look like, and why he believes central bank digital currencies are &quot;anti-democratic.&quot;","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/161064\/cbdcs-are-anti-democratic-says-circles-dante-disparte","publishDate":"2022-08-03T05:00:04","id":7197,"type":null,"title":"CBDCs are &#x27;anti-democratic&#x27; says Circle&#x27;s Dante Disparte","category":["PODCASTS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">72<\/strong><\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 4 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block's Frank Chaparro, and <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Chief Strategy Officer and Head of Global Policy at Circle, Dante Disparte<\/span>.<\/i><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"fe8e919a9d9f8d8abe8a969b9c92919d959d8c878e8a91d09d9193\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK5834626977\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/i><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Circle's USDC stablecoin is the second largest by market capitalization, and has steadily grown in dominance over the last couple of years.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In this episode of The Scoop, Chief Strategy Officer and Head of Global Policy at Circle, Dante Disparte, joins host Frank Chaparro to share his take on what a responsible approach to stablecoin regulation might look like and why he believes central bank digital currencies are \"anti-democratic.\"<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">According to Disparte, the separation between the central banks and citizens' pockets is important to maintain:<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"The gap between the central bank, the banking system, your wallet and how you spend money is a powerful feature and not a bug.\"<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Furthermore, Dante believes that central bank digital currencies ignore the fundamental peer-to-peer potential of digital assets:<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"A central bank digital currency would be the equivalent of building a high speed train engine, but not caring about the rail network, nor the station stops. And the real powerful breakthrough of blockchain based finance is that the infrastructure has networked peer to peer station stops.\"<\/span>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">During this episode, Chaparro and Disparte also discuss:<\/span><\/i>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/decentralized-finance\/stablecoins\/total-stablecoin-supply-daily\/embed\" title=\"Total Stablecoin Supply\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors <em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.chainalysis.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Chainalysis<\/a>&nbsp;&amp;<\/em>&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.iwc.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC Schaffhausen<\/a><\/em><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/b>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Chainalysis<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nChainalysis is the leading blockchain data platform. We provide data, software, services, and research to government agencies, exchanges, financial institutions, and insurance and cybersecurity companies in over 60 countries. Backed by Accel, Addition, Benchmark, Coatue, Paradigm, Ribbit, and other leading firms in venture capital, Chainalysis builds trust in blockchains to promote more financial freedom with less risk. For more information, visit <a href=\"https:\/\/www.chainalysis.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">www.chainalysis.com<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About IWC Schaffhausen<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC Schaffhausen is a Swiss luxury watch manufacturer based in Schaffhausen, Switzerland. Known for its unique engineering approach to watchmaking, IWC combines the best of human craftsmanship and creativity with cutting-edge technology and processes. With collections like the Portugieser and the Pilot’s Watches, the brand covers the whole spectrum from elegant timepieces to sports watches. For more information, visit <a href=\"https:\/\/www.iwc.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC.com<\/a><\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Switzerland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Paradigm","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Dante Disparte","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coatue","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dante","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Chainalysis<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nChainalysis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Accel","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Benchmark","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ribbit","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Head of Global Policy at Circle","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"IWC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dante Disparte","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Schaffhausen","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Disparte","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"IWC Schaffhausen<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC Schaffhausen","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chainalysis<\/a>&nbsp;&amp;<\/em>&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.iwc.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">IWC Schaffhausen","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["CFTC","CONGRESS","CRYPTO","USDC"],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}