{"summary":"The SEC brought charges against crypto platform Beaxy on Wednesday as it continues to go after unregistered parts of the crypto industry.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/223694\/sec-brings-charges-against-beaxy-for-not-registering-as-securities-exchange","publishDate":"2023-03-29T10:30:23","id":7201,"type":null,"title":"SEC brings charges against Beaxy for not registering as securities exchange","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Securities and Exchange Commission charged cryptocurrency platform Beaxy and its executives for allegedly failing to register as an exchange, broker and clearing agency —<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp; <\/span>the latest crypto-related move by the U.S. securities regulator.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The SEC also <a href=\"https:\/\/www.sec.gov\/litigation\/complaints\/2023\/comp-pr2023-64.pdf\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">charged<\/a> founder Artak Hamazaspyan, and a company he controlled, Beaxy Digital Ltd, with raising $8 million in an unregistered offering of the Beaxy token. The SEC also said he used $900,000 for personal use, including gambling.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Executives Nicholas Murphy and Randolph Bay Abbott were also caught up in charges via a company they managed called Windy, which maintained Beaxy. Windy, through the Beaxy Platform, violated securities laws because it didn’t register as an exchange, a clearing agency or a broker, the SEC <a href=\"https:\/\/www.sec.gov\/news\/press-release\/2023-64\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">alleges<\/a>.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“To protect investors, there are separate registration requirements for exchanges, brokers, and clearing agencies, with each essentially acting as a check on the other,” said Gurbir Grewal, director of the SEC’s Division of Enforcement in a statement on Wednesday. “When a crypto intermediary combines all of these functions under one roof—as we allege that Beaxy did—investors are at serious risk.\"<\/span>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Others swept in&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/span><\/strong>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In 2019, Windy entered into an agreement with Brian Peterson and his companies, together named Braverock Entities, to provide “market making services for BXY,” and later one of the companies “entered into a similar market making agreement for another crypto asset security.” That made Peterson and Bravework unregistered securities dealers, the SEC said. &nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Windy, Murphy, Abbott and Peterson agreed to cease all activities as an unregistered exchange, clearing agency, broker and dealer, as well as shut down the Beaxy platform, destroying BXY in Windy’s possession. <\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">As part of the agreement, the four individuals <\/span><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">and the Braverock Entities did not admit or deny the agency’s allegations.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The SEC said it is “litigating its charges against Hamazaspyan for securities fraud and against Hamazaspyan and Beaxy Digital for the unregistered offering of BXY.”&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Brian Peterson","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Abbott","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nicholas Murphy","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Murphy","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Beaxy","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$900,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Beaxy Digital Ltd","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Randolph Bay Abbott","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Artak Hamazaspyan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$8 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Braverock Entities","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Peterson","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bravework","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gurbir Grewal","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Beaxy Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SEC’s Division of Enforcement","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["SEC"],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}