{"summary":"Terraform Labs CEO expressed confidence in the latest efforts to rebuild the Terra blockchain following a collapse in May.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/153681\/do-kwon-has-great-confidence-in-rebuilding-terra-blockchain-wsj","publishDate":"2022-06-22T15:00:52","id":7223,"type":null,"title":"Do Kwon has ‘great confidence’ in rebuilding Terra blockchain: WSJ","category":["ASIA"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Do Kwon, CEO of Terraform Labs, expressed confidence today in the latest efforts to rebuild the Terra blockchain following the collapse of its predecessor in May.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Terraform Labs CEO Do Kwon <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.wsj.com\/articles\/do-kwons-crypto-empire-fell-in-a-40-billion-crash-hes-got-a-new-coin-for-you-11655914487\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">told The Wall Street Journal<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in an interview published Wednesday that he has “great confidence” in the company’s ability to “build back even stronger\" than before.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kwon’s proposal to relaunch the Terra blockchain and create a new token was <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/148629\/do-kwons-plan-to-rebirth-the-terra-blockchain-gets-approved\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">passed<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in late May following majority votes among holders of Terraform Labs’ Luna governance token. The votes paved the way for the creation of the new blockchain called Terra, while the old version was renamed Terra Classic.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Many builders are in the process of relaunching their apps on the new chain,” Kwon said.<\/span>","As previously reported by The Block, the Terra ecosystem dramatically imploded in early May as both the value of the UST stablecoin as well as Terra's native asset, Luna, fell sharply in value. The resultant market chaos took place amid broader macroeconomic turmoil and set the stage for the continued volatility in the crypto market seen in recent weeks.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kwon said he was “devastated” by the Terra crisis. “[I] hope that all the families who’ve been impacted are taking care of themselves and those that they love,” he added.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Following the collapse, Kwon and Terraform Labs were hit by a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/152939\/do-kwon-terraform-labs-others-hit-with-class-action-lawsuit\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">class-action lawsuit<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that accused them of selling unregistered securities and making false statements about the stability of the TerraUSD (UST) stablecoin and related token LUNA. Other defendants named in the case are Jump Crypto, Jump Trading and Three Arrows Capital.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kwon and the company are already the subjects of <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/147509\/korean-law-firm-lkb-decides-to-sue-do-kwon-terra-ust-collapse\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">another ongoing lawsuit<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in South Korea, with prosecutors barring Terra developers from <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/153048\/terra-developers-in-korea-barred-from-leaving-the-country\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">leaving the country<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Some in the crypto community have accused Kwon of running a sophisticated scam, as reported by the WSJ. Cory Klippstein, the CEO of Swan Bitcoin, called Kwon, as quoted by the WSJ, “a fraudster.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kwon rejected that description, saying he made confident bets and statements on behalf of the UST because he “believed in its resilience and its value proposition.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“I’ve since lost these bets, but my actions 100% match my words,” Kwon added. “There is a difference between failing and running a fraud.”<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Cory Klippstein","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"South Korea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"WSJ","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Swan Bitcoin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Kwon","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Luna","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"100%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Terra Classic","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Three Arrows Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jump Crypto","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Terra","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UST","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["DO KWON"],"authors":["Kharishar Kahfi","The Block"]}