{"summary":"Following comments from the CEOs of Alameda Research and Binance on FTT, the token dipped 8.75% before recovering somewhat.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/183570\/binance-to-sell-ftx-token-holdings-alameda-ceo-says-leaked-balance-sheet-is-incomplete","publishDate":"2022-11-06T14:03:30","id":7248,"type":null,"title":"Alameda CEO Caroline Ellison says leaked balance sheet misses full story","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Alameda Research CEO Caroline Ellison said Sunday that leaked information about the firm's balance sheet only tells part of the story.","On Nov. 2, CoinDesk <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/business\/2022\/11\/02\/divisions-in-sam-bankman-frieds-crypto-empire-blur-on-his-trading-titan-alamedas-balance-sheet\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a> that a leaked balance sheet from Alameda listed $3.66 billion in \"unlocked FTT,\" referring to the token of crypto exchange FTX, as well as $2.16 billion worth of \"FTT collateral.\" The leaked balance sheet showed a total of $14.6 billion in assets and some $8 billion in liabilities, which include $7.4 billion worth of loans.","The leaked balance sheet and the FTT holdings further illustrated the close links between the two companies.","Ellison <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/carolinecapital\/status\/1589264375042707458\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweeted<\/a> earlier today that the leaked information on Alameda's balance sheet<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> misses billions worth of other assets.<\/span>","A few notes on the balance sheet info that has been circulating recently:<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n- that specific balance sheet is for a subset of our corporate entities, we have &gt; $10b of assets that aren’t reflected there","<script async=\"async\" src=\"https:\/\/platform.twitter.com\/widgets.js\" charset=\"utf-8\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/script>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ellison continued: \"The balance sheet breaks out a few of our biggest long positions; we obviously have hedges that aren’t listed. Given the tightening in the crypto credit space this year, we’ve returned most of our loans by now.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance CEO Changpeng \"CZ\" Zhao <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/cz_binance\/status\/1589283421704290306?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1589283421704290306%7Ctwgr%5E90af671213ca1616cca4d320cfc8bca70c2dc5a8%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.coindesk.com%2Fbusiness%2F2022%2F11%2F06%2Fbinance-sells-holdings-of-ftx-token-as-alameda-ceo-defends-firms-financial-condition%2F\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a> later that the firm would begin selling off its FTT holdings \"due to recent revelations that have came to light.\" Zhao didn't clarify exactly how much of FTT this would entail, though he said Binance previously received about $2.1 billion worth BUSD and FTT \"[a]s part of Binance’s exit from FTX equity last year.\"<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ellison responded, <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/carolinecapital\/status\/1589287457975304193\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">offering<\/a> to buy Binance’s FTT holdings at $22 per token.<\/span>","FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried also <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/SBF_FTX\/status\/1589314321792008193\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">responded<\/a> to CZ's post: \"I wish the best to everyone driving the industry forward. I respect the hell out of what y'all have done to build the industry as we see it today, whether or not they reciprocate, and whether or not we use the same methods. Including CZ.\"","The public announcements on Sunday sent FTT's price gyrating, according to TradingView data.","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/chart\/?symbol=FTX%3AFTTUSD\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">FTTUSD Chart by TradingView<\/a><\/em>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Sunday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ellison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"TradingView","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"earlier today","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Caroline Ellison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$22","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$7.4 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"CoinDesk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$14.6 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$3.66 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$10b","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$2.16 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nov. 2","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$2.1 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$8 billion","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE","FTX"],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}