{"summary":"Auros has missed a scheduled repayment on a loan it took on the Maple Finance lending protocol.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/196961\/crypto-market-maker-auros-defaults-on-7-5-million-maple-finance-loan-payment","publishDate":"2022-12-21T08:52:15","id":7270,"type":null,"title":"Crypto market maker Auros misses $7.5 million Maple Finance loan repayment","category":["DEFI"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto market making firm Auros failed to make a repayment on a $7.5 million stablecoin <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/app.maple.finance\/#\/v2\/lend\/pool\/0x00e0c1ea2085e30e5233e98cfa940ca8cbb1b0b7\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">loan<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> from uncollateralized lending platform Maple Finance<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/PeckShieldAlert\/status\/1605454986439114757\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">according to<\/a> security and analytics firm PeckShield. Auros borrowed these assets from Maple Finance delegate M11.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Auros <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/196418\/auros-bankruptcy-filing-ftx?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filed<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> for bankruptcy protection in the British Virgin Islands last month after losing access to about $20 million of funds it held on the collapsed crypto exchange FTX. A spokesman for Auros declined to comment on its Maple loans.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Previously, Auros also missed repayments after it borrowed 8,400 wrapped ether (WETH) worth $10.8 million, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockresearch.com\/rapid-insights-auros-uncollateralized-defi-loans-192153\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">according to<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> The Block Research.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Maple Finance runs as a decentralized protocol that lets firms access loans without collateral. The platform has continued to suffer from contagion risk from the fallout related to the collapse of FTX.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Auros joins fellow market maker Orthogonal Trading which <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/192097\/maple-finance-default-orthogonal-trading\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">defaulted<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on a Maple Finance loan. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Just like Auros, Orthogonal had funds frozen on FTX.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“The fallout of FTX has caused an industry-wide credit crunch which has negatively impacted many market participants,” <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockresearch.com\/rapid-insights-auros-uncollateralized-defi-loans-192153\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">noted<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Arnold Toh, research analyst at The Block.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Recently, Maple<\/span> <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/194907\/maple-finance-releases-version-2-0-after-36-million-default-on-platform\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">updated<\/span><\/a> <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">its protocol to a second version aimed at opening up the lending platform to a wider range of institutional borrowers, including those from outside the crypto industry. With the new update, called Maple 2.0, the team hopes to reduce the risks by diversifying the quality of borrowers using its platform.<\/span>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A previous version of the article inaccurately stated the Auros loan was defaulted. Technically, the loan was <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/maplefinance\/status\/1605550295697612801?s=46&amp;t=VI104mvRLH91yq2r4a7zxA\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">described<\/a> as \"impaired\" by Maple.&nbsp;<\/em>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Disclaimer: Beginning in 2021, Michael McCaffrey, the former CEO and majority owner of The Block, took a series of loans from founder and former FTX and Alameda CEO Sam Bankman-Fried. McCaffrey resigned from the company in December 2022 after failing to disclose those transactions.<\/em>","&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$10.8 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Maple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Maple Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Auros","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Arnold Toh","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"PeckShield","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Orthogonal Trading","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"December 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"British Virgin Islands","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$20 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"last month","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Michael McCaffrey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$7.5 million","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["INVESTMENT FIRMS","LENDING"],"authors":["Vishal Chawla","The Block"]}