{"summary":"In this episode of The Scoop, Aptos Co-Founders Mohammad Shaikh and Avery Ching share lessons learned from building Facebook&#x27;s Libra, and lay out their vision for the Aptos Network.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/189309\/inside-aptos-the-1-9-billion-blockchain-born-out-of-the-shuttered-libra-project","publishDate":"2022-11-23T05:00:41","id":7284,"type":null,"title":"Inside Aptos — the $1.9 billion blockchain born out of the shuttered Libra project","category":["LAYER 1S"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 116<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 4 of The Scoop was recorded live with&nbsp;<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro and Kevin Peng, and Aptos Co-Founders Avery Ching and Mohammad Shaikh.<\/strong><\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests can be sent to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"7c0c13181f1d0f083c0814191e10131f171f0e050c0813521f1311\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK2212235338\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Aptos, a new Layer 1 blockchain originating from the Facebook blockchain initiative Libra (later renamed 'Diem'), recently <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/177817\/aptoss-layer-1-mainnet-launching-soon-date-not-finalized\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">launched<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> its mainnet.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The architecture behind Aptos was designed to serve millions of people at scale and uses the Move programming language originally intended for Libra.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In this episode of The Scoop, Aptos Co-Founders Mohammad Shaikh and Avery Ching explain why they believe Aptos empowers developers to build faster, more secure applications, and why applications built on Aptos will help onboard millions of users into web3.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">According to Ching, experiences built on Aptos will look and feel more like what users are accustomed to on existing Web2 platforms:<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“When we think about what's going to onboard people into web3 from web2, one thing that people are used to in web2 is extremely good latency for their products … being able to see those same kinds of experiences in web3 through the Aptos network is something that will be very powerful.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In addition to user experience, the Move language offers developers a Rust-based alternative to Solana — something some teams who were developing on Solana are currently <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/173036\/aptos-lures-solana-developers-tired-of-eating-glass\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">exploring<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">While vulnerabilities in smart contracts have cost DeFi projects billions of dollars, the Aptos co-founders claim the Move language allows for fewer vulnerabilities. As Shaikh explains,<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Making sure that engineers or product managers who are excited about a use case aren't thwarted by having to deal with smart contract complexity and worry about auditability — that’s really meaningful to us.”<\/span>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">During this episode, Chaparro, Ching, and Shaikh also discuss:<\/span><\/i>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Tron,&nbsp;<\/em><\/a><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.ledn.io\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ledn<\/a><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em><\/b><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nAbout Tron<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Founded in 2013, Huobi Global is one of the largest virtual asset exchanges in the world. Huobi Global serves millions of users across international markets. Since its establishment, Huobi Global has committed to providing first class virtual asset investment services. Huobi Global's robust infrastructure, product innovation and capital strength provides a truly customer-centric and secure trading environment to help our international users to achieve their investment objectives. Please refer to Huobi's official website for more information: <a href=\"http:\/\/www.huobi.com\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">huobi.com<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Ledn<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong>Ledn was founded on the unshakeable conviction that digital assets have the power to democratize access to the global economy. We help you to experience the real life benefits of your Bitcoin without having to sell it. Start a savings account, take out a loan, or double your Bitcoin. For more information visit&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.ledn.io\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ledn.io<\/a><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Mohammad Shaikh","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Shaikh","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Huobi Global","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2013","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ledn<\/a><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em><\/b><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nAbout Tron<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Founded","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kevin Peng","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Aptos","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Huobi","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ching","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Solana","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ledn<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong>Ledn","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Avery Ching","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ching","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["APTOS"],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}