{"summary":"The Solana blockchain appears to be losing momentum, with its daily active addresses hitting nearly a 3-year low.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/249304\/solana-daily-active-addresses","publishDate":"2023-09-05T16:33:54","id":7291,"type":null,"title":"Solana users fall to lowest level in more than 2 years","category":["CRYPTO ECOSYSTEMS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Layer 1 blockchain <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Solana <\/span><span class=\"articleTooltip\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"\/price\/33827\/solana-sol-usd\" class=\"articleTooltip__link\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"><img src=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2023\/10\/solana.png\" alt=\"\" title=\"\" class=\"articleTooltip__tokenImage\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">SOL<\/span> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText articleTooltip__tokenText_price articleTooltip__tokenText_positive\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">\n      +0.50%\n    <\/span><\/a> <!----><\/span><\/span> is continuing to lose momentum, with the number of daily active addresses hitting the lowest point since The Block started tracking the data in late 2020.<\/span>","The number of daily active addresses on Solana, using a seven-day moving average, plummeted to around 204,000 on Aug. 31, according to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/on-chain-metrics\/solana\/number-of-active-addresses-on-the-solana-network-daily-7dma\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block’s Data Dashboard<\/a>.","The 7DMA metric shows the average value of a data point over the past week and can help spot trends.","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/on-chain-metrics\/solana\/number-of-active-addresses-on-the-solana-network-daily-7dma\/embed\" title=\"Number of Active Addresses on the Solana Network (Daily, 7DMA)\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","The decline in Solana's active users has intensified following crypto exchange <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/187982\/ftx-bankruptcy-filings-highlight-complete-failure-of-corporate-controls\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">FTX's bankruptcy<\/a> last November and the Securities and Exchange Commission's depiction of Solana's native <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/233174\/solana-matic-cardano-others-securities-sec-binance-lawsuit\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">SOL token as a security<\/a>.","\"The Solana ecosystem was already seeing a decline in active users prior to the collapse of FTX, but the fact that the blockchain had such strong ties to the exchange and Alameda Research [FTX’s sister trading firm] hurt its reputation a bit,\" said Rebecca Stevens, data analyst at The Block Research. \"The SEC alleging that SOL is a security also hurt the token's price and has caused it to be delisted in the U.S. on several platforms like <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/234404\/etoro-delists-algo-dash-mana-matic-on-us-platform?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">eToro<\/a> and <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/233961\/robinhood-ends-support-for-solana-polygon-cardano-amid-sec-exchange-crackdown\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Robinhood<\/a>,\" she added.","The price of SOL currently stands at around $20, down about 7% in the past seven days, per <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coingecko.com\/en\/coins\/solana\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CoinGecko data<\/a>. Solana is currently ranked tenth in terms of total value locked, which currently sits at around $311 million, according to <a href=\"https:\/\/defillama.com\/chains\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">DefiLlama data<\/a>.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Solana <\/span><span class=\"articleTooltip\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"\/price\/33827\/solana-sol-usd\" class=\"articleTooltip__link\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"><img src=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2023\/10\/solana.png\" alt=\"\" title=\"\" class=\"articleTooltip__tokenImage\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">SOL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$20","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"7%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Rebecca Stevens","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SOL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Aug. 31","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda Research [FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$311 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Solana","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block’s Data Dashboard","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"+0.50%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Solana","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["SOLANA"],"authors":["Yogita Khatri","The Block"]}