{"summary":"Modulo Capital is a multi-strategy hedge fund started in early 2022, operating in the same Bahamian condo community that SBF lived in. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/196433\/alameda-gave-400-million-to-startup-based-in-sbfs-bahamian-condo-community-coindesk","publishDate":"2022-12-19T17:14:35","id":7315,"type":null,"title":"Alameda gave $400 million to startup in same condo as SBF: CoinDesk","category":["VENTURE CAPITAL"],"content":["Modulo Capital, a relatively unknown firm that appears to have a lot in common with Sam Bankman-Fried and Caroline Ellison, received a $400 million loan from Bankman-Fried's investment firm, Alameda Research, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/business\/2022\/12\/19\/ftxs-bankman-fried-gave-ex-jane-street-traders-who-formed-modulo-capital-400m\/?utm_term=organic&amp;utm_campaign=coindesk_main&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_content=editorial&amp;utm_source=twitter\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CoinDesk<\/a> first reported. Ellison was the CEO of Alameda","Modulo Capital was founded by three former Jane Street traders, a New York-based company that employed Bankman-Fried and Ellison prior to their moves into the crypto industry. Modulo Capital operates out of the same Bahamian luxury condominium community that the two resided in.&nbsp;","Modulo Capital is one of the largest investments Alameda Research made, coming in at $400 million. People familiar with the matter told CoinDesk that Modulo approached other institutional finance investors before landing on Alameda.&nbsp;","Bankman-Fried was <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/186393\/sam-bankman-fried-arrested-in-the-bahamas\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">arrested<\/a> on Dec. 12 in the Bahamas for charges including wire fraud conspiracy, securities fraud and money laundering. He has since agreed to be <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/196429\/bankman-fried-will-agree-to-extradition-to-u-s-reports\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">extradited<\/a> to the U.S. to face fraud charges, The Block previously reported.&nbsp;","<i data-stringify-type=\"italic\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Disclaimer: Beginning in 2021, Michael McCaffrey, the former CEO and majority owner of The Block, took a series of loans from founder and former FTX and Alameda CEO Sam Bankman-Fried. McCaffrey resigned from the company in December 2022 after failing to disclose those transactions.<\/i>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Ellison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Caroline Ellison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Modulo","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Dec. 12","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bahamas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"December 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$400 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Michael McCaffrey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}