{"summary":"Prosecutors reiterated their call for eight years of jail time for Lee Jeong-hoon over alleged fraud, local media reported.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/263442\/prosecutors-file-appeal-in-alleged-fraud-case-involving-ex-bithumb-chair-report","publishDate":"2023-11-16T23:59:34","id":7323,"type":null,"title":"Prosecutors file appeal in alleged fraud case involving ex-Bithumb chair: report","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Prosecutors <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">in South Korea filed an appeal in an alleged fraud case involving Lee Jeong-hoon, former chair of local crypto exchange Bithumb.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">South Korean news outlet Seoul Economic Daily <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.sedaily.com\/NewsView\/29X9RNO3JE\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> today that prosecutors had reiterated their call for an eight-year jail term for Lee, in an appeal hearing on Thursday.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The case centers on the proposed October 2018 takeover of<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;Bithumb, a plan involving both Lee and&nbsp;<\/span><a href=\"http:\/\/wiki.hash.kr\/index.php?title=%EA%B9%80%EB%B3%91%EA%B1%B4&amp;mobileaction=toggle_view_desktop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kim Byung-kun<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, who was chair of BK Medical Group and a cosmetic surgeon, and alleged fraud-related wrongdoings involving at least 110 billion won ($85.2 billion).<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Lee was previously <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">found not guilty in the first instance — after prosecutors had sought eight years of jail time — earlier this year<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The appeal judgment against Lee is scheduled for January 18, 2024, according to the local media report.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The news comes less than a week after Bithumb was <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/262741\/south-korea-bithumb-ipo-2025\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reportedly <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">starting to plan for an initial public offering<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in Korea. Edaily <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.edaily.co.kr\/news\/read?newsId=01843366635805064\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on Sunday that Bithumb chose Samsung Securities as its underwriter last month for a potential IPO planned in the second half of 2025 on Kosdaq.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bithumb did not immediately respond to The Block’s request for comment.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Sunday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"South Korea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"October 2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Korea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$85.2 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Bithumb","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BK Medical Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"January 18, 2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Seoul Economic Daily","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lee Jeong","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kim Byung","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"110 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Kosdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"second half of 2025","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Samsung Securities","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["CRYPTO"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}