{"summary":"MoonPay will use its utility minting service Hypermint to create up to 7 million NFTs for a scavenger hunt at Universal Studios Theme Parks. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/171491\/moonpay-universal-create-an-in-person-nft-based-scavenger-hunt-with-more-than-6-million-tokens","publishDate":"2022-09-21T00:01:07","id":7324,"type":null,"title":"MoonPay and Universal create an NFT-based scavenger hunt","category":["NFTS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The crypto payment platform MoonPay has helped its partner Universal Studios create an NFT-based scavenger hunt at its Universal Theme Parks.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">MoonPay will use its utility minting service Hypermint to create up to 7 million NFTs, which can be claimed at a Universal Theme Park in Orlando, Florida or Hollywood, California as part of the “Halloween Horror Nights” NFT scavenger hunt.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We're really excited about this because this is a real world use case that we've been trying to demonstrate with people,” MoonPay CEO Ivan Soto-Wright told The Block. “We're going beyond just the profile picture identity movement with NFTs to actual real world utility.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Park guests won’t require advanced crypto knowledge — or even knowing how to set up a crypto wallet — to claim these NFTs. “It's just basically a claim page where you put in your email address, and boom, what we do in the background is we mint that NFT, we spin up a wallet for that particular person and then they're able to claim it when they're ready,” Soto-Wright said.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Seven types of NFTs can be found in both the Orlando and Hollywood Universal Parks. Those who collect all seven NFTs receive a “gold medal NFT,” which is “eventually going to do something” Soto-Wright said, without sharing additional details.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">MoonPay originally launched <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/153119\/moonpay-officially-launches-utility-nft-minting-service-hypermint\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Hypermint<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in June of this year as a service that lets brands mint up to 100 million digital assets at once. In the case of the Halloween Horror Nights scavenger hunt, these NFTs will be used as proof of attendance protocols or POAPs, or digital tokens that prove someone attended an event such as The Ethereum <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/170564\/i-attended-the-merge-and-all-i-got-was-this-lousy-poap\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Merge<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Universal Pictures, the U.S. film studio behind Universal Theme Parks, was one of Hypermint’s launch partners, The Block previously reported.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Soto","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Florida","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"June of this year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Universal Theme Park","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Hollywood Universal Parks","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hollywood","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Ethereum <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/170564\/i-attended-the-merge-and-all-i-got-was-this-lousy-poap\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Merge","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ivan Soto","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Universal Theme Parks","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"California","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Wright","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"MoonPay","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Orlando","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}