{"summary":"Former Uber executive Karan Chawla joined 21Shares four weeks ago as its new Vice President of Product.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/143410\/new-21shares-vp-of-product-is-the-latest-defector-from-big-tech","publishDate":"2022-04-25T14:47:11","id":7344,"type":null,"title":"New 21Shares VP of Product is the latest defector from big tech","category":["CRYPTOCURRENCY"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto exchange-traded product (ETP) provider 21Shares has snatched former Uber executive Karan Chawla from the ride-hailing and delivery app and named him its new vice president of product.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Chawla, who was head of payments for the US, Canada and APAC at Uber for the last seven years, will “lead development of 21Shares’ product organization and roadmap to provide investors with access to the world’s most innovative DeFi protocols,” the company said in a statement on Monday.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Speaking with The Block, Chawla said that, having joined Uber when it was still a “big startup,” he was looking forward to returning to a company with that “early-stage feel.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“I think it’s still early days [for crypto] and it’s such a big opportunity. The key for us is going to be velocity. We need to be able to move quickly if there’s an opportunity,” he said.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Chawla is not alone. The shift in longtime big tech employees moving to join crypto startups has been picking up momentum. Speaking with The New York Times in December, former Google executive-turned-startup-founder Sridhar Ramaswamy likened it to “a giant sucking sound coming from crypto.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Among the defections are ride-hailing app Lyft’s CFO Brian Roberts move to OpenSea, and Jack Dorsey, who stepped down from Twitter to focus on his crypto and web3 company Block (formerly Square).<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">More and more talent is also moving from traditional finance to crypto. 21Share’s own head of trading Gurjeet Kundi, who joined the company in March, was formerly head of cross-asset ETF trading at Mizuho and spent close to two decades in ETF-related positions at Bank of America, Deutsche Bank and UniCredit.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block has also reported no fewer than 15 Citibank employees have <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/news+\/140447\/mapping-out-the-great-citi-crypto-exodus\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">moved<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to a range of crypto companies in the last months.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Deutsche Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Canada","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bank of America","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Brian Roberts","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"APAC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chawla","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"December","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Jack Dorsey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Mizuho","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The New York Times","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Uber","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sridhar Ramaswamy","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gurjeet Kundi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"UniCredit","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Citibank","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Callan Quinn","The Block"]}