{"summary":"Sam Bankman-Fried is headed back to the U.S. to face criminal charges over the collapse of FTX after a judge approved his extradition from the Bahamas, the Wall Street Journal said.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/197107\/bankman-fried-extradition-to-u-s-approved-wsj","publishDate":"2022-12-21T12:23:39","id":739,"type":null,"title":"Bankman-Fried extradition to U.S. approved: WSJ","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["Sam Bankman-Fried is headed back to the U.S. to face criminal charges over the collapse of FTX after a judge approved his extradition from the Bahamas, the Wall Street Journal <a href=\"https:\/\/www.wsj.com\/articles\/sam-bankman-fried-expected-back-in-bahamas-court-11671581149?mod=e2tw\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a>.","Bankmnan-Fried, who has been jailed since his arrest last week, agreed not to contest his extradition, the WSJ said.","U.S. authorities have charged Bankman-Fried with several crimes, accusing him of committing or conspiring to commit fraud on FTX's customers and lenders, money laundering and conspiracy to defraud the U.S. and violate campaign finance disclosure laws.","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"WSJ","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bahamas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"last week","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["FTX","SAM BANKMAN-FRIED"],"authors":["Larry DiTore","The Block"]}