{"summary":"Earlier this month, MoonPay said it had hired in Lindsey Haswell from Blockchain.com as its first chief legal officer.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/213338\/asiff-hirji-moonpay-president-coo","publishDate":"2023-02-22T12:55:54","id":7417,"type":null,"title":"Asiff Hirji steps in as MoonPay president amid top-level reshuffle","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Asiff Hirji, the former president and COO of crypto exchange Coinbase, is joining the ranks of top execs at MoonPay as its president, a spokesperson told The Block.","Hirji left Coinbase <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/25476\/coinbase-president-and-coo-asiff-hirji-is-departing-the-firm\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">in 2019<\/a> after about a year and a half on the job. During his time there, he helped drive the firm's entrance into new markets, including Coinbase Custody. He was also, more recently, the president of blockchain-based lender <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/54353\/former-coinbase-coo-joins-blockchain-financial-services-firm-figure-as-president\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Figure<\/a>, which he left after three years in December 2022.","MoonPay had said in July last year that Hirji was set to join as advisor to Ivan Soto-Wright, the company's CEO. The company announced a slew of <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/157625\/moonpay-bolsters-team-with-hires-from-cisco-cash-app-and-coinbase\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">other executive<\/a> hires at the same time.&nbsp;","Akash Garg, also brought in in July as CTO, appears to have left the firm in January, according to his <a href=\"https:\/\/www.linkedin.com\/in\/akashdgarg\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">LinkedIn<\/a> profile.&nbsp;","Earlier this month, MoonPay <a href=\"https:\/\/www.reuters.com\/legal\/legalindustry\/crypto-startup-moonpay-hires-legal-chief-blockchaincom-2023-02-16\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a> it had hired in Lindsey Haswell from Blockchain.com as its first chief legal officer.","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This story was updated after publication to reflect an inaccuracy in Hirji's job title relayed by the company.<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Asiff Hirji","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lindsey Haswell","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"MoonPay","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Coinbase Custody","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"July last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ivan Soto","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"December 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Hirji","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Wright","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"MoonPay","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CTO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hirji","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["HIRING","MOVES","PAYMENTS"],"authors":["Lucy Harley-McKeown","The Block"]}