{"summary":"Crypto stocks sank in line with equities today. Crypto prices continued to tread water on Tuesday, with bitcoin around $17,000 and ether over $1,200.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/192650\/coinbase-slips-7-silvergate-sinks-over-4-as-equities-have-another-down-day","publishDate":"2022-12-06T16:24:11","id":7422,"type":null,"title":"Coinbase slips 7%, Silvergate sinks over 4% as equities have another down day","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["Bitcoin and ether were little changed amid a plunge in equities.","Bitcoin was trading just below $17,000, up about 0.2% by 4:00 p.m. EST, according to TradingView data. The leading cryptocurrency by market cap was at $16,993, while ether traded down 0.3% at $1,259.","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/symbols\/BTCUSD\/?exchange=COINBASE\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BTCUSD chart by TradingView<\/span><\/a>","Binance's BNB was up 0.6% over the past day, Ripple's XRP gained 0.9%, and Polygon's MATIC lifted 0.2%.&nbsp;","The U.S. Dollar Index rose to 105.575 at 4:00 p.m. EST, up from 105.1 before the market opened today.&nbsp;","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/chart\/?symbol=NASDAQ%3ACOIN\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">DXY chart by TradingView<\/span><\/a>","The S&amp;P 500 dropped 1.4%, while the Nasdaq 100 slipped 2%.","Coinbase slumped 7.8%, according to Nasdaq data. Shares of the exchange were trading at $42.38 at the close.&nbsp;","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/symbols\/NYSE-SI\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">SI chart by TradingView<\/span><\/a>","Silvergate closed down 4.6% to $23.13 — narrowly avoiding two-year lows.","Block shed 2.9% to $61.33, while MicroStrategy bucked the dip to add 0.2%. Meta sank 6.8% today following a report of EU concerns over targeted advertising in the bloc.&nbsp;","Grayscale's two main products — GBTC and ETHE — are trading at ever-widening discounts to net asset value (NAV). GBTC's discount widened to 43.06%, while ETHE's reached another all-time low of 46.45%.&nbsp;","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/crypto-markets\/structured-products\/premium-of-gbtc\/embed\" title=\"Daily GBTC Premium\/Discount to NAV\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","&nbsp;","Fir Tree Capital said it is <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/192682\/hedge-fund-fir-tree-files-lawsuit-against-grayscale-bloomberg?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">suing<\/a> Grayscale for information to investigate potential mismanagement and conflicts of interest, Bloomberg reported, citing Delaware court documents.&nbsp;","Fir Tree is aiming to use the information to push Grayscale to address the considerable discount it trades at relative to the bitcoin it holds by lowering fees and resuming redemptions, Bloomberg cited sources as saying. The complaint alleges Grayscale has harmed investors through \"shareholder-unfriendly actions.\"","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$1,259","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"7.8%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"TradingView","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Delaware","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Grayscale","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$23.13","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2.9%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"0.9%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"EU","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"S&amp;P","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1.4%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"0.3%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$61.33","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$17,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$42.38","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"4:00 p.m. EST","content":"TIME"},{"type":"46.45%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"6.8%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"43.06%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"4.6%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"0.6%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"0.2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. Dollar Index","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MicroStrategy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$16,993","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Nasdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}