{"summary":"Employees working for the U.S. arm of FTX&#x27;s cryptocurrency exchange business are trying to sell company assets, in some cases without CEO Sam Bankman-Fried&#x27;s “participation,” according to Bloomberg News, which cited two people familiar with the matter.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/185672\/ftx-us-employees-attempt-to-sell-assets-in-ceos-absence-bloomberg","publishDate":"2022-11-10T18:41:26","id":7424,"type":null,"title":"FTX US employees attempt to sell assets in CEO’s absence: Bloomberg","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Employees working for the U.S. arm of FTX's cryptocurrency exchange business are trying to sell company assets, in some cases without CEO Sam <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bankman-Fried's “participation,” according to Bloomberg News, which cited two people familiar with the matter. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Pitched assets including stock-clearing platform Embed and the naming rights to an arena in Miami, the report said. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">While FTX has descended into chaos in recent days after a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/184636\/binance-backs-out-of-ftx-acquisition-deal\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">failed takeover<\/a> by rival Binance, the embattled crypto CEO <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/185486\/ftx-us-warns-trading-may-be-halted-in-coming-days\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">has <\/a><\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">stressed that the American branch of FTX is separate from the global brand and in good financial health. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"FTX US, the US based exchange that accepts Americans, was not financially impacted by this shitshow. It's 100% liquid. Every user could fully withdraw (modulo gas fees etc). Updates on its future coming,\" Bankman-Fried wrote in a thread Thursday.<\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Miami","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX US","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"100%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bloomberg News","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}