{"summary":"Talos targets global expansion with strategic new hires following a $110 million Series B funding round in May.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/172907\/talos-targets-expansion-hires-for-three-key-positions","publishDate":"2022-09-26T14:48:14","id":7442,"type":null,"title":"Talos targets expansion, hires for three key positions","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Crypto trading company Talos announced that it will hire a new head of sales, client success director and business development director.","The hirings follow a $110 million dollar Series B funding round last May.","Digital asset trading company Talos announced it will grow the ranks of its team with three strategic hires.&nbsp;","As it expands globally, Talos will bring in Frank Van Zegveld as head of sales for Europe, the Middle East and Africa; Matt Houston to serve as client success director; and Hillary Conley as business development director, CoinDesk first <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/business\/2022\/09\/26\/crypto-trading-firm-talos-to-expand-in-europe-us-with-new-hires-after-raising-105m\/?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=onecryptofeed&amp;utm_campaign=headlines\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a>.","Previously holding senior positions at Solid Trading and Lucera Financial Infrastructures, Zegveld will be based in Amsterdam. He will join Talos in October.","The hirings at Talos follow the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/145995\/crypto-firm-talos-raises-series-b-citi-wells-fargo\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">close<\/a> of a $105 million Series B funding round last May, led by General Atlantic and joined by Citigroup, Citigroup, Wells Fargo Strategic Capital, BNY Mellon, DRW, SCB 10x, Stripes and Voyager, among others.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Middle East","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Lucera Financial Infrastructures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Amsterdam","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Frank Van Zegveld","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Citigroup","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wells Fargo Strategic Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hillary Conley","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$105 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"BNY Mellon","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Zegveld","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"General Atlantic","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Solid Trading","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$110 million dollar","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"SCB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Africa","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Matt Houston","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"October","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Jeremy Nation","The Block"]}