{"summary":"Geneva, Switzerland \/ February 13, 2023 \/ – TRON DAO announced last week the establishment of a $100M USD Artificial Intelligence Development Fund.  ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/211050\/tron-dao-commits-100m-for-artificial-intelligence-development-fund","publishDate":"2023-02-13T09:00:10","id":7457,"type":null,"title":"TRON DAO Commits $100M for Artificial Intelligence Development Fund","category":["SPONSORED"],"content":["<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Geneva, Switzerland \/ February 13, 2023 \/ –<\/b> <a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TRON DAO<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> announced last week the establishment of a $100M USD <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/ecosystem-fund\/#:~:text=AI%20Fund,the%20blockchain%20world.\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Artificial Intelligence Development Fund<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Three areas of focus have been initially identified:&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">However, innovators and developers whose imaginations arrive at further use cases should absolutely consider applying for funding.&nbsp;<\/span>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A.I. Service Payment Platform<\/b><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TRON’s industry-leading decentralized financial infrastructure is ripe for A.I. infusion, as it will enable self-learning, on-the-go, adaptable capabilities in all aspects of decentralized commerce, including:<\/span><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/b>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A.I. Oracle<\/b><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TRON’s efficient and inexpensive blockchain network, along with its data-focused Layer2 blockchain, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/bt.io\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">the BitTorrent Chain<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, are perfectly oriented for A.I. integration, as its fully decentralized file storage system (BTFS) is leveraged to achieve intelligent management of data, including underlying calling SDKs and API communication.&nbsp;<\/span>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A.I. Generated Content<\/b><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Integrating A.I. tools into content generation will increase efficiency and allow for on-the-go user research to inform creators and developers of market wants and needs. A.I. will also enhance NFT utilization by constantly learning advanced ways to create as well as utilize NFTs.&nbsp;<\/span>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Casting Vision<\/b>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">H.E. Justin Sun, founder of TRON and Ambassador of Grenada to the WTO, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/justinsuntron\/status\/1621811959883776003?s=20&amp;t=zz2d6udCeo10FskLOUjK0A\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweeted<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on February 6, 2023, a thread, summarized here:<\/span><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/b>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">THE BOTTOM LINE<\/b>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The result of blending A.I. and blockchain tech will be a new, decentralized, intelligent ecosystem that is secure, trustworthy, tamper-proof, uncensorable, and adaptable. The hope of the initiative is that developers are inspired to use A.I. in current as well as future applications built on the TRON blockchain, AND that they apply for grants to help them do so.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">When asked, “Which blockchain is integrating artificial intelligence,” ChatGPT responded, “Currently none.” In the near future, with the self-learning capability of A.I., that answer is sure to change. It’s yet another way TRON is empowering decentralized commerce and community for every person on the planet.&nbsp;<\/span>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This post is commissioned by TRON and does not serve as a testimonial or endorsement by The Block. This post is for informational purposes only and should not be relied upon as a basis for investment, tax, legal or other advice. You should conduct your own research and consult independent counsel and advisors on the matters discussed within this post. Past performance of any asset is not indicative of future results.<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"BitTorrent Chain","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"A.I. Generated Content","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"A.I.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Switzerland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"February 6, 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Geneva","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"USD <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/ecosystem-fund\/#:~:text=AI%20Fund,the%20blockchain%20world.\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Artificial Intelligence Development Fund","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$100M","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Grenada","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"February 13, 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"A.I.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Oracle","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"WTO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"A.I. Service","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"H.E. Justin Sun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"TRON DAO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"API","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sponsored","The Block"]}