{"summary":"Mosaic Exchange Limited and its owner ran a &quot;fraudulent digital asset commodity scheme,&quot; a U.S. regulator said on Thursday.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253642\/cftc-charges-mosaic-and-founder-over-digital-asset-commodity-scheme","publishDate":"2023-09-29T11:49:10","id":7459,"type":null,"title":"CFTC charges Mosaic and founder over &#x27;digital asset commodity scheme&#x27;","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto trading platform Mosaic Exchange Limited and its owner ran a \"fraudulent digital asset commodity scheme,\" which included lying about how many assets it had and its profitable track record, according to the Commodity Futures Trading Commission.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">That scheme affected at least 17 people in the U.S. and other countries who gave the platform \"<\/span><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">hundreds of thousands of dollars' worth of bitcoin or other funds\" to be used to trade but were then misappropriated, the CFTC said on Thursday in a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.cftc.gov\/PressRoom\/PressReleases\/8789-23\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s5\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">statement<\/span><\/a>.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">From February 2019 through June 2021, the CFTC said Mosaic and its founder Sean Michael falsely said Mosaic was a crypto trading platform with tens of millions of dollars in assets under management, while also offering an algorithm that had profit margins of up to 60 percent a month. The platform and Michael also said they had a \"partnership\" with BitMEX and Binance, which wasn't true, the CFTC said.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Mosaic, however, never had a partnership or broker agreement with Binance. Nor did it have a partnership agreement with BitMEX,\" according to the agency's complaint.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Some customer funds were misappropriated and used for Michael's restaurant and travel expenses, the CFTC said.<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Mosaic worked \"<\/span><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">under the guise\" that the platform would enter into futures, swaps and leveraged spot transactions, CFTC Commissioner Kristin Johnson said in a statement.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s6\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"<\/span><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The entire scheme was a sham, a virtual house of cards,\" Johnson said.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"June 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sean Michael falsely","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"February 2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Johnson","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"tens of millions of dollars","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"60 percent","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Commodity Futures Trading Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mosaic Exchange Limited","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CFTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Michael","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Binance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kristin Johnson","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["CFTC"],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}