{"summary":"The full VASP license granted by VARA allows it to offer crypto custodial services to institutional clients and sophisticated investors.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/263102\/crypto-custodian-hex-trust-obtains-full-license-in-dubai","publishDate":"2023-11-15T01:08:28","id":7494,"type":null,"title":"Crypto custodian Hex Trust obtains full license in Dubai","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Hex Trust, an institutional crypto custodian, obtained a full Virtual Asset Service Provider license in Dubai as it looks to expand its global presence.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The company announced today that <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Dubai’s Virtual Assets Regulatory Authority granted the full license, <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">allowing it to offer crypto custodial services to institutional clients and sophisticated investors. Hex Trust in February <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/hextrust.com\/resources-collection\/hex-trust-becomes-the-first-fully-operational-virtual-asset-custodian-in-dubai\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">received an MVP operational license<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Filippo Buzzi, Hex Trust’s regional director of MENA, said in a statement that the firm is committed to expanding into the Middle East as it “<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">sees enormous potential for digital asset growth given the progressive regulations, welcoming governments, and thriving crypto ecosystem in the region.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Hex Trust, which <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/137892\/hex-trust-raises-series-b-funding-crypto-custodian\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">raised $88 million in its Series B funding round<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> last year, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/hextrust.com\/resources-collection\/hex-trust-receives-regulatory-approval-in-france-to-provide-digital-asset-custody-services\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">received regulatory approval in France<\/span><\/a> in August<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to offer services including digital asset custody, purchasing, selling and trading.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Middle East","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$88 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Filippo Buzzi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"MENA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dubai","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"France","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Dubai’s Virtual Assets Regulatory Authority","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"February","content":"DATE"},{"type":"MVP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Virtual Asset Service","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}