{"summary":"Crypto prices dipped at the end of the work week while equities were more fortunate. Silvergate was up almost 6% after plunging Thursday.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/216892\/bitcoin-below-23000-as-prices-dip-silvergates-dive-takes-a-breather","publishDate":"2023-03-03T13:00:10","id":7501,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin below $23,000 as prices dip, Silvergate&#x27;s dive takes a breather","category":["TOKEN PROJECTS"],"content":["Crypto prices continued to decline heading into the weekend.","Bitcoin was trading around $22,400 by 12:45 a.m. EST, down 4.5%, according to TradingView data. Ether dropped 4.7% to $1,570.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/symbols\/BTCUSD\/?exchange=COINBASE\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BTCUSD chart by TradingView<\/a><\/span>","Altcoins were trading in a similar direction. Binance's BNB slid 2.7%, Ripple's XRP shed 2.3%, and Polygon's MATIC was down 2.1%","Silvergate's plunge to a breather, with shares rising 5.6% to $6.05, according to TradingView data. The bank's stock <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/216548\/silvergates-network-unravels-leaving-crypto-industry-in-search-of-new-partners\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">took a beating<\/a> on Thursday, a day after it warned in a regulatory <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/216408\/silvergate-may-be-poorly-capitalized-reevaluating-strategy-in-light-of-regulatory-challenges\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filing<\/a> that it may be \"less than well-capitalized\" and was \"re-evaluating its business.\" Shares sank about 50%.","Jack Dorsey's Block added 2.5% to trade above $80. Coinbase shares were up 0.1% to about $63.80.","Shares in MicroStrategy were trading down 2.2% to $247. Co-founder Michael Saylor <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/208527\/michael-saylor-says-silvergate-has-been-responsible-amid-crypto-collapse\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a> Silvergate was \"responsible\" amid the collapse of other crypto institutions, including the FTX exchange, and said he'd keep doing business with the crypto-friendly bank.","Saylor <a href=\"https:\/\/www.microstrategy.com\/content\/dam\/website-assets\/collateral\/financial-documents\/financial-document-archive\/form-8-k_3-2-2023.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">failed<\/a> in his bid to dismiss claims that he didn't adequately pay his income taxes, interest and penalties due in Washington, DC.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"4.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"TradingView","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"12:45 a.m. EST","content":"TIME"},{"type":"4.7%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"5.6%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$247","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"weekend","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2.7%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$1,570","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2.3%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"50%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2.1%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"0.1%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"DC","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$80","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Michael Saylor","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$63.80","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Washington","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$22,400","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2.2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Jack Dorsey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Silvergate","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$6.05","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"MicroStrategy","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN","BNB","EQUITY MOVERS"],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}