{"summary":"Crypto stocks soared on Wall Street today, with the widely shorted Silvergate seeing a lion&#x27;s share of gains.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/212191\/silvergate-hurtles-back-above-20-with-crypto-stocks-in-the-green-across-the-board","publishDate":"2023-02-15T17:10:46","id":7507,"type":null,"title":"Silvergate hurtles back above $20 with crypto stocks in the green across the board","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["Crypto-related stocks soared in trading on Wall Street today. Silvergate, Coinbase, and MicroStrategy led the way with double-digit gains.","Silvergate rose 28.5% to $22.40 at the close, according to Nasdaq data. The crypto-friendly bank has attracted notable investors in recent weeks. BlackRock increased its stake to 7.2% on Jan. 31, while <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/211495\/citadel-securities-takes-5-5-stake-in-crypto-friendly-bank-silvergate-capital-shares-rise\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Citadel Securities<\/a> and <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/211577\/susquehanna-advisors-group-buys-7-5-stake-in-silvergate-following-citadel-securities\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Susquehanna Advisors Group<\/a> reported 5.5% and 7.5% stakes in the firm, respectively, yesterday.","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/chart\/xAJYa739\/?symbol=NYSE%3ASI\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">SI chart by TradingView<\/a>","Despite the interest from Ken Griffin's firm, it doesn't change what is fundamentally at play for the bank, said Andrew Defrance, an analyst at KBW. \"It could lead to a squeeze short term given how high the short interest is, but there would need to be some sort of clarity to be a thesis-changing event for shorts\/longs here,\" he added.","Short interest in Silvergate remains high, with around 72% of outstanding shares currently sold short, according to NYSE data via <a href=\"https:\/\/fintel.io\/ss\/us\/si\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Fintel<\/a>.&nbsp;","Coinbase gained around 17.5%, trading just below $70 at the close. The crypto exchange appears to have shrugged off last week's regulatory woes for now.","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/symbols\/NASDAQ-COIN\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">COIN chart by TradingView<\/span><\/a>","MicroStrategy jumped 10% to trade above $298 by the close. The software firm, better known in recent years for its bet on bitcoin, is up over 100% year-to-date. MicroStrategy owns over 132,500 BTC, according to The Block data, with the stock considered a proxy for investing in bitcoin by some.","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/crypto-markets\/public-companies\/microstrategy-bitcoin-holdings\/embed\" title=\"MicroStrategy Bitcoin Holdings\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Shares in Robinhood were also higher today, gaining 5.7% to trade above $10. The retail investing platform&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/212262\/robinhood-cryptocurrency-trading-volume-jumps-95-in-january\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a> a 95% increase in crypto trading volumes in January to $3.7 billion.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Andrew Defrance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"TradingView","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"7.2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$10","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"10%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jan. 31","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Robinhood","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"72%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$22.40","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"100%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Susquehanna Advisors Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$3.7 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"KBW","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"7.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"5.7%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"17.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"BlackRock","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"5.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"95%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"28.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"NYSE","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"last week","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Citadel Securities","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$298","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Fintel","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MicroStrategy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$70","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Ken Griffin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nasdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["ANALYST REPORTS","EQUITY MOVERS"],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}