{"summary":"Join Frank Chaparro on December 17th at 12pm ET for a panel discussion on developing a digital asset strategy.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/87269\/the-block-presents-developing-a-digital-asset-strategy-brought-to-you-by-paxos","publishDate":"2020-12-10T11:31:22","id":7532,"type":null,"title":"The Block Presents: Developing a Digital Asset Strategy — Brought to you by Paxos","category":["WEBINAR"],"content":["Join Frank Chaparro on December 17th at 12pm ET for a panel discussion on developing a digital asset strategy.","In this event we will explore key considerations firms must take in developing their own digital asset strategy. Including:","You can register for the event and learn more about our panelists below:&nbsp;","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Register for the Event<\/strong>","<iframe title=\"Developing a Digital Asset Strategy — Brought to you by Paxos | The Block\" src=\"https:\/\/app.livestorm.co\/p\/af86081c-fef8-40ee-a55f-866616e90807\/form\" width=\"100%\" height=\"360\" frameborder=\"0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Our panelists:&nbsp;<\/strong><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Caitlin Long<\/strong> - CEO, Avanti Bank<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sina Nader<\/strong> - COO, FTX.US<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Andrew Peel<\/strong> - Head of Digital Asset Markets, Morgan Stanley<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Walter Hessert<\/strong> - Head of Corporate Strategy, Paxos<\/span>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This event is brought to you by <\/strong><a href=\"https:\/\/www.paxos.com\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"nofollow noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Paxos.<\/strong><\/a> Paxos is a regulated financial institution building infrastructure to enable the movement between physical and digital assets. Launched earlier this year, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.paxos.com\/crypto-brokerage\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"nofollow noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Paxos Crypto Brokerage<\/a> is an API-based, turnkey solution that enables companies including PayPal and Revolut to integrate cryptocurrency buying, selling, holding and sending capabilities into their own applications. Paxos also offers other enterprise-grade solutions including stablecoin as a service and blockchain-based settlement of securities and commodities.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Avanti Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Andrew Peel","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"December 17th","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Walter Hessert","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Paxos","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"PayPal","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Morgan Stanley","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Paxos Crypto Brokerage","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Head of Digital Asset Markets","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sina Nader","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sponsored","The Block"]}