{"summary":"Fintech unicorn Nubank has submitted filings to the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) and Brazil&#x27;s Comissão de Valores Mobiliários (CVM relating to a proposed initial public offering (IPO).","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/122299\/brazils-nubank-submits-filing-for-proposed-ipo","publishDate":"2021-10-27T14:40:58","id":7550,"type":null,"title":"Brazil’s Nubank submits filing for proposed IPO","category":["FINTECH"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The parent company of Brazil fintech unicorn Nubank announced on Wednesday that it has submitted filings to regulators in the U.S. and Brazil regarding a proposed initial public offering (IPO).&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Nu Holdings Ltd. said in a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.businesswire.com\/news\/home\/20211027005661\/en\/Nu-Announces-Confidential-Submission-of-Draft-Registration-Statement-for-Proposed-Initial-Public-Offering\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">press release<\/a> that it “confidentially submitted a draft registration statement” with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), via a Form-1. The company has also filed a reference form with Brazil’s SEC equivalent, the Comissão de Valores Mobiliários (CVM).&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">According to a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2021-10-27\/buffett-backed-nubank-submits-confidential-filing-for-u-s-ipo\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bloomberg report<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> quoting an unnamed source, the IPO would launch on the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) and the transaction would happen in December. However, it noted that talks are still ongoing and those details could change. Nu said in its press release that the IPO would happen after both the SEC and CVM finish their own review processes, which is “subject to market and other conditions.”&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Nubank, which offers digital banking products such as bank accounts, personal loans and life insurance with little or no fees, now counts more than 40 million customers in Brazil, Mexico and Colombia.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Industry watchers have expected the neobank company to file for an IPO at some point, especially after it scored a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.wsj.com\/articles\/berkshire-hathaway-to-buy-500-million-stake-in-brazils-nubank-11623153600?mod=markets_lead_pos6\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$500 million investment <\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">from Warren Buffett’s Berkshire Hathaway in June. That deal pushed Nubank’s value to <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.reuters.com\/article\/nubank-ipo-idUSL4N2RN44Q\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$30 billion<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, outlets including Reuters and Forbes have reported. The company also <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.reuters.com\/business\/buffett-backed-nubank-turns-profit-brazil-2021-10-13\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">recently posted<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> its first-ever semester profit in Brazil, according to Reuters.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Nubank's parent company said in its press release that the proposed IPO involves registering and listing Class A ordinary shares in the U.S. The number and price range of those shares have yet to be determined, it said.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In addition, the proposal includes “the registration and admission to negotiate a program of Brazilian Depositary Receipts (“BDRs”) in Brazil” as well as “the registration of initial public offering for distribution of BDRs in Brazil representing a fraction of Class A ordinary shares.”<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"IPO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Brazil","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"New York Stock Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mexico","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"December","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Colombia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$500 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Reuters","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"June","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Comissão de Valores Mobiliários (CVM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Nu Holdings Ltd.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Nubank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CVM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Warren Buffett’s Berkshire Hathaway","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$30 billion","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["FINTECH"],"authors":["Kristin Majcher","The Block"]}