{"summary":"DeForm is a San Francisco-based startup that gives marketers blockchain-based tools to help augment the digital marketing landscape.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/247338\/web3-marketing-firm-deform-raises-4-6-million-in-seed-funding","publishDate":"2023-08-30T12:00:03","id":7585,"type":null,"title":"Web3 marketing firm DeForm raises $4.6 million in seed funding","category":["VENTURE CAPITAL"],"content":["Web3 marketing firm DeForm has secured $4.6 million in seed funding.&nbsp;","Born from its parent firm Contribution Labs, the San Francisco-based startup gives marketers blockchain-based tools to help augment the digital marketing landscape. Marketers can use the DeForm platform to understand a user based on their wallet transaction history and token ownership, and thus provide tailored marketing initiatives.","The platform itself is blockchain agnostic but built using <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/169539\/web3-unicorn-alchemy-is-raising-for-a-new-venture-fund\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Alchemy's<\/a> developer platform.&nbsp;","Kindred Ventures led the round, which had additional participation from Elad Gil, Scalar Capital, A.Capital, Alchemy Ventures, Naval Ravikat, Sota Watanabe, Sep Kamvar, Scott Belsky, Marc Bhargava and others.&nbsp;","DeForm intends to use the funds to expand its team, as well as to continue tackling the hurdles for verifying consumer transaction history across different blockchains.","\"The biggest challenge that we face right now is checking for wallet activity, just because there's a lot of different individual activity that happens throughout so many different chains. Some of them are supported by default infrastructure providers, others are not,\" DeForm CEO and co-founder Catherine Chang told The Block.&nbsp;","Checking for wallet activity for customers using a different L1 or L2 blockchain comes with time-consuming checks and balances, as well as determining what is and isn't arbitrary, Chang noted.","\"It can become pretty challenging for our team to sift through the masses of data to figure out specific activities,\" she added.&nbsp;","Despite the technical challenges, DeForm has already penned notable partnerships, such as with Coinbase's new Layer 2 network <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/243899\/base-mainnet-onchain-summer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Base<\/a> for the platform's digital asset program.&nbsp;","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"We launched the Genesis Builder NFT as a permanent onchain record of our appreciation for builders who built their projects on Base Mainnet from its very early stages,\" Base creator Jesse Pollak said in a statement. \"Working with DeForm has been invaluable in this process to help us collect and verify the information we’d need to make the program a success.\"<\/span>","(Corrects story to describe Alchemy as a development platform.)","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"San Francisco","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sep Kamvar","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Catherine Chang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Scalar Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sota Watanabe","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Marc Bhargava","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Naval Ravikat","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Genesis Builder NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alchemy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Scott Belsky","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Contribution Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$4.6 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Jesse Pollak","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alchemy Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Elad Gil","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chang","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["SEED &AMP; PRE-SEED"],"authors":["MK Manoylov","The Block"]}