{"summary":"The US Senate confirmed Michael Barr, a former Ripple adviser, to serve in a key watchdog role for the U.S. Federal Reserve.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/157460\/former-ripple-adviser-barr-confirmed-by-senate-for-fed-job","publishDate":"2022-07-13T17:36:02","id":7587,"type":null,"title":"Former Ripple adviser Barr confirmed by Senate for Fed job ","category":["REGULATION"],"content":["The Senate confirmed Michael Barr to serve as oversight chief for the U.S. Federal Reserve on Wednesday, ending a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/134605\/fintech-charters-and-corruption-allegations-trigger-senate-standoff-over-fed-nominees\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">lengthy and dramatic<\/span><\/a> nomination process that stretched over six months.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","President Joe Biden nominated Barr — a former advisor to distributed ledger tech startup Ripple — to serve as vice chair of supervision for the Fed in the spring, after Republicans and key swing vote Sen. Joe Manchin (D-WV) <a href=\"https:\/\/www.manchin.senate.gov\/newsroom\/press-releases\/manchin-i-am-unable-to-support-nomination-of-sarah-bloom-raskin-to-federal-reserve-board\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">opposed<\/a> his initial nominee. Sarah Bloom Raskin withdrew from the process in March.","Barr served in the Treasury Department during the Obama administration and helped develop the 2010 Dodd-Frank regulatory framework for financial institutions. He is a faculty member at the University of Michigan.","Barr’s confirmation means a former crypto industry adviser will work in a key role in overseeing financial institutions as inflation soars and markets remain volatile.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","The Senate <a href=\"https:\/\/www.senate.gov\/legislative\/LIS\/roll_call_votes\/vote1172\/vote_117_2_00250.htm#position\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">voted<\/a> 66-28 to confirm Barr’s nomination to serve a four-year term as vice chairman for supervision of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System. Forty-five Democrats and 21 Republicans voted to confirm Barr. The 28 Senators who voted against his confirmation were all Republicans. Six Senators did not vote.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","The vice chair of supervision role is critical in “regulating our nation’s financial institutions to ensure Americans are treated fairly and to protect the stability of our economy,” Biden said in a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.whitehouse.gov\/briefing-room\/statements-releases\/2022\/04\/15\/statement-from-president-biden-on-his-intent-to-nominate-michael-barr-to-serve-as-vice-chair-for-supervision-of-the-federal-reserve\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">statement<\/a> when he announced his intent to nominate Barr.&nbsp;","&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"the University of Michigan","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Michael Barr","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Fed","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2010","content":"DATE"},{"type":"28","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Joe Manchin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Obama","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Treasury Department","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sarah Bloom Raskin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Barr","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S. Federal Reserve","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"spring","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Joe Biden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Biden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Senate","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Stephanie Murray","The Block"]}