{"summary":"With the Twitter takeover finalized, billionaire Elon Musk becomes the sole director of the social media platform.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/181457\/elon-musk-takes-sole-control-of-twitter","publishDate":"2022-10-31T15:19:19","id":7612,"type":null,"title":"Elon Musk takes sole control of Twitter","category":["MERGERS & ACQUISITIONS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Elon Musk is in charge. He became the sole director of Twitter after all other directors were kicked to the curb following his purchase of the social media giant.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Effective at the time of Musk’s takeover, former directors let go included Bret Taylor, Parag Agrawal, Omid Kordestani, David Rosenblatt, Martha Lane Fox, Patrick Pichette, Egon Durban, Fei-Fei Li and Mimi Alemayehou, according to a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.sec.gov\/ix?doc=\/Archives\/edgar\/data\/0001418091\/000119312522272772\/d411753d8k.htm\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filing<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission detailing terms of the material agreement for the $44 billion deal.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Musk, who notably attempted to back out of the deal before it was finalized, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/180752\/binance-confirmed-as-investor-in-twitter-takeover-as-musk-reportedly-plans-to-take-reins-as-ceo\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">received<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> $500 million in partial funding from Binance.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A number of large advertisers including Ford and GM reportedly said they will pause advertising as they assess the direction Twitter takes under Musk.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Binance","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"GM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Parag Agrawal","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Egon Durban","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Fei","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bret Taylor","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Elon Musk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fei Li","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$44 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$500 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Ford","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Musk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Martha Lane Fox","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Patrick Pichette","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Mimi Alemayehou","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"David Rosenblatt","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Omid Kordestani","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["ELON MUSK","TWITTER"],"authors":["Jeremy Nation","The Block"]}