{"summary":"The chief operating officer of crypto-focused venture capital and hedge fund Pantera Capital has left after just two months in the job.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/166721\/pantera-capital-coo-leaves-after-just-two-months-with-the-firm","publishDate":"2022-08-31T07:36:35","id":7631,"type":null,"title":"Pantera Capital COO leaves after just two months with the firm","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Samir Shah has stepped down as chief operating officer at Pantera Capital after just two months in the job, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.linkedin.com\/in\/samir-shah-690688\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">according<\/a> to his LinkedIn profile.","Shah only <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/news+\/160410\/54-key-crypto-hires-exits-and-moves-july-2022\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">joined<\/a> the firm in July, having spent nearly 13 years at the investment bank JPMorgan, most recently serving as head of asset management sales. Pantera Capital is a crypto-focused venture capital and hedge fund with over $4.7 billion in assets under management, according to its <a href=\"https:\/\/panteracapital.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">website<\/a>. The fund recently also lost its general counsel, Joe Cisewski.&nbsp;","Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) Commissioner Christy Goldsmith Romero <a href=\"https:\/\/www.cftc.gov\/PressRoom\/PressReleases\/8564-22?utm_source=govdelivery\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/a> on July 26 that Cisewski was joining the agency as chief of staff and senior counsel. Cisewski previously worked for the CFTC under former Commissioner <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/123003\/ftx-us-hires-gensler-era-cftc-commissioner-to-spearhead-lobbying\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Mark Wetjen<\/a>.","Earlier in the summer, Pantera made headlines as it <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/147668\/terra-pantera-capital-cashed-out-80-investment-before-ust-crash\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">cashed out<\/a> nearly 80% of its investment in the Terra ecosystem before the TerraUSD stablecoin collapsed at the beginning of May. More recently, in July, the firm <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/158678\/nft-fraud-fighters-optic-raise-11-million-in-seed-funding-round\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">co-led a seed round<\/a> in NFT fraud fighters Optic with Kleiner Perkins.","Pantera Capital did not immediately respond to request for comment from The Block, nor did Shah when contacted on LinkedIn.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Cisewski","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"80%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"July 26","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Commissioner <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/123003\/ftx-us-hires-gensler-era-cftc-commissioner-to-spearhead-lobbying\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Mark Wetjen","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Kleiner Perkins","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$4.7 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Shah","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Pantera Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Christy Goldsmith Romero","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CFTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Terra","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Pantera","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Joe Cisewski","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Samir Shah","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"summer","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["CFTC"],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}