{"summary":"FTX investors including Temasek, Sequoia Capital and SoftBank are writing off hundreds of millions of dollars they poured in the now-failed exchanged,","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/187527\/temasek-sequoia-softbank-take-hundreds-of-millions-in-ftx-write-downs-bloomberg","publishDate":"2022-11-16T08:55:48","id":7655,"type":null,"title":"Temasek, Sequoia, SoftBank take more the $600 million in FTX write-downs: Bloomberg","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["FTX investors including Temasek, Sequoia Capital and SoftBank are writing off hundreds of millions of dollars they poured in the now-failed exchanged, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2022-11-16\/singapore-s-temasek-to-write-down-over-200-million-in-ftx\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bloomberg<\/a> reported, citing people familiar.&nbsp;","Singapore's Temasek International is writing off its up to $300 million FTX investment, while Sequoia Capital wrote down the full value of its $214 million bet on the exchange. SoftBank Group Corp. is expecting a loss of $100 million on its investment.&nbsp;&nbsp;","The news comes days after FTX filed for bankruptcy protection and amid a series of cryptic tweets by former CEO Sam Bankman-Fried that he's trying to raise liquidity and make customers whole.&nbsp;","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$214 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Sequoia Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$100 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SoftBank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Temasek","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SoftBank Group Corp.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"millions of dollars","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$300 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Temasek International","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Christiana Loureiro","The Block"]}