{"summary":"FTX creditors will be represented by Paul Hastings LLP in the crypto exchange&#x27;s high-profile bankruptcy proceedings.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/197446\/ftx-paul-hastings","publishDate":"2022-12-22T08:52:57","id":7705,"type":null,"title":"FTX creditors tap Paul Hastings LLP for representation: reports","category":["BANKRUPTCY"],"content":["FTX creditors will be represented by Paul Hastings LLP in the crypto exchange's high-profile bankruptcy proceedings.","Paul Hastings was <a href=\"https:\/\/www.wsj.com\/articles\/ftx-customer-committee-taps-paul-hastings-for-exchanges-chapter-11-case-11671666596?mod=article_relatedinline\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">chosen<\/a> from a pool of candidates by a nine-member committee formed last Thursday, according to The Wall Street Journal, citing people familiar with the matter. The law firm later <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/business\/2022\/12\/22\/ftx-creditors-hire-law-firm-paul-hastings-as-representation-wsj\/?utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_campaign=headlines\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">confirmed<\/a> the news to CoinDesk.","The ongoing bankruptcy proceedings for FTX see the company attempting to reclaim more than $1 billion spread around the world. Its founder and former CEO, Sam Bankman-Fried, was in FBI custody and extradited to the U.S. from the Bahamas on criminal charges.&nbsp;Caroline Ellison, the former CEO of Bankman-Fried's sister firm Alameda Research, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/197342\/bankman-fried-in-fbi-custody-ellison-wang-plead-guilty-and-are-cooperating\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">agreed<\/a> to a plea deal with the U.S. Department of Justice. FTX co-founder Gary Wang did the same.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"copyright\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice.",""],"entity":[{"type":"Paul Hastings","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Paul Hastings LLP","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"last Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$1 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Caroline Ellison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FBI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. Department of Justice","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bahamas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gary Wang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Adam James","The Block"]}