{"summary":"If recent headlines are any indication, Wall Street&#x27;s slow embrace of bitcoin – or, at least, financial instruments tied to it – is beginning to pick up the pace.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/65470\/anthony-scaramucci-paul-tudor-jones-took-a-sledgehammer-to-the-wall-between-wall-street-and-bitcoin","publishDate":"2020-05-15T16:37:18","id":772,"type":null,"title":"Anthony Scaramucci: Paul Tudor Jones took &quot;a sledgehammer&quot; to the wall between Wall Street and bitcoin","category":["PODCASTS"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 19 of Season 2 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block’s Frank Chaparro and Ryan Todd along with Skybridge Capital’s Anthony Scaramucci.&nbsp;<\/i>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/a>, or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to&nbsp;<a target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"671708030406141327130f02050b08040c04151e1713084904080a\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/span><\/a>.<\/em>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode of The Scoop is brought to you by&nbsp;<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitstamp<\/strong>,&nbsp;the original global cryptocurrency exchange. Since 2011, Bitstamp has been a cornerstone of the industry, earning the trust of over four million individuals and top financial institutions looking for a reliable trading venue. Whether you’re trading on our web platform, mobile app or industry-leading APIs, Bitstamp gives you the professional-grade tools you need to execute your strategy.&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/bitstamp.net\/app?r=pro%E2%80%93&amp;utm_source=Website&amp;utm_medium=podcast&amp;utm_campaign=theblock&amp;utm_content=ctaapp\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Download the Bitstamp app<\/b><\/a>&nbsp;or visit&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.bitstamp.net\/pro\/?utm_source=Website&amp;utm_medium=podcast&amp;utm_campaign=theblock&amp;utm_content=ctaweb\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitstamp.net\/Pro<\/b><\/a>&nbsp;to learn more and start trading today!<\/em>","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK6766073074\" width=\"100%\" height=\"200\" frameborder=\"0\" scrolling=\"no\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","If recent headlines are any indication, Wall Street's slow embrace of bitcoin – or, at least, financial instruments tied to it – is beginning to pick up the pace.","Earlier this week, it was reported that JPMorgan <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/64906\/jpmorgan-now-serves-crypto-exchanges-coinbase-and-gemini-first-clients-report\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">is offering banking services<\/a> to cryptocurrency exchanges Coinbase and Gemini. And macro investor&nbsp;Paul Tudor Jones recently revealed that he allocated as much as 2% of his assets to bitcoin, while his fund has opened to door <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/64398\/paul-tudor-jones-says-he-is-buying-bitcoin-as-a-hedge-against-central-bank-money-printing\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">to buying bitcoin futures<\/a>. Elsewhere, derivatives markets are heating up with volumes and open interest on CME Group's bitcoin option contract hitting fresh highs on Thursday.&nbsp;","Market participants point to the juxtaposition of central bank money printing and bitcoin's fixed-supply – the latter of which was very much on display this week during the halving event – as one catalyst for recent interest.","On this episode of The Scoop, Skybridge Capital's Anthony Scaramucci explores these developments and why he is \"there\" when it comes to being convinced to allocate some capital to bitcoin.&nbsp;","\"Paul is closed for new investors, but if he wasn’t closed for new investors, I would be in his fund,\" Scaramucci said. \"And I have no problem owning, as a pass-through through his fund, some level of digital currency exposure.\"","In this episode, the former 10-day-long White House communications director said that Jones has helped the idea of owning bitcoin acceptable go mainstream.","An admitted non-crypto expert, Scaramucci said there is a technological opportunity for peer-to-peer transfer of value with permanency.","&nbsp;\"There is an era coming where everybody is going to want to own something that is less manipulated by the governments as it relates to a store of value,\" he said.","Scaramucci said that a few more announcements like Paul Tudor Jones' revelation that he will take on exposure to bitcoin will cause the \"wall to fall down.\"&nbsp;","We also explore:&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Jones","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ryan Todd","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gemini","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2011","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CME Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Anthony Scaramucci","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"White House","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Paul","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bitstamp","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Scaramucci","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Skybridge Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Paul Tudor Jones","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}