{"summary":"The Bank of Canada recently confirmed a 12-month research project exploring the use cases of central bank digital currencies with MIT.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/141269\/consensus-on-cbdc-design-among-central-banks-not-a-priority-bank-of-canada-says","publishDate":"2022-04-12T08:16:56","id":7743,"type":null,"title":"Consensus on CBDC design among central banks not a priority, Bank of Canada says","category":["CENTRAL BANKS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">As central banks around the world explore central bank digital currencies (CBDCs), the Bank of Canada (BOC) is keen to stress that rollout efforts don't require coordination between nations — and may not even need blockchain technology at all.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CBDCs are digital forms of fiat currencies that are controlled by a nation’s monetary authority, with rollout programs currently overseen by <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">supranational working groups. In 2020, it was announced that officials from the Bank of International Settlements and the Bank of England <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.bankofcanada.ca\/2020\/01\/central-bank-working-group-cbdc\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">would oversee a six-strong group of central banks<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, including the BOC, as they pool together research on CBDC use cases.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Yet Dinesh Shah, the BOC’s director of fintech research, told The Block in an interview last week that reaching consensus on CBDC implementation with other central banks is “not a central focus” — unless the bank chose to explore cross-border payments.&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ultimately, Shah says that decisions regarding a CBDC are specific to individual countries due to their differing payment systems. He explains that the six-strong group formed in early 2020 primarily exists to pool research.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Even if there’s no consensus, that open sharing of ideas is very valuable,” he adds.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In Canada, research on this topic began around 2010, with Shah joining as the BOC’s first technologist in 2014. While one of his first tasks was explaining the technology behind bitcoin to policymakers and economists, the catalyst for the research was not crypto itself, but the decline of cash.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“At the Bank of Canada, what [the research] really came out of was not really thinking about cryptocurrencies, but it was more what was happening with cash demand,” he says. “Like in many other countries, there's been this steady decline in everyday cash use, even though there's been an increase in the amount of cash out there in the economy.”&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Shah stressed that no formal decision has been made to issue a Canadian CBDC. It’s still quite early days, he says — so much so that the role of blockchain technology, decentralized digital ledgers that underpin the vast majority of cryptocurrencies, in designing any CBDC is not clear.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Blockchain technology “is not a given but it’s still on our list of potentials,” he says, noting that he has displayed some skepticism in the past about its fit with a retail CBDC. His views echo that of other central bankers, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/cointelegraph.com\/news\/blockchain-not-suitable-for-cbdc-says-swiss-national-bank-economist\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">notably Thomas Moser<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> of the Swiss central bank.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Recently, the BOC <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/138067\/canadas-central-bank-and-mit-to-collaborate-on-cbdc-research\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced a 12-month research project<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> with <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">MIT.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Although it’s currently unclear what form their research findings will take — “depending on what we find, there may be some papers that come out of it” —&nbsp;he confirmed that the bank will collaborate with the <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.bankofengland.co.uk\/news\/2022\/march\/boe-and-massachusetts-institute-of-technology-joint-cbdc-collaboration\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bank of England<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> and <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.bostonfed.org\/news-and-events\/press-releases\/2022\/frbb-and-mit-open-cbdc-phase-one.aspx\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">the Federal Reserve Bank of Boston<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, which are also MIT research partners.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2014","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Federal Reserve Bank of Boston","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Canada","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"supranational","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2010","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bank of England","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Shah","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"fintech","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bank of International Settlements","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bank of Canada","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dinesh Shah","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"MIT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BOC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thomas Moser","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bank of Canada (BOC","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Tom Matsuda","The Block"]}