{"summary":"FSB Europe Group said crypto conglomarates and exchanges need urgent regulation.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/185509\/european-g20-leaders-call-for-urgent-regulation-of-crypto-conglomerates","publishDate":"2022-11-10T15:04:20","id":7788,"type":null,"title":"European G20 leaders call for urgent regulation of &#x27;crypto conglomerates&#x27;","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Central bankers and financial regulators making up the Financial Stability Board’s European arm discussed the urgent need to regulate crypto given “recent developments,” and endorsed their October report on stablecoins.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Europe’s financial leaders agreed on the urgent need to regulate “so-called crypto conglomerates and exchanges that vertically integrate multiple functions,\" according to a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.fsb.org\/2022\/10\/international-regulation-of-crypto-asset-activities-a-proposed-framework-questions-for-consultation\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">press release<\/span><\/a>.<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> The statement does not directly cite the implosion of FTX, but comes in the context of the exchange's failure.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The group of European G20 members making up FSB Europe, along with leadership for the European Commission and European Banking Authority, which joined the regular meeting in Lisbon, also expressed intentions to tighten regulation over digital assets.&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">FSB members further touted the central banker group's <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/176025\/g20-central-bankers-warn-stablecoins-arent-stable-recommend-action-around-crypto-assets\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">October reports<\/a> on stablecoins and regulating digital currencies.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Comments on the FSB’s crypto regulations are still open until Dec. 15, and a final report of regulatory recommendations is expected in the summer of 2023.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"FSB Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"European Banking Authority","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"summer of 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FSB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"European G20","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"October","content":"DATE"},{"type":"European Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lisbon","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Dec. 15","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Financial Stability Board","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["EUROPEAN COUNCIL"],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}