{"summary":"Blockchain can widen access to alternative investments and clear U.S. regulations could allow for tokenization of trillions in real-world assets on-chain.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/239022\/carlos-domingo-securitize-scoop","publishDate":"2023-07-11T16:04:00","id":7800,"type":null,"title":"Here’s how financial giants like KKR and Hamilton Lane are diving into crypto","category":["CRYPTO INFRASTRUCTURE"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 64<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 5 of The Scoop was recorded with <b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro and Securitize Founder &amp; CEO Carlos Domingo.<\/b><\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on <a href=\"https:\/\/www.youtube.com\/channel\/UCqjFueYMJ78eF6G0lGLzzpQ\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Youtube<\/a>, <\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a>,<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Please send feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"265649424547555266524e43444a49454d084549\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm\/?e=BLOCK6705840047\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Carlos Domingo is the founder and CEO of Securitize, Inc. — a compliance platform for trading security tokens or digital securities on the blockchain used by the likes of KKR and <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/229366\/securitize-hamilton-lane-tokenized-fund-ploygon\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Hamilton Lane<\/a>.","In this episode, Domingo explains how blockchain technology can be used to unlock broader access to alternative investments and how regulatory clarity in the U.S. could help trillions of dollars of real world assets be tokenized on-chain.","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Outline:<\/strong>","1:17 - About Securitize<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n2:32 - Market Evolution<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n7:22 - Tokenization<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n8:07 - Transfer Agent License<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n9:58 - Broker Dealers<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n12:00 - Prometheum<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n13:04 - Special Purpose Broker Dealer<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n16:38 - Alternative Trading Systems<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n19:05 - Second Order Effects of Regulation<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n21:30 - Tokenization of Real World Assets<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n28:02 - What’s Next for Securitize<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n31:32 - Closing Thoughts","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"trillions of dollars","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Domingo","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hamilton Lane","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securitize Founder &amp; CEO Carlos Domingo","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Carlos Domingo","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Securitize, Inc.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"KKR","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}