{"summary":"Following bitcoin&#x27;s surge in value overnight, CFTC&#x27;s Summer Mersinger said investing in cryptocurrency is no longer a fad.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/259168\/crypto-investing-isnt-just-a-fad-cftc-commissioner-mersinger-says-amid-latest-etf-fueled-bitcoin-rally","publishDate":"2023-10-24T10:43:42","id":7802,"type":null,"title":"Crypto investing isn&#x27;t just a fad, CFTC Commissioner Mersinger says amid latest ETF-fueled bitcoin rally","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Commodity Futures Trading Commission's Summer Mersinger, in comments made following bitcoin's latest surge in price over the past day, said investing in cryptocurrency is no longer a fad.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitcoin surged <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/259100\/bitcoin-ticks-above-35000-as-spot-etf-hype-builds\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">to over $35,000<\/a> on Tuesday morning amid rising anticipation that spot bitcoin ETFs could soon be approved.&nbsp;<\/span><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Republican commissioner told CoinDeskTV that certain bitcoin-related ETFs have traded for some time and that there is institutional interest in investing in crypto.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"I think there's a lot of interest in these products,\" Mersinger said. \"And, you know, the market is ready for these products to be available.\"<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"There was a thought at some point by regulators that this was almost a fad that people would move on,\" Mersinger later said. \"The more we see traditional finance stepping in and really investing, it's just further proof that these products aren't going away.\"<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The latest uptick in bitcoin's price came after BlackRock's proposed spot bitcoin ETF, the iShares Bitcoin Trust, made an <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/258041\/blackrocks-spot-bitcoin-etf-appears-on-dtcc-website-with-ticker-ibtc\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">appearance<\/span><\/a> on a list maintained by the Depository Trust and Clearing Corporation, which some analysts took as a positive step toward final approval by the Securities and Exchange Commission.<\/span>","BlackRock's fund is one of a dozen bitcoin ETFs awaiting approval by the SEC. The agency has not yet approved a spot fund but did allow bitcoin futures ETFs to begin trading in 2021.&nbsp;","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Other big names have filed for spot bitcoin ETFs including Grayscale Investments, Fidelity and WisdomTree.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$35,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"BlackRock","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mersinger","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"WisdomTree","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fidelity","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Grayscale Investments","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitcoin Trust","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Commodity Futures Trading Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"morning","content":"TIME"},{"type":"Depository Trust and Clearing Corporation","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["CFTC","SEC"],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}