{"summary":"The Sandbox is releasing 2,333 Gordon Ramsay avatars players can use as their digital identity on the metaverse platform.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/217564\/gordon-ramsays-sandbox-avatar-nfts-coming-to-the-metaverse","publishDate":"2023-03-06T16:59:00","id":7807,"type":null,"title":"Gordon Ramsay’s Sandbox avatar NFTs coming to the metaverse","category":["METAVERSE & NFT"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Lovably cantankerous head of “Hell’s Kitchen” Gordon Ramsay is getting the full blockchain treatment. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Metaverse gaming platform The Sandbox announced that Ramsay — a Michelin star chef and main draw of the reality cooking show “Hell’s Kitchen” — is being turned into a collection of non-fungible token (NFT) avatars that users will be able to mint later this month. There will be a total of 2,333 Ramsay avatars, The Sandbox <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/TheSandboxGame\/status\/1632833682636505088?s=20\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said via Twitter<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Users of The Sandbox will be able to roam and play games inside the blockchain-enabled metaverse platform using one of the Ramsay avatars. The Sandbox has also dropped an NFT avatar collection based on the web3 enthusiast and musical celebrity Snoop Dogg. The rapper’s avatar collection has generated nearly $12 million in trading volume, according to OpenSea.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Web3 gaming and metaverse platforms have generally struggled to go mainstream and attract a significant number of users, but some companies, including The Sandbox, have been highly successful in attracting major corporate partners and some celebrities keen to get in on the ground floor. Late last year The Sandbox <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.animocabrands.com\/the-sandbox-partners-with-itv-studios-to-spice-up-metaverse-with-gordon-ramsays-hells-kitchen\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced a partnership<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> with ITV Studios and plans to create a metaverse experience inspired by Ramsay’s show “Hell’s Kitchen.”<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Screenshot from Gordon Ramsay avatar teaser trailer on Twitter.<\/em>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Sandbox has also worked with large companies like <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/138003\/banking-giant-hsbc-partners-with-metaverse-firm-the-sandbox\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">HSBC<\/a>, Warner Music, PlayBoy, Gucci and Ubisoft. Additionally, long-time celebrity influencer Paris Hilton <a href=\"https:\/\/www.sandbox.game\/en\/blog\/paris-hilton-x-the-sandbox\/3254\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">struck a deal<\/a> with the company last year.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nWhile speaking at NFT Paris, <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sebastien Borget, chief operating officer of The Sandbox, told The Block <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/215900\/the-sandbox-sebastien-borget-future-corporate-partnerships\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">he believes<\/a> that the brand recognition his company has achieved thus far will eventually help lure independent creators to build on the platform. The Sandbox has said it has 201,000 monthly active users.&nbsp;<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nThe Sandbox plans, in the coming days, to release more details on how users will be able acquire a Ramsay avatar.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Snoop Dogg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"HSBC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Michelin","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Sandbox","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Warner Music","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$12 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"PlayBoy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Paris Hilton","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Paris","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ramsay","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gordon Ramsay","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ubisoft","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ramsay","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sebastien Borget","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kitchen” Gordon Ramsay","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gucci","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}