{"summary":"Michael Sonnenshein took the reigns of cryptocurrency asset manager Grayscale Investments earlier this year.  At the helm of the more than $30 billion","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/95033\/grayscales-ceo-details-hiring-plans-the-long-term-goal-of-a-bitcoin-etf","publishDate":"2021-02-16T15:06:17","id":7828,"type":null,"title":"Grayscale&#x27;s CEO details hiring plans, the long-term goal of a bitcoin ETF","category":["INVESTMENTS"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 8 of Season 3 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block’s Frank Chaparro and Grayscale CEO Michael Sonnenshein<\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"6f1f000b0c0e1c1b2f1b070a0d03000c040c1d161f1b00410c0002\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode of The Scoop is brought to you by&nbsp;<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"http:\/\/kraken.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kraken<\/a>.<\/strong><\/i>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kraken<\/em><\/strong>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Whether you’re an experienced crypto trader or just starting out, Kraken has the tools to help you achieve financial freedom. With 50+ cryptocurrencies to choose from, industry-leading security and a wide variety of features to suit any investing strategy, Kraken puts the power in your hands to buy, sell and trade digital assets. Visit&nbsp;<a href=\"http:\/\/kraken.com\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kraken.<wbr data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">com<\/a>&nbsp;to get started&nbsp;<span class=\"sh-date\" tabindex=\"0\" data-date-isostring=\"2021-02-04T20:00:00.000Z\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">today<\/span>.<\/em>","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK1894543905\" width=\"100%\" height=\"200\" frameborder=\"0\" scrolling=\"no\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Michael Sonnenshein took the reigns of cryptocurrency asset manager Grayscale Investments earlier this year.&nbsp;","At the helm of the more than $30 billion investment firm, Sonnenshein is charting a course for a broad expansion of the business, which is best known for its Grayscale Bitcoin Trust.","\"We brought in $5.7 billion last year,\" Sonnenshein said. \"We are launching new products, we are investing in technology, we're building out the various teams, it's really about continuing to stay ahead of the growth we are experiencing at really an unprecedented rate.\"","<iframe title=\"AUM of the Grayscale Bitcoin Trust\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/crypto-markets\/grayscale\/aum-of-the-grayscale-bitcoin-trust\/embed\" width=\"100%\" height=\"420\" frameborder=\"0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","New inflows into the firm helped push Grayscale's assets under management (AUM) to new highs, while also lining its pockets with fee-based revenue. Estimates by The Block Research suggest Grayscale has brought in more than $109 million year-to-date.&nbsp;","In addition to new hires, the firm has a plan for upgrading its GBTC product to an exchange-traded fund should the regulators ultimately approve such a product.&nbsp;","\"We spent the better part of 2017 in SEC registration for Grayscale Bitcoin Trust,\" Sonnenshein told The Block. \"And we made a lot of progress with the commission and ultimately realized the regulatory environment wasn't ready for a bitcoin ETF and we pulled out of that process.\"","He added:","\"But we hope in the future, like we were planning to in 2017, to register and uplift GBTC onto a national securities exchange as a bonafide ETF.\"","Still, competition is mounting, with BlockFi and Osprey recently rolling out new funds. There's also Bitwise, which has seen its assets under management climb towards $1 billion in recent months.&nbsp;","In this episode of The Scoop, Sonnenshein breaks down its hiring goals for 2021 as well as the following:","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Grayscale Bitcoin Trust","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Grayscale","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitwise","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$109 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Grayscale Investments","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$5.7 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Kraken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sonnenshein","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sonnenshein","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Michael Sonnenshein","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$30 billion","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN"],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}