{"summary":"Fintech firm Amun AG, which currently offers crypto exchange-traded products (ETPs) in Switzerland and Germany, has received regulatory nod to expand its","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/49857\/amun-gets-regulatory-nod-to-offer-crypto-exchange-traded-products-in-eu","publishDate":"2019-12-10T01:00:22","id":7878,"type":null,"title":"Amun gets regulatory nod to offer crypto exchange-traded products in EU ","category":["CRYPTOCURRENCY"],"content":["<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Fintech firm Amun AG, which currently offers crypto exchange-traded products (ETPs) in Switzerland and Germany, has received regulatory nod to expand its offerings in the European Union (EU).<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Announced Tuesday, Swiss-based Amun said the Swedish Financial Supervisory Authority (SFSA), or the Finansinspektionen, has approved its base prospectus to offer investment products tied to cryptocurrencies.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Amun currently offers&nbsp;<\/span><a class=\"_e75a791d-denali-editor-page-rtfLink\" href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/41884\/swiss-six-exchange-lists-bitcoin-and-ether-exchange-traded-product\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">nine<\/span><\/a><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;cryptocurrency ETP products, including a bitcoin (BTC)-based ETP, an ether (ETH)-based ETP and an XRP-based ETP. These are currently offered in Switerzland and Germany via SIX Swiss Exchange, BX Swiss and Boerse Stuttgart.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ETPs are passive investment products that allow investors to gain access to cryptocurrencies without the need to hold them directly. With the SFSA’s approval in place, Amun has been authorized to offer these investment products in Sweden as well as the EU.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We plan on passporting our Swedish EU approved prospectus around the continent” to offer all products, Hany Rashwan, co-founder and CEO of Amun, told The Block. <\/span><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">On specifically choosing Sweden to get its base prospectus approved, Rashwan said Amun reached out to a few European regulators but chose the SFSA because it is a “forward-thinking regulator” and Sweden has a “highly crypto-engaged” population.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We continue to engage with a number of regulators across the continent and intend to speak to more in the near future. The future of regulated crypto in Europe is quite bright,” Rashwan added.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Amun’s president Ophelia Snyder said the SFSA approval took 4 months of consultancy period and that there is a “strong” demand for ETPs in Sweden among both retail and institutional investors.<\/span>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">EU expansion&nbsp;<\/strong>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Amun is yet to announce which exchanges in the EU it will list its ETPs on. Rashwan told The Block that the firm is expecting to list it on “three European exchanges by end of 2020.”<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">With nearly $55 million in current assets under management (AUM), Amun is expecting to add another around $20 million from upcoming offerings in the EU, Rashwan told The Block.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Looking ahead, Amun is aiming to go global. “We’re on one continent; five more to go,” said Rashwan.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Amun is <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/15137\/amun-ag-raises-4m-prepares-to-launch-xrp-index-product\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">backed by Graham Tuckwell<\/a>, an Australian multi-millionaire and the first person to set up an exchange-traded fund (ETF) tracking the price of gold. Tuckwell led Amun’s $4 million seed round in March of this year.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Rashwan told The Block that the firm currently has no plans to raise more funds in the near future. Amun has a headcount of 18 and is looking to further expand its team next year, said Rashwan.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto-tied investment products<\/strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">An increasing number of firms, both from traditional finance and crypto space, are building and offering investment products tied to cryptocurrencies. Just last week, New York-headquartered WisdomTree, with over $60 billion in client assets, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/49050\/another-bitcoin-exchange-traded-product-gets-launched-this-time-by-traditional-asset-manager-wisdomtree\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">launched<\/a> a physically-backed bitcoin ETP. Canadian asset manager 3iQ also recently <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/48675\/canadian-asset-manager-set-to-offer-trading-of-bitcoin-fund-in-coming-months\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filed<\/a> a prospectus for a regulated fund tied to bitcoin. It could list on the Toronto Stock Exchange and start trading by end of this year.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission is also taking efforts as it <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/49740\/15-billion-asset-manager-is-the-latest-to-receive-sec-approval-for-its-bitcoin-futures-fund\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">approved<\/a> a new bitcoin futures fund last week, which is managed by the $15 billion asset manager Stone Ridge. The fund will invest in cash-settled bitcoin futures and not directly invest in cryptocurrencies.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Other players offering investment products tied to cryptocurrencies include CoinShares' XBT Provider and Digital Currency Group’s Grayscale. The latter remains the market leader - it saw inflows rise by 200% in Q3 at $254.9 million. A market observer recently&nbsp;<\/span><a class=\"_e75a791d-denali-editor-page-rtfLink\" href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/daily\/43598\/grayscale-sees-inflows-up-by-200-in-q3-but-where-are-its-competitors\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">told<\/span><\/a><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;The Block that Grayscale's availability on the public market holds strong appeal to both institutional and retail investors and some of Grayscale's offerings are traded at very high premiums on the secondary market.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Amun AG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hany Rashwan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Grayscale","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Switzerland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"EU","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"WisdomTree","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Stone Ridge","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Graham Tuckwell","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Toronto Stock Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Amun","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ophelia Snyder","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Switerzland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Swiss Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Germany","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$55 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Digital Currency Group’s Grayscale","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sweden","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Amun","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$4 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Boerse Stuttgart","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Rashwan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"European Union (EU","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"200%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"SFSA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Swiss","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$15 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"last week","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$254.9 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"ETP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$20 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$60 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"March of this year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Swedish Financial Supervisory Authority","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["XRP"],"authors":["Yogita Khatri","The Block"]}