{"summary":"The meetings came to light during part of an FBI agent&#x27;s testimony during Sam Bankman-Fried&#x27;s criminal trial on Tuesday. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/258043\/inside-the-trial-sbf-had-meeting-scheduled-with-bill-clinton-weeks-before-ftx-crash","publishDate":"2023-10-17T22:17:54","id":788,"type":null,"title":"Inside the trial: SBF had meeting scheduled with Bill Clinton weeks before FTX crash","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried's calendar was full of meetings with people in power in September 2022, less than two months before the exchange's <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/186132\/ftx-collapse-timeline-six-days-that-rocked-the-crypto-industry\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">collapse<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, according to the testimony of Richard Busick, a special agent with the FBI's Cellular Analysis Survey Team.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Busick testified in New York Southern District court on Tuesday as a prosecution witness in Bankman-Fried's ongoing <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/tag\/sbf-trial\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">criminal trial<\/a>.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">According to Busick, he was assigned to locate the whereabouts of Bankman-Fried's mobile phone using the data from cell towers between June 2021 and November 2022. That mobile phone data, together with emails retrieved by the Department of Justice, detailed a busy September.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">According to the emails, on Sept. 20, Bankman-Fried was listed as having a meeting with former President Bill Clinton at a Hilton hotel in New York City, Assistant U.S. Attorney Danielle Kudla told the court. Just days earlier on Sept. 16, Bankman-Fried was recorded as meeting with the New York State Governor Kathy Hochul at a restaurant, \"most likely, Capital Grille on East 42nd Street,\" Kudla told the court, adding that the exact location hasn't been confirmed by Hochul's office yet.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">During the next two days, Bankman-Fried was said to have met with Yasir bin Othman Al-Rumayyan, chairman of the Saudi state-owned petroleum company Saudi Aramco, and Saudi Arabia's minister of investments Khalid A. Al-Falih, according to the emails and cell phone data gathered by the DOJ.<\/span>","Bankman-Fried also had a meeting with New York City mayor Eric Adams on March 3, 2022, according to the data cited by Kudla.","The contents of the meetings or the reasons they were held wasn't disclosed.","Earlier this week, Nishad Singh, FTX's former Head of Engineering, detailed efforts by Bankman-Friend to direct <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/257840\/inside-sbfs-trial-nishad-singh-said-no-but-not-often-enough\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">political donations<\/a>. His efforts to acquire political influence also emerged as a key theme in Michael Lewis’ new book, \"<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/255259\/going-infinite-sbfs-hairbrained-schemes-in-new-michael-lewis-book\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Going Infinite<\/a>.\"","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">FTX went through a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/186132\/ftx-collapse-timeline-six-days-that-rocked-the-crypto-industry\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">liquidity crisis<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in early Nov. 2022 and filed for bankruptcy on Nov.11. In December, a U.S. grand jury <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/194667\/disgraced-former-ftx-ceo-sam-bankman-fried-criminally-indicted\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">charged<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Bankman-Fried with fraud, after which he was <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/186393\/sam-bankman-fried-arrested-in-the-bahamas\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">arrested<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in the Bahamas and <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.wsj.com\/articles\/sam-bankman-fried-expected-back-in-bahamas-court-11671581149\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">extradited<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to the U.S.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Around that time, former Alameda Research CEO Caroline Ellison and FTX co-founder and former CTO Gary Wang <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/197573\/ellison-and-wang-guilty-pleas-unsealed-as-bankman-fried-granted-bail\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">pled guilty<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to several charges of fraud each. Nishad Singh also <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/213024\/former-ftx-exec-nishad-singh-plans-to-plead-guilty-to-criminal-charges-bloomberg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">pled guilty<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> two months later. All three have testified as prosecution witnesses during Sam Bankman-Fried's ongoing trial in New York.<\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"New York City","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Nov.11","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Caroline Ellison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cellular Analysis Survey Team","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York State","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Eric Adams","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Hilton","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DOJ","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Busick","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Michael Lewis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"November 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Richard Busick","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kudla","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nov. 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"December","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Saudi state","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"March 3, 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Head of Engineering","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"September 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"two months later","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gary Wang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Falih","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Saudi Arabia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Yasir bin Othman Al-Rumayyan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bill Clinton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"New York Southern District","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Danielle Kudla","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kathy Hochul","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"June 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Department of Justice","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Saudi Aramco","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sept. 16","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Nishad Singh","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FBI","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hochul","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sept. 20","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bahamas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Khalid A. Al","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["FTX","SBF TRIAL"],"authors":["Anna Baydakova","The Block"]}