{"summary":"The U.S. is behind on getting its regulatory act together while the rest of the world embraces crypto, said Coinbase CEO Brian Armstrong.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/216244\/coinbase-ceo-defends-staking-calls-for-us-to-create-clear-rule-book","publishDate":"2023-03-01T12:19:17","id":7889,"type":null,"title":"Coinbase CEO defends staking, calls for US to create &#x27;clear rule book&#x27;","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The U.S. is behind on getting its regulatory act together while the rest of the world embraces crypto, according to Coinbase CEO Brian Armstrong.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The executive, in an interview on Bloomberg TV, also defended Coinbase's staking product as not being a security and reiterated that the company is prepared to defend that in court if necessary, though they prefer to work collaboratively with regulators.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">He also noted that crypto isn't going anywhere.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"A lot of traditional financial services firms are integrating this technology,\" Armstrong said. \"Everybody from JPMorgan, Visa and Mastercard, Franklin Templeton they have projects and teams internally working on how to integrate crypto into their services.\"<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The CEO backed the overall concept of stablecoins, but noted that not all of them pass muster with the company, pointing to the recent <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/215435\/coinbase-to-halt-trading-of-binances-busd-for-not-meeting-listing-standards\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">delisting<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> of Binance USD after Paxos was told by the New York Department of Financial Services to stop issuing the coin.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"My number one priority this year is the policy environment,\" Armstrong said. \"The rest of the world has actually embraced crypto. We've seen all the major financial hubs, Singapore, Hong Kong and London, and the EU just passed comprehensive crypto legislation … We need a clear rule book so that this industry can be built here.\" &nbsp; <\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Bloomberg TV","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York Department of Financial Services","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Mastercard","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Paxos","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Binance USD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"EU","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Brian Armstrong","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Armstrong","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"London","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Franklin Templeton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Christiana Loureiro","The Block"]}