{"summary":"United Talent Agency adds another top web3 player to its roster by signing prolific technology entrepreneur Kevin Rose.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/199944\/early-facebook-investor-and-proof-ceo-kevin-rose-signs-with-hollywoods-uta-exclusive","publishDate":"2023-01-06T20:00:09","id":7901,"type":null,"title":"Early Facebook investor and Proof CEO Kevin Rose signs with Hollywood&#x27;s UTA: Exclusive","category":["METAVERSE & NFT"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Hollywood’s United Talent Agency has nabbed another top-flight web3 client in Kevin Rose, The Block learned exclusively.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kevin Rose, who was an early-stage investor in both Facebook and Twitter, also is co-founder and CEO of Proof, an NFT firm that counts both the Moonbirds and Proof Collective projects among the collections it manages. Last summer Proof <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/166580\/a16z-leads-50-million-in-funding-for-nft-organization-proof-collective\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">raised <\/a><\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$50 million in a Series A fundraise<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> led by the prominent web3 venture capital firm a16z.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The signing announcement comes on the heels of several months of plummeting NFT sales and shaken confidence in the digital-asset industry. Similar to other top Hollywood talent agencies, which have <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/188777\/wme-talent-agency-signs-valfre-artist-part-of-instagrams-nft-push-exclusive\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">continued to sign<\/a> successful web3 creators in recent months, UTA’s adding Rose to its client roster demonstrates that Tinseltown’s most powerful power brokers have not given up on the NFT space.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Under UTA’s head of web3 Lesley Silverman, the firm also represents NFT artist <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/173219\/uta-signs-on-nft-artist-diana-sinclair-the-hollywood-reporter\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Diana Sinclair<\/a> and the popular <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">DeadFellaz brand. UTA said it will manage the web3 interests of Rose and all <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">his subsidiary businesses.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kevin Rose, courtesy of Proof.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Proof’s Moonbirds collection projects has so far generated more than 177,000 ETH ($224 million) in trading volume, <a href=\"https:\/\/opensea.io\/collection\/proof-moonbirds\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">according to OpenSea<\/a>.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Rose is also responsible for founding the social news site Digg. And as a general partner at True Ventures and Google Ventures he invested in companies such as Art Blocks, Oura, Blue Bottle, Medium and Next Door.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Oura","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Digg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Diana Sinclair","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"True Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tinseltown","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Kevin Rose","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lesley Silverman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Moonbirds","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"United Talent Agency","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$224 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"summer","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$50 million","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}