{"summary":"Uniswap now has a new committee that will evaluate crypto bridge providers after the fallout from the BNB deployment.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/216855\/uniswap-forms-six-member-crypto-bridge-assessment-committee","publishDate":"2023-03-03T07:24:44","id":7928,"type":null,"title":"Uniswap forms six-member crypto bridge assessment committee","category":["CRYPTO ECOSYSTEMS"],"content":["Uniswap DAO has created a committee tasked with evaluating crypto bridge providers for future deployments of its decentralized exchange on blockchain networks.","The new group <a href=\"https:\/\/gov.uniswap.org\/t\/cross-chain-bridge-assessment-process\/20148\/47\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">dubbed<\/a> Uniswap Bridge Assessment Committee has six members. These include Zellic co-founder Jazzy Bedi, Chaos Labs VP of Business Operations Ben O’Neill and co-authors of the Crosschain Risk Framework Ermyas Abebe and Peter Robinson. Sean Casey, CEO of Enzyme Finance protocol development at Avantgarde and David Hyland-Wood, adjunct associate professor at the University of Queensland School of Engineering, are the other committee members.","The committee will evaluate eight bridge providers, namely Axelar, Celer, deBridge, Hyperlane, LayerZero, Multichain, Router Protocol and Wormhole. Bridge providers enable users to transfer crypto tokens across different networks. The committee will also look into three bridge-agnostic solutions as part of their assessment process.","The committee’s stated goal is to provide short-term recommendations for the DAO concerning crypto bridges. These recommendations will be used in future cross-chain deployments.","The need for the committee arose amid <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.pro\/news\/post\/207297\/uniswap-temperature-check-spurs-feverish-backroom-maneuvering-among-crypto-vc-heavyweights\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">intense debate<\/a> during a recent governance process to deploy Uniswap v3 on the BNB Chain. Some community members <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.pro\/news\/post\/208815\/li-fi-calls-on-uniswap-not-to-deploy-on-bnb-chain-with-only-one-bridge\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">faulted the selection<\/a> of only one bridge provider for the proposed deployment. The process <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/210570\/uniswap-dao-completes-vote-for-proposed-bnb-deployment\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">eventually ended<\/a> with Wormhole chosen as the sole bridge solution.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Bedi","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Crosschain Risk Framework Ermyas Abebe","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"David Hyland","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ben O’Neill","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Multichain","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Peter Robinson","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Uniswap DAO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hyperlane","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"University of Queensland School of Engineering","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Router Protocol","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sean Casey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"DAO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Uniswap Bridge Assessment Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Enzyme Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Zellic","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["CROSS-CHAIN SWAPS","DAOS","DEXS","UNISWAP"],"authors":["Osato Avan-Nomayo","The Block"]}