{"summary":"In 2013, Tom Farley invested $10 million in Coinbase on behalf of the New York Stock Exchange. Now he&#x27;s CEO of a new crypto exchange.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/111284\/former-nyse-president-tom-farley-bullish-ceo","publishDate":"2021-07-14T12:46:16","id":798,"type":null,"title":"How Tom Farley went from NYSE president to CEO of a crypto exchange","category":["THE BLOCK"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode <\/i><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">39<\/strong><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> of Season 3 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block’s Frank Chaparro and Former NYSE President and Incoming CEO of Bullish, Tom Farley. <\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on <\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, <\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, <\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, <\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"c1b1aea5a2a0b2b581b5a9a4a3adaea2aaa2b3b8b1b5aeefa2aeac\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors <a href=\"http:\/\/eventussystems.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Eventus<\/a>, <a href=\"http:\/\/kraken.com\/scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kraken<\/a>, and Exodus<\/strong>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Eventus is the leading global provider of multi-asset class trade surveillance, transaction monitoring and market risk solutions. Eventus offers a powerful, award-winning trade surveillance platform that is easy to deploy, customize and operate. Eventus is proven in the most complex, high-volume and real-time environments and supports many of the industry’s leading crypto exchanges including Coinbase, Gemini, ErisX and OSL. The company’s rapidly growing client base relies on Eventus’ responsive support and product development teams to overcome its most pressing regulatory challenges.<\/em>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Kraken<\/strong>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Whether you’re an experienced crypto trader or just starting out, Kraken has the tools to help you achieve financial freedom. With 50+ cryptocurrencies to choose from, industry-leading security and a wide variety of features to suit any investing strategy, Kraken puts the power in your hands to buy, sell and trade digital assets. Visit <\/em><a href=\"http:\/\/kraken.com\/scoop\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kraken.com<\/em><\/a><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to get started today.<\/em>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Exodus<\/strong>","<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nTom Farley, in many respects, was early to crypto.&nbsp;","The 45-year-old — who is best known for his time as the head of the New York Stock Exchange — vividly recalls a conversation with early Coinbase employee Dan Romero, who connected him Coinbase co-founder and fellow Duke alumnus, Fred Ersham.&nbsp;","\"So I met with Fred and was blown away by what they were doing and agreed to put ten million dollars on behalf of the New York Stock Exchange into Coinbase,\" Farley said on the most recent episode of The Scoop. He made that investment in 2013.&nbsp;","Fast forward to 2021: Farley has officially gone full crypto, announcing last week that he would join EOS-backed crypto exchange Bullish as its CEO following the completion of a SPAC deal that would merge the company with Far Peak, the SPAC company Farley joined after his tenure at NYSE.","On this episode of The Scoop, Farley joins The Scoop's Frank Chaparro to discuss the deal, which is expected to be valued at a whopping $9 billion. Farley will enter a crowded market with well-placed competitors like Coinbase, which recently went public at a valuation above $50 billion. Bullish aims to win over clients with a blended market structure that borrows from the DeFi world and centralized exchange space, Farley explained.&nbsp;","“Bullish is really tipping our hat to the successful use of liquidity pools and automated market makers, and it's combining them with a CeFi market structure,\" Farley said. \"And so each pair not only will be underpinned by the liquidity pool, but we will also accept bids and offers from third parties and we’ll allow third parties to cancel bids and offers. So in that respect, we will look much like a traditional CeFi.\"","Farley also unpacks:","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Tom Farley","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gemini","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2013","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York Stock Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ten million dollars","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Fred","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kraken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"OSL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$50 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Farley","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"SPAC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NYSE","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$9 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Dan Romero","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Fred Ersham","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}