{"summary":"In this episode of The Scoop, The Block&#x27;s Frank Chaparro continues our coverage of FTX’s demise with Jim Greco, a General Partner at F9 Research, and Douglas Colkitt, Founder of Crocodile Labs.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/187004\/ftxs-demise-part-3-how-sam-bankman-frieds-crypto-empire-imploded","publishDate":"2022-11-15T05:46:49","id":8080,"type":null,"title":"FTX&#x27;s demise part 3: How Sam Bankman-Fried&#x27;s crypto empire imploded","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 112<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 4 of The Scoop was recorded live with <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro, F9 Research General Partner Jim Greco, and Crocodile Labs Founder Douglas Colkitt<\/strong><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/strong><\/i><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests can be sent to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"53233c373032202713273b36313f3c303830212a23273c7d303c3e\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i><\/span>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK2158783779\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In this breaking news episode of The Scoop, we <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/185182\/ftxs-demise-part-2-with-wintermutes-evgeny-gaevoy-and-cryptoquants-ki-young-ju\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">continue<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> our coverage of FTX’s demise with Jim Greco, a general partner at F9 Research, and Douglas Colkitt, founder of Crocodile Labs.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">According to Greco, many market participants knew about the relationship between Alameda and FTX. Still, few thought former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried would risk jeopardizing the success of his exchange:<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Most professionals knew of the Alameda connection, but we all thought that this exchange is so valuable — it's worth $32 billion — why would he do something that would destroy the equity value in this exchange?” said Greco.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Not only did Bankman-Fried end up destroying the value of his exchange, but it’s now apparent that he did so in an effort to <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/185415\/ftx-lent-alameda-billions-of-dollars-in-customer-assets-wsj\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">prop up<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Alameda’s unsuccessful trading operation, said Greco.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Colkitt added that recent events have shattered the perception that Alameda was one of the top performing firms in the space:<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Nobody really expected FTX to run out of money because they thought Alameda must be making so much money, but it's really quite the opposite — they just seemed so incompetent that even with all these advantages they were losing money,” said Colkitt.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">During this episode Chaparro, Colkitt, and Greco also discuss:<\/span><\/i>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nThis episode is brought to you by our sponsors <a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Tron, <\/em><\/a><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.ledn.io\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ledn<\/a><\/em><\/b><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nAbout Tron<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/b><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TRON is dedicated to accelerating the decentralization of the internet via blockchain technology and decentralized applications (dApps). Founded in September 2017 by <a href=\"https:\/\/www.hejustinsun.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">H.E. Justin Sun<\/a>, the TRON network has continued to deliver impressive achievements since MainNet launch in May 2018. July 2018 also marked the ecosystem integration of <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bittorrent.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BitTorrent<\/a>, a pioneer in decentralized web3 services boasting over 100 million monthly active users. The TRON network completed full decentralization in December 2021 and is now a community-governed DAO. | <a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/hackathon\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TRONDAO<\/a> | <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/trondao\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Twitter<\/a> | <a href=\"https:\/\/discord.gg\/tron\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Discord<\/a> |<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Ledn<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ledn was founded on the unshakeable conviction that digital assets have the power to democratize access to the global economy. We help you to experience the real life benefits of your Bitcoin without having to sell it. Start a savings account, take out a loan, or double your Bitcoin. For more information visit <a href=\"https:\/\/www.ledn.io\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ledn.io<\/a><\/span><\/em>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Douglas Colkitt","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$32 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"BitTorrent","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"F9 Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Crocodile Labs Founder Douglas Colkitt","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Crocodile Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Colkitt","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Greco","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"May 2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"September 2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"H.E. Justin Sun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"July 2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"December 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ledn<\/a><\/em><\/b><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nAbout Tron<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/b><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TRON","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ledn<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ledn","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jim Greco","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}