{"summary":"Following the launch of the web3 mobile game &quot;NFL Rivals&quot; Mythical Games is launching a racing game on Apple and Android.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/254929\/mythical-games-launches-racing-game-on-apple-and-android-devices-following-nfl-rivals","publishDate":"2023-10-05T09:32:03","id":8167,"type":null,"title":"Mythical Games launches racing game on Apple and Android devices, following NFL Rivals","category":["GAMING"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Mythical Games, which recently launched the blockchain-powered video game NFL Rivals on Apple and Android, is now releasing another mobile title called “<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Nitro Nation World Tour.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">With <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Nitro Nation World Tour” players race while earning and collecting car NFTs fashioned after well-known automobile brands like <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Aston Martin, Jaguar, Pagani and McLaren Automotive. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Mythical developed the new game with <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CM Games, <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">the original creators of the “Nitro Nation” franchise, the company said in a statement.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">McLaren Automotive partnered with Mythical for the launch, the gaming company also said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">After a months-long soft launch, Mythical’s NFL Rivals unveiled <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/247208\/crypto-nfl-game-scores-millions-of-downloads-full-gameplay-going-live\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">full gameplay<\/a> in August, timed to the preseason of the NFL, by far the most popular sport in the United States. The game, available on Apple and Android devices, has been downloaded millions of times, according to Mythical.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In the past Apple <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/231646\/apples-crypto-policy-softens-as-stepn-offers-in-app-digital-asset-trading\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">has been resistant<\/a> to blockchain-enabled mobile games, so it's notable that NFL Rivals allows players <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">to buy and sell gaming assets without having to leave the app. The same is true for players using Android devices.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Among web3 gaming startups, Mythical has secured an exceptionally high-profile list of backers. NBA legend Michael Jordan and venture capital firm a16z are both investors in the company. In 2021 the company’s valuation hit $1.25 billion.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Jaguar","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1.25 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"McLaren Automotive","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Nitro Nation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nitro Nation World Tour","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Aston Martin","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Pagani","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Michael Jordan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFL Rivals","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"United States","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}