{"summary":"Institutional clients are warming up to digital assets, according to incoming Komainu CEO Nicolas Bertrand.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/172942\/komainu-taps-former-italian-stock-exchange-head-as-ceo","publishDate":"2022-09-26T21:00:24","id":8179,"type":null,"title":"Komainu taps former Italian stock exchange head as CEO","category":["HIRING"],"content":["Effective immediately, London-based CEO Nicolas Bertrand will take over the digital asset custody firm Komainu.","Institutional clients are showing greater interest in digital assets, according to Bertrand.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Nomura-backed digital asset custodian Komainu named Nicolas Bertrand its new chief executive, Bloomberg first <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2022-09-26\/nomura-backed-digital-asset-firm-komainu-names-bertrand-as-ceo?leadSource=uverify%20wall\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bertrand, who formerly served for more than a decade as Italian stock exchange Borsa Italia's head of derivatives markets and commodities, will start immediately and is based in London.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bertrand stated that he has no plans to raise additional funds, will attempt to reduce spending, and remain focused on innovation, according to Bloomberg. Bertrand added that Koimanu has provisional approval to operate in Dubai, and will seek to obtain similar licensing for the UK.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Komainu recruits executives from the traditional finance exchange ecosystem into its C-suite. Just last April, the company attempted to hire then CEO of the London Metal Exchange, Matthew Chamberlain, who ultimately opted to <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/143720\/incoming-komainu-ceo-to-stay-at-london-metal-exchange-following-nickel-squeeze\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">remain<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> at the helm of the metal marketplace amid an emerging nickel crisis.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Komainu <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/68825\/nomura-and-ledger-launch-digital-asset-custodian-for-institutional-investors\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">launched<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in 2020, with funding from investment firm CoinShares, Japan-based investment bank Nomura, and crypto cold storage wallet maker Ledger. In March 2021, Komainu <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/97676\/crypto-custodian-komainu-raises-25-million-series-a-alan-howard\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">raised<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> $25 million in a Series A funding led by hedge fund manager Alan Howard.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Komainu","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nomura","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Komainu","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Metal Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bertrand","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"last April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Matthew Chamberlain","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Japan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"March 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Borsa Italia","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dubai","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Nicolas Bertrand","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"London","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Alan Howard","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$25 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Koimanu","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Jeremy Nation","The Block"]}