{"summary":"State Street, one of the largest custody banks in the world, has yet to launch a service to store crypto assets but that doesn&#x27;t mean it is actively involved in the digital asset market. Leading the charge is Jay Biancamano, Managing Director of digital product development and innovation at the firm.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/56920\/state-street-exec-explains-why-stocks-wont-be-tokenized-anytime-soon","publishDate":"2020-02-27T16:00:34","id":818,"type":null,"title":"State Street exec explains why stocks won&#x27;t be tokenized anytime soon","category":["CAPITAL MARKETS"],"content":["<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 8 of Season 2 of The Scoop was recorded at The Block offices with Frank Chaparro and Jay Biancamano, Managing Director at State Street<\/em><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on <a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/a>, or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to&nbsp;<a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection#d7a7b8b3b4b6a4a397a3bfb2b5bbb8b4bcb4a5aea7a3b8f9b4b8ba\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"dcacb3b8bfbdafa89ca8b4b9beb0b3bfb7bfaea5aca8b3f2bfb3b1\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/span><\/a><\/em>","<iframe src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK9527353347\" width=\"100%\" height=\"200\" frameborder=\"0\" scrolling=\"no\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Leading the crypto charge at custodian bank giant State Street is&nbsp;<a class=\"c-link\" href=\"https:\/\/www.linkedin.com\/in\/jay-biancamano-7a96401\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" aria-describedby=\"slack-kit-tooltip\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Jay Biancamano<\/a>, managing Director of digital product development and innovation at the firm.","Its most notable foray to date: <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/50820\/state-street-ties-up-with-gemini-trust-to-examine-reporting-process-of-bitcoin-and-ether\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">a partnership with crypto exchange Gemini<\/a> on trade reporting. And the bank has previously indicated that it is working on a series of proofs-of-concept related to the technology.","Biancamano's finger is on the pulse of all things market structure, having worked at trading technology firms like ITG, Liquidnet, and Fidessa.","Thus, he has seen the shift to electronic trading take place in U.S. equities. In this episode of The Scoop, Biancamano and The Block's Frank Chaparro explore how the digitization of assets will transform the trading landscape.","In this episode, we look at:","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Fidessa","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Jay Biancamano","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Liquidnet","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"ITG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"State Street","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}