{"summary":"The Financial Conduct Authority has appointed New Zealand&#x27;s Binu Paul as head of digital assets.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/177210\/uks-financial-conduct-authority-names-new-digital-assets-head-exclusive","publishDate":"2022-10-14T08:25:24","id":8199,"type":null,"title":"UK’s Financial Conduct Authority names new digital assets head: Exclusive","category":["HIRING"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Financial Conduct Authority (FCA), the UK’s financial regulatory body, has appointed Binu Paul, the former fintech specialist lead from the Financial Markets Authority (FMA) in New Zealand, as its head of digital assets.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Paul announced his <a href=\"https:\/\/www.linkedin.com\/posts\/binupaulnz_paul-departs-fma-for-top-uk-fintech-job-activity-6974872127707496448-icoP\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">leave<\/a> from the FMA on Sept. 11 after a two-year role leading efforts to support innovation in New Zealand’s financial services sector. Previously, he managed the FMA’s intelligence team, with an earlier career in investment and portfolio management.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Paul takes the place of<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/142647\/uks-top-regulator-appoints-interim-digital-assets-head\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Victoria McLoughlin,<\/span><\/a> who has held<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> the fort as the interim head of digital assets since April.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The FCA currently has <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/176539\/uk-regulator-pushes-line-that-crypto-investors-must-be-prepared-to-lose-all-their-money\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">39<\/a> crypto firms on its official register. Its current licensing process for crypto is based on compliance to strict anti-money laundering requirements. The cumbersome and lengthy procedure previously caused some companies to <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/139679\/blockchain-com-becomes-latest-firm-to-retreat-from-uk-regulation-application\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">give up<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on the prospect and seek approval in other jurisdictions.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The financial regulator is seeking ways to encourage regulated innovation through programs such as the Regulatory Sandbox, a testing ground for fintech proposals, and Innovative Pathways, a springboard for innovative financial products.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Elsewhere in the UK, legislation outlined in the <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/158648\/uk-treasury-unveils-plan-to-regulate-stablecoins-in-financial-services-and-markets-bill\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Financial Services and Markets<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> bill may allow stablecoins to be used as payments in the country in the future.&nbsp;<\/span>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Correction: This article was updated to correct the number of firms on the FCA's crypto-asset register.&nbsp;<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"New Zealand","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Victoria McLoughlin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FCA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"fintech","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Financial Services","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sept. 11","content":"DATE"},{"type":"UK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Financial Markets Authority (FMA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Financial Conduct Authority (FCA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binu Paul","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FMA","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["FCA","FINTECH"],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}