{"summary":"In this episode of The Scoop we are joined by the Odd Lots team, Bloomberg&#x27;s Tracy Alloway and Joe Weisenthal. We explore the parallels between the lack of reporters at the cutting edge of the repo markets and blind spots in today&#x27;s coverage of the coronavirus.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/63999\/bloombergs-tracy-alloway-and-joe-weisenthal-on-how-this-crisis-is-different-from-08","publishDate":"2020-05-05T18:00:05","id":8208,"type":null,"title":"Bloomberg&#x27;s Tracy Alloway and Joe Weisenthal on how this crisis is different from &#x27;08","category":["THE BLOCK"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 16 of Season 2 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with Frank Chaparro, Ryan Todd, along with Bloomberg Financial Journalists and co-hosts of the Odd Lots podcast, Tracy Alloway and Joe Weisenthal.&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/i>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/a>, or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to&nbsp;<a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection#b2c2ddd6d1d3c1c6f2c6dad7d0deddd1d9d1c0cbc2c6dd9cd1dddf\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"176778737476646357637f72757b78747c74656e6763783974787a\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/span><\/a>.<\/em>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode of The Scoop is brought to you by <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitstamp<\/strong>,<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> the original global cryptocurrency exchange. Since 2011, Bitstamp has been a cornerstone of the industry, earning the trust of over four million individuals and top financial institutions looking for a reliable trading venue. Whether you’re trading on our web platform, mobile app or industry-leading APIs, Bitstamp gives you the professional-grade tools you need to execute your strategy. <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/bitstamp.net\/app?r=pro%E2%80%93&amp;utm_source=Website&amp;utm_medium=podcast&amp;utm_campaign=theblock&amp;utm_content=ctaapp\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Download the Bitstamp app<\/b><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or visit <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.bitstamp.net\/pro\/?utm_source=Website&amp;utm_medium=podcast&amp;utm_campaign=theblock&amp;utm_content=ctaweb\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitstamp.net\/Pro<\/b><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to learn more and start trading today!<\/span><\/em>","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK9286818248\" width=\"100%\" height=\"200\" frameborder=\"0\" scrolling=\"no\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","We are going to rewind the clock on this episode of The Scoop with the Odd Lots team, Bloomberg's Tracy Alloway and Joe Weisenthal.","The podcast duo – whose combined time covering global financial markets spans more than &nbsp;three decades – take us back to their times at the FT's Alphaville and The Business Insider, respectively, where they covered the 2008-2009 financial crisis.&nbsp;","In this episode, the podcasters become the \"podcast-ees.\" The episode explores how there are parallels between the dearth of reporters at the cutting edge of the repo markets and blind spots in today's coverage of the coronavirus.","We also dive into:","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Ryan Todd","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Joe Weisenthal","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2011","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2008","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tracy Alloway","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2009","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bitstamp","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg Financial Journalists","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}