{"summary":"Crypto exchange Kraken is shutting its Abu Dhabi office and laid off eight people in the MENA region.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/208090\/crypto-exchange-kraken-closes-abu-dhabi-office","publishDate":"2023-02-02T10:29:38","id":8222,"type":null,"title":"Crypto exchange Kraken closes Abu Dhabi office","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Crypto exchange Kraken is shutting its Abu Dhabi office and winding down support for the United Arab Emirates’s local currency.","\"As part of a recent review, we have decided to suspend AED (dirham) support,\" a Kraken spokesperson said to The Block. \"All clients, including in MENA and the UAE, will continue to be able to use all of Kraken’s other products and services as normal.\"","Bloomberg first <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2023-02-02\/crypto-exchange-kraken-shuts-abu-dhabi-office-cuts-jobs\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a> the news. The publication noted that a<span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> registry for Abu Dhabi Global Market no longer showed an active entity in Kraken's name. The exchange received a crypto license in Abu Dhabi in April 2022.<\/span>","Kraken recently <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/191023\/kraken-cuts-30-of-staff-to-weather-crypto-winter\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">laid off<\/a> around 30% of its global workforce. The pullback in the MENA region impacted eight members of staff, a spokesperson said.","Benjamin Ampen, managing director for MENA, will stay with the exchange, according to Bloomberg.","\"We have already notified impacted clients of this recent change, and our best-in-class client support teams continue to offer our services to ensure a smooth trading experience,\" a Kraken spokesperson said.","Both Kraken and Coinbase also <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/198209\/kraken-quits-japan-as-crypto-exchange-volumes-slide\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">shut down<\/a> operations in Japan recently. Kraken is one several crypto exchanges implementing <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/206479\/weekly-wrap-up-big-funding-rounds-layoffs-and-ftx-developments\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">layoffs<\/a> as a cost-cutting measure.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"MENA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Benjamin Ampen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kraken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"United Arab Emirates","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"30%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Japan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kraken spokesperson","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Abu Dhabi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Abu Dhabi","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"UAE","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["KRAKEN"],"authors":["Kari McMahon","The Block"]}