{"summary":"GBTC&#x27;s discount to NAV has narrowed in the wake of a flurry of new Bitcoin ETF filings, suggesting increased investor confidence.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/236339\/gbtcs-discount-to-nav-narrows-as-bitcoin-etf-race-kicks-off","publishDate":"2023-06-26T08:47:07","id":8224,"type":null,"title":"GBTC&#x27;s discount to NAV narrows as Bitcoin ETF race kicks off","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["Grayscale's flagship Bitcoin Trust has seen its discount to net asset value shrink in the wake of a flurry of new filings for spot bitcoin exchange-traded funds, according to The Block's data dashboard.&nbsp;","GBTC was trading at a 31.32% discount to NAV on June 23, a decline from a discount of 44.02% on June 13. Shares of GBTC can trade at a discount or premium to bitcoin depending on investor demand. Until early 2021, shares in the fund traded at a premium before flipping to a discount following a wide-spread crypto credit crunch.&nbsp;","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/crypto-markets\/structured-products\/premium-of-gbtc\/embed\" title=\"Daily GBTC Premium\/Discount to NAV\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","The narrowing of the discount likely reflects investor confidence in GBTC upgrading to an exchange-traded fund, which the US Securities and Exchange Commission has so far blocked. The asset manager is <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/217787\/grayscale-products-buoyed-following-oral-arguments-in-case-against-the-sec\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">suing<\/a> the agency over this matter.&nbsp;","The entrance of BlackRock into the race for spot bitcoin ETF approval has provided a new glimmer of hope for issuers that an ETF might ultimately receive a greenlight.","Indeed, Bloomberg's Eric Balchunas <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/EricBalchunas\/status\/1671304815542935552?s=20\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">described<\/a> BlackRock's surprise filing as a move that \"breathed new life into the race.\"","Since its filing on June 15, a number of issuers — <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/235753\/wisdomtree-invesco-and-blackrock-are-now-all-gunning-for-a-bitcoin-etf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">including<\/a> WisdomTree and Invesco — have resubmitted filings for their own funds following BlackRock's lead.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"BlackRock","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"WisdomTree","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NAV","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"44.02%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"31.32%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Bitcoin Trust","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"June 15","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Invesco","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"US Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"June 13","content":"DATE"},{"type":"June 23","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Eric Balchunas","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}