{"summary":"The Block recently published a research report examining the The State of The Digital Asset Data and Infrastructure Landscape,  examining the growth within this sector. In this webinar The Block&#x27;s Head of Research, Larry Cermak, is joined by executives from leading data service and infrastructure providers to explore the findings of the report.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/66166\/the-block-presents-the-state-of-the-digital-asset-data-and-infrastructure-landscape","publishDate":"2020-05-22T11:27:20","id":8249,"type":null,"title":"The Block Presents: The State of The Digital Asset Data and Infrastructure Landscape","category":["THE BLOCK"],"content":["The Block recently published a research report examining the The State of The Digital Asset Data and Infrastructure Landscape, examining the growth within this sector. The Block’s Director of Research, Larry Cermak, hosted a webinar with executives from leading data service and infrastructure providers to explore the findings of the report.","Larry Cermak was joined by <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Tim Rice<\/strong>, CEO of <a href=\"https:\/\/coinmetrics.io\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Coin Metrics<\/a>, <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Mike Alfred<\/strong>, CEO of <a href=\"https:\/\/www.digitalassetsdata.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Digital Assets Data<\/a>, and <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Adam Traidman<\/strong>, CEO of <a href=\"https:\/\/blockset.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BRD<\/a>.","In this webinar Larry and the panelists discuss:","You can view the entire webinar below, along with the related slides. You can also view and register for all of The Block’s upcoming webinars.&nbsp;","The full report is available to view and download <a href=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2020\/05\/The-State-of-the-Digital-Asset-Data-and-Infrastructure-Landscape.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">here.<\/a>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block Presents: The State of the Digital Asset Data and Infrastructure Landscape<\/strong>","<iframe src=\"https:\/\/www.youtube.com\/embed\/6YlMS3lYOFI\" width=\"560\" height=\"315\" frameborder=\"0\" allowfullscreen=\"allowfullscreen\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","&nbsp;","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2020\/05\/APRIL2020-PRESENTATION-whiteFINAL.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">View the presentation slides here<\/a>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Upcoming Webinars:<\/strong>","<iframe title=\"The Block events | Livestorm\" src=\"https:\/\/app.livestorm.co\/the-block\/upcoming?limit=6\" width=\"100%\" height=\"400\" frameborder=\"0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Larry Cermak","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Digital Asset Data","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mike Alfred","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Block’s Director of Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Larry","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tim Rice","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Adam Traidman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The State of The Digital Asset Data","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Digital Assets Data","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN"],"authors":["The Block","The Block"]}