{"summary":"An objection was filed by U.S. Trustee Andrew Vara against FTX&#x27;s proposed sales of LedgerX as well as units in Europe and Japan.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/199982\/us-trustee-objects-to-ftxs-planned-sale-of-ledgerx-and-other-units-reuters","publishDate":"2023-01-08T04:09:16","id":8301,"type":null,"title":"US trustee objects to FTX&#x27;s planned sale of LedgerX and other units: Reuters","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["U.S. Trustee Andrew Vara filed the objection in response to FTX’s proposed asset sales.","Vara expressed concern the sales might compromise information related to FTX’s bankruptcy.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A U.S. trustee&nbsp; filed an objection to FTX's plan to sell the company's LedgerX as well as FTX units in Europe and Japan.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">FTX filed for bankruptcy protection in November, amid mounting debt from failed investments and alleged mismanagement of funds by senior executives within the company.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The company had <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/191947\/ledgerx-for-sale-with-interest-from-blockchain-com-gemini-others-bloomberg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">stated<\/a> previously that it planned to sell its LedgerX, FTX Japan and FTX Europe businesses. However, U.S. Trustee Andrew Vara filed an objection to these sales on Jan. 7, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.reuters.com\/business\/finance\/us-trustee-files-objection-ftxs-planned-asset-sales-2023-01-07\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">according<\/a> to Reuters.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In his filing, the federal bankruptcy watchdog<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> requested that an investigation be conducted prior to the sale of the units in order to ascertain whether they have access to information related to FTX's bankruptcy proceedings.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"The sale of potentially valuable causes of action against the Debtors' directors, officers and employees, or any other person or entity, should not be permitted until there has been a full and independent investigation into all persons and entities that may have been involved in any malfeasance, negligence or other actionable conduct,\" the filing said, according to Reuters.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">As a U.S. trustee, Vara is a part of the Department of Justice, which supervises bankruptcy proceedings in the United States and has a duty to ensure that bankrupt entities are not engaging in activities that would be detrimental for creditors or others with interests in the case.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The development comes after former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/198982\/bankman-fried-pleads-not-guilty-to-criminal-charges\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">pleaded not guilty<\/a> last week to criminal charges that he <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">cheated investors and caused them financial loss through his actions.<\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Department of Justice","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Vara","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FTX Japan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Jan. 7","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Japan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Reuters","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Andrew Vara","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"United States","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Vishal Chawla","The Block"]}