{"summary":"The rollout will be in phases and comes nine months after FTX launched the card in the U.S.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/175494\/ftx-to-launch-visa-debit-card-in-40-new-countries","publishDate":"2022-10-07T07:05:56","id":8306,"type":null,"title":"FTX to launch Visa debit card in 40 new countries","category":["PAYMENTS AND BANKING"],"content":["Crypto exchange operator FTX is set to launch a Visa debit card in over 40 new countries, nine months after <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/SBF_FTX\/status\/1484583780241313796?s=20&amp;t=Kz6b9MCdJZ1z4ND_GdKacQ\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">introducing it<\/a> in the U.S.","The global expansion means more FTX customers will be able to spend their crypto balances held at the exchange via the card, according to an announcement on Friday. FTX has <a href=\"https:\/\/card.ftx.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">opened a waitlist<\/a> for interested customers.","Latin America, Europe and Asia are the firm's targeted markets for expansion. Specifically, Latin American countries will be FTX's first focus, followed by European states before the end of the year and Asian nations next year.","FTX Card allows users to spend funds directly from their FTX accounts. The card is accepted at any retailer that accepts Visa debit cards.","\"This card allows users to make use of their FTX crypto balances 24 hours a day, 365 days a year securely and with no administrative or processing fees,\" FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried said in the statement.","FTX won't initially provide rewards for spending via the card, unlike its rival <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/82683\/coinbase-visa-crypto-debit-card-us-launch-bitcoin-2021\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Coinbase<\/a>, which rewards U.S. users of its Visa debit card in cryptocurrencies, including bitcoin.&nbsp;","“While there are currently no card specific benefits or perks outside of being able to spend your FTX cryptocurrency account balances, additional card rewards and benefits may be announced at a later date,\" Adam Jacobs, global head of payments at FTX, told The Block.&nbsp;","FTX's card in the U.S. is issued by Evolve Bank &amp; Trust. The crypto exchange didn't reveal the banking partners for its international expansion efforts.","Visa continues to expand its crypto partnerships and believes that \"digital currencies will have a lasting impact on the future of financial services and money movement,\" according to Cuy Sheffield, head of crypto at Visa.","The payments giant has provided cards for 70 of digital currency platforms, including Binance, BlockFi, Crypto.com, Coinbase and Fold, Sheffield told The Block.&nbsp;","\"We're excited to partner with leading crypto exchanges like FTX to bring more flexibility and ease-of-use to the way people use their crypto — unlocking the ability to use a crypto balance to fund purchases anywhere Visa is accepted,\" Sheffield said in the statement.","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Update: This story has been updated with details of the FTX card's rewards.&nbsp;<\/em>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Sheffield","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Latin America","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sheffield","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Fried","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Asia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Cuy Sheffield","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Adam Jacobs","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Evolve Bank &amp; Trust","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Yogita Khatri","The Block"]}