{"summary":"The Block&#x27;s Frank Chaparro will be joined by leaders from BitGo, Coinbase, and Genesis for a panel discussion around the state of crypto prime brokerage. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/84435\/the-block-presents-the-state-of-prime-brokerage-brought-to-you-by-genesis","publishDate":"2020-11-12T15:45:39","id":831,"type":null,"title":"The Block Presents: The State of Prime Brokerage — Brought to you by Genesis","category":["WEBINAR"],"content":["On Tuesday, December 1st The Block’s Frank Chaparro will be joined by leaders from BitGo, Galaxy Digital, and Genesis for a panel discussion around the state of crypto prime brokerage.&nbsp;","As a precursor to the event, you can read The Block’s research titled <a href=\"https:\/\/tblck.co\/CryptoPrime\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"nofollow noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“What does Prime Brokerage look like for Digital Assets?”<\/a>","You can register for the event and learn more about our panelists below:&nbsp;","&nbsp;","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" title=\"The Block Presents: The State of Prime Brokerage — Brought to you by Genesis | The Block\" src=\"https:\/\/app.livestorm.co\/p\/e3ddffe6-5583-436d-92a7-e4d51555791a\/form\" width=\"100%\" height=\"360\" frameborder=\"0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Michael Moro – CEO, Genesis<\/strong>","Michael Moro is the CEO of Genesis, responsible for planning and executing the strategic vision of the firm. Previously, he served as Chief Operating Officer for Genesis Trading and was responsible for overseeing all day-to-day operations. He started his career at Citi in investment banking, covering financial institutions and finance companies. He is a graduate of Georgetown University and holds FINRA Series 7, 24, 63 and 86\/87 licenses. Additionally, he sits on the Oversight Committee for the CME CF Bitcoin Pricing Products.","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Nick Carmi – CEO, BitGo Prime&nbsp;<\/strong>","Nick Carmi is responsible for Financial Services. Nick has over 25 years of leadership experience in the financial markets, with a strong background in Fixed Income, Foreign Exchange, OTC Derivatives and most recently Cryptocurrencies. Nick joins BitGo from Tower Research Capital, where he was Global Head of Fixed Income and Foreign Exchange Business Management, with primary focus on managing the counterparty relationships and facilitating product expansion. Prior to Tower, Nick was US Head of Foreign Exchange Prime Brokerage (FXPB) at Deutsche Bank. Before that, Nick was an entrepreneur: he was the co-founder and CEO of SpreadZero, an innovative, bespoke Fixed Income trading platform where participants can choose between one-to-one or many-to-many trading models. Earlier in his career he held senior positions at Barclays, Lehman Brothers, UBS, and Credit Suisse. He holds bachelor’s and master’s degrees in applied mathematics and statistics from Stony Brook University.","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Greg Tusar – VP, Institutional Product, Coinbase<\/strong>","Greg Tusar serves as VP, Institutional Product for Coinbase, leading the development of the firm’s efforts in areas such as Prime Brokerage and Custody, Financing, and its Exchange. Greg joined from Tagomi Systems, where he was co-founder and CTO. Coinbase acquired Tagomi in August, 2020 to expand its Institutional offerings.","Prior to founding Tagomi in 2017, Greg was Head of Global Execution Services and Platforms at KCG Holdings, responsible for its Retail Market Making and Institutional efforts. Mr. Tusar joined KCG in August 2013 from Goldman Sachs, where he spent 13 years, most recently as a Partner and global head of the firm’s equities electronic trading business. Mr. Tusar helped Goldman Sachs expand its electronic trading franchise working closely with Institutions to help improve their execution costs, and also helping the firm invest in and shape industry infrastructure including several exchanges and technology providers.","Greg was previously a limited partner at Spear, Leeds and Kellogg (“SLK”), when Goldman Sachs acquired the firm in 2000. He also worked for seven years at TLW Securities, most recently as its Chief Executive Officer, before it was acquired by SLK in 1999. He began his career at Mentor Graphics, an electronic design automation firm.","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Genesis&nbsp;<\/strong>","Genesis is a global leader in institutional digital asset markets, facilitating billions in trades, loans and transactions on a monthly basis.&nbsp;&nbsp;","Its products are catered to the needs of HNW, institutional and corporate clients. Genesis provides a single point of access for digital asset trading, derivatives, borrowing, lending, custody and prime brokerage services.","Genesis has a proven track record driving results for some of the world’s largest digital asset focused hedge funds, family offices and market makers. <a href=\"https:\/\/genesistrading.com\/wp-content\/uploads\/2020\/10\/AboutGenesisLong.pdf\" data-saferedirecturl=\"https:\/\/www.google.com\/url?q=https:\/\/genesistrading.com\/wp-content\/uploads\/2020\/10\/AboutGenesisLong.pdf&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1604148365430000&amp;usg=AFQjCNE0rBHP-Q-qN32TXBygGaWs8A2U3A\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Click here<\/a> to learn more about Genesis. <a href=\"https:\/\/genesistrading.com\/wp-content\/uploads\/2020\/10\/AboutPrime.pdf\" data-saferedirecturl=\"https:\/\/www.google.com\/url?q=https:\/\/genesistrading.com\/wp-content\/uploads\/2020\/10\/AboutPrime.pdf&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1604148365430000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEHx_61gvBzwM-sbs7m_sPNVpTJbA\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Click here<\/a> for details about Genesis Prime, its digital asset prime brokerage. <a href=\"https:\/\/genesistrading.com\/wp-content\/uploads\/2020\/10\/Q3-Report_.pdf\" data-saferedirecturl=\"https:\/\/www.google.com\/url?q=https:\/\/genesistrading.com\/wp-content\/uploads\/2020\/10\/Q3-Report_.pdf&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1604148365430000&amp;usg=AFQjCNEyu9984JZiFjZw6U59wWNE70jy2Q\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Click here<\/a> for Genesis’ Q3 results, including $4.5 billion in spot volume traded, $1 billion in derivatives volume traded, and $5.2 billion in new loan originations."],"entity":[{"type":"Galaxy Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Greg","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$1 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Tagomi","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UBS","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Financial Services","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nick","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Georgetown University","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"TLW Securities","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CME CF Bitcoin Pricing Products","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$5.2 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Global Head of Fixed Income and Foreign Exchange Business Management","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lehman Brothers","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tower Research Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Genesis","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"FINRA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"August, 2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Leeds","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tusar","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Foreign Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Credit Suisse","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Citi","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Deutsche Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"KCG Holdings","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Michael Moro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Greg Tusar","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2000","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Stony Brook University","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nick Carmi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"December","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tagomi Systems","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1999","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Head of Global Execution Services","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$4.5 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Goldman Sachs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"US Head of Foreign Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Oversight Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"August 2013","content":"DATE"},{"type":"CTO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spear","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Retail Market Making","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"VP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Barclays","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sponsored","The Block"]}