{"summary":"CMS Holdings co-founders Bobby Cho and Daniel Matuszewski appeared on The Block&#x27;s The Scoop podcast, talking bitcoin and the crypto brokerage wars.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/73179\/cms-defi-traders-bitcoin-volatility","publishDate":"2020-07-28T15:59:50","id":8310,"type":null,"title":"CMS Holdings co-founders say DeFi claimed trader attention before bitcoin&#x27;s volatility spike","category":["PODCASTS"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 29 of Season 2 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block’s Frank Chaparro and co-founders of CMS Holdings Bobby Cho and Daniel Matuszewski.<\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"1868777c7b796b6c586c707d7a74777b737b6a61686c77367b7775\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode of The Scoop is brought to you by Bitstamp, the original global cryptocurrency exchange. Since 2011, Bitstamp has been a cornerstone of the industry, earning the trust of over four million individuals and top financial institutions looking for a reliable trading venue. <\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Whether you’re trading on our web platform, mobile app or industry-leading APIs, Bitstamp gives you the professional-grade tools you need to execute your strategy.&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/bitstamp.net\/app?r=pro%E2%80%93&amp;utm_source=Website&amp;utm_medium=podcast&amp;utm_campaign=theblock&amp;utm_content=ctaapp\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Download the Bitstamp app<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or visit&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.bitstamp.net\/pro\/?utm_source=Website&amp;utm_medium=podcast&amp;utm_campaign=theblock&amp;utm_content=ctaweb\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitstamp.net\/Pro<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;to learn more and start trading today!<\/i>","&nbsp;","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK9197021487\" width=\"100%\" height=\"200\" frameborder=\"0\" scrolling=\"no\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","During 2017's initial coin offering craze, breaking news could move markets — up until last week, not so much. Daniel Matuszewski and Bobby Cho have been in the over-the-counter trading space since the early days of crypto, working at the desks of firms like Circle and DRW before founding their own trading company, CMS Holdings.","In this week's episode of The Scoop, the pair explained how attention moved to several different cryptocurrencies and DeFi opportunities as bitcoin trading opportunities waned.","But, of course, the crypto markets move faster than podcasts can be dropped, and the environment has changed with implied volatility spiking according to Skew data. After months of steady price and low volatility, the price of bitcoin <a href=\"https:\/\/www.forbes.com\/sites\/youngjoseph\/2020\/07\/27\/bitcoin-price-hits-10900-for-first-time-since-2019-what-traders-are-saying\/#66b366742a4e\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">neared $11,000<\/a> this week.","","","In this week's episode, Cho and Matuszewski give the trader perspective on bitcoin and the DeFi scene, including:&nbsp;&nbsp;","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen to this week's episode on Apple, Spotify, GooglePlay, Stitcher, or wherever you listen to podcasts.<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"DRW","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Daniel Matuszewski","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2011","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Matuszewski","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$11,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bitstamp","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CMS Holdings","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CMS Holdings Bobby Cho","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bobby Cho","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Aislinn Keely","The Block"]}