{"summary":"Blockchain analytics firm Flipside Crypto hires new General Manager to lead DAO strategy.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/165022\/daphne-kwon-joins-flipside-crypto-as-general-manager-of-dao-initiatives","publishDate":"2022-08-23T10:17:03","id":8312,"type":null,"title":"Daphne Kwon joins Flipside Crypto as general manager of DAO Initiatives","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Daphne Kwon, who most recently served as chief strategy officer at Meredith Corporation, joined blockchain analytics firm Flipside Crypto<\/span><span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kwon will work to grow the company's Decentralized Autonomous Organization (DAO) strategy as general manager of DAOs, Flipside said in a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.prnewswire.com\/news-releases\/flipside-crypto-lands-daphne-kwon-to-serve-as-gm-for-the-companys-dao-initiatives-301610724.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">press release.<\/a> She'll assume the role effective immediately.<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"The future of organizations will be shaped by what is evolving right now in the DAO space,” Kwon said in the statement. \"My role at Flipside puts me right at the center of it all, working with a vibrant community of Web3 thought leaders.\"&nbsp; <\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">DAOs are a decentralized system for organizing a group of people – like a digital co-op with a shared bank account. These organizations are typically without leaders or centralized leadership, instead operate by bringing proposals to the DAO and giving token holders a chance to vote on them.<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kwon's hiring comes after Flipside Crypto <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/142018\/blockchain-analytics-company-flipside-crypto-raises-50-million\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/span><\/a><span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in April that it had raised $50 million at a $350 million valuation. Flipside analyzes blockchain networks to gain insight into the impact of on- and off-chain activities on holders, miners, voters and token holders. <\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In October 2021, the company contributed intellectual property to MetricsDAO, to help organizations access analytics for crypto projects. During its funding announcement in April, it said the funds would&nbsp;also be used to activate more DAOs over the coming year.<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Prior to her stint at Meredith, Kwon held a position as COO at Betaworks Studio and CFO at Gwyneth Paltrow’s wellness company, Goop. <\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$350 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Meredith Corporation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Meredith","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Flipside","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Kwon","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gwyneth Paltrow","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Decentralized Autonomous Organization (DAO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Daphne Kwon","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Betaworks Studio","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Flipside Crypto","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"October 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"DAO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$50 million","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["HIRING"],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}