{"summary":"Some crypto stocks performed better than others on Thursday, with Block gaining and Silvergate falling.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/191532\/bitcoin-dips-under-17000-block-and-coinbase-see-mixed-fortunes-and-silvergate-sinks","publishDate":"2022-12-01T16:32:08","id":8322,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin dips under $17,000, Block and Coinbase see mixed fortunes and Silvergate sinks","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["Crypto prices traded down on Thursday as bitcoin flipped either side of $17,000 just 24 hours after reaching a two-week high.","Meanwhile, crypto stocks traded in a wide range during the day's session, led by declines for Silvergate.","Bitcoin failed to hold on above $17,000 for 24 hours, trading at $16,866 at 4:00 p.m. EST, falling 1.1% from yesterday. The leading cryptocurrency by market cap <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/191071\/bitcoin-trades-over-17000-following-powells-speech-december-decisions-loom-large\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">rose<\/a> after a speech by U.S. Federal Reserve Chair Jerome Powell on Wednesday.&nbsp;","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/symbols\/BTCUSD\/?exchange=COINBASE\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BTCUSD chart by TradingView<\/span><\/a>","Ether was trading at $1,275, down 1.8% over the past 24 hours. Binance's BNB experienced a sharper sell-off in that time, dropping by 3.1%.&nbsp;","U.S. indices saw mixed fortunes on Thursday, with the S&amp;P 500 closing down 0.09% and the Nasdaq 100 rising 0.1%.","Shares in crypto bank Silvergate fell sharply today, shedding over 7.8% to $25.27. The bank has been linked to BlockFi and FTX and revealed some exposure to both firms.&nbsp;","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/symbols\/NYSE-SI\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">SI chart by TradingView<\/a><\/span>","Coinbase shares dropped 0.9% on Thursday, changing hands for around $45.32, according to Nasdaq data.","Michael Saylor's MicroStrategy briefly traded above $200 today, for the first time since Nov. 9, before surrendering those gains. Shares in the company were trading at $198.94 at 4:00 p.m. EST.&nbsp;","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/symbols\/NASDAQ-MSTR\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">MSTR chart by TradingView<\/span><\/a>","Jack Dorsey's Block performed slightly better than its peers, gaining over 2% to trade at $69.15.&nbsp;","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Silvergate","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"7.8%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"TradingView","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"0.9%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1.8%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$69.15","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$1,275","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"S&amp;P","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nov. 9","content":"DATE"},{"type":"0.1%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"4:00 p.m. EST.","content":"TIME"},{"type":"$17,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$16,866","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$200","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"4:00 p.m. EST","content":"TIME"},{"type":"0.09%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Michael Saylor","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$198.94","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"U.S. Federal Reserve Chair Jerome Powell","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$25.27","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"today","content":"DATE"},{"type":"3.1%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"1.1%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$45.32","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Jack Dorsey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MicroStrategy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nasdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE","BITCOIN","BNB","COINBASE","DOGECOIN","ECONOMIC INDICATORS","EQUITY MOVERS","ETHEREUM","FTX"],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}