{"summary":"a16z&#x27;s Chris Dixon is joining the board of directors of NFT platform OpenSea. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/160368\/dixon-takes-over-katie-hauns-board-seat-at-opensea","publishDate":"2022-07-30T14:34:02","id":8333,"type":null,"title":"Dixon takes over Katie Haun&#x27;s board seat at OpenSea","category":["VENTURE CAPITAL"],"content":["a16z's Chris Dixon has joined the board of non-fungible token trading platform OpenSea, according to a blog post published Saturday.&nbsp;","\"I’m excited to formally welcome Chris Dixon to the OpenSea Board of Directors,\" co-founder Devin Finzer wrote in a blog. \"Chris has been extremely influential in shaping my views on web3.\"","Dixon is taking former a16z venture investor Katie Haun's seat. Haun joined the board of the NFT firm in July 2021 after the venture firm led a $100 million Series B financing round. She left a16z's crypto investment practice to launch Haun Ventures, which reportedly raised $1.5 billion in fresh funding.&nbsp;","\"Katie has been another invaluable source of wisdom for OpenSea over the years,\" Finzer wrote. \"And thanks to her long standing relationship with Chris, she was able to execute a smooth handoff and remains close to us in her capacity as an investor through Haun Ventures.\"","OpenSea, which touted a $13.3 billion valuation in a January funding round, is among the several firms navigating a tough market for NFT trading and a broader slide in crypto prices. The firm—which has seen volumes drop precipitously since the beginning of the year—laid off about 20% of its staff in July.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Haun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$13.3 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Devin Finzer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Katie Haun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$100 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"20%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Katie","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Chris Dixon","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$1.5 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"OpenSea Board of Directors","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Haun Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Saturday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Chris","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["KATIE HAUN","OPENSEA"],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}