{"summary":"Sam Bankman-Fried, the former CEO of FTX, insisted the U.S. arm of his company &quot;was not financially impacted by this shitshow&quot; a day before it filed for bankruptcy.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/185977\/bankman-fried-said-ftx-us-was-fine-one-day-before-bankruptcy-filing","publishDate":"2022-11-11T11:21:54","id":8334,"type":null,"title":"Bankman-Fried said FTX.US was &#x27;FINE!&#x27; one day before bankruptcy filing ","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["Former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried insisted the U.S. arm of his crypto empire was “FINE!” after the company’s utility token collapsed — right up until FTX.US filed for bankruptcy on Friday morning.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","“FTX US USERS ARE FINE!” Bankman-Fried <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/SBF_FTX\/status\/1590709169757491202\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">wrote<\/a> in a series of tweets on Thursday. <span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“<\/span>FTX US, the US-based exchange that accepts Americans, was not financially impacted by this shitshow.”","A day later, Bankman-Fried resigned his post as CEO, and FTX.US filed for bankruptcy in Delaware. FTX announced it had moved to file for Chapter 11, along with more than 100 of its affiliated corporate entities, including Bankman-Fried’s Alameda Research trading firm.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","The shocking collapse of the crypto exchange began last weekend when rival exchange Binance announced it would sell a large position of FTX’s utility token, FTT. Bankman-Fried insisted his company was “fine” on Monday, but by Tuesday the firm was in turmoil.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> A spokesperson for FTX declined to comment.&nbsp;<\/span>","Even as Bankman-Fried acknowledged the international arm of his company was facing trouble, he assured users of FTX.US throughout the week that the entity was not impacted. The former CEO said he was “shocked” by what had happened on Friday, after announcing FTX.US would file for bankruptcy.","“I'm piecing together all of the details, but I was shocked to see things unravel the way they did earlier this week,” Bankman-Fried <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/185964\/bankman-frieds-really-really-sorry-again-following-bankruptcy-filing\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said on Twitter<\/a>.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"FTT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Delaware","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"last weekend","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Fried","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"morning","content":"TIME"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"the U.S.","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Stephanie Murray","The Block"]}