{"summary":"Cboe is a Wall Street powerhouse.  On a typical trading day, the exchange operator handles about a third of U.S. equity volumes. In derivatives, major","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/93443\/bitcoin-indexes-with-cboe-scoop-podcast","publishDate":"2021-02-02T13:55:05","id":838,"type":null,"title":"Cboe&#x27;s Catherine Clay breaksdown its bitcoin market data ambitions","category":["BITCOIN"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 6 of Season 3 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block’s Frank Chaparro and Catherine Clay of Cboe Global Markets.<\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"c3b3aca7a0a2b0b783b7aba6a1afaca0a8a0b1bab3b7aceda0acae\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode of The Scoop is brought to you by Blockset. With&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/newsletter.theblockcrypto.com\/l\/7ongM1BS4pW2oMzRHwneMw\/V1Ujzkd447eIMGZOacS39Q\/r7uLQEbKLnxHG2n9jmci4Q\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Blockset<\/a>, companies gain access to tools such as:<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">1. A highly scalable API that supports Bitcoin, Ethereum, Ripple, and other top chains<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n2. AML\/KYC data expediting time to market by complying with legal requirements<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n3. Leading custody solutions using modern multi-party compute (MPC) technology&nbsp;<\/i>","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK1552558638\" width=\"100%\" height=\"200\" frameborder=\"0\" scrolling=\"no\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Cboe is a Wall Street powerhouse.&nbsp;","On a typical trading day, the exchange operator handles about a third of U.S. equity volumes. In derivatives, major Wall Street products such as the VIX and S&amp;P 500 options trade hands every day through its venue.&nbsp;","Cboe is now trying its hand at the crypto market — again, that is. More than a year after it <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/93321\/robinhood-payment-for-order-flow-2020\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">shuttered<\/a> its bitcoin futures product, the exchange said that it would re-enter the market through a partnership with crypto data services provider CoinRoutes.&nbsp;&nbsp;","On today's episode of <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/podcasts\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Scoop<\/a>, Cboe global head of information solutions Catherine Clay lays out the firm's ambitions to build out a business in crypto market data. Clay also touches on how Cboe's plans set the stage for a wide range of tradable products, including a bitcoin VIX-like product to an exchange-traded fund.&nbsp;","\"You can even think about creative indices that reflect portfolio allocations with digital assets as a component,\" Clay said. \"Bringing this real price data in for the creation and calculation of indexes falls very much in line with how we think about educating the investment sphere and giving people some idea about how to construct portfolios for crypto.\"","For Clay, the relatively undeveloped state of the crypto data ecosystem harkens back to her time trading internet stock derivatives in the 1990s.&nbsp;","\"It really reminds me of when I was a derivatives trader back in the late 90s trading the internet stock back then that were really volatile,\" she said. \"I remember standing in the pit where I was the lead market maker for Netscape and Double Click and you could imagine back then there was very little data available to understand where the derivatives—the options— listed on those underlying should be priced and traded.\"","In this episode of The Scoop, Clay also discusses","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Catherine Clay","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Double Click","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Cboe Global Markets","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"S&amp;P","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Netscape","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1990s","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Cboe","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"AML","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MPC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Clay","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN"],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}