{"summary":"Join The Block&#x27;s Frank Chaparro for a discussion on the rapid evolution of the blockchain platform market, and how organizations should better prepare.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/82940\/enterprise-blockchain-calls-for-immediate-changes-in-future-implementations-presented-by-unbound-tech","publishDate":"2020-10-29T19:59:36","id":8386,"type":null,"title":"Enterprise Blockchain: Calls for immediate changes in future implementations — Presented by Unbound Tech","category":["WEBINAR"],"content":["As demand increases for blockchain technology, enterprises are having to balance between scalability vs. usability while preserving strict privacy standards. According to Gartner, the demand will only increase with estimations that by 2021, 90% of current enterprise blockchain platform implementations will require replacement to remain competitive, secure, and avoid obsolescence.","Join The Block’s Frank Chaparro for a discussion on the rapid evolution of the blockchain platform market, and how organizations should better prepare.","Register for the event and learn about our panelists below:&nbsp;","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" title=\"Enterprise Blockchain: Calls for immediate changes in future implementations — Presented by Unbound Tech | The Block\" src=\"https:\/\/app.livestorm.co\/p\/bfceda36-66d1-481f-86a9-d94d8aec60e9\/form\" width=\"100%\" height=\"360\" frameborder=\"0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About our Panelists:<\/strong>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Rebecca Aspler Director, Product Management, Unbound Tech&nbsp;<\/strong>","Leading the blockchain product line at Unbound Tech, Rebecca is driving innovation all the way from prototyping, market-fit validation, roadmap planning to periodical features-prioritization and specification. Staying informed of the market landscape, Rebecca is also analyzing the digital assets and enterprise blockchain ecosystem, products and constantly evolving regulations. Prior to this role and specializing in product management for large scale cloud-based (SaaS) enterprise software applications, Rebecca has led product management groups and operations at companies such as SAP and Teoco, growing new products from inception point to profitable product lines; serving successfully various Fortune 1,000 companies","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Omid Malekan – Adjunct professor, Columbia Business School<\/strong>","Omid Malekan is an adjunct professor at Columbia Business School and a blockchain innovation consultant for Fortune 100 companies. He’s the author of the book&nbsp;The Story of the Blockchain, a Beginner’s Guide to the Technology That Nobody Understands&nbsp;and has been working in the industry for over 5 years. Prior to getting the Bitcoin bug, he worked in financial services and media. His proudest achievement is being called “misguided” by Ben Bernanke in his memoir.","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Adam Mastrelli- Digital Assets and Blockchain, IBM<\/strong>","Adam Mastrelli has designed his life to avoid complacency and crafted an expansive range of experiences that includes documentary filmmaking, spending 10,000+ hours on stage\/screen as a professional actor, and NGO management.","Adam leads North American IBM Systems Digital Asset\/Blockchain (LinuxONE) solutions that power institutional custody, exchange wallets, and tokenization solutions requiring advanced secure private key management. Adam is responsible for market development, and building sales and services infrastructure. Adam also helps clients enhance their solution’s capabilities by leveraging IBM’s Hyper Protect Services on premise and on the IBM Cloud.","Recently, Adam spent 3+ years as an intrapreneur building out IBM Blockchain Ventures &amp; the IBM Blockchain Accelerator focused on designing and scaling blockchain networks.","In addition, Adam currently hosts a television show on the The Smithsonian Channel called ‘Secrets Unlocked’.","Adam received his Bachelors in Sociology and Markets and Management from Duke University and an MBA in Emerging Markets Finance from the University of Florida. His competitive and team spirit were fostered as a Division 1 Soccer player at Duke, and he continues to push himself in every aspect of his life, completing the New York City marathon and the 56-mile Comrades ultra marathon in South Africa. He is proficient in Italian and Spanish and can make small talk in Mandarin, Swedish and Zulu. He thrives on new technologies, global experiences, and the next challenge that lies ahead.","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><u data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Unbound<\/u><\/strong>","In a world moving towards everything encrypted, signed, and authenticated, secure and operationally efficient, cryptographic infrastructure is an absolute must for enterprises. Unbound Tech’s solutions leverage the latest in MPC technology and have been selected to secure many of the world’s largest banks and Fortune 500 companies. With a headquarters in New York and an international headquarters in Israel, Unbound Tech and its NextGen Key Orchestration Platform provides the cryptographic infrastructure to enable enterprises worldwide to easily secure and manage all their information and digital assets. Learn more at&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.unboundtech.com\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"nofollow noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">www.unboundtech.com<\/a>&nbsp;and follow us on LinkedIn, Twitter, and Facebook."],"entity":[{"type":"90%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"New York City","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Technology That Nobody Understands","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Adam","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Adam Mastrelli","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"South Africa","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Duke","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Israel","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"IBM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Duke University","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Columbia Business School","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NextGen Key Orchestration Platform","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"IBM Blockchain Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ben Bernanke","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Omid Malekan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"SAP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Smithsonian","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Emerging Markets Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Product Management","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"IBM’s Hyper Protect Services","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Unbound Tech","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gartner","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MPC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mandarin","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"NGO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"the University of Florida","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"IBM Systems Digital Asset\/Blockchain","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Rebecca","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sponsored","The Block"]}