{"summary":"The Ethereum network is to activate the Zhejiang public test network on Feb. 7 as part of its preparation for the Shanghai-Capella upgrade in March.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/208470\/ethereum-developers-to-open-testing-of-shanghai-capella-upgrade-on-feb-7","publishDate":"2023-02-03T09:03:54","id":8399,"type":null,"title":"Ethereum developers to open public testing of Shanghai-Capella upgrade on Feb. 7","category":["CRYPTO ECOSYSTEMS"],"content":["The Ethereum network is set to activate the Zhejiang public test network on Feb. 7, as the platform prepares for the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/193350\/ethereum-developers-target-march-2023-for-shanghai-hard-fork\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Shanghai-Capella upgrade<\/a> in March. Zhejiang is currently in a preview phase and will be upgraded once more in the coming days for public use.","Shanghai-Capella, also referred to as Shapella, is an upgrade aimed at enabling ether (ETH) withdrawals from network validators — a feature that is currently unavailable. Shanghai will upgrade the execution layer of Ethereum, while Capella will upgrade the consensus layer of the blockchain. To reach the final upgrade in March, developers have planned multiple phases of public testing, beginning with Zhejiang.&nbsp;","Ethereum DevOps and client teams are working to resolve any technical issues before the Zhejiang activation, <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/TimBeiko\/status\/1621210105479061505\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">according<\/a> to Tim Beiko from the Ethereum Foundation. Once activated next week, Zhejiang will be open to the public for testing. Users will have the opportunity to run validator nodes and test unstaking of ETH with validators.","After Zhejiang, the Ethereum network team will then move on to other public testnets, including Sepolia in February and <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/162913\/ethereums-final-proof-of-stake-test-merge-is-live-on-goerli\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Goerli<\/a> in early March. Goerli will be the final dress rehearsal before mainnet Shanghai-Capella launch by end of March assuming everything goes as planned, Beiko <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/TimBeiko\/status\/1621210920465895424\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">added<\/a>.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tim Beiko","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Capella","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Feb. 7","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Shapella","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"February","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Beiko","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Zhejiang","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Shanghai","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ethereum Foundation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Zhejiang","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["ETHEREUM"],"authors":["Vishal Chawla","The Block"]}