{"summary":"Circle is considering going public through an initial public offering after a plan to do similar via a SPAC failed to materialize.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/262100\/usdc-stablecoin-issuer-circle-mulls-ipo-in-2024-bloomberg","publishDate":"2023-11-07T19:23:16","id":8402,"type":null,"title":"USDC stablecoin issuer Circle mulls IPO in 2024: Bloomberg","category":["STABLECOINS"],"content":["Circle, the issuer of the USDC stablecoin with a market cap over $24 billion, is considering an initial public offering in 2024, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2023-11-07\/stablecoin-issuer-circle-internet-said-to-consider-2024-ipo\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">according to Bloomberg<\/a>.","The company has been talking to advisers about a potential IPO, Bloomberg reported, citing anonymous sources. \"While it’s not clear how much Circle would seek to be valued in an IPO, it was valued at $9 billion when it tried to go public in a blank-check deal in 2022,\" according to the report.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nIn 2021, Circle <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/110806\/confirmed-stablecoin-firm-circle-public-spac-merger\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">agreed to go public<\/a> through a merger with a Special Purpose Acquisition Company (SPAC) named Concord Acquisition Corp., but that arrangement later fizzled. \"Becoming a U.S.-listed public company has long been part of Circle’s strategic aspirations. We don’t comment on rumors,\" a representative for Circle told Bloomberg.","Circle's investors including financial heavyweights like Goldman Sachs, Fidelity and Blackrock. The USDC stablecoin, once boasting a market cap near $56 billion, began a dramatic decline in June 2022.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"June 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Concord Acquisition Corp.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Fidelity","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$24 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Blackrock","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$56 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Special Purpose Acquisition Company (SPAC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Goldman Sachs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Circle","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$9 billion","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}