{"summary":"Binance KR would support Binance KRW (BKRW) stablecoin at launch. The stablecoin is backed by South Korean won (KRW) and recently got listed on Binance.com.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/60384\/binance-is-launching-a-new-exchange-in-south-korea-next-week","publishDate":"2020-03-31T05:45:08","id":8406,"type":null,"title":"Binance is launching a new exchange in South Korea next week","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["Binance is launching a new crypto-to-crypto exchange in South Korea next week.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nAnnouncing the news on Tuesday, Binance <a href=\"https:\/\/www.binance.com\/en\/blog\/421499824684900487\/Binance-to-Launch-Korean-Crypto-Exchange-on-Binance-Cloud\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a> the new exchange, Binance KR, would open for registration and deposits on April 2. Trading would open on April 4, while withdrawals on April 9.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nBinance KR would support Binance KRW (BKRW) stablecoin at launch. The stablecoin is backed by South Korean won (KRW) and recently got listed on Binance.com.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nKorean users will be able to convert KRW into BKRW stablecoins, which can then be used for trading bitcoin (BTC), ether (ETH), Binance coin (BNB) and BKRW.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nBinance said the new exchange would also “soon” support Tether (USDT) and Binance USD (BUSD) stablecoins for trading.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BxB acquisition&nbsp;<\/strong><\/span><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nBinance KR’s launch comes with the news of Binance Ltd.’s acquisition of BxB, the fintech company behind KRWb, a KRW-backed stablecoin. Just last month, Binance <a href=\"https:\/\/www.binance.com\/ua\/blog\/421499824684900360\/Binance-%D1%96%D0%BD%D0%B2%D0%B5%D1%81%D1%82%D1%83%D1%94-%D1%83-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D1%80%D0%B5%D0%B9%D1%81%D1%8C%D0%BA%D1%83-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BC%D0%BF%D0%B0%D0%BD%D1%96%D1%8E-%D1%81%D1%82%D0%B5%D0%B9%D0%B1%D0%BB%D0%BA%D0%BE%D1%97%D0%BD%D1%96%D0%B2-BxB\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">invested<\/a> in BxB. <br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nIt is worth noting that Binance Ltd. is the entity that would offer Binance KR and BKRW.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n“We are pleased to provide a digital asset platform for users in Korea to bring the trading depth, security and transaction speed of Binance.com to Binance KR,” said Binance CEO Changpeng “CZ” Zhao. “Our decision to list BKRW trading pairs will allow us to seamlessly connect crypto to the South Korean won in order to expand our local services.”","Binance Ltd. co-CEO Jiho Kang said the firm is “committed” to bringing a “fully compliant” crypto exchange to the Korean market via Binance Cloud and BKRW. <a href=\"https:\/\/www.binance.com\/en\/blog\/421499824684900422\/Binance-Announces-B2B2C-Cloud-Solution-for-Launching-Digital-Asset-Trading-Platforms\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance Cloud<\/a> is an infrastructure solution launched last month, for the exchange’s customers and partners to launch crypto exchanges leveraging its technology and liquidity.&nbsp;<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nBinance KR is the fifth local exchange of Binance. The <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/42606\/binance-to-support-wechat-and-alipay-for-buying-bitcoin-in-china\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">other four<\/a> separate exchanges are in Singapore, Jersey, Uganda, and the U.S.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"South Korea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Jiho Kang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"April 2","content":"DATE"},{"type":"South Korean","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"April 4","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Korea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance USD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"KRW","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Uganda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Binance Ltd.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Binance KR","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance KRW","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"last month","content":"DATE"},{"type":"April 9","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Binance Cloud","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jersey","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE","BUSD"],"authors":["Yogita Khatri","The Block"]}