{"summary":"Binance has tapped former Mexico securities chief Adalberto Palma Gómez to join its new advisory board.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/168727\/binance-adds-former-mexico-securities-chief-to-new-global-advisory-council","publishDate":"2022-09-08T18:05:14","id":8427,"type":null,"title":"Binance adds former Mexico securities chief to new global advisory council","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Binance has added Adalberto Palma Gómez, former president of Mexico's National Banking and Securities Commission (CNBV), to its new global advisory board.","Mexican business news outlet <a href=\"https:\/\/www.eleconomista.com.mx\/sectorfinanciero\/Expresidente-de-la-CNBV-se-suma-al-consejo-asesor-global-de-Binance-20220907-0109.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">El Economista<\/a> first reported news of the appointment, which Binance confirmed to The Block in a statement.","Palma was appointed as the CNBV's president in November 2018 and <a href=\"https:\/\/www.forbes.com.mx\/adalberto-palma-renucia-a-la-cnbv-alistan-anuncio\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">resigned<\/a> from the role in March 2020. He has more than 30 years of financial experience, Binance said, serving in executive roles at Banamex, Citibank and Bankers Trust in addition to being an independent advisor for Mexico's Institute for the Protection of Bank Savings (IPAB).&nbsp;","Binance announced Palma's addition to its <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/167857\/binance-taps-ex-central-bank-head-economy-minister-of-brazil-as-advisor\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">advisory board<\/a> just days after the exchange revealed that former Brazilian finance minister Henrique Meirelles would also be joining the group. Meirelles left his role as Sao Paulo's finance minister in April and also served as Brazil's finance minister between 2016-2018.&nbsp;","Binance, the world's largest cryptocurrency exchange, has been building its local presence in Latin American countries with a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/147212\/crypto-ceos-are-courting-brazils-central-bank-as-legislation-moves-through-national-congress\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">large focus<\/a> on Brazil.&nbsp;","\"Binance will release more details about the new advisory board soon,\" the exchange said in a Portuguese-language statement.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Henrique Meirelles","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2016","content":"DATE"},{"type":"El Economista","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"November 2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Adalberto Palma Gómez","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Banamex","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Brazil","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Mexico","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Institute for the Protection of Bank Savings (IPAB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"March 2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Palma","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sao Paulo","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bankers Trust","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"National Banking and Securities Commission (CNBV","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CNBV","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Binance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Citibank","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE"],"authors":["Kristin Majcher","The Block"]}