{"summary":"Join The Block&#x27;s Director of News Frank Chaparro on Thursday February 18th at 12pm ET \/ 9am PT for a panel discussion exploring the applications of Dollar Stablecoins across capital markets and how this technology will shape financial infrastructure of the future.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/94898\/dollar-stablecoins-as-market-infrastructure-dex-defi-the-future-of-capital-markets-brought-to-you-by-circle","publishDate":"2021-02-19T15:28:18","id":8433,"type":null,"title":"Dollar Stablecoins as Market Infrastructure: DEX, DeFi &amp; the Future of Capital Markets | Full Video","category":["SPONSORED"],"content":["The Block’s Director of News Frank Chaparro hosted a&nbsp;panel discussion exploring the applications of Dollar Stablecoins across capital markets and how this technology will shape financial infrastructure of the future.","You can view the recording in its entirety and learn more about our panelists below:","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" src=\"https:\/\/www.youtube.com\/embed\/ULXGhE6dqBg\" width=\"560\" height=\"315\" frameborder=\"0\" allowfullscreen=\"allowfullscreen\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><u data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About our panelists:<\/u><\/strong>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Jeremy Allaire, CEO, Circle<\/strong>","Jeremy Allaire is Co-Founder, Chairman and CEO of Circle, a global financial technology firm that enables businesses of all sizes to harness the power of stablecoins and public blockchains for payments and commerce. Founded in 2013, Circle is the pioneer of USD Coin (USDC), the fastest growing, fully-reserved, and regulated dollar stablecoin. Governed by the Centre Consortium, led by Circle and Coinbase, USDC's market cap reached $5.4 billion January 2021, growing by more than 800% in the past 12 months, with over $300 billion in transaction volume. Previously, Mr. Allaire co-founded and led multiple global internet technology companies with thousands of employees, hundreds of millions of consumers served, and multiple successful public offerings on NASDAQ. He has provided expert testimony on digital assets and monetary policy before the US Senate Committee on Homeland Security &amp; Government Affairs, US Senate Banking Committee, and he has been named to the International Monetary Fund (IMF) High-Level Advisory Group on FinTech. Mr. Allaire provides perspective and policy recommendations at the highest levels inside financial bodies across the US, UK, and Europe.","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Robert Leshner, Founder, Compound<\/strong>","Robert is the Founder of Compound, the first and largest decentralized money market protocol, and invests in early stage DeFi companies at Robot Ventures. He was formerly a professional economist and Chartered Financial Analyst.","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sam Bankman-Fried, CEO, FTX &amp; Alameda Research<\/strong>","Before founding Alameda and then FTX, Sam was a trader on Jane Street Capital’s international ETF desk. He traded a variety of ETFs, futures, currencies, and equities, and designed their automated OTC trading system. He graduated from MIT with a degree in physics.","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This event is brought to you by Circle<\/strong>","Circle is a financial technology firm that enables businesses of all sizes to harness the power of stablecoins and public blockchains for payments, commerce and financial applications. Circle is also a principal developer of USD Coin (USDC), which together with Coinbase and the Centre Consortium oversees the standards and protocol for what has become the fastest-growing, regulated, fully-reserved stablecoin in the world. There are nearly 6 billion USDC in circulation, growing by more than 1000% year-over-year with $300 billion processed in on-chain transactions. Today, Circle's transactional services, business accounts, and platform APIs are giving rise to a new generation of financial services and commerce applications that hold the promise of raising global economic prosperity for all through programmable internet commerce. Learn more at&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/circle.com.\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"nofollow noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">https:\/\/circle.com.<\/a>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"International Monetary Fund (IMF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"US Senate Banking Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chartered Financial Analyst","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2013","content":"DATE"},{"type":"January 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NASDAQ","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Founder of Compound","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$5.4 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$300 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"1000%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"UK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Allaire","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sam","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Robot Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USD Coin (USDC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jeremy Allaire","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FinTech","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Centre Consortium","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"800%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"US Senate Committee on Homeland Security &amp; Government Affairs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MIT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Circle","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"FTX &amp; Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Level Advisory Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Robert Leshner","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sponsored","The Block"]}