{"summary":"After he agreed to testify, Sam Bankman-Fried is slated to appear before the the U.S. House Committee on Financial Services on Dec. 13.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/193831\/congressional-committee-confirms-sbf-as-ftx-hearing-witness","publishDate":"2022-12-09T19:29:16","id":8437,"type":null,"title":"Congressional committee confirms SBF as FTX hearing witness","category":["LEGAL"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Disgraced FTX founder Sam Bankman-Fried is slated to testify in a congressional hearing on the collapse of the company, the U<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.S. House of Representatives Committee on Financial Services confirmed.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bankman-Fried’s panel was added to the list of witnesses for a hearing on Tuesday, Dec. 13, the committee said. Before Bankman-Fried testifies, the committee will call upon current FTX CEO John J. Ray III.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bankman-Fried earlier today <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/193619\/sam-bankman-fried-says-he-will-testify-before-congressional-committee\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">confirmed<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> his willingness to testify on the matter of the FTX collapse. He tweeted that he plans to offer insights on his personal and business failings, the solvency of FTX US and possible recourse for U.S. customers.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>The Block's former CEO had agreed to a loan&nbsp;from FTX co-founder Sam Bankman-Fried's Alameda Research through an undisclosed arrangement.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Fried","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dec. 13","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"S. House of Representatives Committee on Financial Services","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"John J. Ray III","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["COURT HEARINGS","FTX","HOUSE FINANCIAL SERVICES COMMITTEE"],"authors":["Jeremy Nation","The Block"]}