{"summary":"Here&#x27;s how crypto mining companies performed on Thursday, June 30.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/155233\/bitcoin-mining-stock-report-thursday-june-30","publishDate":"2022-06-30T17:18:26","id":8453,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin mining stock report: Thursday, June 30","category":["MINING"],"content":["A majority of bitcoin miner stocks tracked by The Block fell on Thursday.","Digihost Technology, Bit Digital and Marathon fell by 9.73%, 9.03% and 7.93%, respectively.","Meanwhile, Cipher Mining, Iris Energy and Stronghold Digital Mining's stocks rose by 7.87%, 4.69% and 2.47%.","New York's Department of Environmental Conservation announced during the afternoon that it <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/155188\/greenidges-permit-renewal-denied-by-new-york-regulators\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">denied Greenidge's air permit renewal<\/a> and the miner stated that it would challenge the decision and keep operations running in the meantime.","The company's stock was down by 7.30% at the end of the trading session.","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Here's how crypto mining companies performed on Thursday, June 30:<\/em>","","","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Stronghold Digital Mining","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2.47%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Greenidge","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Cipher Mining","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"June 30","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Marathon","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"9.03%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"7.30%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"7.87%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"9.73%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Bit Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"7.93%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"4.69%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Department of Environmental Conservation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Iris Energy","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Catarina Moura","The Block"]}