{"summary":"Goldman may be looking to advise the crypto exchange giant on how to smoothen possible regulatory wrinkles with the CFTC.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/142799\/goldman-sachs-reportedly-seeking-closer-ties-with-ftx-crypto-exchange","publishDate":"2022-04-21T06:26:35","id":8489,"type":null,"title":"Goldman Sachs reportedly seeking closer ties with FTX crypto exchange","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["Goldman Sachs is reportedly looking to help crypto exchange giant FTX navigate its way through US regulations, among other concerns, according to a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.ft.com\/content\/53dde228-02bb-4193-b47e-0d171ae96073\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">report<\/a> by Financial Times on Thursday.","People familiar with the matter cited by the publication said Goldman CEO David Solomon and FTX chief Sam Bankman-Fried (SBF) held discussions in March about possible avenues of collaboration.","The two were said to have talked about ways in which Goldman Sachs could advise FTX on the latter’s plan to offer retail trading of crypto derivatives. The exchange’s US arm <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/137304\/cftc-opens-up-ftx-uss-derivatives-trading-model-to-public-comment\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filed for approval<\/a> with the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) in March for margin trading of crypto derivatives.","FTX’s crypto derivates application was the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/140026\/ftx-derivatives-proposal-takes-center-stage-at-congressional-hearing-with-cftc-chairman\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">subject of a Congressional hearing<\/a> with the CFTC chairman in March.","According to the Financial Times, Solomon proposed that Goldman advise FTX in a dialogue with the CFTC. Other topics discussed included plans for future funding rounds and a possible initial public offering for FTX.","FTX raised $400 million in a Series C funding round in January that valued the company at $32 billion. SBF is reportedly talking with private investors about another possible funding round.","Solomon’s reported overtures to SBF are in keeping with Goldman’s expanding footprint in the crypto space. This trend is a departure from the largely anti-crypto posturing of major players on Wall Street in previous years.","Goldman already offers over-the-counter (OTC) <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/138626\/goldman-sachs-otc-crypto-options-trade\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">crypto options trading<\/a> and was part of a new <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/141019\/certik-raises-88-million-valuation-2-billion-goldman-sachs-others\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">funding round<\/a> for blockchain security outfit Certik earlier in April.","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$32 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Solomon","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Goldman’s","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Goldman Sachs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Goldman","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"David Solomon","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"CFTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$400 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Financial Times","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["FTX","GOLDMAN SACHS","SAM BANKMAN-FRIED"],"authors":["Osato Avan-Nomayo","The Block"]}