{"summary":"Top Hollywood and web3 talent representative United Talent Agency has signed Bobby Kim, co-creator of the popular NFT collection Adam Bomb Squad.  UTA, a","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/207667\/hollywood-agency-uta-signs-the-hundreds-adam-bomb-squad-co-creator-bobby-kim","publishDate":"2023-02-01T13:00:13","id":8522,"type":null,"title":"Hollywood agency UTA signs The Hundreds, Adam Bomb Squad co-creator Bobby Kim","category":["METAVERSE & NFT"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Top Hollywood and web3 talent representative United Talent Agency has signed Bobby Kim, co-creator of the popular NFT collection Adam Bomb Squad.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">UTA, a prominent dealmaker in the entertainment industry, will represent Hundreds — aka Bobby Hundreds — in “all areas,” including aiding the creator with film and television projects, the talent agency said. Hundreds is a well-known “designer, author, photographer, and Web3 creator,” UTA said in a statement.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Hundreds’s non-fungible token collection Adam Bomb Squad dropped during 2021’s bull run and sold 25,000 NFTs in under an hour. Additionally, Adam Bomb Squad NFTs have generated more than $35 million in trading volume, according to OpenSea data.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Although the NFT market has cooled significantly during the current bearish market, Hollywood continues to both pursue up-and-coming talent and develop collections based on world-famous intellectual property like the HBO series “<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/201081\/game-of-thrones-nft-collection-sells-out-in-7-hours-despite-weird-avatar-hands\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Game of Thrones<\/a>.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The streetwear designer Kim co-founded The Hundreds in 2003 with partner <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ben Shenassafar. The Hundreds has worked with well-known brands like Disney and the National Basketball Association, the company’s website said.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kim has authored a new book that is set for release entitled \"NFTs Are a Scam,\" UTA said.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","UTA's web3 endeavors are led by Lesley Silverman. The firm also represents Proof CEO Kevin Rose, and the NFT artist <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/173219\/uta-signs-on-nft-artist-diana-sinclair-the-hollywood-reporter\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Diana Sinclair.<\/a>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Hundreds co-founder Bobby Kim, aka Bobby Hundreds.<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2003","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bobby Hundreds","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$35 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Diana Sinclair","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"UTA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"National Basketball Association","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kevin Rose","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lesley Silverman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"HBO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Adam Bomb Squad","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ben Shenassafar","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"United Talent Agency","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bobby Kim","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Disney","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}