{"summary":"Bitwise has launched a Web3 ETF, which is listed on NYSE Arca.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/174739\/bitwise-launches-web3-focused-etf","publishDate":"2022-10-04T13:39:34","id":8525,"type":null,"title":"Bitwise launches web3-focused ETF","category":["BLOCKCHAIN"],"content":["Crypto index fund manager Bitwise Asset Management has launched the Bitwise Web3 exchange-traded fund (ETF), which includes exposure to five categories of web3 companies.&nbsp;","The Bitwise Web3 ETF (BWEB) is now <a href=\"https:\/\/www.nyse.com\/quote\/ARCX:BWEB\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">listed<\/a> and trading on NYSE Arca, a U.S. <a href=\"https:\/\/www.sec.gov\/Archives\/edgar\/data\/1928561\/000138713122010245\/bitwise-497_100422.htm\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) filing<\/a> dated Oct. 4 shows. NYSE Arca is an an all-electronic, U.S.-based exchange for listing and trading ETFs.","BWEB is based on the Bitwise Web3 Equities Index and has management fees equivalent to .85% of average daily net assets. The fund's inception is listed as October in a prospectus filed with the SEC.&nbsp;","\"With the Bitwise Web3 ETF, we’re excited to give investors the opportunity to capture one of the fastest-emerging themes in technology through a diverse mix of companies that we believe will lead the charge,\" Bitwise Chief Investment Officer Matt Hougan said in a statement.&nbsp;","BWEB includes exposure to web3 companies in five categories: infrastructure providers, finance, metaverse and digital worlds, \"web3-enabled creator economy\" and development and governance. The ETF offers exposure to up to 40 companies, with at least 85% of the portfolio \"directly linked to business activities associated with one or more key areas of growth in web3,\" Bitwise <a href=\"https:\/\/bwebetf.com\/?_ga=2.116868358.1622575466.1664900678-476886872.1664900678\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a> on its website.","Bitwise has more than $1.3 billion in assets under management. One of its flagship products is the Bitwise Crypto Industry Innovators ETF (BITQ), which is also listed on NYSE Arca with a net asset value (NAV) of $63 million <a href=\"https:\/\/www.marketwatch.com\/investing\/fund\/bitq\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">according to<\/a> MarketWatch.&nbsp;","&nbsp;","&nbsp;","&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Oct. 4","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Matt Hougan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$63 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Bitwise","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1.3 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":".85%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Bitwise Crypto Industry Innovators ETF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MarketWatch","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitwise Web3 Equities Index","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitwise Chief Investment","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"85%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"U.S. <a href=\"https:\/\/www.sec.gov\/Archives\/edgar\/data\/1928561\/000138713122010245\/bitwise-497_100422.htm\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitwise Asset Management","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"October","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bitwise Web3 ETF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NYSE Arca","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Kristin Majcher","The Block"]}