{"summary":"Crypto exchange Huobi seems to have confirmed that it is moving its headquarters from Seychelles to the Caribbean island of Dominica. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/182572\/huobi-tweet-headquarters-moving-caribbean","publishDate":"2022-11-03T07:26:57","id":8554,"type":null,"title":"Huobi tweet suggests its headquarters is moving to the Caribbean","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto exchange Huobi seems to have confirmed that it is moving its headquarters from Seychelles to the Caribbean island of Dominica.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Justin Sun, the founder of Tron who was <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/175867\/justin-sun-denies-being-real-buyer-of-huobi-stake-sale-exclusive\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">appointed<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> as an advisor on Huobi’s global board, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.ft.com\/content\/314de28a-5fc9-4865-ae2a-8ba52023c7b6\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">told<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> The Financial Times that the Caribbean “is a very crypto-friendly community” and that Dominica is “one of the frontrunners.”&nbsp;<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Huobi appeared to confirm that it will move to Dominica by <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/HuobiGlobal\/status\/1587627671470497792\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">retweeting<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Sun’s statements and the linked FT report with a single parasol emoji.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Furthermore, Tron partnered with Dominica’s government last month to develop a national blockchain infrastructure and issue a national fan token. Sun said in the interview that Dominica’s prime minister, Roosevelt Skerrit, is “a very tech-savvy person\" and claimed that \"he understands how crypto and the technology work.”<\/span>","\"Dominica is one of the many locations due to its crypto-friendly legislation,\" Huobi Global relationship manager Cynthia Lo told The Block. \"It's at an early stage of our strategic plan to re-establish Huobi as the leading global exchange after its China exit,\" she added.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Huobi is not the first crypto exchange to apparently move its headquarters to the Caribbean in search of a friendlier regulatory landscape. FTX <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/118663\/ftx-will-begin-to-move-key-operations-to-bahamas-as-part-of-hq-shift\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">moved<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> from Hong Kong to the Bahamas last year.<\/span>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Update: Added comments from Huobi Global.<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Roosevelt Skerrit","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Huobi Global","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Cynthia Lo","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Justin Sun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Seychelles","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Caribbean","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bahamas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Dominica","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Financial Times","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Huobi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"China","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["HTX","JUSTIN SUN"],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}