{"summary":"Marathon hasn&#x27;t previously owned the facilities where it operates, instead contracting with hosting providers. The UAE&#x27;s electricity prices are significantly lower than in the U.S. Marathon Digital Holdings, Inc. said it was forming the joint venture in a Securities and Exchange Commission filing on Friday, expanding out in Abu Dhabi.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/206208\/marathon-forms-abu-dhabi-bitcoin-mining-jv-initial-project-of-250mw","publishDate":"2023-01-27T10:46:47","id":8556,"type":null,"title":"Marathon forms Abu Dhabi bitcoin mining JV; initial project of 250MW","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto miner Marathon Digital is forming a joint venture with FS Innovation in Abu Dhabi to create and operate mining facilities. &nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> The company said in a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.sec.gov\/ix?doc=\/Archives\/edgar\/data\/1507605\/000149315223002672\/form8-k.htm\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filing<\/a> the initial project will consist of two digital asset mining sites comprising 250 MW. The new entity will be 80% owned by FSI and 20% owned by Marathon, and will cost an initial $406 million.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Marathon <\/span>hasn't previously owned the facilities where it operates, instead contracting with hosting providers. The mining industry has been struggling with high energy costs and the slumping price of bitcoin from a 2021 high. Many are highly indebted and some have filed for bankruptcy.&nbsp;","Electricity costs about $0.081 per kilowatt hour for households in the United Arab Emirates, compared to $0.175 in the U.S., according to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.globalpetrolprices.com\/United-Arab-Emirates\/electricity_prices\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Globalpetrolprices.com<\/a>.","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Marathon declined to comment on the new venture.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Marathon <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/amp\/post\/199480\/bitcoin-miner-marathon-closes-2022-with-103-7-million-cash-after-paying-down-debt\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">closed out<\/span><\/a> 2022 with $104 million cash after paying down all of its revolver borrowings. &nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Earlier this month, Marathon’s CEO Fred Thiel said the company made “significant progress” in increasing its hashrate while also moving to more sustainable sources. &nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We remain confident in our ability to scale Marathon into one of the largest and most energy efficient bitcoin mining operations globally,” Thiel said. “We have thousands of miners ready to be energized over the coming months, which we expect to more than triple our current production capacity to approximately 23 exahashes by mid-year.”<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"80%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$0.081","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$0.175","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$406 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Marathon","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fred Thiel","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"20%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Thiel","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"United Arab Emirates","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$104 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Crypto miner Marathon Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FS Innovation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Abu Dhabi","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"FSI","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["MINING COMPANIES"],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}