{"summary":"HashKey COO Livio Weng said that the exchange also plans to mint its own HSK utility token and may list it next year.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/260140\/hong-kong-crypto-exchange-hashkey-launches-app-targets-retail-users","publishDate":"2023-10-31T23:11:02","id":8557,"type":null,"title":"Hong Kong crypto exchange HashKey launches app, targets retail users","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">HashKey Exchange, an Asia-based cryptocurrency exchange with operations in Hong Kong, officially launched its app for retail trading today as it expands its presence in Hong Kong.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In an interview with The Block, Livio Weng, HashKey’s chief operating officer, said that HashKey has received approval from the Securities and Futures Commission to launch the app to serve both professional investors and retail users.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The app launch comes after the exchange started to <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/247368\/hashkey-crypto-retail-trading-hong-kong\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">offer retail trading services on its website on Aug. 28<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We’ve recorded large trading volume since we began to serve retail users,” Weng said, adding that the daily trading volume reached over $100 million on Oct. 30 alone, with the volume of trading pairs BTC-USD, ETH-USD, BTC-HKD and ETH-HKD amounting to over $2.7 million.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The app is particularly essential for running a retail trading platform, according to Weng. “Generally speaking, about 85% of users trade via apps, according to our research,” he said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The SFC has appeared to take a more stringent approach when overseeing crypto exchanges following the <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/252265\/hong-kong-blocks-access-to-jpexs-website-and-app-amid-probes\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">alleged fraud scandal of the JPEX crypto exchange<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. Earlier this month, the SFC said that it had <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/258733\/hong-kong-regulator-updates-policy-for-virtual-asset-activities\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">updated its regulatory framework<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> with two additional investor protection measures.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Weng said that the SFC has started to check its app since July with the company submitting several rounds of supplementary materials for the review.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">HashKey currently <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/hashkey-pro.zendesk.com\/hc\/en-gb\/articles\/22970994704537-Platform-Requirements-List-of-Country-and-Regional-Banks-Accepted-for-Banking-Transfer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">allows users from 17 jurisdictions<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> — including Hong Kong, Singapore, Malaysia, Israel, the U.K. and the U.S. — to link their bank cards to deposit via fiat currency with the exchange. “We support deposits made in Hong Kong dollars and U.S. dollars,” Weng said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">HashKey also plans to mint its own ERC-20 utility token dubbed HSK, Weng said.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The HSK token is expected to be used as a tool that incentivizes contributors across HashKey's ecosystem to “fuel the growth of the entire ecosystem,” the exchange’s website said. HashKey plans to mint a total of 1 billion HSK tokens with 65% of them dedicated to ecosystem growth, 30% to staff incentives and 5% to the company’s insurance vault, according to its <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.hashkey.com\/assets\/HSKWhitepaper.08ca5c9d.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">whitepaper<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Weng added that the exchange also plans to list HSK but that may not take place until the middle of next year.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">HashKey is also exploring realistic practices for real-world asset tokenization (RWA) as discussions surrounding such a new asset class have gained traction lately, according to Weng.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“RWA is becoming an important strength for regulated exchanges,” Weng said. “If you want to pursue ‘effective RWA,’ then you have to do it through licensed exchanges.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Weng explained that HashKey is licensed to issue and trade security tokens in Hong Kong and the company is “exploring two important RWA cases that may bring huge impact to the market.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We’re in talks with the SFC [for RWA cases] right now,” Weng said, adding that the negotiations with the regulator have reached “the latter half phase.”<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$100 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Malaysia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.K.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"20","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Asia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"30%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Israel","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"HSK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Livio Weng","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"HashKey","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securities and Futures Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SFC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Aug. 28","content":"DATE"},{"type":"65%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$2.7 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"85%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"USD","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Oct. 30","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Weng","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"HashKey Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["ASIAN REGULATION","CRYPTO"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}