{"summary":"In part two of this two-part macro special of The Scoop, Nouriel Roubini discusses some alternative assets that could gain prominence in the event of a global financial meltdown, and explains why he prefers gold over bitcoin in such a situation.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/184068\/nouriel-roubini-outlines-the-10-forces-that-can-cripple-the-economy-part-2","publishDate":"2022-11-18T05:00:33","id":856,"type":null,"title":"Nouriel Roubini outlines the 10 forces that can cripple the economy: part 2","category":["MACRO"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 114<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 4 of The Scoop was recorded live with <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro<\/strong>&nbsp;and<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Roubini Macro Associates Chairman and CEO Nouriel Roubini.<\/strong><\/i><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests can be sent to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"9eeef1fafdffedeadeeaf6fbfcf2f1fdf5fdece7eeeaf1b0fdf1f3\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i><\/span>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK6071844565\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Part one of this two-part special on Nouriel Roubini’s new book, <\/span><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Megathreats<\/span><\/i><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, examines how the economy is facing a combination of interconnected phenomena that Roubini believes will result in a severe economic crisis.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Roubini discusses some alternative assets that could gain prominence in the event of a global financial meltdown and explains why he prefers gold over bitcoin in such a situation, among other topics in his book <em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Megathreats: Ten Dangerous Trends That Imperil Our Future, And How to Survive Them<\/em>.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">According to Roubini, the \"weaponization\" of the U.S. dollar is making it less attractive as a reserve currency:<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We have weaponized the dollar as a tool of national security and foreign policy… If I owe you a billion it is my problem; if I owe you a trillion it is your problem because we could default on those treasuries eventually if there is a conflict…”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Similar to USD, Roubini believes other common reserve currencies such as the euro, yen, pound, and Swiss franc can be similarly weaponized, leaving gold as the only widely held reserve currency that remains a viable option:<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“What's the only other asset that is a liquid asset that can be a reserve currency? … What's the only one that cannot be seized if there are sanctions? It’s gold — as long as you keep it in your own vault.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Although ardent bitcoin proponents claim BTC has similar properties, Roubini is dismissive of the largest cryptocurrency’s potential to be used legitimately in global commerce.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies — we know they are not currencies,” Roubini says, “They are not a unit of account, nobody's pricing anything in Bitcoin, they're not scalable means of payment.”&nbsp;<\/span>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">During this episode Chaparro and Roubini also discuss:<\/span><\/i>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors <a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Tron, <\/em><\/a><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.ledn.io\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ledn<\/a><\/em><\/b><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nAbout Tron<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/b><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TRON is dedicated to accelerating the decentralization of the internet via blockchain technology and decentralized applications (dApps). Founded in September 2017 by <a href=\"https:\/\/www.hejustinsun.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">H.E. Justin Sun<\/a>, the TRON network has continued to deliver impressive achievements since MainNet launch in May 2018. July 2018 also marked the ecosystem integration of <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bittorrent.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BitTorrent<\/a>, a pioneer in decentralized web3 services boasting over 100 million monthly active users. The TRON network completed full decentralization in December 2021 and is now a community-governed DAO. | <a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/hackathon\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TRONDAO<\/a> | <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/trondao\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Twitter<\/a> | <a href=\"https:\/\/discord.gg\/tron\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Discord<\/a> |<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Ledn<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ledn was founded on the unshakeable conviction that digital assets have the power to democratize access to the global economy. We help you to experience the real life benefits of your Bitcoin without having to sell it. Start a savings account, take out a loan, or double your Bitcoin. For more information visit <a href=\"https:\/\/www.ledn.io\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ledn.io<\/a><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"BitTorrent","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Roubini","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"July 2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Roubini","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"December 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Roubini Macro Associates","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Nouriel Roubini","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Roubini","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ledn<\/a><\/em><\/b><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nAbout Tron<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/b><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TRON","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"May 2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ledn<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ledn","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"euro","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"September 2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"H.E. Justin Sun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}