{"summary":"Galaxy Digital&#x27;s Mike Novogratz joined The Scoop&#x27;s Frank Chaparro and discussed the significance of Paul Tudor Jones&#x27; letter outlining his case for owning bitcoin as a hedge against central bank money printing. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/64586\/it-opens-up-a-new-universe-mike-novogratz-on-the-significance-of-paul-tudor-jones-bullish-bitcoin-take","publishDate":"2020-05-08T17:11:18","id":858,"type":null,"title":"&#x27;It opens up a new universe&#x27;: Mike Novogratz on the significance of Paul Tudor Jones&#x27; bullish bitcoin take","category":["THE BLOCK"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 17 of Season 2 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with Frank Chaparro along with Galaxy Digital CEO Mike Novogratz.<\/i>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/a>, or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to&nbsp;<a target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"3d4d52595e5c4e497d4955585f51525e565e4f444d4952135e5250\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/span><\/a>.<\/em>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode of The Scoop is brought to you by&nbsp;<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitstamp<\/strong>,&nbsp;the original global cryptocurrency exchange. Since 2011, Bitstamp has been a cornerstone of the industry, earning the trust of over four million individuals and top financial institutions looking for a reliable trading venue. Whether you’re trading on our web platform, mobile app or industry-leading APIs, Bitstamp gives you the professional-grade tools you need to execute your strategy.&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/bitstamp.net\/app?r=pro%E2%80%93&amp;utm_source=Website&amp;utm_medium=podcast&amp;utm_campaign=theblock&amp;utm_content=ctaapp\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Download the Bitstamp app<\/b><\/a>&nbsp;or visit&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.bitstamp.net\/pro\/?utm_source=Website&amp;utm_medium=podcast&amp;utm_campaign=theblock&amp;utm_content=ctaweb\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitstamp.net\/Pro<\/b><\/a>&nbsp;to learn more and start trading today!<\/em>","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK4384358785\" width=\"100%\" height=\"200\" frameborder=\"0\" scrolling=\"no\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Unless you were hiding under a rock on Thursday, you would have seen the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/64398\/paul-tudor-jones-says-he-is-buying-bitcoin-as-a-hedge-against-central-bank-money-printing\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">letter by macro investor Paul Tudor Jones<\/a> that outlines his case for owning bitcoin as a hedge against central bank money printing.&nbsp;","In the letter – titled The Great Monetary Inflation – Jones dropped the bombshell update that Tudor Investment Corp could allocate a percentage of its assets to bitcoin futures.&nbsp;Although Jones doesn't subscribe to owning bitcoin \"in isolation\" or view himself as a \"crypto nut,\" the coin community propelled into euphoria at the sight of one of the most respected fund managers giving the burgeoning asset a stamp of approval.&nbsp;","Galaxy Digital's Mike Novogratz – having once sat in a similar seat to Jones as a macro investor – joined The Scoop's Frank Chaparro and discussed the significance of Jones' letter.&nbsp;This latest episode also digs into:","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Jones","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Galaxy Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2011","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tudor Investment Corp","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bitstamp","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mike Novogratz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Paul Tudor Jones","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN"],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}