{"summary":"As Paxos continues to revamp its platform, today it announced another feature that will allow users to purchase PAX and transfer it between wallets","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/25298\/paxos-deploys-new-feature-to-allow-fast-creation-transfer-of-pax-between-wallets","publishDate":"2019-05-30T11:01:24","id":8585,"type":null,"title":"Paxos deploys new feature to allow fast creation, transfer of PAX between wallets","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">As Paxos continues to revamp its platform, today it announced another feature that will allow users to purchase PAX and transfer it between wallets faster. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The new feature, dubbed Auto-Transfers, is Paxos’ latest effort to make digital asset transactions similar to those of physical assets on traditional exchanges, Paxos product manager Dave Wells told The Block. Auto-Transfers creates and sends PAX across different exchanges with very little time lag, which allows them to take advantage of market rallies. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We’re closing the barriers between physical and digital assets. The faster and easier you can <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">get your PAX, the faster you can transact with your assets,” Wells said<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A few weeks ago, Paxos announced an overhaul of its exchange platform <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/2019\/05\/13\/stablecoin-pax-can-now-be-redeemed-instantly-on-an-integrated-platform-with-exchange-itbit\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">to support instant redemption of PAX to U.S. dollars<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. The move was an attempt to boost PAX’s presence in the stablecoin market. Now, the speedy creation and transfer of PAX between wallets may help further advance that endeavor by making PAX “the fastest way to get from USD to crypto assets,” according to Wells. <\/span>","\"By increasing the speed at which you can create, redeem and use PAX, we’re also providing another layer of confidence to our customers as it improves their experience and they can ensure their funds are always available and accessible,\" said Wells.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Wells","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Wells","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Paxos","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"USD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dave Wells","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"PAX","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Celia Wan","The Block"]}