{"summary":"Crypto-friendly Rep. McHenry, R-N.C., is reportedly taking over as Speaker of the House on a temporary basis following a dramatic oust.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/254607\/crypto-friendly-rep-patrick-mchenry-becomes-speaker-pro-temp-following-house-speaker-oust","publishDate":"2023-10-03T17:21:02","id":8596,"type":null,"title":"Crypto-friendly Rep. Patrick McHenry becomes speaker pro temp following House speaker oust","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto-friendly Rep. Patrick T. McHenry, R-N.C., is reportedly taking over as Speaker of the House on a temporary basis following the dramatic ouster of Rep. Kevin McCarthy, R-Calif.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The House voted on Tuesday to remove McCarthy from his leadership role following a power struggle between McCarthy and far-right lawmakers, including Rep. Matt Gaetz, R-Fla.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">McHenry had sided with McCarthy in that fight, <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/PatrickMcHenry\/status\/1708917674309238988\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">posting<\/span><\/a> on X a day before the vote that “wasting time on a motion to vacate is a disservice to the American people.”&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">McHenry is chair of the House Financial Services Committee, which advanced two bills over the summer to regulate crypto and one more specific to stablecoins. The congressman also just threatened a subpoena against Securities and Exchange Commission Chair Gary Gensler last week, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253305\/gensler-takes-heat-from-lawmakers-over-his-approach-to-regulating-crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">accusing<\/span><\/a> him of<\/span><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> not being transparent to Congress regarding his interactions with bankrupt crypto exchange FTX and its former CEO Sam Bankman-Fried.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Either we find a path forward where the SEC recognizes Congress as a co-equal branch of government and is responsive to our oversight duties, or my only option is to issue a subpoena,” McHenry said at a Sept. 27 hearing.&nbsp;<\/span>","House Majority Whip Rep. Tom Emmer, R-Minn., has seemingly been floated as a possible House Speaker and Gaetz reportedly said he thinks Emmer would \"make a great speaker.\" Emmer too has been friendly toward crypto and critical of the SEC.&nbsp;","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This marks the first time in history that the House Speaker position has been vacant, according to reports.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">House rules don’t specifically lay out how long the speaker pro tempore can remain in power before a new vote is conducted for a permanent speaker, according to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.nbcnews.com\/politics\/congress\/kevin-mccarthy-ousted-speaker-house-next-steps-rcna118561\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">NBC<\/span><\/a>.<\/span>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Updated at 6 p.m. ET to include details on Rep. Emmer<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"6 p.m.","content":"TIME"},{"type":"Emmer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kevin McCarthy","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sept. 27","content":"DATE"},{"type":"House Speaker","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gaetz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gary Gensler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"House Financial Services Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"McHenry","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fla.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Tom Emmer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NBC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Congress","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"McCarthy","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"House","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Patrick T. McHenry","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Minn.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Calif.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"summer","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Matt Gaetz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"McHenry","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}