{"summary":"Singapore-based crypto lender Hodlnaut held assets worth $12.9 million (18.1 million Singapore Dollar) on FTX on October 25.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/185218\/embattled-crypto-lender-hodlnaut-held-13-million-on-ftx-before-withdrawal-freeze","publishDate":"2022-11-10T07:32:01","id":8628,"type":null,"title":"Embattled crypto lender Hodlnaut held $13 million on FTX before withdrawal freeze","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["Troubled Singapore-based crypto lender Hodlnaut<span class=\"vLqKYe\" data-mid=\"\/m\/02f32g\" data-name=\"Singapore Dollar\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> held assets worth $13.1 million (S$<span class=\"DFlfde eNFL1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">18.4 million) <\/span><\/span><span class=\"vLqKYe\" data-mid=\"\/m\/02f32g\" data-name=\"Singapore Dollar\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">as of October 25 on the collapsed cryptocurrency exchange FTX. It is unclear whether Hodlnaut’s managers moved funds away from FTX before operations were halted.<\/span>","The lender under judicial protection also held assets on other centralized exchanges such as Deribit, Binance, OKX and Tokenize for a total of $18.3 million (S$25.7 million), according to court documents dated October 25. Its share on FTX was more than 70% of its holding on centralized exchanges.&nbsp;","We have reached out to Hodlnaut and will update this article should we hear back.","In August, Hodlnaut halted withdrawals amid a liquidity crisis. It later <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/164756\/hodlnaut-financial-shortfall-193-million-crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">emerged<\/a> that it had a nearly $200 million financial shortfall in a court affidavit filed.&nbsp;","In particular, the document shows that Hodlnaut parked some $317 million in UST, the failed stablecoin, in the Anchor Protocol on Terra as a way to pass high yields through to its customers. In May, Terra’s stablecoin UST <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/145871\/ust-stablecoin-falls-to-record-low-amid-continued-market-tumult\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">sharply de-pegged<\/a> from the dollar, inflicting losses of $189.7 million on Hodlnaut, per the affidavit.&nbsp;","On Tuesday, FTX halted withdrawals amid a liquidity crisis. That day, FTX said that it had agreed to an acquisition by rival Binance. Yesterday, that acquisition <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/184636\/binance-backs-out-of-ftx-acquisition-deal\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">fell through<\/a> after Binance reviewed FTX's financials.","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"70%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$18.3 million (S$25.7 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$317 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"October 25","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Deribit","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$189.7 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Terra","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$200 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"UST","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$13.1 million (S$<span class=\"DFlfde eNFL1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">18.4 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Tom Matsuda","Yogita Khatri","The Block"]}