{"summary":"Pan-African exchange Yellow Card Financial raised $40 million in its latest fundraising round.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/171019\/yellow-card-crypto-exchange-raises-40-million-in-series-b-round","publishDate":"2022-09-19T10:27:53","id":8648,"type":null,"title":"Yellow Card crypto exchange raises $40 million in Series B round","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["Pan-African cryptocurrency exchange Yellow Card Financial raised $40 million in its Series B funding round, the company <a href=\"https:\/\/www.prnewswire.com\/news-releases\/pan-african-crypto-exchange-yellow-card-secures-40m-in-series-b-funding-round-301626945.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/span><\/a> on Monday.","“This fundraise in this market not only showcases the resilience of our team but also reiterates the appetite and necessity for cryptocurrency in&nbsp;Africa,\" Yellow Card CEO and co-founder Chris Maurice said in a statement.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","Polychain Capital led the fundraising round, which comes after Yellow Card <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/news+\/122302\/yellow-cards-ceo-is-preparing-the-crypto-exchange-for-pan-african-expansion\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">raised<\/span><\/a> $15 million in a Series A round last year. Yellow Card launched in Nigeria in 2019 and operates in 16 countries.&nbsp;","Participants in the latest fundraising round included Valar Ventures, Third Prime Ventures and Sozo Ventures, among others.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$40 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Third Prime Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chris Maurice","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Yellow Card Financial","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$15 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Nigeria","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sozo Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Africa","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Yellow Card","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Valar Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["SERIES B"],"authors":["Stephanie Murray","The Block"]}