{"summary":"A digital euro will protect people from data collection for commercial purposes, Christine Lagarde said on Wednesday at a conference in Frankfurt.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/173303\/digital-euro-would-not-be-used-for-commercial-purposes-ecb-lagarde","publishDate":"2022-09-28T04:43:35","id":8657,"type":null,"title":"A digital euro would not be used for commercial purposes, ECB&#x27;s Lagarde says","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A digital euro issued by the European Central Bank (ECB) “will not be used for commercial purposes,” according to Christine Lagarde, the central bank’s president.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The ECB provides “the guarantee that those payments will not be exploited for commercial purposes,\" Lagarde said on Wednesday at a conference in Frankfurt when talking about the possibilities of a central bank digital currency (CBDC)&nbsp;. \"<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This is not the business of a central bank.\"<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The ECB president referred back to a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.ecb.europa.eu\/press\/pr\/date\/2021\/html\/ecb.pr210113~ec9929f446.en.html\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">survey<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> from January 2021, which was rolled out ahead of launching its digital euro investigation, that privacy ranked at the top of European respondents' list of features expected from a digital currency.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Lagarde said that a digital euro is essentially a bank note “with a little less anonymity,” but she promised that — unlike companies that sell data collected through payments — a European CBDC would protect citizens.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Any U.S. CBDC would also have a focus on privacy, if adopted, Jerome Powell, the Federal Reserve chairman, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/173111\/the-fed-has-not-decided-to-proceed-with-a-digital-dollar-says-powell\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on Tuesday.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Privacy-protection is one of the four CBDC characteristics Powell named, alongside intermediated, identity-verified and interoperable. However, the U.S. central bank has “not decided to proceed” with a CBDC for now.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The ECB’s digital euro prototype, on the other hand, is in the works. The central bank <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/170734\/amazon-among-five-companies-to-develop-digital-euro-prototype-for-the-ecb\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> the five partner companies that will help build the trial payment system earlier this month. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">T<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">he evaluation and results of the project are expected in March 2023.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Federal Reserve","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Lagarde","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"ECB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Christine Lagarde","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"January 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"European Central Bank (ECB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Powell","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"March 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Frankfurt","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Jerome Powell","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["ECB","FEDERAL RESERVE"],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}