{"summary":"Top Hollywood talent agency adds Mexican contemporary artist Ilse Valfré to its roster of web3 creators which already includes Mack Flavelle and Bright Moments.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/188777\/wme-talent-agency-signs-valfre-artist-part-of-instagrams-nft-push-exclusive","publishDate":"2022-11-21T12:31:15","id":8660,"type":null,"title":"WME talent agency signs Valfré, artist part of Instagram’s NFT push: Exclusive","category":["NFTS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Powerhouse Hollywood talent agency WME is once again showing its faith in web3’s future potential by adding contemporary artist Ilse Valfré to its roster, The Block learned exclusively.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Valfré, who has 897,000 <a href=\"https:\/\/www.instagram.com\/valfre\/?hl=en\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Instagram followers<\/a>, was recently selected to participate in the social media company’s trial program which allows creators to showcase, mint and sell non-fungible tokens on the platform. Her compositions often feature \"eccentric female characters\" drawn with a blend of retro and contemporary sensibilities. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Despite a dramatic drop in cryptocurrency prices and NFT sales volumes —by dollar value— in recent months, the talent agency, which represents stars like <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Dwayne “The Rock” Johnson, Charlize Theron<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> and <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Alicia Keys<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, has clearly demonstrated its interest in representing top web3 creators. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">WME's portfolio of web3 artists and collections includes <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bright Moments, Non-fungible Heroes and <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Boss Beauties. It<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> also recently signed <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CryptoKitties and Dapper Labs cofounder Mack Flavelle<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, as <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/177662\/dapper-labs-cryptokitties-co-founder-signs-with-hollywood-agency-wme-exclusive\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">previously reported<\/a> by The Block.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Cyber Gal\" by Ilse Valfré<\/em>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Meta-owned Instagram’s announcement <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/182451\/instagram-to-support-polygon-powered-nft-marketplace\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">earlier this month<\/a> that it will host a digital collectible (NFT) marketplace could end up becoming a major milestone in bringing the world of crypto-asset ownership to a larger consumer base. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The social media giant's move has coincided <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/183292\/with-twitter-and-opensea-deal-adrift-magic-eden-emerges-as-key-nft-partner\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">with efforts<\/a> by Twitter and Reddit to also bring NFTs to mainstream consumers. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The trial program, which will <a href=\"https:\/\/about.fb.com\/news\/2022\/05\/introducing-digital-collectibles-to-showcase-nfts-instagram\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">initially utilize<\/a> the Polygon blockchain, kicks off with a small set of U.S.-based creators, including Valfré. Instagram also said it <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">will not charge fees on NFT sales until 2024.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Growing up in the small border town of Playas De Tijuana, located near the Mexican-U.S. border below San Diego, Valfré is no stranger to NFTs. She dropped a <a href=\"https:\/\/opensea.io\/collection\/valfrelandia\/activity?search[eventTypes][0]=AUCTION_CREATED\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">600-piece collection<\/a> of hand-drawn character types in April called <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Valfrélandia.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Valfré also has an expansive commercial operation that includes the sale of stationary, home decor and apparel which feature her art.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Tijuana","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Reddit","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"San Diego","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Mack Flavelle","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ilse Valfré","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Dapper Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alicia Keys","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Johnson","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Valfré","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Valfrélandia","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["NFT ARTISTS"],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}