{"summary":"Trump-era Comptroller of the Currency Joseph Otting joined Blockchain.com&#x27;s board of directors.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/186956\/former-comptroller-otting-joins-blockchain-com-board","publishDate":"2022-11-16T07:00:04","id":8708,"type":null,"title":"Former Comptroller Otting joins Blockchain.com board","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Blockchain.com added former Comptroller of the Currency Joseph Otting to its board of directors.","Otting oversaw all federally chartered banks during his time as comptroller.","Blockchain.com is adding a banking expert to its board of directors, Joseph Otting, the former U.S. Comptroller of the Currency, the company said in a blog post.","“I’m honored to join the board of <span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Blockchain.com<\/span> and help it navigate the regulatory landscape as one of the most established firms in its space,” Otting said in a statement.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","Otting served as comptroller during the Trump administration, from 2017 to 2020. The comptroller oversees federally chartered banks, savings associations and federal branches of foreign banks that operate in the United States.","Otting previously worked in the banking industry, serving as president of CIT Bank and OneWest Bank. Otting has also held roles at U.S. Bancorp, Union Bank of California and Bank of America.<span class=\"Apple-converted-space\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","The company’s board of directors includes Jim Messina, the Obama-era White House deputy chief of staff, and former American Airlines CEO Tom Horton.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"American Airlines","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Joseph Otting","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bank of America","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Obama","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"White House","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. Bancorp, Union Bank of California","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tom Horton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"OneWest Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Trump","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"CIT Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Otting","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"United States","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Jim Messina","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Stephanie Murray","The Block"]}