{"summary":"NFT marketplace Rarible now functions as an aggregator.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/177770\/rarible-introduces-nft-aggregator-to-help-shoppers-bargain-hunt","publishDate":"2022-10-17T17:26:51","id":8713,"type":null,"title":"Rarible introduces NFT aggregator to help shoppers bargain hunt","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">NFT marketplace Rarible has introduced a non-fungible token (NFT) aggregator that enables shoppers to browse listings across several marketplaces and compare prices.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The aggregator, now <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/rarible.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">public<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on Rarible’s homepage, displays a search bar that allows users to browse NFTs based on filters such as price, trending projects, recently-listed NFTs and auctions about to end.&nbsp;<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Rarible’s co-founders Alexei Falin and Alex Salnikov confirmed Rarible’s move into aggregation to The Block during the Ethereum Foundation’s recent Devcon conference in Bogotá, Colombia.<\/span>","\"It's pretty much like Google for NFTs,\" <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Falin told The Block, adding that the aggregator also helps users find the best prices across marketplaces and blockchains.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> The company also has made several social media posts about an upcoming announcement this Thursday. \"Rarible’s second chapter. Coming next week,” according to a post on Rarible’s Twitter account on Oct. 13.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Rarible’s aggregator pulls in data about NFTs across several marketplaces. For example, the tool shows an <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/rarible.com\/token\/0xed5af388653567af2f388e6224dc7c4b3241c544:7582?tab=overview\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Azuki<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> NFT listed on OpenSea, LooksRare and x2y2 at a price of 11.99 ETH on each platform. Rarible does not charge any extra buying and selling fees through its platform for these transactions.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Rarible’s aggregator also includes filters to narrow down NFT projects based on several criteria. Users can browse NFTs by blockchains including Ethereum, Solana, Tezos, Flow and Polygon, as well as the Layer-2 scaling solution Immutable X. The tool features filters to search NFTs based on edition type and buying method (auction, open to offers or immediate purchase).<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">NFT platforms have been adding aggregation tools this year as they compete to have the lowest fees. Uniswap labs acquired the NFT marketplace aggregator <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/153366\/uniswap-labs-acquires-nft-marketplace-genie\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Genie<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in June, and OpenSea acquired NFT aggregator service <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/143297\/opensea-acquires-nft-aggregator-gem\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Gem<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in April.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Falin and Salnikov founded Rarible in 2019. The startup announced in June 2021 that it had <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.crunchbase.com\/funding_round\/rarible-series-a--c91673e5\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">closed<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> a $14.2 million Series A funding round led by Venrock and CoinFund. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Rarible expanded its offerings for gaming NFTs in September through a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/169458\/nft-marketplace-rarible-partners-with-immutable-to-sell-gaming-nfts\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">partnership<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> with Immutable X, adding the ability to buy and sell NFTs related to titles such as Gods Unchained, Guild of Guardians and Illuvium.&nbsp;<\/span>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Additional reporting by Callan Quinn.&nbsp;<\/span><\/i>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Alexei Falin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bogotá","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Rarible","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Venrock","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Callan Quinn","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Salnikov","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"June 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$14.2 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Ethereum Foundation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Colombia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Azuki<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Guild of Guardians","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"June","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Oct. 13","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alex Salnikov","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Rarible","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Devcon","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["RARIBLE"],"authors":["Kristin Majcher","The Block"]}