{"summary":"FTX Europe is the latest Bankman-Fried firm to face scrutiny as its recently acquired European investment firm license is set to be suspended.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/185865\/ftx-european-investment-license-facing-suspension-cyprus","publishDate":"2022-11-11T07:33:45","id":8752,"type":null,"title":"FTX faces having European investment license suspended: Bloomberg","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["FTX's European Union license in Cyprus could be suspended in yet another blow to Sam Bankman-Fried's crypto exchange, according to Bloomberg.&nbsp;","FTX Europe looks set to have its European Union investment firm license suspended as soon as today, Bloomberg <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2022-11-11\/ftx-ftt-to-have-eu-operating-license-revoked-by-cyprus-regulator-cysec\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a>, citing people familiar with the matter. The exchange <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/170923\/crypto-exchange-ftx-obtains-european-investment-firm-license\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">received<\/a> the license — which enables it to operate across Europe — a little under two months ago.&nbsp;","Bankman-Fried's exchange was granted the license by the Cyprus Securities and Exchange Commission. The license requires FTX Europe to meet standards outlined in the European Union's MiFID II directive. The standards include the segregation and protection of client funds, business transparency and capital adequacy.","FTX first came under scrutiny last week when a balance sheet relating to its sister trading shop Alameda Research was leaked. The balance sheet showed significant liabilities and holdings of FTT, FTX's exchange token.&nbsp;","Pressure from Binance's threatened sales of FTT put increasing pressure on FTX and its trading arm. By Tuesday, Binance had agreed to acquire the struggling exchange — but the deal was off on Wednesday after a review of FTX's finances.&nbsp;","In the days since rumors over the firm's potential insolvency have grown to a fervor. The exchange is <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/185461\/ftxs-bankman-fried-seeks-more-than-9-billion-for-exchange-rescue-reuters\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">seeking<\/a> to raise more than $9 billion to plug a financial shortfall, Reuters reported on Thursday.","Zane Tackett, head of institutional sales at FTX, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/185776\/ftxs-head-of-institutional-sales-resigns-says-team-were-completely-in-the-dark-about-insolvency\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">resigned<\/a> on Nov. 8 and sent a letter to clients stating that his team was \"completely in the dark\" about the firm's potential insolvency over the course of this week.&nbsp;","FTX had no comment to add when contacted by The Block.","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Updated to add FTX's response to a request for comment from The Block.&nbsp;<\/em>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"European Union","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Cyprus Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cyprus","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Nov. 8","content":"DATE"},{"type":"European Union","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Reuters","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Zane Tackett","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$9 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Binance","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["EUROZONE REGULATION","FTX","SAM BANKMAN-FRIED"],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}