{"summary":"You tuned in on YouTube, trolled Twitter and loved the launch party. Now, the Ethereum Foundation is offering you a Proof of Attendance Protocol to prove you went all-in on The Merge.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/170564\/i-attended-the-merge-and-all-i-got-was-this-lousy-poap","publishDate":"2022-09-15T15:51:02","id":876,"type":null,"title":"I attended The Merge and all I got was this lousy POAP","category":["ETHEREUM"],"content":["You tuned in on YouTube, trolled Twitter and loved the launch party. Now, you can commemorate the fact that you went all-in on The Merge with a Proof of Attendance Protocol.","For a mere $10, you can be the proud owner of a POAP, NFTs that are often used as collectables or memorabilia given at in-person events, or in this case, one of the most significant virtual worldwide events and upgrades in Ethereum’s history.&nbsp;","The POAPs were the brainchild of ETHStaker, a Reddit community formed around Ethereum proof of stake discussion.","More than 6,000 POAPs have been purchased, according to The Block Research analyst Simon Cousaert, who built a Dune Analytics <a href=\"https:\/\/dune.com\/SimonC\/ethereum-merge-poap-buys\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">dashboard<\/a> to track activity.","","The POAP collection process details were livestreamed during the Merge viewing party in the U.S. overnight hours. Purchase activity initially spiked when The Merge occurred and has leveled off significantly since then.","Should you be itching to get your own POAP, they can be had for a donation of $10 dollars minimum in USDC, RAI, DAI, ETH, or MATIC to the Ethereum Name Service (ENS) address “Stateful.eth.” Ethereum mainnet, Polygon, Arbitrum and Optimism are all supported networks for the POAP purchase. The funds collected from the POAP will be donated to core developers at Protocol Guild which was decided by EthStaker, The Daily Gwei, and Bankless.","The POAP purchase window will officially close on Sept. 18, 00:00 UTC.","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Correction: The story was corrected throughout to reflect the POAPs are being issued by ETHStaker, not the Ethereum Foundation.<\/em>&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"POAP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Reddit","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Polygon","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$10","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Sept. 18","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$10 dollars","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Protocol Guild","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ethereum Foundation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bankless","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Simon Cousaert","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Dune Analytics","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ethereum Name Service","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"USDC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Proof of Attendance Protocol","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["ETHEREUM"],"authors":["Mike Truppa","The Block"]}