{"summary":"Circle has started sharing detailed disclosures about its USDC reserve assets on a monthly basis.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/157709\/circle-discloses-55-7-billion-worth-of-cash-treasury-reserves","publishDate":"2022-07-14T19:19:32","id":8789,"type":null,"title":"Circle discloses $55.7 billion worth of cash, Treasury reserves","category":["STABLECOINS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Circle issued its first monthly <a href=\"https:\/\/6778953.fs1.hubspotusercontent-na1.net\/hubfs\/6778953\/USDC%20Reserves%20Reports\/USDC%20Reserve%20Breakdown_June.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">report<\/a> closely detailing reserves for its US-dollar backed stablecoin, showing $55.7 billion in cash and three-month US Treasury securities at the end of June.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The fintech company, best known for its dollar-pegged stablecoin, USDC, disclosed in the unaudited report that it is holding $13.58 billion in cash at regulated US banks. The banks include: Bank of New York Mellon, Citizens Trust Bank, Customers Bank, New York Community Bank, Signature Bank, Silicon Valley Bank, Silvergate Bank and US Bancorp.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Circle, which has described USDC as being fully backed, reported 55.57 billion USDC in circulation as of June 30. The company also <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/152448\/circle-announces-new-euro-backed-stablecoin\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">launched<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> a euro-backed stablecoin called EUROC in June. These securities have a weighted average maturity of 43.9 days.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In addition, Circle disclosed holding $42.12 billion in three-month Treasury securities. The list shows 19 securities maturing between July 5 and September 29 of this year.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“The USDC reserve is held solely in cash and three-month US Treasuries, held in segregated accounts for the benefit of USDC holders, and is entirely separate from Circle’s operations,” the blog post said.&nbsp; The company added that it has received third-party attestations on a monthly basis since introducing USDC in 2018.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The disclosure is the latest in a series of Circle <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.circle.com\/blog\/how-to-be-stable-usdc-transparency-and-trust\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">blog posts<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> entitled “How To Be Stable,” which Circle co-founder and CEO <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/145701\/circle-ceo-jeremy-allaire-breaks-down-mystery-of-stablecoin-yield\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Jeremy Allaire<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> highlighted in a July 2 Twitter thread <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/155654\/circle-denies-rumors-usdc-stablecoin-is-troubled-amid-market-downturn\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">denying rumors<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> circulating on social media that claimed USDC was facing collapse.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In a new <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/jerallaire\/status\/1547608325478498307\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">thread<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> posted today, Allaire said the disclosure about USDC reserves was part of the company’s ongoing efforts to focus on transparency.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“As part of our commitment to increasing transparency and disclosure around USDC, today we're publishing our first monthly breakdown of the USDC reserve assets, by each and every Treasury bond and list of cash reserve custodians,” Allaire wrote.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We are not done, we are continuing to do more to provide even greater transparency, including seeking permission from our banking partners to disclose how much cash at each institution, as well as moving towards daily public reporting on reserve assets. We will get there,” Allaire added.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Paxos <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/paxos.com\/2022\/07\/08\/paxos-leads-digital-asset-industry-by-becoming-first-issuer-to-disclose-full-monthly-reserve-holdings-backing-usdp-and-busd-regulated-stablecoins\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced on July 8<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that it would start providing detailed disclosures for the reserves backing its Pax Dollar (USDP) and Binance USD (BUSD) stablecoins on a monthly basis. It offers the latter through a partnership with Binance.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Silvergate Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York Community Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$13.58 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Bank of New York Mellon","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Citizens Trust Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance USD","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$42.12 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Allaire","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$55.7 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"US Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jeremy Allaire","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"July 2 Twitter","content":"DATE"},{"type":"June 30","content":"DATE"},{"type":"July 8","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"July 5","content":"DATE"},{"type":"today","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Signature Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"US Bancorp.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"EUROC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"June","content":"DATE"},{"type":"USDC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Circle","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"September 29 of this year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Customers Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Silicon Valley Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["USDC"],"authors":["Kristin Majcher","The Block"]}