{"summary":"CME Group has launched euro-denominated bitcoin and ether futures denominated.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/166325\/derivatives-marketplace-cme-goes-live-with-euro-denominated-bitcoin-ether-futures","publishDate":"2022-08-29T15:31:26","id":8798,"type":null,"title":"Derivatives marketplace CME goes live with euro-denominated bitcoin, ether futures","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["CME Group, a derivatives marketplace, has launched bitcoin and ether futures denominated in the euro.","The offerings were first announced earlier this month and complement the existing dollar-denominated futures CME launched in 2021.&nbsp;","\"Designed to match their U.S. dollar-denominated counterparts, Bitcoin Euro and Ether Euro futures contracts will be sized at five bitcoin and 50 ether per contract,\" CME said in a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.cmegroup.com\/media-room\/press-releases\/2022\/8\/29\/cme_group_announceslaunchofeuro-denominatedbitcoinandetherfuture.html\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">statement<\/a> Monday. \"These new contracts will be cash-settled, based on the CME CF Bitcoin-Euro Reference Rate and CME CF Ether-Euro Reference Rate, which serve as once-a-day reference rates of the euro-denominated price of bitcoin and ether.\"<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nWhile derivatives volumes have dropped amid the fall in crypto prices, cryptocurrency derivatives trading on centralized exchanges rose 13% to more than $3 trillion last month from June, according to researcher CryptoCompare. The derivatives market comprised 69% of total crypto volumes in July compared to 66% in the previous month.","Volumes for CME bitcoin futures have trended downward since peaking in October. Last month, CME bitcoin futures volumes were a reported $38 billion, down from a record of more than $108 billion, according to data compiled by The Block Research.","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/crypto-markets\/futures\/average-daily-volume-of-cme-bitcoin-futures-monthly\/embed\" title=\"Volume and OI of CME Bitcoin futures\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","CME's ether futures volume reached nearly $16 billion in July, compared to more than $34 billion in November, per the Data Dashboard.","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/crypto-markets\/futures\/average-daily-volume-of-cme-ethereum-futures-monthly\/embed\" title=\"Volume and OI of CME Ethereum futures\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bitcoin Euro","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$16 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"CME Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$34 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"66%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$108 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$3 trillion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"69%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$38 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Ether Euro","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"13%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"euro","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CME","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"last month from June","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Euro Reference Rate","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Data Dashboard","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"October","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Michael McSweeney","The Block"]}