{"summary":"The later-stage fund will aim to close at €100 million and is already launching in multiple markets across Europe.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/141454\/fabric-vc-looks-to-close-two-web3-funds-worth-245-million","publishDate":"2022-04-11T08:43:06","id":8800,"type":null,"title":"Fabric Ventures looks to close two web3 funds worth $245 million","category":["VENTURE CAPITAL"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Fabric Ventures is in the final stages of completing an early-stage web3 fund and on track to close another focused on later-stage investments.<\/span>","The pair will be worth more than <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> €225 million ($245 million) combined, Richard Muirhead, managing partner at the London-based venture capital firm, told The Block.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The first of the two — a fund focusing on early-stage companies — was described by Muirhead&nbsp; as \"significantly oversubscribed\" and has extended its hard cap to close at €125 million in order to introduce additional investors. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Fabric is also in the process of raising a second fund, focused on investments in companies at Series B stage and onwards, which is set to be capped at €100 million.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Fabric X, their ideation stage program, is already launching in multiple markets across Europe. Fabric has backed \"open economy founders from concept to scale,\" it says.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The new capital follows a $130 million raise in July, which included ​​around €25 million from the European Investment Fund (EIF).&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">It was the first EIF-backed fund mandated to invest in digital assets and blockchain technology. At the time, it received backing from 33 founders, partners and executives from Ethereum, Wise, PayPal, Square, Google, PayU, Ledger, Raisin, Ebury, PPRO, NEAR, Felix Capital, LocalGlobe, Earlybird, Accelerator Ventures, Aztec Protocol, Raisin, Aragon, Orchid, MySQL, Verifone, OpenOcean, Claret Capital and more.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Muirhead said the firm anticipates raising again in spring 2023.&nbsp;<\/span>","Fabric has previously backed projects across the spectrum of digital assets including Ramp, Axie Infinity parent Sky Mavis and Ledger.&nbsp;","It's the latest example of new capital flowing into the space. <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/140793\/pantera-capital-sets-out-stall-to-raise-new-200-million-fund?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Earlier in April,<\/a> Pantera also said it is raising a new fund, targeting a $200 million close at the start of May.&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/139897\/gumi-cryptos-capital-unveils-new-110-million-fund-to-invest-in-early-stage-startups?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In March<\/a>, blockchain-focused venture capital firm gumi Cryptos Capital (gCC) also said it has raised $110 million to invest in early-stage startups.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Earlybird","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"EIF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"PayPal","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Richard Muirhead","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Felix Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$130 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"London","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Pantera","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Aragon","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$200 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"MySQL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"},{"type":"spring 2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$110 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$245 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Verifone","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Claret Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Muirhead","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Infinity","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Raisin","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"gumi Cryptos Capital (gCC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Accelerator Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ebury","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Mavis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Lucy Harley-McKeown","The Block"]}