{"summary":"The Web3 Domain Alliance established itself as a new coalition this week to combat fraud and promote technological advancement and user experience of the next generation of web3 domains.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/181751\/web3-domain-alliance-starts-with-unstoppable-domains-bonfida-as-founding-members","publishDate":"2022-11-02T08:40:06","id":8814,"type":null,"title":"Web3 Domain Alliance starts with Unstoppable Domains, Bonfida as founding members","category":["STARTUPS"],"content":["<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Web3 Domain Alliance established itself as a new coalition this week to combat fraud and naming collisions as well as to promote technological advancement and user experience of the next generation of web3 domains.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nUnstoppable Domains, Tezos Domains, Polkadot Name System, Hedera and Bonfida, which oversees the Solana naming service, are among the founding members, according to a press release.<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;134233117&quot;:false,&quot;134233118&quot;:false,&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335551550&quot;:1,&quot;335551620&quot;:1,&quot;335559685&quot;:0,&quot;335559737&quot;:0,&quot;335559738&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Web3 domains such as .sol or .crypto can be used in place of lengthy wallet addresses for sending and receiving cryptocurrencies, as well as for website hosting and as a single sign-on method for many web3 apps. The domains are minted on the blockchain.<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;134233117&quot;:false,&quot;134233118&quot;:false,&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335551550&quot;:1,&quot;335551620&quot;:1,&quot;335559685&quot;:0,&quot;335559737&quot;:0,&quot;335559738&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","Demand is rising for web3 domains with unique ownership on two of the largest domain platforms, Unstoppable Domains and the Ethereum Name Service (ENS), reaching all-time highs, according to <a href=\"https:\/\/dune.com\/metaland\/ethereum-name-service-community-dashboard\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">data<\/a> from Dune Wizard Metaland on Dune Analytics.","","","Unstoppable Domains itself recently <a href=\"https:\/\/unstoppabledomains.com\/blog\/coin\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">experienced<\/a> a naming collision challenge with its .coin domain when it clashed with the. coin domain issued by blockchain platform Emercoin.&nbsp;","Ultimately, Unstoppable Domains decided to stop supporting the .coin domains and offered the owners credits worth three times what they paid.","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In the web2 world, domain names are organized and managed by the nonprofit Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers (ICANN). The group helps to implement domain industry standards.<\/span>","<span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;134233117&quot;:false,&quot;134233118&quot;:false,&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335551550&quot;:1,&quot;335551620&quot;:1,&quot;335559685&quot;:0,&quot;335559737&quot;:0,&quot;335559738&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"We're still in the dial-up phase of web3,\" Unstoppable Domains SVP Sandy Carter said in an interview with The Block at the Web Summit in Lisbon. Carter believes this stage of web3 is emulating the early internet and that standardization will be key to its maturity.&nbsp;<\/span>","The organization plans to focus on aligning intellectual property rights of all web3 naming services and protecting consumers.","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The cross-chain coalition includes naming systems across the Polygon, Ethereum, Solana, Tezos, Polkadot, Hedera, Bitcoin and Klayton blockchains.<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;134233117&quot;:false,&quot;134233118&quot;:false,&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335551550&quot;:1,&quot;335551620&quot;:1,&quot;335559685&quot;:0,&quot;335559737&quot;:0,&quot;335559738&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Noticeably missing from the coalition is the Ethereum Name Service, which manages one of the most popular web3 domains .eth.<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;134233117&quot;:false,&quot;134233118&quot;:false,&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335551550&quot;:1,&quot;335551620&quot;:1,&quot;335559685&quot;:0,&quot;335559737&quot;:0,&quot;335559738&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","The alliance contacted ENS to see if it would join but the deal has not materialized, Carter said, adding that it is planning three phases of participants. The second phase will include wallets and browsers, and the third will include metaverse and gaming companies.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Carter","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Hedera","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hedera","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bonfida","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Tezos","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ethereum Name Service","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dune Analytics","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers (ICANN","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dune Wizard Metaland","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Klayton blockchains","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sandy Carter","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Polkadot","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Lisbon","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Web3 Domain Alliance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Kari McMahon","Lucy Harley-McKeown","The Block"]}