{"summary":"Vauld, a Singapore-based crypto trading and lending platform with most of its team in India, has suspended withdrawals.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/155679\/vauld-halts-withdrawals-hires-legal-financial-advisors","publishDate":"2022-07-04T02:41:53","id":8817,"type":null,"title":"Vauld halts withdrawals and hires legal and financial advisors","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Vauld, a Singapore-based crypto trading and lending platform with most of its team in India, has become the latest crypto firm to halt customer withdrawals amid the market tumult.","CEO Darshan Bathija <a href=\"https:\/\/www.vauld.com\/blog\/corporate-statement\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a> in a blog post on Monday that the firm has \"made the difficult decision to suspend all withdrawals, trading and deposits on the Vauld platform with immediate effect.\"","Vauld is struggling financially due to a combination of factors, including a volatile market and the financial difficulties of business partners, according to Bathija. Since June 12, the platform has seen customer withdrawals of nearly $198 million, triggered by the implosion of the TerraUSD stablecoin, Celsius's decision to halt withdrawals and Three Arrows Capital's woes, said Bathija.","Vauld is open to potential restructuring options. To that end, the firm has hired Kroll as its financial advisor and Cyril Amarchand Mangaldas and Rajah &amp; Tann Singapore LLP as its legal advisors in India and Singapore, respectively.","\"Our management remains fully committed to working with our financial and legal advisors to the best of our abilities to explore and analyse all possible options, including potential restructuring options, that would best protect the interests of Vauld's stakeholders,\" said Bathija.","Vauld is currently also in discussions with potential investors, according to Bathija.","\"We intend to apply to the Singapore courts for a moratorium i.e. a suspension of the commencement or continuation of any proceedings against the relevant companies so as to give us breathing space to carry out the proposed restructuring exercise,\" he added.","Vauld (formerly Bank of Hodlers) is <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/112912\/peter-theil-valar-crypto-platform-vauld-series-a\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">backed by high-profile investors<\/a>, including Peter Thiel's Valar Ventures, Coinbase Ventures and Pantera Capital. The firm has raised $27.5 million in total funding to date.","The news comes less than a month after Vauld&nbsp;<a class=\"c-link c-link--focus-visible\" tabindex=\"-1\" href=\"https:\/\/www.vauld.com\/blog\/vauld-continues-to-operate-as-usual\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-stringify-link=\"https:\/\/www.vauld.com\/blog\/vauld-continues-to-operate-as-usual\/\" data-sk=\"tooltip_parent\" data-remove-tab-index=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a> it “continues to operate as usual despite volatile market conditions” on June 16. “We do not have any exposure to Celsius or Three Arrows Capital, and we remain liquid despite market conditions. Over the last few days, all withdrawals were processed as usual and this will continue to be the case in the future,” the firm said at the time.<span class=\"c-message__edited_label\" dir=\"ltr\" data-sk=\"tooltip_parent\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Darshan Bathija","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Peter Thiel","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bank of Hodlers)","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bathija","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Vauld","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$198 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Rajah &amp; Tann Singapore LLP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cyril Amarchand Mangaldas","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Vauld","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Pantera Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Celsius","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"India","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Coinbase Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kroll","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"June 16","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$27.5 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Valar Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"June 12","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Yogita Khatri","The Block"]}