{"summary":"Super Bowl LVI was dubbed the &#x27;Crypto Bowl&#x27; by some, but Super Bowl LVII will be considerably less crypto-centric.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/210876\/cryptocurrency-adverts-benched-ahead-of-super-bowl-lvii","publishDate":"2023-02-12T07:33:05","id":8857,"type":null,"title":"Cryptocurrency adverts benched ahead of Super Bowl LVII","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Coinbase, Crypto.com, eToro, and FTX advertised at Super Bowl LVI as last year crypto markets were firmly part of the zeitgeist. This year, declining prices amid a turbulent macroeconomic backdrop and several high-profile collapses have pushed crypto to the sidelines.","Still, there will be some representation during one of the most-watched events on television — one that brings in an audience of about 100 million people annually.","NFT and gaming company Limit Break <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/208594\/ftx-backed-nft-company-airing-6-5-million-super-bowl-commercial\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">spent<\/a> $6.5 million to advertise during Super Bowl LVII. The firm will be pushing its \"free-to-own\" digital collectibles this evening.&nbsp;","Limit Break, which received investment from collapsed crypto exchange FTX last year, spent the money on a 30-second spot.","\"This marks the first time an NFT developer has purchased a Super Bowl ad,\" the company said.","Two crypto advertisers had commercials booked with Fox, with two more almost completed, Mark Evans, executive vice president of ad sales for Fox Sports, <a href=\"https:\/\/apnews.com\/article\/kansas-city-chiefs-philadelphia-eagles-super-bowl-sports-fox-corp-5d9922047c7fb640ddbf8caf5100ece2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">told<\/a> AP. Still, the deals were never finalized following the collapse of FTX. \"There's zero representation in that category on the day at all,\" Evans said.","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$6.5 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Mark Evans","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fox Sports","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"this evening","content":"TIME"},{"type":"Fox","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Evans","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["COINBASE","CRYPTO BANKS AND LENDERS","FINTECH","FTX"],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}