{"summary":"Tornado Cash developer Alexey Pertsev will remain detained until his next hearing in April, a Dutch court ruled.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/211965\/tornado-cash-developer-alexey-pertsev","publishDate":"2023-02-15T12:42:39","id":8861,"type":null,"title":"Tornado Cash developer Alexey Pertsev to remain detained until April hearing","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Alexey Pertsev, the developer behind the crypto mixer Tornado Cash, will remain detained until his next hearing scheduled for April 21, a Dutch court ruled.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In addition, a pre-trial review will take place on May 24, the court of East Brabant handling the case told The Block.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Authorities in the Netherlands first <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/163206\/suspected-tornado-cash-developer-arrested-in-amsterdam\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">arrested<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Pertsev in August, days after U.S. authorities placed sanctions on Tornado Cash, a crypto mixing service that allows users to obscure the details of transactions. The U.S. Treasury accused Tornado Cash — which redistributes crypto from multiple users in a pool, making the flows more difficult to trace — of \"laundering funds for malicious cyber actors.\"<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The money flows allegedly “included funds stolen through hacks by a group believed to be associated with North Korea,\" the<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Dutch Fiscal Information and Investigation Service <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">stated at the time of the arrest.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This is the third time that Pertsev’s appeal was rejected. Since August, he has remained detained for three months at a time. His last appeal was <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/189086\/tornado-cash-developer-alexey-pertsev-to-be-detained-another-three-months-in-amsterdam\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">rejected<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in November.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Pertsev’s arrest sparked a broader debate about what it means for regulators to sanction software and <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/163415\/tornado-cash-developer-arrest-sparks-fears-of-global-crypto-enforcement\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">spurred<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> fears of unprecedented crypto enforcement.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"May 24","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Netherlands","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S. Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dutch Fiscal Information and Investigation Service","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"North Korea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"April 21","content":"DATE"},{"type":"East Brabant","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alexey Pertsev","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["COURT HEARINGS","CRIME","MIXERS"],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}