{"summary":"Top News from Friday to Today WE ARE GOING ALL IN. Source BREAKING: Binance co-founder Heyi announces at Shanghai Blockchain Week happening this week that","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/40161\/global-coin-research-blockchain-smart-phones-on-the-rise-binance-announces-fiat-to-crypto-otc","publishDate":"2019-09-19T13:10:12","id":8862,"type":null,"title":"Global Coin Research: Blockchain smart phones on the rise, Binance announces fiat to crypto OTC","category":["ASIA"],"content":["WE ARE GOING ALL IN.&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"http:\/\/bit.ly\/2Nds04g\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Source<\/a><\/em>","<strong class=\"gc hs\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BREAKING:<\/strong> Binance co-founder Heyi announces at Shanghai Blockchain Week happening this week that Binance will introduce fiat to crypto OTC within one month. She says that Binance has already connected to fiat systems in 170 countries. <a class=\"bi cs ht hu hv hw\" href=\"https:\/\/globalcoinresearch.us17.list-manage.com\/track\/click?u=859b0d423a7f7baa4cdb46f26&amp;id=a55d1297d5&amp;e=801c3a4138\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google translate<\/a>","<strong class=\"gc hs\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitcoin Mining Power<\/strong> Hits New High as Half a Million New ASICs Go Online.&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"http:\/\/bit.ly\/30p3Q99\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Source<\/a><\/em><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nGCR learned that the recently launched Antminer S17e by Bitmain was sold out in a day.","<strong class=\"gc hs\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Blackstone CEO Steve Schwarzman<\/strong>- “[Blockchain technology] is a very good idea, and it will end up being adopted because it’s good technology. Applying it to the creation of money is sort of, for my taste, pretty odd.”&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"http:\/\/bit.ly\/2Ib5kh8\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Source<\/a><\/em>","<strong class=\"gc hs\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">GCR first broke in English news that Binance has made its first strategic investment in China<\/strong> with Chinese media site Mars Finance. The company just completed its third round of financing since starting out last year with investors Binance, Ceyuan Ventures and Matrixport. Ceyuan Ventures is a previous venture founded by the partner of Dragonfly Bo Feng.&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"http:\/\/bit.ly\/30rbj7w\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Source<\/a><\/em>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitcoin.com<\/strong><strong class=\"gc hs\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;Announces Partnership With Taiwan’s HTC<\/strong>-&gt; HTC’s flagship EXODUS 1 smartphone is now the first phone that provides Bitcoin Cash (BCH) support without having to download a BCH wallet from an app store.&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"http:\/\/bit.ly\/2IaFUA5\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Source<\/a><\/em>","<strong class=\"gc hs\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Korean branch of crypto exchange OKEx<\/strong> is delisting all five of its listed privacy coins — Dash, Monero, Zcash, Super Bitcoin and Horizen — citing regulatory demands.&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"http:\/\/bit.ly\/2IbLxhp\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Source<\/a><\/em>","<strong class=\"gc hs\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Mike Kennedy,&nbsp;<\/strong>founder of Zelle, is joining Interstellar as the new CEO.&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"http:\/\/bit.ly\/2UP8IDo\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Source<\/a><\/em>","<strong class=\"gc hs\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bobby Lee Returns With Ballet<\/strong>, a Crypto Hardware Wallet for the Masses.&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"http:\/\/bit.ly\/2UTQhNQ\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Source<\/a><\/em>","<strong class=\"gc hs\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Korean exchange Hanbitco’s&nbsp;<\/strong>representative Kim Seong-ah was elected as chairman of the Korea Blockchain Association cryptocurrency exchange.&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"http:\/\/bit.ly\/30sWfGp\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Source<\/a><\/em>","<strong class=\"gc hs\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Non-custodial exchange KyberSwap<\/strong> rolls out fiat-to-crypto gateway.&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"http:\/\/bit.ly\/2UP9VKW\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Source<\/a><\/em>","<strong class=\"gc hs\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">U.S.-based cryptocurrency exchange Coinbase<\/strong> is evaluating the launch of an initial exchange offering (IEO) platform in the near future.&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"http:\/\/bit.ly\/2UUjMPn\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Source<\/a><\/em>","<strong class=\"gc hs\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Huobi Group Founder and CEO Leon Li&nbsp;<\/strong>has been named CEO, Chairman of the Board, and Executive Director of the Board of Hong Kong Stock Exchange-listed firm Pantronics Holdings Limited. Under a new proposal, the name of Pantronics may be changed to Huobi Technology Holdings Limited.&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"http:\/\/bit.ly\/2UShMan\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Source<\/a><\/em>","<strong class=\"gc hs\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Facebook’s Libra is not intended<\/strong> to challenge the “monetary sovereignty of nations,” according to cofounder and Calibra CEO David Marcus.&nbsp;At Ethereal in Tel Aviv, Calibra COO, Tomer Barel, explained that Libra will compete with cash effectively because it’s not owned by a single entity.&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"http:\/\/bit.ly\/30qq4rj\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Source<\/a><\/em>","<strong class=\"gc hs\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Blockchain adoption in Africa&nbsp;<\/strong>is on the rise. A look at Nigeria and Kenya.&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"http:\/\/bit.ly\/2LytrIr\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Source<\/a><\/em>","<strong class=\"gc hs\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Deloitte, a major audit firm,<\/strong> is exploring the use of virtual currency inside the company, and is making efforts such as permitting payments using Bitcoin (BTC) in employee cafeterias.&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"http:\/\/bit.ly\/2Ic5F2R\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Source<\/a><\/em>","<strong class=\"gc hs\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Blockchain Smartphones&nbsp;<\/strong>Preparing to Debut One after Another Per Korea Media:&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"http:\/\/bit.ly\/2Ly0DzH\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Source<\/a><\/em>","<strong class=\"gc hs\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Chinese Regulators Demand&nbsp;<\/strong>a Clean-Up of Crypto Mining in Inner Mongolia.&nbsp;<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"http:\/\/bit.ly\/2LBK0U5\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Source<\/a><\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Masses","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Shanghai Blockchain Week","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BCH","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Super Bitcoin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Heyi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Matrixport","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Zelle","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitmain","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Leon Li","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Tomer Barel","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Taiwan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Board of Hong Kong Stock Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Crypto Hardware Wallet","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tel Aviv","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Monero","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"David Marcus","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Board","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Steve Schwarzman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Mars Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Korea Blockchain Association","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Huobi Technology Holdings Limited","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"fiat","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kenya","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Calibra","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Zcash","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Korea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Dragonfly Bo Feng","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Huobi Group Founder","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"HTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"GCR","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ceyuan Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Blackstone","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Calibra COO","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kim Seong","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nigeria","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Pantronics Holdings Limited","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Inner Mongolia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bobby Lee","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Africa","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"China","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Crypto Mining","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mike Kennedy","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Contributor Network","The Block"]}