{"summary":"Crypto markets tank after FTX Chapter 11 filing.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/185859\/bitcoin-ether-drop-as-ftxs-bankruptcy-filing-spooks-crypto-markets","publishDate":"2022-11-11T09:56:29","id":8868,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin, ether drop as FTX&#x27;s bankruptcy filing spooks crypto markets","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["Crypto prices sank on the news that FTX and more than 100 corporate entities affiliated with the firm are <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/185083\/ftx-files-for-chapter-11-bankruptcy\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filing<\/a>&nbsp;for bankruptcy.&nbsp;","Bitcoin dropped 5.2% at $16,551, while ether crashed 6.5% to $1,215.","BTCUSD chart by TradingView","Rumors of FTX's insolvency had been swirling in the lead-up to the filing. Former Head of Institutional Sales Zane Tacket revealed via <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/tackettzane\/status\/1591047749675651072?s=20&amp;t=hCcYvgW7QDlcvJE9605wmg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Twitter<\/a> that the firm had $8.8 billion in liabilities, just $900 million in liquid assets, and $5.2 billion in less liquid or illiquid assets.&nbsp;","The exchange was also <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/185461\/ftxs-bankman-fried-seeks-more-than-9-billion-for-exchange-rescue-reuters\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">seeking<\/a> up to $9 billion in funding to plug its financial hole, according to a Reuters report.","Prices had been lifted by a positive U.S. inflation data report on Thursday. Crypto prices immediately jumped following the news, as did equities. Bitcoin traded at $16,420 before the release, jumping to $17,540 shortly after, according to data via Coinbase. These gains have now been erased.&nbsp;","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$1,215","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$900 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$16,551","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"TradingView","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"6.5%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$8.8 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"5.2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Zane Tacket","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$17,540","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Reuters","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$5.2 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$9 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$16,420","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN","BNB","ETHEREUM","FTX","POLYGON","SOLANA","TETHER","USDC","XRP"],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}