{"summary":"Genesis Global Holdco reached an agreement in principle with Digital Currency Group and other creditors on Monday.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/209145\/genesis-gemini-and-dcg-reach-agreement-in-bankruptcy-court","publishDate":"2023-02-06T18:37:14","id":8895,"type":null,"title":"Genesis, Gemini and DCG reach agreement in bankruptcy court","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Genesis, its parent Digital Currency Group, Gemini and other creditors have reached a bankruptcy agreement to recover assets.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sean O’Neal, a lawyer representing the debtors, <\/span><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> said the sides agreed in principle and were working to finish the term sheet, with plans to file that as early as tonight or Tuesday. The deal involves Genesis Global Capital, DCG, two ad hoc creditor groups, including those representing more than $2 billion dollars in claims against GGC, and Gemini Trust Company, he said. &nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">As part of the plan, DCG will contribute its equity interest in Genesis Global Trading to Genesis Global Holdco, bringing all Genesis entities under the same holding company, according to a statement released on Monday. &nbsp;<\/span><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Genesis Global Holdco filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/190311\/digital-currency-groups-genesis-global-files-for-bankruptcy-protection\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">last month<\/span><\/a>&nbsp;after taking a financial hit following the collapses of crypto hedge fund Three Arrows Capital and exchange FTX last year. &nbsp;&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Gemini is committed to contributing $100 million to the proposed plan, Anson B. Frelinghuysen, a lawyer representing Gemini lenders, said today during a proceeding in the U.S. Bankruptcy Court for the Southern District of New York.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Gemini founders Cameron and Tyler Winklevoss are doing this because they believe in the debtors’ reorganization and the Gemini platforms and they want to do the right thing for their users,” he said. &nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Gemini’s Cameron Winklevoss called the plan a “critical step forward,” on Twitter on Monday.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“T<\/span><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">here is still much work to be done to complete this process, including further due diligence of Genesis financials and judicial approval of this plan, but we are confident that we now have a framework in place to execute on,” he tweeted.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S. Bankruptcy Court","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DCG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Southern District of New York","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gemini founders Cameron","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$100 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"today","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$2 billion dollars","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Sean O’Neal","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Digital Currency Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tyler Winklevoss","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Genesis Global Trading to Genesis Global Holdco","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cameron Winklevoss","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Anson B. Frelinghuysen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Genesis Global Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Holdco","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gemini Trust Company","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}