{"summary":"Launched in May 2019, crypto exchange FTX has showcased the breakneck growth of the burgeoning market for digital asset derivatives. The Binance-backed firm is known for its diversity of products, offering trading of futures tied to dozens of cryptocurrencies.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/54170\/uncovering-the-key-differences-between-crypto-derivatives-markets-in-north-america-and-asia-with-ftx-alameda-research-ceo-sam-bankman-fried","publishDate":"2020-01-28T14:38:32","id":8899,"type":null,"title":"Uncovering the key differences between crypto derivatives markets in North America and Asia with FTX &amp; Alameda Research CEO Sam Bankman-Fried","category":["ASIA"],"content":["<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 3 of Season 2 of The Scoop was recorded over Skype with Frank Chaparro and Sam Bankman-Fried, CEO of FTX and Alameda Research. Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on <a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/a>, or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to&nbsp;<a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection#c5b5aaa1a6a4b6b185b1ada0a7a9aaa6aea6b7bcb5b1aaeba6aaa8\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"5d2d32393e3c2e291d2935383f31323e363e2f242d2932733e3230\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/span><\/a>.<\/em>","<iframe src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK2299537334\" width=\"100%\" height=\"200\" frameborder=\"0\" scrolling=\"no\" data-mce-fragment=\"1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-mce-type=\"bookmark\" class=\"mce_SELRES_start\" data-v-f87c67ca>﻿<\/span><span data-mce-type=\"bookmark\" class=\"mce_SELRES_start\" data-v-f87c67ca>﻿<\/span><span data-mce-type=\"bookmark\" class=\"mce_SELRES_start\" data-v-f87c67ca>﻿<\/span><span data-mce-type=\"bookmark\" class=\"mce_SELRES_start\" data-v-f87c67ca>﻿<\/span><span data-mce-type=\"bookmark\" class=\"mce_SELRES_start\" data-v-f87c67ca>﻿<\/span><\/iframe>","&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Skype","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}