{"summary":"Former Ralph Lauren executive Alice Delahunt has raised $9.5 million for a digital fashion startup to equalize creative opportunities in fashion.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/203258\/seven-seven-six-syky-funding","publishDate":"2023-01-18T07:59:51","id":8905,"type":null,"title":"Seven Seven Six leads $9.5 million Series A for digital fashion brand Syky","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Digital fashion brand Syky completed a $9.5 million Series A round led by Seven Seven Six.","Brevan Howard Digital, Leadout Capital, First Light Capital Group, and Polygon Ventures also joined the round, according to a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.prnewswire.com\/news-releases\/web3-fashion-platform-syky-closes-9-5m-series-a-funding-round-led-by-alexis-ohanians-seven-seven-six-301723125.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">release<\/a> on Tuesday.&nbsp;","Syky, led by former Ralph Lauren Chief Digital Officer Alice Delahunt, aims to build a blockchain-enabled luxury platform. The company plans to \"<span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">build a platform that equalizes creative <\/span><span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">opportunity for aspiring designers, showcases the best of fashion<\/span> <span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">from emerging and <\/span><span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">established brands, and cultivates a community passionate about the evolution of fashion,\" said Delahunt, who worked as a global director of digital and social at Burberry before joining Ralph Lauren.<\/span>","Seven Seven Six's Alexis Ohanian noted the fund backed Delahunt's<span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> \"vision to build the leading fashion platform and c<\/span><span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ommunity for the next generation of designers and consumers.\"<\/span>","Following the raise, Syky is set to release its first NFT range on Jan. 20, known as The Keystone. <span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The collection will work as a <\/span><span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">membership pass for fashion enthusiasts and leaders who want to \"shape the future of <\/span><span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">fashion in digital, physical and augmented worlds.\" 50 NFTs from the collection will be awarded to aspiring designers.&nbsp;<\/span>","Membership grants holders access to digital and physical fashion events and networking opportunities. Holders will also receive exclusive access to designer collection drops and early access to Syky releases.&nbsp;","Fashion brands, including <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/149502\/prada-becomes-the-latest-fashion-brand-to-launch-nfts\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Prada<\/a> and <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/174617\/hugo-boss-to-launch-nft-and-360-degree-metaverse-experience-with-imaginary-ones\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Hugo Boss<\/a>, launched NFT collections last year as brands explored the space, while Decentraland <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/139904\/inside-the-first-ever-metaverse-fashion-week\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">hosted<\/a> the first Metaverse Fashion Week in March 2022.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Howard Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Delahunt","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Leadout Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Polygon Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ralph Lauren","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alexis Ohanian","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jan. 20","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$9.5 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"March 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alice Delahunt","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"First Light Capital Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Syky","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Keystone","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["SERIES A"],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}