{"summary":"Juthica Chou dissects the impact of crypto&#x27;s recent rally on the options market, and highlights key signals for the coming weeks.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/260138\/bitcoin-options-kraken","publishDate":"2023-10-31T08:01:05","id":8943,"type":null,"title":"Kraken head of OTC explains the bullish signals to look for in bitcoin options","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 93<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 5 of The Scoop was recorded with <b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro and Kraken head of OTC options trading Juthica Chou<\/b><\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on <a href=\"https:\/\/www.youtube.com\/channel\/UCqjFueYMJ78eF6G0lGLzzpQ\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Youtube<\/a>, <\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a>,<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Please send feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"11617e757270626551657974737d7e727a3f727e\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm\/?e=BLOCK9246404315\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Juthica Chou is the head of OTC options trading at Kraken and the former president of LedgerX.","In this episode, Chou explains how crypto's recent rally is being reflected in the options market, and what signals to pay attention to in the weeks ahead.","According to Chou, volatility has returned to the market after months of relatively little activity:","\"The market's definitely pricing some big moves. And I always say, like if it can go up fast, it can go down faster.\"","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors <a href=\"https:\/\/www.paypal.com\/crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">PayPal.<\/em><\/a><\/b><\/span>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Make your crypto move with PayPal. Get started today at <a href=\"https:\/\/www.paypal.com\/crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">PayPal.com\/crypto<\/a><\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Juthica Chou","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Juthica Chou","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"OTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"PayPal","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Chou","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kraken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Chou","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}