{"summary":"FINPR is a Dubai-based crypto PR agency that broadened its influencer marketing service by increasing the number of Key Opinion Leaders (KOLs) to 1400+ advertising formats by 700+ crypto and Web3 influencers. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/253233\/finpr-a-leading-web3-influencer-marketing-agency","publishDate":"2023-10-03T09:01:02","id":8966,"type":null,"title":"FINPR: A Leading Web3 Influencer Marketing Agency","category":["SPONSORED"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">FINPR is a Dubai-based <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/finpr.agency\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">crypto PR agency<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that broadened its influencer marketing service by increasing the number of Key Opinion Leaders (KOLs) to 1400+ advertising formats by 700+ crypto and Web3 influencers.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Over 450 of these KOLs are YouTubers, while the rest are active on social media platforms like X, Instagram, and TikTok. This diversification establishes FINPR as a leading player among Web3 influencer marketing service providers regarding KOLs offered.<\/span>","<a href=\"https:\/\/finpr.agency\/crypto-influencer-marketing\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto influencer marketing<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> has proven a potent tool for generating relevant traffic for Web3 and blockchain startups. It is instrumental in building trust, acquiring customers, and enhancing brand visibility.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Even amidst the ongoing crypto bear market, FINPR continues to observe solid demand for influencer marketing from Web3 companies. \"Crypto exchanges, wallets, and protocols are willing to allocate budgets for influencers, especially when they have prior experience and know how to achieve positive ROI,\" remarks FINPR’s CEO Kirill Bezverhi.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In addition to influencer marketing, FINPR offers a spectrum of services like crypto PR publications, community management, crypto exchange listing, SEO, and PPC ads management among others.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">When it comes to blockchain PR, FINPR provides access to 230+ crypto media outlets in 15 languages, including English, German, French, Turkish, Arabic, Korean, Indonesian, and more. The media list offered by FINPR features 100 English-language outlets, 16 Turkish-language, 13 German, 14 Arabic, and 13 Spanish-language media outlets, among others.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The total tally of media options this <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/finpr.agency\/web3-pr-agency\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Web3 PR agency<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> offers to its clients in the crypto, Web3, and fintech sectors now exceeds 450 outlets, encompassing business, tech, finance, and news media.<\/span>","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About FINPR<\/b>","<a href=\"https:\/\/finpr.agency\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">FINPR<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> is a crypto marketing &amp; PR agency based in Dubai. Since its launch in 2017, the agency has facilitated the marketing and PR efforts of over 250 NFT, DeFi, Web3, Crypto, and FinTech startups, including Gate.IO, BestChange, and Klaytn. The services offered by FINPR include crypto PR, influencer marketing, community management, crypto SEO, marketing strategy creation, crypto exchange listings, content creation, and more.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"FinTech","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FINPR","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"PPC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Klaytn","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"fintech","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"TikTok","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kirill Bezverhi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"crypto marketing &amp; PR","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dubai","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Instagram","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Crypto","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sponsored","The Block"]}