{"summary":"Tornado Cash co-founder Storm arrested while co-founder Semenov is added to a list of individuals and companies sanctioned by US government.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/247049\/tornado-cashs-semenov-added-to-us-government-sanctions-list","publishDate":"2023-08-23T12:50:39","id":8978,"type":null,"title":"Tornado Cash&#x27;s Storm arrested by FBI, Semenov added to sanctions list","category":["PEOPLE"],"content":["Tornado Cash co-founder Roman Storm has been arrested while fellow co-founder Roman Semenov added to a <a href=\"https:\/\/ofac.treasury.gov\/specially-designated-nationals-and-blocked-persons-list-sdn-human-readable-lists\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">list<\/a> of individuals and companies subject to have their assets blocked and prohibited from doing business with U.S. persons.","The U.S. Department of the Treasury's <span class=\"treas-header__name\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Office<\/span><span class=\"treas-header__name\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> of <\/span><span class=\"treas-header__name\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Foreign <\/span><span class=\"treas-header__name\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Assets<\/span><span class=\"treas-header__name\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Control, or OFAC, announced Wednesday that Semenov <a href=\"https:\/\/ofac.treasury.gov\/recent-actions\/20230823\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">has been added<\/a> to its <\/span><span class=\"treas-page-title\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Specially Designated Nationals list of sanctioned companies and individuals. <br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nMeanwhile, the U.S. Department of Justice, or DOJ, said it had charged Storm and Semenov with \"conspiracy to commit money laundering, conspiracy to commit sanctions violations, and conspiracy to operate an unlicensed money transmitting business.\"<\/span>","The Federal Bureau of Investigation and the Internal Revenue Service arrested Storm on Wednesday, OFAC said while Semenov remains at large, according to the DOJ.","\"Tornado Cash has been used to launder funds for criminal actors since its creation in 2019, including to obfuscate hundreds of millions of dollars in virtual currency stolen by Lazarus Group hackers,\" OFAC <a href=\"https:\/\/home.treasury.gov\/news\/press-releases\/jy1702\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said in a statement<\/a>. The sanctions were coordinated with the help of the DOJ, the statement also said.","The update to OFAC's list of sanctioned entities also included several ether wallet addresses and specifically mentioned North Korean sanctions regulations.","They eight wallet addresses sanctioned have processed more than $11.5 million in various crypto assets, according to&nbsp;blockchain analytics firm Elliptic Connect.","\"OFAC publishes a list of individuals and companies owned or controlled by, or acting for or on behalf of, targeted countries,\" according to the office's website.","\"Collectively, such individuals and companies are called 'Specially Designated Nationals' or 'SDNs.' Their assets are blocked and U.S. persons are generally prohibited from dealing with them,\" the website also states.","Roughly <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/163415\/tornado-cash-developer-arrest-sparks-fears-of-global-crypto-enforcement\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">a year ago<\/a>, OFAC designated Tornado Cash as well as an ecosystem of linked wallets, saying that bad actors including North Korea’s Lazarus group had used the platform to launder more than $7 billion.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Tornado Cash is an open-source software that can be used to anonymize transactions on the Ethereum blockchain.<\/span>","In June, the Blockchain Association called the U.S. Treasury Department’s decision to sanction Tornado Cash “unprecedented and unlawful.\" Those that oppose the sanctions have <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/233000\/crypto-policy-tornado-cash-sanctions-legal-brief\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a> the government overstepped its authority by targeting software, rather than an individual or entity, among other issues.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Lazarus","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Blockchain Association","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"obfuscate hundreds of millions of dollars","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Internal Revenue Service","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. Treasury Department","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S. Department of the Treasury's <span class=\"treas-header__name\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Office<\/span><span class=\"treas-header__name\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> of <\/span><span class=\"treas-header__name\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Foreign <\/span><span class=\"treas-header__name\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Assets<\/span><span class=\"treas-header__name\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Control","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lazarus Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"North Korea","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Specially Designated Nationals","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$11.5 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S. Department of Justice","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Federal Bureau of Investigation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$7 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Elliptic Connect","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"June","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"DOJ","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"OFAC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Roman Semenov","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Semenov","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}