{"summary":"This comes days after Silvergate said it was in the &quot;process of reevaluating its business strategies&quot; and companies severed ties. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/217042\/silvergate-bank-to-release-nearly-9-9-million-to-blockfi","publishDate":"2023-03-03T16:20:44","id":8986,"type":null,"title":"Silvergate Bank to release nearly $9.9 million to BlockFi","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A bankruptcy judge has ordered Silvergate Bank to release nearly $9.9 million to crypto lender BlockFi, days after the bank said it was “reevaluating its business” and could be \"l<span class=\"\" dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ess than well-capitalized,\" which led to<\/span> a swarm of companies severing ties with the bank.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">U.S. Bankruptcy Judge Michael B. Kaplan said Silvergate had to return $9,850,000 deposited by BlockFi, according to a court filing on Friday. &nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BlockFi filed for <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/188915\/crypto-firm-blockfi-files-for-bankruptcy\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">bankruptcy protection<\/span><\/a> in November 2022. Soon after filing, BlockFi began negotiating with Silvergate for the release of $10 million in a reserve account held at the bank, and it reached an agreement on Friday for the bank to release a majority of those funds within two business days.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Silvergate has faced its own issues this week. In addition to capitalization problems, the La Jolla, Calif.-based bank said in a Securities and Exchange Commission filing on Wednesday that it faces, \"<span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">various <\/span><span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">litigation (including private litigation) and regulatory and other inquiries and investigations against or with respect to the Company, investigations from our <\/span><span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">banking regulators, congressional inquiries and investigations from the U.S. Department of <span class=\"highlight selected appended\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Justice.\"&nbsp;<\/span><\/span><\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">That's led to a raft of customer departures from the bank that built itself a position in the center of much of the U.S. crypto industry. Customers began <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/216548\/silvergates-network-unravels-leaving-crypto-industry-in-search-of-new-partners\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">dropping<\/span><\/a> the next day, including Coinbase, Circle, Paxos and Gemini, some citing their <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/216537\/coinbase-drops-silvergate-for-signature-for-prime-customers\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">moves<\/span><\/a> were made out of an “abundance of caution.” &nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Silvergate Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"La Jolla","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Michael B. Kaplan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Silvergate","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$9,850,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Calif.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S. Department of <span class=\"highlight selected appended\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Justice","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Circle","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$9.9 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"November 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$10 million","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}