{"summary":"A bankruptcy court allowed the sale of Compute North assets for $1.55 million to Crusoe Energy Systems.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/187900\/bankrupt-compute-north-selling-1-55-million-in-assets-to-crusoe","publishDate":"2022-11-16T23:34:34","id":8998,"type":null,"title":"Bankrupt Compute North selling $1.55 million in assets to Crusoe","category":["CRYPTO INFRASTRUCTURE"],"content":["Bitcoin mining hosting provider Compute North is selling 11 containers for around $1.55 million to Crusoe Energy Systems.","The U.S. Bankruptcy Court in the Southern District of Texas, Houston Division approved the sale, according to documents <a href=\"https:\/\/document.epiq11.com\/document\/getdocumentbycode?docId=4120276&amp;projectCode=CPN&amp;source=DM\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filed<\/a> Wednesday.","Crusoe had already made a deposit worth $187,000 on Oct. 28, according to the filing. The company did not receive any other qualifying bids before the deadline.","As other companies in the bitcoin mining industry struggle with liquidity and have been forced to sell off assets, Crusoe has been on a shopping spree, also <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/176598\/bitcoin-miner-crusoe-acquires-great-american-mining\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">acquiring<\/a> its competitor Great American Mining in October <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/153816\/bitcoin-miner-crusoe-acquires-electrical-manufacturer-easter-owens\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">and electrical manufacturer Easter-Owens Electric Co<\/a> in July.","The Denver-based company operates modular data centers, using natural gas that would otherwise be flared. It recently <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/142890\/flare-gas-powered-bitcoin-miner-crusoe-energy-systems-raises-505-million\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">raised $505 million<\/a> in a Series C round to accelerate the growth of its mining operation.","Compute North filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy in September, stating that it had between $100 million-$500 million both in estimated liabilities and estimated assets. Recently it also agreed to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/181992\/bankrupt-mining-provider-compute-north-sells-assets-to-its-former-lender\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">sell two mining facilities<\/a> to its former lender Generate Capital for $5 million.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S. Bankruptcy Court","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Compute North","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$505 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$100 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Generate Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$1.55 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Southern District of Texas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Denver","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Great American Mining","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$500 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Crusoe Energy Systems","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Houston Division","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$187,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Oct. 28","content":"DATE"},{"type":"October","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Owens Electric Co","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$5 million","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["MINING COMPANIES"],"authors":["Catarina Moura","The Block"]}