{"summary":"DIBA launches “the first Bitcoin NFT marketplace” to leverage RGB smart contracts.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/231379\/bitcoin-nft-marketplace-rgb-protocol","publishDate":"2023-05-18T12:52:19","id":9017,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin NFT marketplace using RGB protocol launches, CEO calls BRC-20 tokens a dumb ‘experiment’","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">With interest in tokenized assets on Bitcoin at an all-time high amid massive growth in both the trading volume of Ordinals and BRC-20 tokens market capitalization, a Tim Draper-backed NFT marketplace has announced its launch.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">U.S.-based DIBA, an acronym for <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Digital Bitcoin Art and Assets,<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> said it's rolling out what it calls “the first Bitcoin NFT marketplace” to leverage RGB smart contracts. The RGB protocol is designed to <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">provide “enhanced security, privacy, scalability, and reduced transaction fees” while making it easier to tokenize assets on Bitcoin, said DIBA’s founder and CEO <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Gideon Nweze.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“This marks a major milestone in the transition of the internet onto Bitcoin,” Nweze said. “T<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">his will revolutionize Bitcoin since it is highly compatible with existing Bitcoin infrastructure. You can think of DIBA as a gateway to what's possible on Bitcoin.”<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Nweze, although bullish on Bitcoin's potential, hasn’t been thrilled by recent innovations like Ordinals and BRC-20 tokens, though they <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">demonstrate “there is demand for such assets” on the popular blockchain, he said.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“BRC-20 is the dumbest technical experiment in crypto, and I have been around for some time,” said <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Nweze. “<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ordinals and BRC-20 tokens are basically trying to force Ethereum on Bitcoin. In practice, it's inefficient, clunky, and not as effective as it could be.”<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">DIBA’s launch includes promoting BitMask, a “Bitcoin-only” crypto wallet that can “<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">hold music and art unique digital assets,” or UDAs, the company said in a statement. With the backing of <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Draper Associates, a venture capital firm, one of DIBA's missions is “to bring Bitcoin utility to the masses through enabling the exchange of UDAs,” the company also said.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Another of <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Nweze’s main goals includes fostering a mass migration of tokenized assets like NFTs from <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ethereum to Bitcoin. He also thinks the move could help avoid regulatory complications in the U.S.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>“Bitcoin is the only asset considered not a security by the SEC, and smart contracts that inherit Bitcoin's properties might be viewed favorably by the regulators,” he said.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"RGB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DIBA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Draper Associates","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"20","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Nweze","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tim Draper","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BRC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gideon Nweze","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"This marks","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}