{"summary":"Bitcoin was trading below $23,000 as broader crypto prices perked up. Equities were in the red.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/209660\/bitcoin-steady-around-23000-as-ether-moves-higher-equites-in-the-red","publishDate":"2023-02-08T11:04:19","id":9019,"type":null,"title":"Bitcoin steady around $23,000 as ether moves higher; equites in the red","category":["MARKETS"],"content":["Bitcoin was hovering around $23,000 as ether gained. The Sandbox token jumped on news of metaverse partnership talks with Saudi Arabia. Equities slipped.","The leading cryptocurrency by market capitalization was trading around $22,900 at 10:30 a.m. EST, down about 0.2% over the past day, according to TradingView data. It&nbsp;had risen on Tuesday ahead of U.S. Federal Reserve Chair Jerome Powell's <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/209334\/crypto-markets-tread-water-ahead-of-fed-speech\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">talk<\/a> with Carlyle Group's David Rubenstein.","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.tradingview.com\/chart\/xAJYa739\/?symbol=COINBASE%3ABTCUSD\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BTCUSD chart by TradingView<\/span><\/a>","Ether added 2% over the past day as it traded above $1,660. Binance's BNB was flat, Ripple's XRP gained 1.2%, and Solana's SOL jumped 2%. Polygon's MATIC soared almost 6%, trading above $1.30.","The Sandbox token price continues to soar after the metaverse game platform revealed discussions of a partnership with Saudi Arabia. SAND was trading around $0.84, up nearly 18% by 10:30 a.m. EST, according to TradingView data. The token began to climb following <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/209630\/sand-token-jumps-over-20-following-metaverse-discussions-with-saudi-arabia\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">news<\/a> of a memorandum of understanding with the Middle Eastern nation around 4 p.m. EST yesterday.&nbsp;","The Nasdaq 100 was down around 1.2%, while the S&amp;P 500 dropped 0.7%.&nbsp;","Coinbase shares dipped about 2%, clinging to $70 by 10:30 a.m. EST, according to Nasdaq data.&nbsp;","Silvergate was down about 2.4% to $18. Jack Dorsey's Block fell 1% to trade just above $83, while MicroStrategy dropped over 2.6% to $276.50.","CME Group said on its earnings call earlier that it remains confident in its reputation as the trusted regulated marketplace for digital assets.","The CME added over 700 new digital asset customers in January as trading volumes <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/207249\/cmes-crypto-derivatives-reach-new-highs-as-traders-seek-safe-port-in-storm\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">soared<\/a>. Bitcoin options volume on the CME reached an all-time high of $1.1 billion in January, according to The Block data.&nbsp;","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/crypto-markets\/options\/volume-and-oi-of-cme-bitcoin-options\/embed\" title=\"Volume and OI of CME Bitcoin options\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","The exchange also noted that 934 accounts were added in November, more than double the typical monthly figure, and said it was a sign of the marketplace broadly turning to CME during stress periods.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Saudi Arabia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"10:30 a.m. EST","content":"TIME"},{"type":"6%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"TradingView","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"0.7%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"CME Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1.30","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"S&amp;P","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$0.84","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Carlyle Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"1.2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$18","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"CME","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"David Rubenstein","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Middle Eastern","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$83","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2.6%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2.4%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$276.50","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$1,660","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"0.2%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Jack Dorsey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"18%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$23,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Jerome Powell","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"BNB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$22,900","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"4 p.m. EST yesterday","content":"TIME"},{"type":"1%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"$1.1 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$70","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"MicroStrategy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nasdaq","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN","EARNINGS","ECONOMIC INDICATORS","EQUITY MOVERS","ETHEREUM","POLYGON","RATE DECISIONS"],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}