{"summary":"ScienceMagic.Studios is a “token venture asset studio working with the biggest communities and brands,” Pal said.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/155650\/raoul-pal-co-founds-new-token-venture-asset-business-in-web3","publishDate":"2022-07-03T05:39:40","id":9042,"type":null,"title":"Raoul Pal co-founds new token venture asset business in web3 ","category":["NFTS"],"content":["<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Macro investor Raoul Pal said today in a <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.linkedin.com\/posts\/raoul-pal-real-vision_sciencemagicstudios-activity-6949184443592970241-zWj1\/?utm_source=linkedin_share&amp;utm_medium=ios_app\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">LinkedIn post<\/span><\/a><span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that he has co-founded a new business in web3.<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.sciencemagicstudios.xyz\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ScienceMagic.Studios<\/span><\/a><span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> is a “token venture asset studio working with the biggest communities and brands,” Pal said in the post.<\/span>&nbsp;<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n&nbsp;<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">He added that the company’s&nbsp;mission is&nbsp;to “tokenize the world’s largest cultural communities –&nbsp;music, fashion, movies\/book\/TV franchises and sports –&nbsp;utilizing NFTs, social tokens and metaverse.”<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Pal’s LinkedIn profile lists him as co-founder and&nbsp;CEO of the&nbsp;Real Vision Group, publisher of&nbsp;the Global Macro Investor and co-founder of Exponential Age Asset Management.&nbsp;<\/span>&nbsp;<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n&nbsp;<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Pal said&nbsp;that investors in the new enterprise include Liberty City Ventures, Coinbase Ventures, DCG, Brevan Howard Digital and other firms. He also identified his co-founders as Kevin Kelly of Delphi Digital and David Pemsel, ex-CEO of the Guardian Media Group.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"DCG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Brevan Howard Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Real Vision Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"today","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Raoul Pal","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Liberty City Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Exponential Age Asset Management","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Guardian Media Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coinbase Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kevin Kelly","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"David Pemsel","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Delphi Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Mike Millard","The Block"]}