{"summary":"The WSJ reports that crypto exchanges FTX and Binance are leading the auction for embattled crypto-lender Voyager.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/171533\/binance-and-ftx-lead-voyager-auction-wsj","publishDate":"2022-09-20T17:58:23","id":9053,"type":null,"title":"Binance and FTX lead Voyager auction: WSJ","category":["LEGAL"],"content":["Crypto exchanges FTX and Binance are leading the auction for embattled crypto-lender Voyager, according to a new <a href=\"https:\/\/www.wsj.com\/articles\/binance-and-ftx-make-top-bids-for-bankrupt-lender-voyager-11663708731\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">report<\/a> from the Wall Street Journal.","The <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/168264\/bankrupt-voyager-digital-to-hold-asset-auction-on-september-13\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">auction<\/a> for Voyager began last week in the law offices of Kirkland &amp; Ellis, though a bid has yet to be accepted six days on. According to today's report, Binance bid approximately $50 million for the platform's assets. That's a slightly higher bid than FTX, according to the WSJ's sources.&nbsp;","Lawyers in the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/155990\/crypto-broker-voyager-digital-files-for-chapter-11-bankruptcy\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">bankruptcy<\/a> process have yet to give an update on the bidding process, disclosing only that it remains ongoing. Bidders may submit a variety of types of proposals, from a simple purchase of Voyager's assets to an attempted restructuring and resuscitation of the firm.","Voyager has not broadly disclosed its ideal proposal, though it did <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/159387\/voyager-document-says-ftx-alameda-proposal-has-misleading-or-outright-false-claims\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">push back<\/a> when FTX publicized its <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/159209\/ftx-alameda-propose-early-liquidity-plan-for-voyager-digital-customers\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">plan<\/a> to provide early liquidity to customers, saying the exchange failed to respect the confidentiality stipulations of the bidding process. At the time, counsel called it a low-ball bid and sought to dispel the notion that FTX was a frontrunner for the platform.&nbsp;","Meanwhile, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/business\/2022\/09\/16\/binances-attempt-to-buy-voyager-digitals-assets-complicated-by-national-security-concern-source\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reports<\/a> have circulated that Binance is facing some opposition over its bid due to concerns that the U.S. government might take issue with its attempt to purchase the platform.&nbsp;","The auction winner is slated for announcement at a Sept. 29 hearing.","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Kirkland &amp; Ellis","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"WSJ","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sept. 29","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$50 million","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE","FTX"],"authors":["Aislinn Keely","The Block"]}