{"summary":"The Treasury undersecretary for domestic finance said there were plans among Federal Reserve, White House, and departmental officials to meet &quot;regularly&quot; to discuss a potential digital dollar.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/216340\/u-s-treasury-convening-regular-biden-administration-discussions-on-cbdc","publishDate":"2023-03-01T14:38:00","id":9066,"type":null,"title":"U.S. Treasury convening regular Biden administration discussions on CBDC","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The U.S. Treasury, Federal Reserve and White House officials “will begin to meet regularly” to talk about a possible central bank digital currency, said Nellie Liang, undersecretary for domestic finance at Treasury, in a speech delivered to the Atlantic Council in Washington.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Treasury-led CBDC working group will study the issue further and<\/span><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> complement the Fed’s ongoing research into a digital dollar. Treasury recommended the working group in one of the digital asset policy papers it released last September.&nbsp;<\/span>","Liang emphasized that the working group does not necessarily signal a shift in U.S. policy over a digital dollar, with the Fed still in a lead research role.","\"The Fed has also emphasized that it would only issue a CBDC with the support of the executive branch and Congress, and more broadly the public,\" said Liang.&nbsp;","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A CBDC could be either retail or wholesale, Liang said. A wholesale CBDC would be accessible to financial institutions that are already eligible for central bank accounts. A retail CBDC would be a complement to cash, and not replace it. &nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Full consideration of these issues for a possible CBDC – wholesale, retail, or both – will take some time to complete, but the Working Group plans to provide interim public updates,” Liang said.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Fed has said it would only issue a CBDC if it had support from the executive branch, Congress and the public, though several Fed leaders have made public remarks indicating that a push for a digital dollar is not imminent. One of the Fed's most-engaged leaders on the digital dollar issue, Lael Brainard, is now the National Economic Council director, a top White House advisory position to President Joe Biden. <\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Nellie Liang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Working Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"U.S. Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fed","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Washington","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Lael Brainard","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Congress","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"National Economic Council","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"White House","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Liang","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Joe Biden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Fed","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Federal Reserve and White House","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Atlantic Council","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"last September","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["CBDCS","FEDERAL RESERVE","TREASURY DEPARTMENT"],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}