{"summary":"Matt Hougan, global head of research at Bitwise, told The Block: “We did indeed withdraw the application. This is a procedural step, and we intend to refile our application at an appropriate time.”","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/53058\/bitwise-withdraws-bitcoin-etf-proposal","publishDate":"2020-01-15T01:46:31","id":9090,"type":null,"title":"Bitwise withdraws bitcoin ETF proposal","category":["BITCOIN"],"content":["Cryptocurrency asset management firm Bitwise - for now, at least - has withdrawn its bitcoin exchange-traded fund (ETF) proposal.","According to a <a href=\"https:\/\/sec.report\/Document\/0001493152-20-000557\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">note<\/a> submitted to the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) on Tuesday, Bitwise said the move is “consistent with the public interest and protection of investors.”","Matt Hougan, global head of research at Bitwise, confirmed the move to The Block, stating:","“We did indeed withdraw the application. This is a procedural step, and we intend to refile our application at an appropriate time.”","Hougan added that the firm is currently “working hard” on answering the questions that the SEC raised in its <a href=\"https:\/\/www.sec.gov\/rules\/sro\/nysearca\/2019\/34-87267.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">112-page response<\/a> to its initial filing. “We remain fully committed to the development of a bitcoin ETF.”","Bitwise is yet to determine timelines for the refiling.","The news comes just weeks after Bitwise <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/51341\/bitwise-writes-to-sec-again-saying-it-is-committed-to-creating-a-bitcoin-etf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a> it is “committed” to provide all investors with the ability to access bitcoin in a regulated and familiar fund format.&nbsp;","Bitwise first filed its ETF proposal along with NYSE Arca in January 2019. Since then, Bitwise has met with the SEC eight times, Hougan told The Block last month, adding that the firm has also submitted 500 pages of a whitepaper and a presentation on fake volume during the period.","In September, Cboe BZX Exchange also <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/linked\/40020\/vaneck-solidx-withdraws-bitcoin-etf-proposal\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">withdrew<\/a> its VanEck\/SolidX bitcoin ETF proposal after facing rejections.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">At present, Wilshire Phoenix’s bitcoin and U.S. Treasury bond ETF proposal is the only proposal pending for review with the SEC and is <a href=\"https:\/\/www.sec.gov\/rules\/sro\/nysearca\/2019\/34-87813.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">expected<\/a> to be ruled on by Feb. 26.<\/span>","Several firms have filed bitcoin ETF proposals, but none has yet got the approval as the SEC remains concerned about market manipulation. Jay Clayton, chairman of the SEC, once <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/4153\/sec-chair-crypto-etf-approval-is-dependent-on-exchanges-being-free-from-manipulation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a>&nbsp;he doesn’t see a pathway to a crypto ETF approval until concerns over market manipulation are addressed.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Bitwise","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Matt Hougan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S. Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jay Clayton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bitwise","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cboe BZX Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Feb. 26","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Wilshire Phoenix","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"January 2019","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Hougan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NYSE Arca","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["SEC"],"authors":["Yogita Khatri","The Block"]}