{"summary":"The venture capital firm says the money will be used to invest in early-stage entrepreneurs all over the world.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/157116\/lightspeed-raises-over-7-billion-across-four-funds-launches-new-crypto-native-team","publishDate":"2022-07-12T10:44:11","id":9092,"type":null,"title":"Lightspeed raises over $7 billion across four funds","category":["VENTURE CAPITAL"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Venture capital firm Lightspeed announced today that it had secured over $7 billion in capital to be invested across four new funds aimed at \"early-stage entrepreneurs across the globe,\" including one focused on India. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The firm also unveiled an independent<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> \"crypto-native team” called Lightspeed Faction, which will be led by investors Sam Harrison and Banafsheh Fathieh. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Faction believes the innovation economy is at the precipice of a significant computing paradigm shift with blockchain companies leading,\" the announcement stated.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The four funds revealed today are called Lightspeed Venture Partners XIV-A\/B LP, Lightspeed Venture Partners Select V LP, Lightspeed Opportunity Fund II LP and Lightspeed India Partners Fund IV. The funds closed with $1.98 billion, $2.26 billion, $2.36 billion and $500 million, respectively.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The announcement comes amid a general slowdown in venture capital dealmaking, as the turbulence in equity markets and rising inflation have had ramifications in the private market. As The Block reported previously, May was the <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/news+\/151103\/may-crypto-funding-roundup-vc-deals\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">slowest month for crypto<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> venture capital deals in the last six months.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Lightspeed India Partners Fund IV","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$2.36 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"B LP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Lightspeed Faction","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lightspeed Opportunity Fund II LP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lightspeed","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lightspeed Venture Partners Select V LP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Harrison","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$7 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$500 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Banafsheh Fathieh","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$1.98 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"India","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Lightspeed Venture Partners XIV","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$2.26 billion","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sam Venis","The Block"]}