{"summary":"Troubled crypto trading and lending firm Genesis owes its creditors at least $1.8 billion, CoinDesk reported Sunday.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/192041\/troubled-crypto-lender-genesis-owes-creditors-at-least-1-8-billion-coindesk","publishDate":"2022-12-05T03:25:38","id":9111,"type":null,"title":"Troubled crypto lender Genesis owes creditors at least $1.8 billion: CoinDesk","category":["FINANCE FIRMS"],"content":["<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Troubled crypto trading and lending firm Genesis owes its creditors at least $1.8 billion, CoinDesk&nbsp;<\/span><a class=\"editor-rtfLink\" href=\"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/business\/2022\/12\/04\/genesis-creditor-groups-loans-amount-to-18b-and-counting-sources\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;Sunday.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Financial Times first&nbsp;<\/span><a class=\"editor-rtfLink\" href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/191928\/genesis-owes-900-million-to-gemini-customers-financial-times\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;on Saturday that Genesis owes customers of Gemini's Earn program $900 million. In addition to that, Genesis owes another $900 million to a group of assorted creditors, which law firm Proskauer Rose is representing, according to the CoinDesk report, which cited an anonymous source.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In addition to the Proskauer group, there is another ad hoc group of Genesis creditors being represented by law firm Kirkland &amp; Ellis, CoinDesk reported. The amount owed to this group is unknown. Bloomberg&nbsp;<\/span><a class=\"editor-rtfLink\" href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/190811\/genesis-creditors-organize-in-bid-to-forestall-bankruptcy-move-bloomberg\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;last week that Proskauer Rose and Kirkland &amp; Ellis are representing groups of Genesis creditors.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Law firm Latham &amp; Watkins is representing the Gemini customers group, according to CoinDesk.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Genesis&nbsp;<\/span><a class=\"editor-rtfLink\" href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/187516\/genesis-halts-customer-withdrawals-in-wake-of-three-arrows-and-ftx-collapses-coindesk\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">halted<\/span><\/a><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;client withdrawals last month after taking large hits from FTX and earlier from Three Arrows Capital. The firm has been trying to raise funds and has hired investment bank Moelis &amp; Company to explore its options, which include a potential bankruptcy.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">U.S. state securities regulators are&nbsp;<\/span><a class=\"editor-rtfLink\" href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/190023\/genesis-global-capital-investigated-by-u-s-regulators-barrons\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reportedly<\/span><\/a><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;investigating Genesis. Alabama is said to be one of the states that is looking into whether Genesis \"enticed residents to invest in crypto-related securities without making the proper registrations,\" according to Barron's.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Sunday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$900 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Gemini","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Proskauer Rose","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"CoinDesk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Latham &amp; Watkins","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1.8 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Kirkland &amp; Ellis","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Moelis &amp; Company","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kirkland &amp; Ellis, CoinDesk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Three Arrows Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alabama","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Proskauer","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Financial Times","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Barron's","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Genesis","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Saturday","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Yogita Khatri","The Block"]}