{"summary":"Big trading firms may provide liquidity for BlackRock&#x27;s spot bitcoin ETF if it obtains regulatory approval, according to CoinDesk. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/260267\/big-market-makers-are-in-talks-with-blackrock-to-provide-liquidity-for-its-proposed-spot-bitcoin-etf-coindesk","publishDate":"2023-10-31T14:39:45","id":9117,"type":null,"title":"Big market makers are in talks with BlackRock to provide liquidity for its proposed spot bitcoin ETF: CoinDesk","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Big trading firms are in talks to provide liquidity for BlackRock’s proposed spot bitcoin exchange-traded fund if it obtains regulatory approval, according to CoinDesk.&nbsp;<\/span>","&nbsp;","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Big trading firms are in talks to provide liquidity for BlackRock's proposed spot bitcoin exchange-traded fund if it obtains regulatory approval, according to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/business\/2023\/10\/31\/blackrocks-bitcoin-etf-might-have-trading-support-of-heavyweights-like-jane-street-jump-and-virtu-source\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reporting<\/span><\/a> from CoinDesk.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Jane Street, Virtu Financial, Jump Trading and Hudson River Trading have reportedly been in talks with BlackRock about a market-making role to provide that liquidity, according to a BlackRock slide deck reviewed by someone familiar with the matter, according to CoinDesk.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Market makers are necessary for ETFs in providing liquidity, matching buyers and sellers, and aiding in creating and redeeming those ETF shares.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BlackRock and Jane Street declined to comment. Virtu Financial, Jump Trading and Hudson River Trading did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Virtu and Jane Street wrote in support of a separate proposal for a spot bitcoin ETF this past summer. \"The bitcoin ecosystem is sufficiently robust to support a US-listed ETP,\" Jane Street wrote in a comment <a href=\"https:\/\/www.sec.gov\/comments\/sr-nysearca-2021-90\/srnysearca202190-20131689-302096.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">letter<\/span><\/a> on Grayscale's proposal for its product.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Virtu also said investors in the U.S. would benefit from SEC approval of Grayscale's proposal for a spot bitcoin ETF, in its <a href=\"https:\/\/www.sec.gov\/comments\/sr-nysearca-2021-90\/srnysearca202190-20123653-279889.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">letter<\/span><\/a> supporting converting GBTC.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitcoin's value swiftly rose over the last few weeks following speculation around BlackRock's highly anticipated spot bitcoin ETF, which<\/span><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> is still under review by the SEC.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BlackRock CEO Larry Fink said earlier this month that a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/257826\/blackrocks-larry-fink-says-bitcoin-rumor-rally-shows-pent-up-interest-in-crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">rally<\/span><\/a> in the price of bitcoin triggered by a false news report that said its spot ETF was approved served as an example of \"pent up interest in crypto.\"&nbsp;<\/span><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The SEC has not yet approved a spot bitcoin ETF.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Hudson River Trading","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"BlackRock","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Grayscale","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"earlier this month","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Virtu Financial","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Larry Fink","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Jane Street","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"CoinDesk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"summer","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["SEC"],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}