{"summary":"Crypto&#x27;s all-in-one market structure was due for a change, in hindsight, DRW&#x27;s crypto trading shop Cumberland said on Monday.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/186676\/cumberland-ftx-collapse-to-trigger-structural-change-in-crypto-markets-away-from-centralization","publishDate":"2022-11-14T10:48:33","id":9203,"type":null,"title":"Cumberland: FTX collapse to trigger structural change in crypto markets, away from centralization","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["The collapse of FTX last week will trigger significant market structure changes, namely moving away from a model of all-in-one platform centralization, crypto trading firm Cumberland said.","The various functions of crypto spot trading have been trending toward a model of all-in-one platform centralization, Cumberland's Head of Trading Jonah Van Bourg <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/CumberlandSays\/status\/1592104977782444033\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/a> on Twitter today. Van Bourg was referring specifically to liquidity, clearing, settlement, custody and lending. These functions were \"coalescing under a very limited number of roofs.\"&nbsp;","Centralized exchanges had many incentives for pushing this all-in-one model. Van Bourg said that, in hindsight, some of these were \"perverse.\"&nbsp;","Last week's <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/186132\/ftx-collapse-timeline-six-days-that-rocked-the-crypto-industry\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">developments<\/a> — the collapse of FTX and its eventual chapter 11 filing — triggered a \"handbrake turn,\" Van Bourg said. He added that the crypto market structure seems likely to mirror foreign exchange markets. Assets and capital aren't left on centralized exchanges in foreign exchange markets.&nbsp;","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Cumberland's Head of Trading Jonah Van Bourg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bourg","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Cumberland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"hindsight","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["FTX","SAM BANKMAN-FRIED"],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}