{"summary":"Rep. Sean Casten, D-Ill., said he plans to introduce a bill to strengthen bank secrecy act requirements for cryptocurrency.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/259559\/senator-elizabeth-warren-finds-support-in-us-house-for-effort-to-tackle-crypto-financed-terrorism","publishDate":"2023-10-25T18:17:53","id":9214,"type":null,"title":"Senator Elizabeth Warren finds support in US House for effort to tackle crypto-financed terrorism","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">U.S. Rep. Sean Casten, D-Ill., said he plans to introduce a bill to strengthen bank secrecy act requirements for cryptocurrency following reports that Hamas raised millions of dollars through crypto ahead of attacks in Israel earlier this month.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">That legislation will be similar to a bill Sen. Elizabeth Warren, D-Mass., <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/258183\/sen-elizabeth-warren-joins-more-than-100-lawmakers-to-ask-biden-about-plans-to-prevent-crypto-financed-terrorism\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">introduced<\/a>, Casten told the House Financial Services Committee's panel on illicit finance and national security on Wednesday during a hearing.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"We will be introducing a bill that Senator Warren has already introduced on the Senate side to do that over here,\" Casten said. Casten did not specify which bill, but Sen. Warren reintroduced a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.warren.senate.gov\/newsroom\/press-releases\/warren-marshall-manchin-graham-renew-push-for-bipartisan-legislation-to-crack-down-on-cryptos-use-in-money-laundering-drug-trafficking-and-financing-of-terrorism-and-rogue-nations\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">bill<\/span><\/a> in July that would <\/span><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">crack down on the use of crypto for money laundering and sanctions evasion as well as extend Bank Secrecy Act requirements to digital asset wallet providers, miners, among other participants.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The use of crypto by terrorist organizations has been spotlighted after a Wall Street Journal <a href=\"https:\/\/www.wsj.com\/world\/middle-east\/militants-behind-israel-attack-raised-millions-in-crypto-b9134b7a?mod=e2tw\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">report<\/span><\/a> found that Hamas, along with other militant groups, raised millions worth of crypto ahead of attacks in Israel. WSJ cited crypto researcher Elliptic, which on Wednesday said that figures recently used to portray the scale of crypto fundraising by Hamas were being <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/259527\/elliptic-says-scale-of-crypto-based-terrorism-funding-is-being-misrepresented\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">misrepresented<\/span><\/a>.&nbsp;<\/span>","\"We have spoken to representatives of the lead signatory, Senator Warren, as well as the authors of the Wall Street Journal article, to clarify this,\" <span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Elliptic said.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Since the recent attacks in Israel on Oct. 7, the firm said only $21,000 in fresh crypto donations have arrived, with much of it already frozen.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"The unique traceability of these assets have meant that the amounts raised remain tiny compared to other funding sources,\" Elliptic said. \"No public crypto fundraising campaign by a terrorist group has received significant levels of donations, relative to other funding sources.\"<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Former House Financial Services Committee Chair Maxine Waters, D-Calif., also asked witnesses on Wednesday about cryptocurrency's connection to Iran and Hamas.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"What we see is Hamas utilizing cryptocurrency to fundraise. That does happen,\" said Adam Zarazinski, CEO of Inca Digital, a data analytics intelligence firm focused on crypto.&nbsp;<\/span>","\"While cryptocurrency can be employed in activities that challenge our security and values, it also holds the potential to democratize finance, spur economic growth, and foster financial inclusion globally,\" he added.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Mass.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Warren","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Adam Zarazinski","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sean Casten","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Inca Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Casten","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Oct. 7","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ill.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Hamas","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Israel","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$21,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Calif.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"millions of dollars","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"House Financial Services Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Former House Financial Services Committee Chair Maxine Waters","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Iran","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Elizabeth Warren","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Senate","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}