{"summary":"Loomdart delves into &#x27;FTX 2.0&#x27; as a unique opportunity to restore value for FTX creditors.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/230763\/loomdart-ftx-restart","publishDate":"2023-05-15T09:36:39","id":9249,"type":null,"title":"Crypto anon Loomdart makes the case for FTX 2.0 to go ahead","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 47<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 5 of The Scoop was recorded with <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro and&nbsp;Loomdart, co-founder of eGirl Capital.<\/strong><\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a>,<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Please send feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"53233c373032202713273b36313f3c30387d303c\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/i>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm\/?e=BLOCK6058825307\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Loomdart, a veteran member of the crypto community and the co-founder of eGirl Capital, is advocating for an FTX reboot.","In this episode, Loomdart explains why 'FTX 2.0' could represent an opportunity for over a million FTX creditors to be made whole in a unique way.","As Loomdart explains,","\"My quickest pitch for FTX 2.0 is you effectively get to 'airdrop' an exchange to over a million people who have a big vested interest in using this exchange.\"","Last month, a potential reboot plan for FTX <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/226908\/ftx-tribe-capital\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reportedly<\/a> caught the attention of venture capital firm Tribe Capital.","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">During this episode, Chaparro and Loomdart also discuss:<\/em>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsor <i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.cleanspark.com\/theblock\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CleanSpark<\/a>.<\/i><\/b><\/span>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About CleanSpark<\/strong>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CleanSpark (NASDAQ: CLSK) is America’s Bitcoin Miner™. Visit <a href=\"https:\/\/www.cleanspark.com\/theblock\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">cleanspark.com\/theblock<\/a> to learn more about the CleanSpark way.<\/span><\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tribe Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"America","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Loomdart","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Loomdart","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}