{"summary":"To help score more branding opportunities, metaverse land developer LandVault has signed with top Hollywood talent agency CAA.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/203461\/metaverse-land-developer-landvault-signs-with-hollywood-powerbroker-caa","publishDate":"2023-01-18T13:53:12","id":9262,"type":null,"title":"Metaverse land developer LandVault signs with Hollywood powerbroker CAA","category":["METAVERSE & NFT"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Virtual land developer LandVault, which has worked with global brands like Mastercard, L’Oreal and Heineken, announced it has signed with top talent agency Creative Artists Agency.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/119987\/hollywood-talent-agency-caa-signs-nft-collector-0xb1-to-help-them-monetize-their-pieces\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CAA<\/a> will advise LandVault “on talent and brand-led metaverse opportunities” and explore “opportunities for newly created” intellectual property, the metaverse land developer’s representative said by email.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">LandVault has worked on more than 200 “metaverse activations” and has developed virtual land for platforms such as Roblox, Sandbox and Decentraland, the company said. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Signing with one of Hollywood’s most powerful dealmakers across sports and entertainment could help LandVault weather the bear market roiling the crypto space. Average land sale prices <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/197062\/metaverse-market-collapses-with-monthly-platform-sales-falling-96-so-far-this-year\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">have plummeted<\/a> since early last year.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">LandVault CEO Sam Huber is nevertheless optimistic. “As we spend more and more time online, the metaverse is going to become an increasingly popular entertainment destination,” he said in a statement. “With this new relationship, we are excited for the opportunity to work with one of the world’s top agencies and their clients as they enter the metaverse.”<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/nft-non-fungible-tokens\/gaming\/metaverse-average-land-sale-price\/embed\" title=\"Metaverse Average Land Sale Price\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Updates by deleting the mention that LandVault is being represented under CAA's Chief Metaverse Officer Joanna Popper and that Mack Flavelle is a client. Flavelle is represented by WME.&nbsp;<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Sam Huber","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Mastercard","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Heineken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"WME","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CAA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mack Flavelle","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Roblox","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Creative Artists Agency","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Decentraland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Joanna Popper","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}