{"summary":"Two of former FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried’s multi-million dollar jets, which have been part of bankruptcy talks, may end up being forfeited. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/254971\/sbf-flew-too-high-and-now-ftxs-luxury-jets-could-be-forfeited","publishDate":"2023-10-05T10:35:02","id":9270,"type":null,"title":"SBF flew too high, and now FTX&#x27;s luxury jets could be forfeited","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A Bombardier Global 5000 BD-700-1A11 and an Embraer Legacy EMB-135BJ are subject to forfeiture, prosecutors said in a filing on <a href=\"https:\/\/storage.courtlistener.com\/recap\/gov.uscourts.nysd.590939\/gov.uscourts.nysd.590939.314.0.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Wednesday<\/span><\/a><\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Bombardier was bought for $15.9 million and the Embraer for $12.5 million, according to court documents.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Two multi-million dollar jets connected to FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried and subject to the failed crypto exchange's bankruptcy over the past year may end up being forfeited.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A Bombardier Global 5000 BD-700-1A11 and an Embraer Legacy EMB-135BJ could be seized, prosecutors said in a filing on <a href=\"https:\/\/storage.courtlistener.com\/recap\/gov.uscourts.nysd.590939\/gov.uscourts.nysd.590939.314.0.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Wednesday<\/span><\/a>.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Bombardier was bought for $15.9 million and the Embraer for $12.5 million, according to court documents.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Paul Aranha founded Trans Island Airways, a Bahamian charter flight company that operated Bankman-Fried's planes to and from the Bahamas, according to a September <a href=\"https:\/\/www.courtlistener.com\/docket\/65748821\/2659\/1\/ftx-trading-ltd\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filing<\/span><\/a>.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"From approximately October 2021, TIA provided more than $15 million worth of private charter and cargo flights, customized plane upgrades and other services to SBF and other FTX executives, employees, business associates, guests, family, and friends,\" Aranha said.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Aranha said FTX wanted upgrades to the planes, including \"state-of-the-art wifi and entirely new interiors.\" Ultimately the planes were never used since the upgrades were still being worked on when FTX collapsed in November, Aranha said.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bankman-Fried is going into the third day of his trial on Thursday. He<\/span><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/236735\/judge-denies-motion-to-dismiss-most-charges-against-sam-bankman-fried\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">faces<\/span><\/a> decades in prison if he is convicted over a slew of charges including fraud over allegations that he and other FTX executives used billions of customer assets to make their own failed investments. FTX filed for bankruptcy late last year.&nbsp;<\/span>","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"TIA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bombardier","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Trans Island Airways","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Paul Aranha","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bombardier Global","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$12.5 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"October 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"November","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$15.9 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bahamas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$15 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Aranha","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Embraer Legacy EMB","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Embraer","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SBF","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["FTX","SBF TRIAL"],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}