{"summary":"The partnership will help fulfill the scaling need of dApps on Astar, a parachain that operates a smart contract platform on Polkadot.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/161182\/alchemy-polkadot-ecosystem-deal-with-astar","publishDate":"2022-08-03T09:28:58","id":9283,"type":null,"title":"Alchemy expands its infrastructure into Polkadot ecosystem via deal with Astar","category":["INFRASTRUCTURE"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Alchemy, a blockchain node <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/149849\/alchemy-is-bringing-its-blockchain-node-infrastructure-to-solana\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">infrastructure provider<\/a>, announced a deal to provide its node infrastructure to Astar, a blockchain on the Polkadot network. <\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Astar offers a smart contract service that supports dApps based on blockchain software stacks like Ethereum Virtual Machine and WebAssembly. It offers interoperability with other Polkadot's parachains. It hosts dApps like ArthSwap, Starlay Finance, AstridDAO, Algem, Sirius Finance and Zenlink.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The partnership, announced on Wednesday, allows Astar developers to use Alchemy's flagship offering called SuperNode to meet infrastructure requirements. <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Essentially, it functions as a middleware platform for Astar’s dApps to stay connected and prevent downtime.<\/span>","“Alchemy infrastructure makes it easier for developers to build any dApp with infinite scalability, accuracy and reliability,” Rob Boyle, head of product at Alchemy, said on the partnership. “We’re thrilled to combine forces with Astar to foster an era of better web3 building that will power the decentralized applications of tomorrow.”","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Alchemy offers its node application programming interface (API) service on three other blockchains including Ethereum, Polygon and Solana. It's used by popular apps on Ethereum like 0x, Aave, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/153478\/dydx-to-expand-to-its-own-blockchain-in-the-cosmos-ecosystem\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">dYdX<\/a>, OpenSea and Nifty Gateway for scaling needs. In February, Alchemy <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/133397\/alchemy-raises-at-10-2-billion-valuation-in-round-led-by-silver-lake\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">raised<\/a> $200 million at a $10.2 billion valuation.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Sirius Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"February","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Zenlink","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Rob Boyle","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ethereum Virtual Machine","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Algem","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$10.2 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Alchemy","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Polkadot","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ethereum","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$200 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Solana","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Starlay Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Vishal Chawla","The Block"]}