{"summary":"Largely an indictment of crypto mining and recent market crashes, the briefing saw almost no attendance as committee members took to the streets to protest the Supreme Court&#x27;s decision to overturn Roe v. Wade. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/154166\/house-dems-skip-closed-door-briefing-on-bitcoin-to-attend-roe-protests-after-supreme-court-ruling","publishDate":"2022-06-24T16:39:43","id":9298,"type":null,"title":"House Dems skip closed-door briefing on Bitcoin to attend Roe protests after Supreme Court ruling","category":["CONGRESS"],"content":["On Friday, Democrats on the House Financial Services Committee held a closed briefing on Bitcoin's environmental impact⁠ today, The Block has learned.","Three sources confirmed the noon briefing to The Block. A memo for the briefing seen by The Block identified four witnesses who were unanimously anti-crypto.","One, Princeton professor Arvind Narayanan, <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/random_walker\/status\/1540339256048205825\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweeted<\/a> shortly before appearing that \"blockchain has so far proven useless. Worse, it's proven a costly distraction to people and communities who are trying to solve real problems.\"","Another, Yvonne Taylor, <a href=\"https:\/\/senecalakeguardian.org\/Yvonne-Taylor\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">leads<\/a> an environmental organization that is working to shut down <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/139363\/greenidge-plans-to-triple-us-bitcoin-mining-capacity-after-securing-100-million-in-new-financing\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">mining operations<\/a> in upstate New York, calling it \"the test case for the encroaching wave of cryptocurrency mining that could result in the conversion of nearly 30 shuttered upstate power plants.\"","Attendance to the briefing, however, was sparse.","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.nytimes.com\/live\/2022\/06\/24\/us\/roe-wade-abortion-supreme-court\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">A Supreme Court decision Friday morning<\/a> overturned the Roe v. Wade decision, ending the federal right to abortion. Consequently, protests have surrounded the Supreme Court complex and pulled in a number of the Democrats on the committee, including <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/aletweetsnews\/status\/1540364776655708166\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Chair Maxine Waters<\/a>.","A source with knowledge of the briefing noted that no representatives attended, with very few staff. Prior to addressing the main issue of environmental impact, those in attendance focused on recent crashes in crypto, especially <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/152262\/following-celsius-freeze-us-policymakers-are-on-high-alert-for-crypto-systemic-contagion\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Celsius<\/a> and <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/146691\/terra-disaster-fuels-work-of-congress-on-stablecoin-legislation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Terra<\/a>.&nbsp;","Staff for Waters had not responded to requests for comment as of press time.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Roe v. Wade","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"upstate New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Supreme Court","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Arvind Narayanan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Yvonne Taylor","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"morning","content":"TIME"},{"type":"Terra","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"House Financial Services Committee","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitcoin","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Princeton","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"the Supreme Court","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["HOUSE FINANCIAL SERVICES COMMITTEE"],"authors":["Kollen Post","The Block"]}