{"summary":"Cameron Winklevoss has extended a “final offer” to Barry Silbert to pay a total debt of US$1.46 billion or risk a lawsuit to be filed against DCG and Silbert.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/237642\/geminis-winklevoss-demands-1-47-billion-payment-from-dcg-in-final-offer","publishDate":"2023-07-03T23:59:38","id":9346,"type":null,"title":"Gemini’s Winklevoss demands $1.47 billion payment from DCG in ‘final offer’","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Gemini threatens a lawsuit against DCG and founder Barry Silbert if they fail to accept the offer by July 6.<\/span>","Gemini Earn users are still in limbo with over $1.2 billion trapped in Genesis, Winklevoss says.","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Cameron Winklevoss, co-founder of crypto exchange Gemini, issued a “final offer” to Barry Silbert, founder of Digital Currency Group (DCG), to repay a total debt of $1.46 billion or risk a lawsuit.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In an&nbsp;<\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/cameron\/status\/1676024844641550337\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">open letter<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> published Monday on Twitter, Winklevoss said that the “games are over” — with Gemini Earn users still stuck in limbo with over $1.2 billion of assets stuck in Genesis Global, which DCG owns.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Winklevoss<\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/cameron\/status\/1676024845732126721\/photo\/1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">demanded<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> DCG make payments totaling $1.465 billion, including the <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/231656\/dcg-misses-630-million-payment-due-earlier-this-month-says-gemini\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">US$630 million payment<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that was due in May. As part of the offer, a payment of $275 million should be made by July 21.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“This proposal is fair and reasonable for everyone and represents the floor that creditors, who are required to support a deal, will accept,” Winklevoss said, adding that if Silbert fails to agree to this deal by 4 p.m. ET on July 6, Gemini will file a lawsuit against DCG and Silbert on July 7.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Gemini, which lent customer funds to Genesis as part of its retail Earn program, had previously <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/cameron\/status\/1616302998736756737?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw%7Ctwcamp%5Etweetembed%7Ctwterm%5E1616302998736756737%7Ctwgr%5E0965a1cab29423dfd80aa7a78f0ee24a06cf0947%7Ctwcon%5Es1_&amp;ref_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.coindesk.com%2Fbusiness%2F2023%2F01%2F20%2Fcameron-winklevoss-threatens-legal-action-against-dcg-ceo-after-genesis-bankruptcy%2F\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">threatened<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to file a lawsuit against DCG and its founder after Genesis Global <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/190311\/digital-currency-groups-genesis-global-files-for-bankruptcy-protection\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filed<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> for Chapter 11 bankruptcy in January.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">DCG, which was caught up the credit crisis that swept crypto last year, has been in negotiations with Genesis creditors, but<\/span> <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/231656\/dcg-misses-630-million-payment-due-earlier-this-month-says-gemini\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">missed<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> a $630 million payment to Genesis in May.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">DCG and Genesis did not immediately respond to The Block’s requests for comment.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In an <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.gemini.com\/earn\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">update<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> on June 30, Gemini said the mediation period has been extended to July 5 to determine the contribution to be made by DCG.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Gemini is disappointed in how long it has taken to negotiate a DCG contribution and we are committed to pushing DCG to pay what it already owes to Genesis and to compensate the Earn lenders for the role that DCG had in Genesis’s failure to return Earn assets to the Earn users,” Gemini wrote in the update.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"July 21","content":"DATE"},{"type":"DCG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gemini","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Winklevoss","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Silbert","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$630 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Barry Silbert","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"US$630 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Genesis","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Genesis","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$275 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"June 30","content":"DATE"},{"type":"4 p.m. ET","content":"TIME"},{"type":"Gemini","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"July 7","content":"DATE"},{"type":"July 6","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"July 5","content":"DATE"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gemini Earn","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Digital Currency Group (DCG","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Genesis Global","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Cameron Winklevoss","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$1.46 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$1.2 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Winklevoss","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$1.465 billion","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["GEMINI"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}