{"summary":"Web3 wallet Omni has raised $11 million in seed funding at a $50 million valuation following its rebranding.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/168262\/web3-wallet-omni-raises-11-million-in-seed-funding-at-a-50-million-valuation","publishDate":"2022-09-07T11:00:25","id":9360,"type":null,"title":"Web3 wallet Omni raises $11 million in seed funding","category":["WALLETS"],"content":["Omni, a noncustodial wallet aiming to increase access to web3 technologies, has raised an $11 million round at a $50 million valuation.","The deal closed in May and included investors such as <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spartan Group, GSR Ventures, and Eden Block, as well as OP Crypto, Shima Capital, Kosmos Ventures, Daedalus Angels, PrimeBlock Ventures, Figment Capital, Lattice Capital and Chorus One according to a statement. This was an equity deal with a token side letter in case Omni plans to release its own token, founder Serafin Lion Engel said over email.<\/span>","Founded by Engel, Alex Harley and James Stackhouse, the wallet — previously named Steakwallet — aims to increase accessibility to technologies such as staking and token swaps.&nbsp;","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"The primary hurdle that stands between users gaining access to the future of the internet, is ease of use. That’s why we built Omni: an incredibly easy-to-use Web 3 application that can do it all without sacrificing even a fraction of self-sovereignty,\" Engel said in the announcement. \"E<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">specially after seeing the CeFi meltdown, we wanted to give users something that was as easy to use as CeFi, but 100% self-custodial and DeFi. And that’s what we’ve done with Omni.\"&nbsp;<\/span>","Omni says that it has built its own custom smart contract middleware that allows users to stake on more than twenty protocols with liquid staking options built in. Users can also move tokens to different blockchains via bridges and displays NFTs from different blockchains on the mobile app.&nbsp;","The wallet plans to use the funding to expand its services and integrations. While currently available on all major Ethereum virtual machines and layer two scaling solutions such as Arbitrum, Optimism and Polygon, the company is readying integration with zkSync and Starknet.&nbsp;","The round follows similar raises by wallets aiming to build a more user-friendly version of MetaMask, the current go-to crypto wallet. In August, DeFi wallet startup Unstoppable Finance <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/160936\/defi-wallet-startup-unstoppable-finance-raises-e12-5-million\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">raised €12.5 million<\/a> in a round led by Lightspeed Ventures. Earlier this year, Ethereum wallet Rainbow <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/134298\/rainbow-raise\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">raised $18 million<\/a> in a round led by Seven Seven Six, the venture capital fund of Reddit co-founder Alexis Ohanian.","Fintech firms such as <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/147333\/robinhood-launches-defi-wallet-to-rival-metamask\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Robinhood<\/a> and <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/147768\/revoluts-planned-native-token-will-reward-customer-loyalty-storonosky-says\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Revolut<\/a> have also pledged to launch challengers to MetaMask, but have yet to follow through.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"OP Crypto","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spartan Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Reddit","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$11 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Engel","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alexis Ohanian","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"100%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Alex Harley","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Rainbow","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fintech","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"GSR Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"PrimeBlock Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Daedalus Angels","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"James Stackhouse","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Unstoppable Finance","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Figment Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Robinhood","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lightspeed Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$18 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Engel","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kosmos Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Eden Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lattice Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Serafin Lion Engel","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Shima Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$50 million","content":"MONEY"}],"hashtag":["WALLETS"],"authors":["Tom Matsuda","The Block"]}