{"summary":"117 Partners Founder Thomas Braziel cast doubt on whether a rejuvenated FTX would ever succeed, calling it &quot;a head fake.&quot;","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/262327\/ftt-rallies-over-80-after-gary-genslers-nod-to-possible-ftx-reboot","publishDate":"2023-11-09T07:08:47","id":9380,"type":null,"title":"FTT rallies over 70% after Gary Gensler gives nod to possible FTX reboot","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["The token associated with the defunct FTX cryptocurrency exchange has experienced a price surge of over 80% in the past 24 hours. The rally comes after U.S. Securities Exchange Commission Chair Gary Gensler hinted that he would be open to a rebooted FTX — as long as its done \"within the law.\"","FTT is now changing hands for $2.27, gaining over 80% in the past 24 hours, as of 6.55 a.m. ET, according to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coingecko.com\/en\/coins\/ftx-token\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CoinGecko<\/a>.","The token's price surge comes as <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/262228\/spot-trading-volume-increases-after-multiple-months-of-decline\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">spot trading volumes<\/a> increase across all major centralized cryptocurrency exchanges.","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"420\" src=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/data\/crypto-markets\/spot\/cryptocurrency-exchange-volume-monthly\/embed\" title=\"Cryptocurrency Monthly Exchange Volume\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","The news comes after it was reported that Gensler said FTX could be revived under new leadership. According to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.cnbc.com\/2023\/11\/08\/secs-gensler-says-rebooted-ftx-is-possible-if-done-within-the-law.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CNBC<\/a> on Wednesday the SEC Chair gave his views on reports that Tom Farley, a former president of the New York Stock Exchange, is among a short list of bidders attempting to buy the bankrupt FTX exchange.&nbsp;","\"If Tom or anybody else wanted to be in this field, I would say, 'Do it within the law,'\" Gensler said at DC Fintech Week. \"Build the trust of investors in what you’re doing and ensure that you’re doing the proper disclosures, and also that you’re not commingling all these functions, trading against your customers. Or using their crypto assets for your own purposes,\" Gensler added.","In September, The Block <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/250492\/crypto-exchange-bullish-among-bidders-for-bankrupt-ftx\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a> that Bullish, the digital asset exchange of which Farley is the CEO, is among the bidders interested in acquiring the defunct trading platform FTX.","Fintech startup Figure Technologies and cryptocurrency venture capital firm Proof Group are also bidding to buy FTX, according to a November 8 <a href=\"https:\/\/www.wsj.com\/livecoverage\/stock-market-today-dow-jones-11-08-2023\/card\/former-nyse-president-in-talks-to-reboot-ftx-exchange-psAcQowWOgoPKMkjanR2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">report<\/a> by the Wall Street Journal.&nbsp;","However, 117 Partners Founder <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/ThomasBraziel\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Thomas Braziel<\/a> cast doubt on whether a rejuvenated <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/259276\/ftx-considers-multiple-proposals-almost-a-year-after-filing-for-bankruptcy\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">FTX<\/a> would ever succeed. \"It’s a head fake, FTT is a zero, no buyer of the assets or relaunch partner is going to use or include FTT,\" he told The Block.","This is not the first time an FTX reboot has been discussed. In January, John J. Ray III, who oversaw Enron’s bankruptcy, floated the idea of restarting the defunct exchange and said that \"if there is a path forward on that, then we will not only explore that, we’ll do it.\"","Ray was appointed CEO of cryptocurrency exchange FTX in the aftermath of its November 2022 collapse. In an interview with the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.wsj.com\/articles\/new-ftx-chief-says-crypto-exchange-could-restart-11674143168?mod=Searchresults_pos1&amp;page=1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Wall Street Journal<\/a> Ray said that he established a task force to investigate the possibility of relaunching FTX.com, the primary international exchange operated by the company.&nbsp;","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Enron","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"DC Fintech Week","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"80%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Tom Farley","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York Stock Exchange","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ray","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S. Securities Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gary Gensler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gensler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Fintech","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Figure Technologies","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Proof Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"November 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Farley","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tom","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"November 8","content":"DATE"},{"type":"6.55 a.m. ET","content":"TIME"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"CNBC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$2.27","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Thomas Braziel","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"John J. Ray III","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"CoinGecko","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BANKRUPTCY FILINGS","COURT HEARINGS","CRIME","CRYPTO MOVERS","FTX","LAWSUITS","SBF TRIAL","SEC"],"authors":["Brian McGleenon","The Block"]}