{"summary":"Blockchain company Aptos closes $150 million round, bringing its total funds raised in 2022 alone to $350 million.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/159439\/aptos-closes-150-million-round-led-by-ftx-ventures-jump-crypto","publishDate":"2022-07-25T09:00:17","id":9403,"type":null,"title":"Aptos closes $150 million round led by FTX Ventures, Jump Crypto","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Aptos, a blockchain startup founded by former Meta employees, this morning announced a $150 million round led by FTX Ventures and Jump Crypto. <\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The startup's latest raise includes new investors such as&nbsp;Griffin Gaming Partners, Franklin Templeton, Circle Ventures and Superscrypt, according to a press release. FTX Ventures previously joined Aptos’ <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/137948\/former-meta-employees-raise-200-million-for-blockchain-startup-aptos\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">funding round<\/span><\/a><span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in March, which saw the blockchain developer raise $200 million from investors like a16z, Tiger Global and Multicoin Capital.<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">FTX Ventures investment partner Ramnik Arora said that blockchain technology needs to prioritise scalability, safety and ease of use to reach “the next billion users.” <\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The blockchain was founded by former Meta employees hoping to bring blockchain technology to a wider audience of&nbsp;<\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/medium.com\/aptoslabs\/the-genesis-of-aptos-ff98d86e9445\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“billions” of people<\/span><\/a><span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. At present Aptos operates on a series of testnets and its mainnet has yet to launch, although it is slated for later this year. <\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Aptos has now raised $350 million so far this year, which it plans to invest in the development of its safe and scalable Layer 1 blockchain.<\/span>","<span data-contrast=\"auto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CEO and co-founder Mo Shaikh said the latest funding round is an endorsement of the company’s work to date and shows the appetite for a “next generation Layer 1.” He added: &nbsp;“We’ve known for a while that, due to issues like outages and downtime, current blockchains are not fit for purpose when it comes to mass web3 adoption.”<\/span><span data-ccp-props=\"{&quot;201341983&quot;:0,&quot;335559739&quot;:160,&quot;335559740&quot;:259}\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Mo Shaikh","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$350 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Jump Crypto","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tiger Global","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Circle Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Aptos","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Multicoin Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$200 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Ramnik Arora","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Franklin Templeton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$150 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Griffin Gaming Partners","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["APTOS"],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}