{"summary":"Blockfolio co-founder Ed Moncada and FTX&#x27;s Sam Bankman-Fried talk about the logic behind the recent acquisition and what the companies are planning.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/76909\/ftx-blockfolio-inside-look","publishDate":"2020-09-03T15:54:06","id":9404,"type":null,"title":"An inside look at FTX’s $150 million acquisition of Blockfolio","category":["THE BLOCK"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 36 of Season 2 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with The Block’s Frank Chaparro, Blockfolio co-founder Ed Moncada and FTX’s Sam Bankman-Fried.&nbsp;<\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"a8d8c7cccbc9dbdce8dcc0cdcac4c7cbc3cbdad1d8dcc786cbc7c5\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode of The Scoop is brought to you by Bitstamp, the original global cryptocurrency exchange. Since 2011, Bitstamp has been a cornerstone of the industry, earning the trust of over four million individuals and top financial institutions looking for a reliable trading venue. <\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Whether you’re trading on our web platform, mobile app or industry-leading APIs, Bitstamp gives you the professional-grade tools you need to execute your strategy.&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/bitstamp.net\/app?r=pro%E2%80%93&amp;utm_source=Website&amp;utm_medium=podcast&amp;utm_campaign=theblock&amp;utm_content=ctaapp\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Download the Bitstamp app<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;or visit&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.bitstamp.net\/pro\/?utm_source=Website&amp;utm_medium=podcast&amp;utm_campaign=theblock&amp;utm_content=ctaweb\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bitstamp.net\/Pro<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;to learn more and start trading today!<\/i>","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK6066214068\" width=\"100%\" height=\"200\" frameborder=\"0\" scrolling=\"no\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Last week, FTX announced it would <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/75965\/ftx-blockfolio-crypto-app-acquisition\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">acquire<\/a> crypto data tracking app Blockfolio for $150 million. As reported at the time, FTX is looking to leverage the Blockfolio acquisition to expand its retail footprint and built on the community of users the app has generated thus far.","In this episode of The Scoop, Blockfolio co-founder Ed Moncada and FTX's Sam Bankman-Fried talk about the logic behind the deal and what they plan to build together in the future.","The pair also talks about the growing decentralized finance (DeFi) movement and how <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/post\/76826\/veteran-market-maker-jump-trading-forays-into-defi-to-provide-liquidity-for-ftxs-solana-based-dex\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Jump Trading<\/a>&nbsp;is going to play a big part in FTX's upcoming decentralized exchange, Serum.","The conversation also touches on:","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2011","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Blockfolio","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bitstamp","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ed Moncada","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$150 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Aislinn Keely","The Block"]}