{"summary":"“This really should put everyone on notice,&quot; Securities and Exchange Commission Chair Gary Gensler said. SEC Chair Gary Gensler sent a warning shot to the cryptocurrency industry on Friday morning on CNBC.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/210587\/kraken-crypto-industry-on-notice-gensler","publishDate":"2023-02-10T09:29:06","id":9411,"type":null,"title":"Kraken move should put crypto industry &#x27;on notice,&#x27; Gensler says","category":["POLICY"],"content":["<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Securities and Exchange Commission Chair Gary Gensler sent another warning shot to the crypto industry this morning, just a day after the regulator said it settled with the Kraken exchange over allegations surrounding its staking program.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“This really should put everyone on notice in this marketplace whether you call it lend, whether you call it earn, whether you call it yield, whether you offer what’s called an annual percentage yield, APY,” Gensler said on CNBC.<\/span>","<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The SEC said Thursday that crypto intermediaries needed to provide \"proper disclosures and safeguards required by our securities laws\" when offering services such as lending or staking. <\/span><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kraken subsequently<\/span><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;agreed to e<\/span><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">nd its on-chain staking services for U.S. clients only without <\/span><span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">admitting or denying the allegations. &nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Those other platforms should take note of this and seek to come into compliance,” Gensler said Friday.<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The move promoted an immediate backlash, with SEC Commissioner Hester Peirce, a longtime crypto advocate, saying she disagreed with the commission's action in a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.sec.gov\/news\/statement\/peirce-statement-kraken-020923?utm_medium=email&amp;utm_source=govdelivery\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">dissenting<\/span><\/a> statement in which she argued that using enforcement actions to set law in an emerging industry is not \"efficient or fair.\" <\/span><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Gensler said Peirce and him “chat regularly” when he was asked about those comments on Friday.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The settlement signaled an <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/210408\/secs-targeting-of-kraken-staking-program-sends-shockwaves-through-industry\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s3\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">aggressive move<\/span><\/a> by the SEC, some experts said on Thursday, calling it a <\/span><span class=\"s4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“bad sign for ‘staking as a service’ as it’s currently offered in the United States.”&nbsp;<\/span>","<span class=\"s2\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The development follows multiple enforcement actions this year. <\/span><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">On Jan. 12, the agency charged both Gemini and Genesis with the unregistered offering and sale of securities through the Gemini Earn lending program.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"this morning","content":"TIME"},{"type":"Hester Peirce","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gemini","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CNBC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kraken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jan. 12","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gary Gensler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Gensler","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Peirce","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"United States","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["GARY GENSLER","KRAKEN","SEC"],"authors":["Sarah Wynn","The Block"]}