{"summary":"Cofounder of CryptoKitties and Dapper Labs Mack Flavelle has signed with top Hollywood talent agency, WME.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/177662\/dapper-labs-cryptokitties-co-founder-signs-with-hollywood-agency-wme-exclusive","publishDate":"2022-10-17T10:27:55","id":9427,"type":null,"title":"Dapper Labs, CryptoKitties co-founder signs with Hollywood agency WME: Exclusive","category":["NFTS"],"content":["<span class=\"TextRun SCXW46060496 BCX0\" lang=\"EN-US\" xml:lang=\"EN-US\" data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"NormalTextRun SCXW46060496 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Cofounder of <\/span><span class=\"NormalTextRun SpellingErrorV2Themed SCXW46060496 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CryptoKitties<\/span><span class=\"NormalTextRun SCXW46060496 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> and Dapper Labs Mack Flavelle has signed with <\/span><span class=\"NormalTextRun ContextualSpellingAndGrammarErrorV2Themed SCXW46060496 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">top<\/span><span class=\"NormalTextRun SCXW46060496 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Hollywood talent agency, WME, The Block learned exclusively.<\/span><\/span><span class=\"LineBreakBlob BlobObject DragDrop SCXW46060496 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"SCXW46060496 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span><br class=\"SCXW46060496 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span class=\"LineBreakBlob BlobObject DragDrop SCXW46060496 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"SCXW46060496 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span><br class=\"SCXW46060496 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span><span class=\"TextRun SCXW46060496 BCX0\" lang=\"EN-US\" xml:lang=\"EN-US\" data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"NormalTextRun SCXW46060496 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Flavelle, considered by some to be a pioneer of NFTs, helped elevate the popularity of non-fungible tokens when he <\/span><span class=\"NormalTextRun SCXW46060496 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">created <\/span><span class=\"NormalTextRun SpellingErrorV2Themed SCXW46060496 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CryptoKitties<\/span><span class=\"NormalTextRun SCXW46060496 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, <\/span><span class=\"NormalTextRun SCXW46060496 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">an NFT<\/span><span class=\"NormalTextRun SCXW46060496 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> series that allows people to buy, breed and sell cartoon cat collectibles. The long-running game, built on the Ethereum blockchain, launched in 2017.<\/span><\/span>","WME is one of the most powerful talent agencies in the entertainment industry, representing top Hollywood actors including Dwayne “The Rock” Johnson and Charlize Theron, and musical artists such as Meek Mill and Alicia Keys.&nbsp;","Mack Flavelle, courtesy of WME","Signing with the agency means Flavelle will be represented by an agency that not only possesses a diversity of interests — the agency’s parent company Endeavor owns the UFC, a professional bull-riding league, and runs fashion shows — but is also known for fostering collaboration among its extensive list of high-profile clients.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<span class=\"TextRun SCXW46060496 BCX0\" lang=\"EN-US\" xml:lang=\"EN-US\" data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"NormalTextRun SCXW46060496 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"LineBreakBlob BlobObject DragDrop SCXW46060496 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">It seems like the slump in NFT prices hasn't dissuaded interest in the area, with WME signing Bright Moments, Non-fungible Heroes and <a href=\"https:\/\/variety.com\/2022\/digital\/news\/beauties-signs-nft-wme-1235343698\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Boss Beauties<\/a> all this year. WME also represents <a href=\"https:\/\/www.hollywoodreporter.com\/business\/digital\/bored-ape-nft-escapeplan-wme-1235115702\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"NormalTextRun SpellingErrorV2Themed SCXW46060496 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Escapeplan<\/span><\/a> — the Bored Ape Yacht Club DJ duo — <span class=\"NormalTextRun ContextualSpellingAndGrammarErrorV2Themed SCXW46060496 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">and<\/span> Pixel Vault, a web3 media company that <a href=\"https:\/\/www.globenewswire.com\/news-release\/2022\/02\/02\/2377893\/0\/en\/Pixel-Vault-Secures-100M-to-Build-World-s-First-Decentralized-Entertainment-Company.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">secured<\/a> a $100 million investment earlier this year.<\/span><\/span><\/span>","<span class=\"TextRun SCXW46060496 BCX0\" lang=\"EN-US\" xml:lang=\"EN-US\" data-contrast=\"none\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"NormalTextRun SCXW46060496 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"LineBreakBlob BlobObject DragDrop SCXW46060496 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Vancouver-based Dapper Labs produced the popular NBA Top Shot collection, a darling of the NFT market after its launch in 2020. Flavelle is also the founder and CEO of Big Head Club, an “end-to-end full-service NFT studio,” which has produced noteworthy collections like Stoner Cats and actor and artist Jim Carrey’s Germinations.<\/span><\/span><\/span><span class=\"LineBreakBlob BlobObject DragDrop SCXW46060496 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br class=\"SCXW46060496 BCX0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Jim Carrey","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Big Head Club","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dapper Labs Mack Flavelle","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mack Flavelle","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$100 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Dapper Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alicia Keys","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Johnson","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Stoner","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bored Ape Yacht Club DJ","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Vancouver","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Flavelle","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UFC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Pixel Vault","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Dwayne “","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Meek Mill","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2020","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}