{"summary":"Withdrawals cannot be resumed immediately as FTX Japan uses the same suspended payment system as its parent company, according to the Japanese public broadcaster.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/188748\/ftx-japan-to-resume-withdrawals","publishDate":"2022-11-21T07:55:56","id":9441,"type":null,"title":"FTX Japanese subsidiary preparing to resume withdrawals by year end: NHK","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["FTX Japan plans to resume customer withdrawals by the end of the year, according to Japanese public broadcaster <a href=\"https:\/\/www3.nhk.or.jp\/news\/html\/20221121\/k10013898981000.html?utm_int=nsearch_contents_search-items_001\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">NHK<\/a>.","Withdrawals cannot be resumed immediately as the exchange uses the same suspended payment system as its parent company FTX, said the report, citing an unnamed executive. It is now developing its own system to allow customers to withdraw assets.","The country’s Financial Services Agency <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/185388\/ftx-japan-ordered-by-countrys-financial-regulator-to-suspend-operations\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ordered<\/a> FTX Japan to suspend operations on Nov. 10. It held 19.6 billion yen ($138 million) in deposits at the time it ceased operations.","FTX, which filed for bankruptcy protection earlier this month, itself owes approximately $3.1 billion to creditors.&nbsp;As a result, it may may sell off subsidiaries including FTX Japan, NHK reported.&nbsp;","FTX Japan isn’t FTX’s only subsidiary facing trouble in the country. It also owns crypto exchange Liquid, which announced the suspension of withdrawals on its Liquid Global Platform on Nov. 15.&nbsp;","On Nov. 20 it also <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/188635\/ftx-acquired-liquid-pauses-trading-five-days-after-suspending-withdrawals\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">suspended trading<\/a> on its platform on instruction of the legal team acting for FTX.","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"’s Financial Services Agency","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$138 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"earlier this month","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"NHK","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$3.1 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"FTX Japan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Japan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"19.6 billion yen","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nov. 10","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Nov. 20","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Nov. 15","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Callan Quinn","The Block"]}