{"summary":"Step, a banking platform for teens and young adults, revealed a cryptocurrency investment platform and $300 million in debt financing.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/176390\/step-secures-300-million-in-debt-funding-launches-crypto-investment-service","publishDate":"2022-10-11T17:21:16","id":9443,"type":null,"title":"Step secures $300 million in debt funding, launches crypto investment service","category":["INVESTMENTS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Step, the banking service aimed at bringing young adults into the investment world, secured $300 million in debt funding, the company announced.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Step said it will expand into crypto investment services, and launched a financial literacy program to improve consumer education on banking and crypto.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Banking platform Step, which caters to a teenaged and young adult clientele, has secured $300 million in new debt funding.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Triplepoint Capital and Evolve Bank &amp; Trust led the funding round, the company said in a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.businesswire.com\/news\/home\/20221011005315\/en\/Step-secures-an-additional-300000000-to-accelerate-growth-launches-crypto-investing-and-a-national-financial-literacy-curriculum\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">press release<\/a>.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The funding round announcement coincided with the company’s launch of a crypto investment platform aimed at minors and young adults, who with the consent of a parent or legal guardian, will be able to buy and sell bitcoin, with additional stocks and cryptocurrencies to join the platform soon, according to Step.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In addition, the company launched a financial literacy program, <a href=\"https:\/\/step.com\/education”?\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Money 101<\/a>, a six-lesson course that spans the banking sector to cryptocurrency investing, said Step.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">With the funding secured, Step’s raise now totals $500 million, including debt and equity financing, from investors such as Crosslink Capital, Stripe, Coatue, General Catalyst, Triplepoint Capital, Charli D’Amelio, Stephen Curry, Justin Timberlake, Will Smith, The Chainsmokers, Alex Rodriguez, and others.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$500 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"General Catalyst","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Crosslink Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Will Smith","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Alex Rodriguez","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Justin Timberlake","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$300 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Triplepoint Capital and Evolve Bank &amp; Trust","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Triplepoint Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Stephen Curry","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Charli D’Amelio","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["DEBT FINANCING"],"authors":["Jeremy Nation","The Block"]}