{"summary":"Investment manager Coatue has reportedly lost two more general partners: Luca Schmid and Sebastian Duesterhoeft.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/175744\/coatue-loses-two-more-partners-including-one-who-led-firms-crypto-investments-the-information","publishDate":"2022-10-08T06:23:35","id":9507,"type":null,"title":"Coatue loses two more partners, including one who led firm&#x27;s crypto investments: The Information","category":["PEOPLE"],"content":["Investment manager Coatue, with over $73 billion in assets under management, has reportedly lost two more general partners in recent months.","Luca Schmid left the firm in August and Sebastian Duesterhoeft departed a month after, The Information <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theinformation.com\/articles\/two-more-coatue-partners-have-departed?rc=zqxydl\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a> on Friday, citing a person familiar with the matter.","Schmid plans to work with Checkout.com's founder and CEO Guillaume Pousaz to start a family office to make investments in fintech startups, and Duesterhoeft is set to join Lightspeed Venture Partners as a partner, according to the report.","Notably, Schmid led some of Coatue's top crypto and fintech investments, including Chainalysis, Fireblocks, Dune Analytics, Checkout.com, Chime and N26, according to his LinkedIn profile. Duesterhoeft, on the other hand, led the firm's tech investments, including Airtable, Snowflake and Snyk, his LinkedIn account indicates.","Schmid and Duesterhoeft are the latest executives to depart Coatue. Last week, The Information <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/174570\/coatues-matt-mazzeo-leaving-to-start-his-own-fund-the-information\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a> that Matt Mazzeo, general partner at Coatue, left the firm to start his own investment fund focused on backing early-stage startups. Mazzeo's deals at Coatue reportedly included NFT marketplace giant OpenSea.","Coatue was founded in 1999 by brothers Philippe and Thomas Laffont as a hedge fund. It became one of the most active tech investors during the recent boom. Earlier this year, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockresearch.com\/mapping-out-coatue-managements-crypto-portfolio-140671\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block Research mapped out Coatue's crypto investments<\/a> and found out that the New York-based firm had invested in at least 14 crypto startups, including Alchemy, Bitmain, CertiK, Dapper Labs and MoonPay.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Checkout.com","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Coatue","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Guillaume Pousaz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"The Block Research","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Coatue","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bitmain","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Dapper Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sebastian Duesterhoeft","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$73 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"1999","content":"DATE"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Luca Schmid","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Philippe","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Dune Analytics","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lightspeed Venture Partners","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Matt Mazzeo","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Thomas Laffont","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Mazzeo","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"MoonPay","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Schmid","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["FINTECH"],"authors":["Yogita Khatri","The Block"]}