{"summary":"One of the world&#x27;s largest pension plans is set to write its investment in FTX down to zero following the firm&#x27;s bankruptcy filings.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/188339\/ontario-teachers-pension-plan-to-write-down-95-million-ftx-investment-to-zero","publishDate":"2022-11-18T10:25:46","id":953,"type":null,"title":"Ontario Teachers&#x27; Pension Plan to write down $95 million FTX investment to zero","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["The Ontario Teachers' Pension Plan (OTPP), one of the most important pension funds in the world, will write down all of its $95 million investment in FTX and FTX US.","The OTPP had invested the money across two funding rounds, initially invested in October 2021 via a Series B and then again in January via a Series C. The OTPP manages over CAD$221 billion ($165 billion).","Other household names caught up with the FTX collapse in BlackRock, Softbank, and Temasek, which also <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/187868\/temasek-writes-down-275-million-investment-in-ftx\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">wrote<\/a> its investment down to zero.","","","In an <a href=\"https:\/\/www.otpp.com\/en-ca\/about-us\/news-and-insights\/2022\/ontario-teachers--statement-on-ftx\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">update<\/a> on Thursday, the pension fund said the investment in FTX reflected its approach to diversification. \"Our strategy aims to diversify investments across asset classes, geography, time horizons, and economic outcomes to mitigate risk and enhance returns.\"&nbsp;","OTTP will write down its investment to zero at the end of the year. The loss from the investment will have a \"limited impact ... given its size relative to our total net assets and our strong financial position.\"","\"However, we are disappointed with the outcome of this investment, take all losses seriously, and will use this experience to further strengthen our approach,\" the firm said.","Sequoia Capital, the Silicon Valley investment firm, was quick off the mark in <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/185136\/sequoia-says-its-investment-in-ftx-is-now-worthless\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">writing<\/a> down its investment to zero on Nov. 9 — it made $213.5 million worth of investments in FTX entities.","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$95 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"BlackRock","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ontario Teachers","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sequoia Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$165 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Temasek","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nov. 9","content":"DATE"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"October 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$213.5 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Silicon Valley","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Softbank","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["SAM BANKMAN-FRIED"],"authors":["Adam Morgan McCarthy","The Block"]}