{"summary":"Hut 8 mined 3,568 bitcoins last year — an increase of 28% over 2021, which it attributes to an increase in hash rate resulting from its fleet expansion.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/218395\/hut-8-reports-annual-revenue-decline-increase-in-mined-bitcoins","publishDate":"2023-03-09T07:41:07","id":9532,"type":null,"title":"Hut 8 reports annual revenue decline, increase in mined bitcoins","category":["CRYPTO INFRASTRUCTURE"],"content":["North American crypto miner Hut 8 <a href=\"https:\/\/www.prnewswire.com\/news-releases\/hut-8-reports-operating-and-financial-results-for-2022-301767560.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a> annual revenue of CA$150.7 million ($109 million) — a decrease of CA$23.1 million compared to the previous year — and a 65% increase in bitcoin holdings.","Hut 8 mined 3,568 bitcoins last year — an increase of 28% over 2021, which it attributed to an increase in hash rate resulting from its fleet expansion.","\"While 2022 was a challenging time for the entire industry, we fared well thanks to our team's commitment to operational excellence, our diversified lines of business and our strong growth profile,\" CEO Jaime Leverton said in a statement.","\"As we look ahead, we will continue to uphold these operating principles as we work to close our business combination with USBTC and begin operating as a U.S.-domiciled, digital asset mining, hosting, managed infrastructure operations and high performance computing organization,\" she added.","Last month, Hut 8 <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/209265\/bitcoin-miners-hut-8-and-us-bitcoin-merge-to-form-new-us-based-entity\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">announced<\/a> a merger with US Bitcoin (USBTC) to form Hut 8 Corp., which will be based in the United States. It also <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/205868\/bitcoin-miner-hut-8-takes-dispute-with-power-supplier-to-court\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">filed<\/a> a statement of claim in the Superior Court of Justice of Ontario against Validus Power Corp. and its subsidiary, Bay Power Corp., the third-party energy supplier to Hut 8's facility in North Bay, Ontario, the month prior.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Bay Power Corp.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Validus Power Corp.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"US Bitcoin (USBTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CA$150.7 million ($109 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"65%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"USBTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CA$23.1 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Hut 8 Corp.","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"28%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Superior Court of Justice","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"North Bay","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Ontario","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Jaime Leverton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"United States","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["EARNINGS","MINING COMPANIES"],"authors":["Adam James","The Block"]}