{"summary":"Australia&#x27;s financial watchdog has sued an Aave and Coinbase-backed fintech company, Block Earner, over unlicensed crypto services.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/189445\/australian-regulator-sues-fintech-company-over-alleged-unlicensed-crypto-services","publishDate":"2022-11-23T04:28:29","id":9550,"type":null,"title":"Australian regulator sues fintech company over alleged unlicensed crypto services","category":["LEGAL"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Australia’s financial regulator has sued Sydney-based Block Earner, citing concerns that the fintech company offered unlicensed crypto products.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Block Earner<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> offers several tiers of products that offer yield on crypto holdings. The Australian Securities and Investment Commission, or ASIC, claims these products are unregistered managed investment schemes that should have been licensed.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ASIC opened up a civil penalty file with the federal court seeking “declarations, injunctions, and pecuniary penalties,” according to a statement <a href=\"https:\/\/asic.gov.au\/about-asic\/news-centre\/find-a-media-release\/2022-releases\/22-324mr-asic-sues-block-earner-for-unlicensed-conduct-over-crypto-asset-based-products\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">released<\/a> by the regulator. The court has yet to schedule the first hearing date.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We are concerned that Block Earner offered financial products without appropriate registration or an Australian Financial Services license, leaving consumers without important protections,” ASIC Deputy Chair Sarah Court said in the statement. “Simply because a product hinges on a crypto-asset, does not mean it falls outside financial services law.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Block Earner had <a href=\"https:\/\/www.crunchbase.com\/funding_round\/block-earner-seed--e11095a6\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">launched<\/a> its seed funding round in 2021 and secured $4.5 million, from investors including Aave CEO Stani Kulechov and Coinbase Ventures. The platform lends out client assets through Aave and Compound protocols.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The firm <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.businessnewsaustralia.com\/articles\/asic-sues-block-earner--alleges-fintech-provided-unlicensed-financial-services.html\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">told<\/span><\/a> <i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Business News Australia <\/span><\/i><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">that the civil penalty file is “disappointing”.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We welcome regulation in our space and have spent considerable resources building regulatory infrastructure to be able to deliver a whole suite of services to Australian users in a regulated and compliant manner under existing guidelines provided by ASIC,” CEO Charlie Karaboga said in comments that were later confirmed to The Block.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“As a case in point, for our upcoming products where the licensing requirements are clear, we have already filed for an application for an Australian Credit License and advised ASIC of our intention to apply for an [Australian Financial Services license],” he added.<\/span>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Update: Story updated after <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Block Earner confirmed its comments on the situation to The Block.&nbsp;<\/span><\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sydney","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$4.5 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"ASIC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"ASIC Deputy Chair Sarah Court","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Charlie Karaboga","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Australia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Coinbase Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Australian Financial Services","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Business News","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Australian Securities and Investment Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Block Earner","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Stani Kulechov","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}