{"summary":"Pertsev has been in Dutch jail since August for his role in forming Tornado Cash, a crypto mixer that hackers used to launder stolen funds. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/189086\/tornado-cash-developer-alexey-pertsev-to-be-detained-another-three-months-in-amsterdam","publishDate":"2022-11-22T11:10:31","id":9563,"type":null,"title":"Tornado Cash developer Alexey Pertsev detained another three months","category":["PEOPLE"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Alexey <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Pertsev, the creator of the crypto mixer Tornado Cash, will be detained in a Dutch jail for another three months, Pertsev's wife Ksenia Malik confirmed.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Dutch authorities arrested Pertsev in August after the U.S. <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/162105\/us-treasury-sanctions-cryptocurrency-mixer-tornado-cash\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">sanctioned<\/a> Tornado Cash’s alleged role in laundering money and use by North Korean hackers. Pertsev's September appeal was rejected and he was forced to remain in jail until Nov. 22. Now, he must remain incarcerated until at least February.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">If Pertsev, a Russian national, were to be released, he may be sent to fight in the war against Ukraine, The Block <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/174016\/arrested-tornado-cash-developer-alexey-pertsev-appeal-rejected\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Malik as saying. She had also previously <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/163297\/arrested-tornado-cash-developer-is-alexey-pertsev-his-wife-confirms\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">confirmed<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that Tornado Cash’s developer is indeed Pertsev.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Tornado Cash pools the funds of multiple users before redistributing, or <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/news+\/82899\/kucoin-thief-dex-money-laundering\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">mixing<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, them. The mixed crypto is often harder to trace, and so hackers looked to Tornado Cash to launder their stolen money.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Last year, for instance, the crowdfunding platform DAO Maker was hacked, and someone laundered more than <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/168828\/tornado-cash-used-to-launder-500000-stolen-from-dao-maker-last-year-security-firms\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$500,000<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> worth of the stolen funds through Tornado Cash. <\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"North Korean","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Malik","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Pertsev","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"February","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alexey <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Pertsev","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ksenia Malik","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$500,000","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Nov. 22","content":"DATE"},{"type":"August","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ukraine","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["MK Manoylov","Yogita Khatri","The Block"]}