{"summary":"Catherine Coley, former head of XRP institutional liquidity at Ripple, has joined Binance.US as CEO, industry sources have told The Block. Coley","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/29867\/ex-ripple-executive-catherine-coley-joins-binance-us-as-ceo","publishDate":"2019-07-02T09:06:29","id":9600,"type":null,"title":"Ex-Ripple Executive Catherine Coley joins Binance.US as CEO","category":["THE BLOCK"],"content":["<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Quick Take<\/strong>","Catherine Coley, former head of XRP institutional liquidity at Ripple, has joined Binance.US as CEO, industry sources have told The Block.","Coley previously worked for Silicon Valley Bank and Morgan Stanley, managing foreign exchange business, before joining blockchain startup Ripple in 2017, according to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.linkedin.com\/in\/catherinegcoley\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">her LinkedIn profile.<\/a>&nbsp;<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\nBinance announced its plans to launch a fiat-to-crypto exchange in the U.S. earlier this month, before breaking the news that its main platform, Binance.com, would <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/2019\/06\/14\/us-customers-to-be-blocked-from-trading-on-binance-com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">stop being available<\/a> in the country in September.","As part of its US launch, Binance has <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/tiny\/binance-is-reportedly-eyeing-expansion-into-u-s\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">partnered<\/span><\/a> with BAM Trading Services, a little-known Californian-registered firm.&nbsp;\"Binance US will be led by our local partner BAM and will serve the U.S. market in full regulatory compliance,\" Binance CEO Changpeng Zhao said last month.","Coley will therefore likely be responsible for working closely with regulators and building the US-based team. It is not yet clear when the new platform will launch.","On the recent hire, CZ <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/former-ripple-exec-to-lead-binances-us-expansion-as-new-exchange-ceo\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said in a press release:<\/a> “I am confident that with Coley’s leadership and Binance’s leading technology platform, <span class=\"skimlinks-unlinked\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance.US <\/span>will be able to provide valuable services to the U.S. community.”","Coley shared her own enthusiasm, noting: “This is just the beginning of a long journey ahead, and I look forward to working with Binance as a partner to unlock more potential for the blockchain ecosystem here in the U.S..\"","Coley joins a small but eclectic handful female executives in major crypto and blockchain, including:","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The story is developing...<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"earlier this month","content":"DATE"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Changpeng Zhao","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Catherine Coley","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"CZ","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"September","content":"DATE"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"BAM Trading Services","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"last month","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Ripple","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Morgan Stanley","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance US","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Silicon Valley Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coley","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Yogita Khatri","Isabel Woodford","The Block"]}