{"summary":"Former Algorand CEO Steve Kokinos has been named as the prospective CEO of the company succeeding Celsius&#x27; operations.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/250184\/celsius-successor-taps-algorand-wework-ubs-execs-new-board","publishDate":"2023-09-11T09:50:54","id":9601,"type":null,"title":"Celsius successor taps former Algorand, WeWork and UBS execs for new board","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Former <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Algorand <\/span><span class=\"articleTooltip\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"\/price\/35271\/algorand-algo-usd\" class=\"articleTooltip__link\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"><img src=\"https:\/\/www.tbstat.com\/wp\/uploads\/2023\/10\/download.png\" alt=\"\" title=\"\" class=\"articleTooltip__tokenImage\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\"> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">ALGO<\/span> <span class=\"articleTooltip__tokenText articleTooltip__tokenText_price articleTooltip__tokenText_negative\" data-v-baf5685a=\"\">\n      -0.74%\n    <\/span><\/a> <!----><\/span><\/span> CEO Steve Kokinos has been named as the prospective CEO of the company succeeding Celsius' operations.<\/span>","Kokinos joins eight other directors appointed to the board of the yet-to-be-named Delaware corporation, currently dubbed \"NewCo,” according to a <a href=\"https:\/\/cases.stretto.com\/public\/x191\/11749\/PLEADINGS\/1174909092380000000044.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">court filing<\/a> on Saturday.","Six of the nine board members were appointed by Celsius’ creditors committee and two by Fahrenheit Holdings — the consortium that made the <a href=\"https:\/\/techcrunch.com\/2023\/05\/25\/arrington-capital-backed-group-to-acquire-celsius-assets\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">winning bid to acquire Celsius’ assets<\/a> in May. The consortium plans to take over Celsius' institutional loan portfolio, staked crypto and bitcoin mining unit.","Kokinos parted ways with the Layer 1 staking-based blockchain Algorand in July 2022 and is a co-owner of Fahrenheit, alongside Arrington Capital, Ravi Kaza, Proof Group and crypto mining firm US Bitcoin Corp.","The new board also includes Michael Arrington of Arrington Capital, the investment firm that led Fahrenheit’s bid; US Bitcoin Corp President Asher Genoot; Frederick Arnold, who is overseeing the estate of the defunct Lehman Brothers; WeWork audit committee Chair and ex-UBS Managing Director Elizabeth LaPuma; and ex-Credit Suisse investment banker Emmanuel Aidoo.","Celsius committee chairs Scott Duffy and Thomas DiFiore were also appointed to the new board. The committee represents the interests of Celsius’ creditors.","<a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/157491\/crypto-lender-celsius-declares-chapter-11-bankruptcy-in-new-york\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Celsius filed for bankruptcy protection<\/a> in July last year owing billions of dollars to investors amid the crypto downturn. Celsius creditors are currently voting on Fahrenheit’s proposed takeover with a <a href=\"https:\/\/www.businesswire.com\/news\/home\/20230817692019\/en\/Celsius-Disclosure-Statement-Approved-by-Court\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">deadline of Sept. 22 to file objections<\/a>. If successful, the acquisition could help investors recover some of those lost funds.","The collapsed crypto lender has also faced scrutiny from multiple regulators, including the Securities and Exchange Commission, the Commodity Futures Trading Commission and the Federal Trade Commission.","The <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/239407\/sec-files-lawsuit-against-celsius-and-ex-ceo-alex-mashinsky\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">SEC sued Celsius and former CEO Alex Mashinsky in July<\/a> this year for allegedly fraudulent activities, unregistered sales of \"crypto asset securities\" and price manipulation of its native CEL token. Mashinsky posted a $40 million bond and pleaded not guilty to criminal charges.","Last week, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/249474\/former-celsius-ceo-mashinskys-home-and-assets-ordered-frozen-in-criminal-case\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Mashinsky's assets and Texas home were frozen<\/a>, according to an unsealed court order.","&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Arrington Capital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"billions of dollars","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Delaware","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$40 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Ravi Kaza","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frederick Arnold","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Steve Kokinos","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Federal Trade Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Emmanuel Aidoo","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Proof Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Lehman Brothers","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Michael Arrington","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Mashinsky","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Saturday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"US Bitcoin Corp","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Fahrenheit Holdings","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NewCo","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Scott Duffy","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"July last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Alex Mashinsky","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Asher Genoot","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"July<\/a> this year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Texas","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thomas DiFiore","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sept. 22","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Commodity Futures Trading Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Elizabeth LaPuma","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"-0.74%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"July 2022","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["BANKRUPTCY FILINGS","CRYPTO BANKS AND LENDERS","INVESTMENT FIRMS"],"authors":["James Hunt","The Block"]}