{"summary":"FTX is considering making a bid for Celsius Network&#x27;s assets, Bloomberg reported late Tuesday.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/173275\/sbf-considering-celsius-bid-bloomberg","publishDate":"2022-09-27T20:07:40","id":9602,"type":null,"title":"FTX&#x27;s Bankman-Fried considering Celsius bid: Bloomberg","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["FTX CEO Sam Bankman-Fried is considering <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2022-09-27\/crypto-billionaire-bankman-fried-eyeing-bid-for-celsius-assets\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">bidding<\/a> on bankrupt Celsius Network's assets, Bloomberg reported late Tuesday.","The cryptocurrency exchange is also working on closing a $1 billion funding round that has not yet been announced, the business news outlet also reported, citing a person familiar with the matter.&nbsp;","Former Celsius Network CEO Alex Mashinsky stepped down earlier on Tuesday after the company's creditor committee <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/173177\/celsius-creditor-committee-called-for-ceos-removal\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">called<\/a> for his removal.","Celsius' native token, CEL, <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/173103\/celsius-tokens-price-tumbles-after-ceo-mashinsky-resigns\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">plunged below<\/a> $1.40 following the news of Mashinsky's departure. However, the digital asset bounced back more than 15% from its lowest 24-hour point after the Bloomberg report, CoinDesk <a href=\"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/business\/2022\/09\/27\/cel-token-jumps-as-sbf-said-to-eye-celsius-in-buying-spree\/?utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=onecryptofeed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=headlines\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/a> late Tuesday.&nbsp;","&nbsp;","","","FTX <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/172946\/ftx-wins-auction-for-bankrupt-crypto-lender-voyager\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">won an auction<\/a> for Voyager Digital's assets on Sept. 26, with a bid coming in at about $1.4 billion.","Disclaimer: The former CEO and majority shareholder of The Block has disclosed a series of loans from former FTX and Alameda founder Sam Bankman-Fried.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"$1.4 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$1 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"The Block","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Celsius Network","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1.40","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Alex Mashinsky","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alameda","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sept. 26","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sam Bankman","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"15%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Voyager Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mashinsky","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["FTX"],"authors":["Kristin Majcher","The Block"]}