{"summary":"Liberty City Ventures led the funding round, which was also supported by Animoca Brands.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/144044\/onefootball-raises-300-million-in-series-d-funding-round","publishDate":"2022-04-28T07:01:16","id":9655,"type":null,"title":"OneFootball raises $300 million in Series D funding round","category":["STARTUPS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Soccer media company OneFootball has raised $300 million in a Series D funding round, the Berlin-based startup announced on Thursday.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Blockchain fund and incubator Liberty City Ventures led the round, with additional investment from Animoca Brands, Dapper Labs, DAH Beteiligungs GmbH, Quiet Capital, RIT Capital Partners, Senator Investment Group and Alsara Investment Group.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The money will support the company’s expansion efforts, investments in web3 companies, and OneFootball Labs, a new joint venture with Animoca Brands and Liberty City Ventures, according to an emailed statement. OneFootball didn’t say what valuation the new funding placed on the company.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The company stated that OneFootball Labs will “enable clubs, leagues, federations and players to release digital assets and fan-centric experiences based on blockchain technology.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">As part of the round, co-founder and executive chairman of Animoca Brands, Yat Siu, will join the boards of OneFootball and OneFootball Labs.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Over the last year, the sporting universe has made progress in harnessing the potential of NFTs and gaming, offering fans new digital experiences based on the important principles of true digital ownership and decentralization,” said Siu in a statement.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“Animoca Brands is proud to have played a role in nearly every significant milestone in the development of true digital property rights via NFTs,” he added.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"OneFootball Labs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Thursday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Senator Investment Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"RIT Capital Partners","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alsara Investment Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Yat Siu","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Berlin","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Liberty City Ventures","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Animoca Brands","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Siu","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$300 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"DAH Beteiligungs GmbH","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["ANIMOCA BRANDS"],"authors":["Callan Quinn","The Block"]}