{"summary":"The South China Morning Post reported that HKVAEX was set up last year by Binance in the hope of pursuing a crypto license.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/259321\/binance-has-set-up-trading-platform-in-hong-kong-to-apply-for-a-license-report","publishDate":"2023-10-25T03:12:02","id":9660,"type":null,"title":"Binance has set up trading platform in Hong Kong to apply for a license: report","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance has reportedly set up a crypto exchange in Hong Kong to apply for a local crypto license, the South China Morning Post reported today, citing three sources familiar with the matter.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The local newspaper <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.scmp.com\/tech\/big-tech\/article\/3239020\/binance-behind-hong-kong-crypto-exchange-hkvaex-which-seeking-licence-city-sources-say\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> that HKVAEX was established in December 2022 by the world’s largest crypto exchange and has shown interest in applying for a license in Hong Kong.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance and HKVAEX did not immediately respond to The Block’s request for comment.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The two companies share resources despite the fact that HKVAEX was created as a separate entity, according to the report.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">HKVAEX told the local media outlet that it is an independent platform operated by its own team and it is currently preparing to apply for a license to operate as a crypto trading platform. Binance told the SCMP that HKVAEX is not in the Binance Group of companies.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Hong Kong in June launched its crypto retail trading licensing scheme in an attempt to position itself as a major crypto hub in Asia, but Binance has yet to officially show public interest in obtaining such a license. Nikkei Asia <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/asia.nikkei.com\/Spotlight\/Cryptocurrencies\/Binance-edges-closer-to-making-bid-for-Hong-Kong-crypto-license\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in March that Binance was hiring officials that it would need to apply for a license to offer services in the city.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance has repeatedly said it puts considerable effort into complying with local rules wherever it operates, while it continues to face regulatory trouble and remains embroiled in <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/233206\/sec-binance-showdown-sends-shockwaves-through-crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">legal disputes in the U.S. with regulators<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">. The global exchange has also seen <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/259092\/binances-uk-chief-departs-as-regulatory-pressure-mounts\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">a wave of executive departures<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> over the past few months.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Meanwhile, in Taiwan, Binance is applying to get registered for anti-money laundering compliance, The Block previously <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/244320\/binance-is-applying-to-get-registered-in-taiwan-for-aml-compliance-sources\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Asia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Taiwan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"South China Morning Post","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"June","content":"DATE"},{"type":"December 2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Nikkei Asia","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Hong Kong","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"SCMP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}