{"summary":"Keyrock announced it has received regulatory clearance from the Swiss Financial Services Standards Association (VQF). ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/252756\/crypto-market-making-firm-keyrock-gains-swiss-regulatory-approval","publishDate":"2023-09-26T07:05:03","id":9686,"type":null,"title":"Crypto market making firm Keyrock gains Swiss regulatory approval","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto market making firm Keyrock has received regulatory clearance from the <\/span><a class=\"editor-rtfLink\" href=\"https:\/\/www.vqf.ch\/en\/vqf\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Swiss Financial Services Standards Association (VQF)<\/span><\/a><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Securing the VQF membership reinforces Keyrock's stance on upholding rigorous regulatory standards within the crypto space. As the landscape evolves, our focus remains steadfast on ensuring both compliance and trust in our services,” Keyrock CEO Kevin de Patoul said in a press release sent to The Block.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The VQF is a self-regulatory organization recognized by the Swiss regulator, the Financial Market Supervisory Authority (FINMA).<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">According to Keyrock's press release, Swiss regulatory approval should provide the market maker with a foothold from which to grow its presence in Europe and across the globe. \"This milestone confirms our commitment to engage with regulatory authorities globally to align our operations with the highest level of compliance requirements,\" Keyrock General Counsel Reza Ghadiri-Zare said. <\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Keyrock is now actively preparing for compliance with&nbsp;<\/span><a class=\"editor-rtfLink\" href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/252376\/binance-participated-in-mica-discussion-with-european-banking-authority\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">MiCA,<\/span><\/a><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;the press release added. This follows the market maker's announcement of an&nbsp;<\/span><a class=\"editor-rtfLink\" href=\"https:\/\/keyrock.eu\/blog\/keyrock-expansion-asia\/\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">expansion into Asia<\/span><\/a><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, earlier this year.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">After receiving regulatory clearance in Switzerland, the market maker announced plans to expand its fiat on\/off-ramp services through its <\/span><span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">over-the-counter (OTC) trading desk. This expansion will include fiat currencies like GBP and more than 10 other currencies, in addition to the existing USD and EUR pairs.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"We are steadfast in our commitment to offering a specialized OTC solution enriched with a variety of currency options, reflecting our essential belief in flow diversity,\" Kevin de Patoul added.<\/span>","<span data-preserver-spaces=\"true\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">OTC trading allows for a more customized approach to swapping assets, as it involves direct interaction between the parties. This service is commonly used for executing larger trades that may not be feasible on traditional exchanges due to liquidity constraints. OTC trading can reduce counterparty risk if transactions take place between two KYC-compliant entities.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"VQF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Zare","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Switzerland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Financial Market Supervisory Authority","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"EUR","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Reza Ghadiri","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Kevin de Patoul","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Asia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Swiss Financial Services Standards Association (VQF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Keyrock","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"GBP","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Keyrock","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"MiCA","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Brian McGleenon","The Block"]}