{"summary":"Joseph Kelly, CEO of Unchained, delves into the company&#x27;s success as one of the last remaining US bitcoin-backed loan providers.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/256312\/unchained-bitcoin-loans","publishDate":"2023-10-13T08:41:23","id":9767,"type":null,"title":"Demand for this bitcoin-backed lender is growing despite rising rates","category":["CRYPTO INFRASTRUCTURE"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 90<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 5 of The Scoop was recorded with <b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro and Unchained CEO Joe Kelly<\/b><\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on <a href=\"https:\/\/www.youtube.com\/channel\/UCqjFueYMJ78eF6G0lGLzzpQ\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Youtube<\/a>, <\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a>,<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Please send feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"d4a4bbb0b7b5a7a094a0bcb1b6b8bbb7bffab7bb\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<\/i>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm\/?e=BLOCK7504436513\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Joesph Kelly is the CEO of Unchained — a bitcoin financial services company that offers services including trading, inheritance solutions, bitcoin-backed loans, and tax-advantaged bitcoin retirement accounts.","In this episode, Kelly explains how his firm managed to become \"the last lender standing in the US market for bitcoin-backed loans,\" and how Unchained has experienced growth despite rising federal interest rates.","Earlier this year, Unchained <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/226848\/bitcoin-services-unchained-funding\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">raised<\/a> $60 million in a Series B funding round led by Valor Equity Partners.","&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Kelly","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"US","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"$60 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Joesph Kelly","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Joe Kelly","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Valor Equity Partners","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}