{"summary":"In this episode of The Scoop, Coinbase CEO Brian Armstrong candidly reflects on Coinbase&#x27;s new documentary, and how thornier moments of the company&#x27;s history as well as his own journey as a founder are portrayed on screen.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/175811\/brian-armstrong-reflects-on-coinbases-origin-story","publishDate":"2022-10-10T05:00:47","id":9835,"type":null,"title":"Brian Armstrong reflects on Coinbase&#x27;s origin story","category":["PODCASTS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 97<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 4 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro and Coinbase CEO Brian Armstrong.<\/strong><\/i><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"24544b404745575064504c4146484b474f47565d54504b0a474b49\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK2813558580\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/i><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The cameras have been rolling over at Coinbase, CEO Brian Armstrong revealed last Friday, when he announced the release of <\/span><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Coin: A Founder’s Story <\/span><\/i><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">— a feature-length film over three years in the making.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In this episode of The Scoop, Brian Armstrong sits down with host Frank Chaparro to share his thoughts on Coinbase’s new film, including his take on how some of the thornier moments of Coinbase’s history are portrayed.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">As Armstrong explains, he decided to produce the $2 million film because he wanted to “demystify” the ups and downs of taking a company public:<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“I decided to make this film because I wanted to tell the story of what it really is like to create a tech company — all the way from being on your laptop and writing the first few lines of code, to going and becoming a public company.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The film candidly portrays highlights, such as the moments before Coinbase’s public listing, as well as controversies, such as Armstrong <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/79517\/a-question-about-black-lives-matter-sparked-an-employee-walkout-at-coinbase-this-summer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">declining<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> to answer a question about the BLM movement at a company all-hands meeting, as well as Coinbase’s controversial acquisition of Neutrino — a market intelligence firm with members linked to selling spyware to countries like Saudi Arabia, Sudan and Venezuela.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ten-time Emmy-award-winning producer Greg Kohs had full creative control over <\/span><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Coin<\/span><\/i><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, and<\/span> <span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Armstrong himself “didn't have the ability to change anything.”&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">With that being said, Armstrong thinks Kohs accurately represented Coinbase’s story, and he’s happy with how it turned out:<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“He did show people who disagree with us, people who thought that we had made mistakes, but I actually thought it was a very fair take — and so I'm happy with how it turned out.”<\/span>","&nbsp;","<b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors <a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Tron<\/em><\/a><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/em><\/b>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Tron<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/b><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TRON is dedicated to accelerating the decentralization of the internet via blockchain technology and decentralized applications (dApps). Founded in September 2017 by <a href=\"https:\/\/www.hejustinsun.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">H.E. Justin Sun<\/a>, the TRON network has continued to deliver impressive achievements since MainNet launch in May 2018. July 2018 also marked the ecosystem integration of <a href=\"https:\/\/www.bittorrent.com\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BitTorrent<\/a>, a pioneer in decentralized web3 services boasting over 100 million monthly active users. The TRON network completed full decentralization in December 2021 and is now a community-governed DAO. | <a href=\"https:\/\/trondao.org\/hackathon\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">TRONDAO<\/a> | <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/trondao\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Twitter<\/a> | <a href=\"https:\/\/discord.gg\/tron\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Discord<\/a> |<\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Saudi Arabia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Venezuela","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"BitTorrent","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kohs","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"July 2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"BLM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$2 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"December 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Greg Kohs","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Brian Armstrong","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Armstrong","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Friday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"May 2018","content":"DATE"},{"type":"September 2017","content":"DATE"},{"type":"H.E. Justin Sun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Sudan","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["BRIAN ARMSTRONG","COINBASE"],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}