{"summary":"Leading progressives in Congress ask federal financial regulators to account for their ethics rules that limit their staff from going to work in the crypto industry. ","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/179692\/warren-aoc-lead-progressive-letter-to-regulators-on-crypto-industry-revolving-door","publishDate":"2022-10-25T12:12:41","id":9841,"type":null,"title":"AOC, Warren want info from regulators on crypto industry &#x27;revolving door&#x27;","category":["POLICY"],"content":["Several progressive lawmakers want to know if and how financial regulators will cut down on their staff leaving to join crypto industry firms.&nbsp;","\"<span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">We write seeking information about the steps your agency is taking to stop the revolving door <\/span><span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">between our financial regulatory agencies and the cryptocurrency (crypto) industry<\/span>,\" one of the Oct. 24 <a href=\"https:\/\/www.warren.senate.gov\/imo\/media\/doc\/10.24%20Letters%20to%20Regulators%20re%20Crypto%20Revolving%20Door.pdf\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">letters to various financial agencies and government offices reads.<\/a> The inquiries were organized by Sen. Elizabeth Warren, D-Mass. and Rep. Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez, D-N.Y. \"<span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The crypto <\/span><span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">sector has rapidly escalated its lobbying efforts in recent months, spending millions in an attempt <\/span><span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">to secure favorable regulatory outcomes as Congress and federal agencies work to craft and <\/span><span dir=\"ltr\" aria-owns=\"pdfjs_internal_id_24R\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">enforce rules to regulate this multi-trillion dollar industry.\"<\/span>","Joining the letter were Reps. Jesús “Chuy” García, D-Ill., Rashida Tlaib, D-Mich., and Sen. Sheldon Whitehouse, D-R.I.","The group sent the letters, which include requests for information on each agencies ethics rules around officials joining private sector firms with interests at the department or regulator they left. Letters requesting a response by Nov. 7 went to the leaders of the Treasury Department, the Securities and Exchange Commission, the Commodity Futures Trading Commission, the Federal Reserve, the Federal Deposit Insurance Commission, the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency and the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau.&nbsp;","According to the lawmakers, over 200 government officials have left to join the digital asset sector in some capacity, ranging from, \"<span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">advisers, board members, investors, <\/span><span dir=\"ltr\" aria-owns=\"pdfjs_internal_id_30R\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">lobbyists, legal counsel, or in-house executives.\" Citing data from an organization called the Tech Transparency Project, they include 31 Treasury officials, 28 SEC officials, 15 CFTC officials, six Fed officials, five OCC officials, three CFPB officials and two FDIC officials in that tally. Their list also includes eight former members of Congress, 79 former congressional staffers, and 32 former White House officials.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\"Americans should be confident that regulators are <\/span><span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">working on behalf of the public, rather than auditioning for a high-paid lobbying job upon <\/span><span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">leaving government service,\" the lawmakers write. \"The rapidly spinning revolving door out of government and into the <\/span><span dir=\"ltr\" role=\"presentation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">crypto sector, however, undermines both imperatives.\"<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Federal Reserve","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sheldon Whitehouse","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Fed","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"OCC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jesús “Chuy” García","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Nov. 7","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Cortez","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"White House","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Treasury Department","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Oct. 24","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Elizabeth Warren","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Consumer Financial Protection Bureau","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mass.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"N.Y.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Congress","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Alexandria Ocasio","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Ill.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"R.I.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"FDIC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Mich.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Commodity Futures Trading Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tech Transparency Project","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Rashida Tlaib","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"CFTC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Treasury","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Federal Deposit Insurance Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["CFTC","ELIZABETH WARREN","FDIC","OCC","SEC"],"authors":["Kollen Post","The Block"]}