{"summary":"Huobi, which rebranded internationally as HTX, has suffered from lackluster global expansion in past campaigns compared to rival Chinese exchanges, Sun said.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/250931\/justin-sun-hopes-htx-rebrand-will-help-exchange-keep-pace-with-rivals-global-expansion","publishDate":"2023-09-14T03:12:02","id":9847,"type":null,"title":"Justin Sun hopes HTX rebrand will help exchange keep pace with rivals&#x27; global expansion","category":["EXCHANGES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Cryptocurrency exchange Huobi, which <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/250701\/crypto-exchange-huobi-rebrands-to-htx-for-tenth-anniversary\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">launched its new international brand HTX on Wednesday<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">, aims to apply for more licenses in more jurisdictions over the next decade as it continues its global drive, Justin Sun said today.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sun, who styles himself as a global advisor to Huobi, said at a media briefing at Token 2049 in Singapore that HTX will be positioned as Huobi’s international brand that aims to serve its English-speaking user base.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Huobi aims to grow to become more than a “Chinese-dominated” exchange, according to Sun. He said the exchange has already obtained seven licenses globally.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We collaborate with [governments in] Lithuania, Dubai, Australia, Latin American countries, including Argentina and Brazil, to launch the crypto exchange [business] in those regions in a compliant way,” Sun said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“It’s very hard for foreigners, Westerners, to pronounce ‘Huobi’... It doesn’t make any sense to them,” Sun said, explaining that the word Huobi means fire and coin in Chinese. “That’s why we rebranded as HTX for international branding.”<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Huobi, however, remains a brand name for Chinese-speaking regions, according to Sun.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Huobi has launched two major international campaigns in the past but these were not “as successful” as those staged by other China-born exchanges that also tried to go global, Sun said.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sun said that Binance, for example, “also comes from China but succeeded big in globalization” — in large part due to better branding.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Sun also pointed out that Huobi has encountered “zero incidents” since its establishment in 2013 and said the team is highly selective when it comes to listing a new tokens.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Going forward, however, HTX plans to engage more with users to hold votes on which crypto projects should be listed on the exchange, with winners listed, Sun said, adding that this constitutes “democratizing” the listing process.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"2049","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"today","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Lithuania","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2013","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Justin Sun","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Brazil","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"HTX","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Argentina","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Singapore","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Dubai","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Australia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Huobi","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Huobi","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"China","content":"LOCATION"}],"hashtag":["HTX","JUSTIN SUN"],"authors":["Timmy Shen","The Block"]}