{"summary":"Coinbase Head of Exchange Vishal Gupta is leaving the crypto exchange.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/225296\/coinbase-vishal-gupta","publishDate":"2023-04-10T13:17:46","id":9863,"type":null,"title":"Coinbase exchange boss exits company","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">U.S.-based cryptocurrency exchange Coinbase is losing a top executive, with the company’s Head of Exchange <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Vishal Gupta deciding to exit.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Gupta worked at Coinbase for more than two and a half years, according to his <a href=\"https:\/\/www.linkedin.com\/in\/vishalkg\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">LinkedIn page<\/a>. Before transitioning into crypto Gupta spent several years at leading traditional finance powerhouse Goldman Sachs<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"https:\/\/www.bloomberg.com\/news\/articles\/2023-04-10\/coinbase-coin-senior-director-gupta-to-leave-for-new-crypto-project\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Bloomberg<\/a> reported Monday that he is departing to work on a \"new project.\"<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The departure comes during a tumultuous time both for crypto and Coinbase. The industry is reeling amid a string of bankruptcies and bank collapses, while Coinbase has found itself <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/222084\/sec-investigating-coinbase-for-its-earn-product-wallet-service-and-exchange-activity\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">in the crosshairs<\/a> of the Securities and Exchange Commission.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Gupta is not the only high-profile executive to depart the company. Coinbase’s Chief Product Officer Surojit <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Chatterjee <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/182404\/coinbase-cpo-departs-as-exchange-restructures-product-team\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">left the exchange<\/a> earlier this year after announcing his departure in 2022.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Gupta","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Coinbase","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Goldman Sachs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Surojit <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Chatterjee","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2022","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Head of Exchange <\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Vishal Gupta","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Bloomberg","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["RT Watson","The Block"]}