{"summary":"Bitcoin activist Bruce Fenton loses his bid for a seat in the Senate in the New Hampshire primary.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/169980\/new-hampshire-bitcoiner-bruce-fenton-poised-to-finish-fifth-in-senate-primary","publishDate":"2022-09-14T10:24:32","id":987,"type":null,"title":"New Hampshire Bitcoiner Bruce Fenton poised to finish fifth in Senate primary","category":["PEOPLE"],"content":["Though a small percentage of the vote remains outstanding, it's safe to say Bruce Fenton, a former bitcoin activist who spent a substantial amount of his holdings to self-fund a primary campaign emphasizing digital asset issues, will not represent the state of New Hampshire in the U.S. Senate.&nbsp;","With approximately 87% of the vote counted as of publication, Fenton remains in a distant fifth to Donald Bolduc, a former military officer, and Chuck Morse, the state senate president, according to the <a href=\"https:\/\/www.nytimes.com\/interactive\/2022\/09\/13\/us\/elections\/results-new-hampshire.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">New York Times<\/a>. Either Bolduc or Morse will then face Senator Maggie Hassan (D-N.H.), the incumbent and general election favorite.&nbsp;","Fenton self-funded his race for the Senate relying on nearly <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/169115\/bitcoiner-bruce-fenton-mines-senate-race-for-support-in-granite-state?utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_medium=social\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">$1.6 million worth of bitcoin<\/a>.&nbsp;","The former Navy medic-turned-bitcoin activist was the volunteer executive director of the Bitcoin Foundation from 2015 to 2016.&nbsp;","\"I learned a lot, met great people, shared ideas, toured our state &amp; leveled up skills,\" Fenton said in a <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/brucefenton\/status\/1569863926946430976?s=20&amp;t=dwFNcrzAJD8HGX_H0kj1iw\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">tweet<\/a> conceding the election. \"<span class=\"css-901oao css-16my406 r-poiln3 r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Today I go back to work on sound money,\" he said in <a href=\"https:\/\/twitter.com\/brucefenton\/status\/1570038609704534017?s=20&amp;t=dwFNcrzAJD8HGX_H0kj1iw\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">another<\/a>.&nbsp;<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Fenton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2015","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Morse","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2016","content":"DATE"},{"type":"New York Times","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Today","content":"DATE"},{"type":"$1.6 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"87%","content":"PERCENT"},{"type":"Chuck Morse","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Bitcoin Foundation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New Hampshire","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Bruce Fenton","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S. Senate","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Donald Bolduc","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Maggie Hassan","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Senate","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Navy","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BITCOIN"],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}