{"summary":"NFT startup Candy Digital is looking to raise $68 million and has already raised $38.5 million from 14 investors since the start of this year.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/203702\/nft-startup-candy-digital-raised-38-5-million-at-the-start-of-this-year","publishDate":"2023-01-20T04:32:44","id":9875,"type":null,"title":"NFT startup Candy Digital raised $38.5 million at the start of this year","category":["DEALS"],"content":["NFT collectibles startup Candy Digital raised $38.5 million from investors with the first sale occurring on Jan. 3. &nbsp;A U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) <a href=\"https:\/\/www.sec.gov\/Archives\/edgar\/data\/1886975\/000188697523000001\/xslFormDX01\/primary_doc.xml\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">regulatory filing<\/a> shows that the startup had been seeking to raise a total of $68 million with $29.7 million still to be sold to investors.","A total of 14 investors have already participated in this offering, according to the filing.","At the start of the year, the startup closed a Series A1 funding round led by Galaxy Digital and ConsenSys. The raise <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/199477\/fanatics-to-sell-candy-digital-stake-to-galaxy-amid-slumping-nft-market-cnbc\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">enabled<\/a> the company to buy sports merchandising platform Fanatics’ out of its majority stake. The financial terms of the Series A1 raise were not disclosed.","Candy Digital did not respond to request for comment on the raise. It's unclear if the filing is linked to the Series A1 or is for a separate fundraising effort.","The startup is a crypto unicorn having <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/121632\/nft-startup-candy-digital-raises-100-million-in-series-a-round\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">raised<\/a> a $100 million Series A round at $1.5 billion valuation in Oct. 2021. Insight Partners and Softbank Vision Fund co-led the Series A round. Other investors in the startup have <a href=\"https:\/\/www.crunchbase.com\/organization\/candy-digital-d2d1\/company_financials\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">included<\/a> ConsenSys, 10T Holdings, Galaxy Digital and NFL star Peyton Manning.","Founded in the summer of 2021, Candy Digital is company that develops and designs digital collectibles. It has <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/130175\/candy-digital-launches-marketplace-for-major-league-baseball-nfts\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">partnered<\/a> with Major League Baseball, WWE and Getty Images among others for creating premium collectibles. It also runs a platform where collectors can buy and trade the collectibles.","Candy Digital was <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/106771\/fanatics-gary-vaynerchuck-and-mike-novogratz-team-up-to-launch-sports-nft-company\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">originally formed<\/a> by Michael Rubin, CEO of Fanatics; Mike Novogratz, founder and CEO of Galaxy Digital and Gary Vaynerchuk, who is a serial crypto investor.","Late last year, Candy Digital <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/190479\/candy-digital-nft-shop-lays-off-large-number-of-employees-amid-market-deterioration\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">cut<\/a> a significant number of jobs citing challenging market conditions.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Galaxy Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Major League Baseball","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$100 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Peyton Manning","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"$38.5 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"WWE","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$1.5 billion","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"10T Holdings","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Jan. 3","content":"DATE"},{"type":"summer of 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"$68 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"$29.7 million","content":"MONEY"},{"type":"Michael Rubin","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Oct. 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Mike Novogratz","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"NFL","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Gary Vaynerchuk","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Candy Digital","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Softbank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Getty Images","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["SERIES A"],"authors":["Kari McMahon","The Block"]}