{"summary":"Binance opened two new offices in Brazil on Monday.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/174457\/binance-opens-two-new-brazil-offices","publishDate":"2022-10-03T12:41:07","id":988,"type":null,"title":"Binance opens two new Brazil offices","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["Global cryptocurrency exchange Binance has officially opened two offices in Brazil, seeking to extend its reach in the South American country where a spate of companies has added digital asset trading services in recent months.&nbsp;","Binance opened two offices Monday in Brazil's finance hub of São Paulo and its second-largest city of Rio de Janeiro. The exchange's CEO Changpeng Zhao (CZ) announced the plan to open the offices in March, according to a Binance statement. The exchange now has a Brazil-based team comprised of more than 150 people.","Brazil's currency, the real, and broader markets <a href=\"https:\/\/www.reuters.com\/world\/americas\/brazil-election-enters-runoff-bolsonaro-dashes-lulas-hope-quick-win-2022-10-03\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">spiked<\/a> on Monday following news of a presidential runoff vote, following a close race on Sunday between incumbent president Jair Bolsonaro and leftist former president Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva.","Binance, the world's biggest cryptocurrency exchange by trading volume, has been strategically eyeing Brazil for months. Company executives reportedly have <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/147212\/crypto-ceos-are-courting-brazils-central-bank-as-legislation-moves-through-national-congress\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">met<\/a> with government officials, and the exchange <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/137755\/binance-is-eyeing-the-potential-acquisition-of-a-brazilian-securities-brokerage\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">signed<\/a> a memorandum of understanding (MOU) in March to acquire locally-regulated securities brokerage Sim;paul Investimentos. Brazil's central bank is analyzing the deal, Binance said, but further details about its status are unclear.","Separately, the company recently <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/167857\/binance-taps-ex-central-bank-head-economy-minister-of-brazil-as-advisor\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">added<\/a> former Brazilian finance minister Henrique Meirelles to its <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/171979\/binance-sets-up-a-new-global-advisory-board-to-navigate-regulation\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">global<\/a> advisory board.&nbsp;","Brazil is still awaiting broad cryptocurrency regulation as a long-awaited bill sits in the country's lower chamber. However, a wave of high-profile payment apps and digital banks have added digital asset trading services within the past year, including <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/172893\/nubank-logs-nearly-1-8-million-crypto-users-in-brazil\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Nubank<\/a>, Mercado Libre and <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/163885\/btg-pactual-confirms-official-launch-of-brazil-crypto-platform\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">BTG Pactual<\/a>. The country <a href=\"https:\/\/blog.chainalysis.com\/reports\/2022-global-crypto-adoption-index\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">ranked seventh<\/a> on Chainalysis' latest Global Crypto Adoption Index.&nbsp;","Acquiring a locally-regulated entity like Sim;paul would be a strategic move for Binance to grow its offerings Brazil. The company has faced some regulatory scrutiny there, having to <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblockcrypto.com\/news+\/115829\/brazils-public-instant-payment-system-pix-crypto\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">suspend <\/a>futures trading on its Brazilian site in August 2021 after the country's Securities and Exchange Commission (<a href=\"https:\/\/www.gov.br\/cvm\/pt-br\/assuntos\/noticias\/cvm-alerta-sobre-realizacao-de-ofertas-irregulares-d5f0e7dc8b8a4a3b851638dbbe031d60\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CVM<\/span><\/a>) said in <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/70481\/brazil-binance-derivatives-regulators\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">July 2020<\/a> that it was not registered to operate in the Brazilian securities market.","Binance underscored that it \"operates in full compliance with the Brazilian regulatory landscape\" and supports regulation.&nbsp;","Binance has been opening offices around the world in local markets, also announcing Monday that it will expand its <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/174399\/binance-signs-agreement-with-kazakhstan-and-plans-regional-hub\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Kazakhstan location<\/a> as it works to build a regional hub. Binance also revealed a new office in New Zealand on Sept. 29, and has also registered with regulators in countries including France, Italy and Spain.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"New Zealand","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Henrique Meirelles","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"France","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"August 2021","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Sept. 29","content":"DATE"},{"type":"São Paulo","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"BTG Pactual","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Securities and Exchange Commission (<a href=\"https:\/\/www.gov.br\/cvm\/pt-br\/assuntos\/noticias\/cvm-alerta-sobre-realizacao-de-ofertas-irregulares-d5f0e7dc8b8a4a3b851638dbbe031d60\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"s1\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CVM","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"South American","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Monday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Spain","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Italy","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Binance","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Nubank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Sunday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Jair Bolsonaro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"paul Investimentos","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Brazil","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Rio de Janeiro","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"March","content":"DATE"},{"type":"July 2020","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Kazakhstan","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"MOU","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE"],"authors":["Kristin Majcher","The Block"]}