{"summary":"Zodia Markets CEO Usman Ahmad talks about starting out beyond the U.S., and then being essentially forced into the market by demand.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/228727\/zodia-markets-us-crypto","publishDate":"2023-04-28T05:00:54","id":9882,"type":null,"title":"The US crypto market is a must, even with regulatory uncertainty","category":["COMPANIES"],"content":["<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 41<\/i><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/i><\/b><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">of Season 5 of The Scoop was recorded with <strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The Block's Frank Chaparro, and Zodia Markets CEO Usman Ahmad<\/strong><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/strong><\/i>","<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.google.com\/feed\/aHR0cHM6Ly9mZWVkcy5tZWdhcGhvbmUuZm0vdGhlYmxvY2stdGhlc2Nvb3A?sa=X&amp;ved=0CAMQ4aUDahcKEwionbSO9fbxAhUAAAAAHQAAAAAQAg\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Podcasts<\/i><\/a><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">,&nbsp;<\/i><a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/i><\/a>,<i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> or wherever you listen to podcasts. Please send feedback and revision requests to <a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection\" class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"bcccd3d8dfddcfc8fcc8d4d9ded0d3dfd792dfd3\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/a>.<br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/i>","<iframe frameborder=\"0\" height=\"200\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm\/?e=BLOCK4275233627\" width=\"100%\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","Usman Ahmad is the CEO of Zodia Markets, a crypto trading firm that partners with institutions and corporations. Zodia Markets is already registered by the UK’s Financial Conduct Authority and is in late stage conversations with the central bank of Ireland, which with new EU regulation means a passport to Europe. But given demand from the U.S., the firm has <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/228290\/stanchart-startup-us-institutional-demand\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">accelerated its strategy<\/a>.","In this episode, Ahmad talks about Zodia, its evolution and the division of custody.","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">During this episode, Chaparro, and Ahmad also discuss:<\/em>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><b data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">This episode is brought to you by our sponsors <i data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><a href=\"http:\/\/circle.com\/Scoop\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Circle<\/a>&nbsp;and <a href=\"https:\/\/www.cleanspark.com\/theblock\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CleanSpark<\/a>.<\/i><\/b><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><br data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">\n<\/strong><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About Circle<\/strong><\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Circle is a global financial technology company helping money move at internet speed. Our mission is to raise global economic prosperity through the frictionless exchange of value. Visit <a class=\"c-link\" href=\"http:\/\/circle.com\/Scoop\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-stringify-link=\"http:\/\/Circle.com\/Scoop\" data-sk=\"tooltip_parent\" aria-describedby=\"sk-tooltip-398\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">circle.com\/Scoop<\/a> to learn more.<\/em><\/span>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About CleanSpark<\/strong>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">CleanSpark (NASDAQ: CLSK) is America’s Bitcoin Miner™. Visit <a href=\"https:\/\/www.cleanspark.com\/theblock\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">cleanspark.com\/theblock<\/a> to learn more about the CleanSpark way.<\/span><\/em>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"UK’s Financial Conduct Authority","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"EU","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"America","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Europe","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Zodia","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Zodia Markets","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ireland","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Chaparro","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Davis Quinton","Frank Chaparro","The Block"]}