{"summary":"Final Fantasy publisher Square Enix has joined gaming blockchain Oasys as its final initial validator ahead of its public launch later this year.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/169165\/square-enix-becomes-validator-on-gaming-blockchain-oasys","publishDate":"2022-09-12T06:36:01","id":9889,"type":null,"title":"Square Enix becomes validator on gaming blockchain Oasys","category":["GAMING AND METAVERSE"],"content":["Final Fantasy publisher Square Enix has joined gaming blockchain Oasys as its final initial validator ahead of its public launch later this year.","It joins 20 other initial node validators including fellow Japanese gaming giants SEGA and Bandai Namco, as well as Ubisoft, Yield Guild Games, WeMade, NEOWIZ, Netmarble and Com2Us.","According to a statement from the company, the two also plan to explore the feasibility of harnessing user contributions in the development of new games on the Oasys blockchain.","Square Enix said earlier this year that exploring the development of decentralized games would be a major strategic theme for the company going forward. In April, it launched its own Blockchain Entertainment Business division.","Square Enix and its fellow gaming validators join other web2 gaming giants that are interested in blockchain. Epic Games announced in June it would have its <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/150444\/epic-games-store-will-host-its-first-web3-game-this-year\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">first blockchain game<\/a> on its store later this year. More recently, it funded Animoca Brands subsidiary Grease Monkey Games to develop a blockchain-based play-to-earn racing game.","Despite some bigger players testing the waters, other gaming studios remain hostile to blockchain. Square Enix's latest announcement comes shortly on the heels of Minecraft makers Mojang Studios <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/158759\/minecraft-developer-mojang-to-restrict-use-of-nfts-blockchain-tech-with-guideline-update\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">rolling back access<\/a> to its platform for NFT-linked projects.","Statements from gaming leaders such as Valve president Gabe Newell and Microsoft's gaming CEO Phil Spencer have also been critical of blockchain gaming. Speaking last month, the latter suggested <a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/166164\/microsoft-gaming-ceo-phil-spencer-gets-why-some-gamers-dont-like-the-metaverse\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">gamers don't get the metaverse<\/a> because proponents advocate so-called \"new\" technologies that have actually existed for years.&nbsp;","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Yield Guild Games","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Phil Spencer","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"SEGA","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Square Enix","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Netmarble","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Enix","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Blockchain Entertainment Business","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"NFT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Animoca Brands","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Oasys","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ubisoft","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"June","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Microsoft","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bandai Namco","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"earlier this year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Gabe Newell","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Mojang Studios","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"April","content":"DATE"}],"hashtag":["VALIDATORS"],"authors":["Callan Quinn","The Block"]}