{"summary":"In an episode of The Scoop, legendary macro investor Raoul Pal joins The Block&#x27;s Frank Chaparro and Ryan Todd to examine the current macro backdrop.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/62148\/macro-investor-raoul-pal-fed-coronavirus","publishDate":"2020-04-16T17:13:01","id":9892,"type":null,"title":"Macro investor Raoul Pal says the Fed is just &#x27;papering up the cracks&#x27; of the coronavirus crisis","category":["BITCOIN"],"content":["<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Episode 13 of Season 2 of The Scoop was recorded remotely with Frank Chaparro, Ryan Todd and Raoul Pal, CEO and founder of Real Vision.&nbsp;<\/em>","<em data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Listen below, and subscribe to The Scoop on&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/podcasts.apple.com\/us\/podcast\/the-scoop\/id1460134454\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Apple<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/open.spotify.com\/show\/7qwrgTJ5CYDXAaVILNZuEd\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Spotify<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/play.google.com\/music\/m\/Imy3oaraedpu5huu2r7nf3pxhry?t=The_Scoop\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Google Play<\/a>,&nbsp;<a href=\"https:\/\/www.stitcher.com\/podcast\/the-block-2\/the-scoop-4\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Stitcher<\/a>, or wherever you listen to podcasts. Email feedback and revision requests to&nbsp;<a href=\"\/cdn-cgi\/l\/email-protection#275748434446545367534f42454b48444c44555e5753480944484a\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener noreferrer\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span class=\"__cf_email__\" data-cfemail=\"15657a717674666155617d7077797a767e76676c65617a3b767a78\">[email&nbsp;protected]<\/span><\/a><\/em>","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" src=\"https:\/\/playlist.megaphone.fm?e=BLOCK4142085661\" width=\"100%\" height=\"200\" frameborder=\"0\" scrolling=\"no\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","The Federal Reserve and the U.S. government are working aggressively to implement policies aimed at addressing the financial crisis triggered by COVID-19 and the economic impact of the societal shutdown.","Americans across the country have begun receiving stimulus checks to recoup lost income. Meanwhile, the Fed has said that it would serve as a backstop for the junk bond market, announcing – for the first time – purchases of corporate bonds, including those in junk territory.&nbsp;","Such actions have triggered a cavalcade of critics, some of whom argue the stimulus doesn't go far enough to address mounting unemployment. Others say the Fed's actions could result in a surge in inflation.","In an episode of The Scoop, Raoul Pal – legendary macro investor and founder of Real Vision joins The Block's Frank Chaparro and Ryan Todd to examine the current macro backdrop.","Pal argues that the impact of COVID-19 on consumer of behavior – including a dip in spending on concerts and restaurants – is not being truly appreciated by the markets.","In this episode, we also explore:","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Raoul Pal","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Federal Reserve","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ryan Todd","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"U.S.","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Spotify","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Fed","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"19","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Apple","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Google","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"The Scoop","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Frank Chaparro","Ryan Todd","The Block"]}