{"summary":"On August 26th at 12pm ET \/ 9am PT, Frank Chaparro will be joined by industry executives exploring the state of institutional spot liquidity within digital assets.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/75402\/the-block-presents-the-state-of-institutional-spot-liquidity-brought-to-you-by-altonomy","publishDate":"2020-08-19T20:06:00","id":9930,"type":null,"title":"The Block Presents: The State of Institutional Spot Liquidity - Brought to you by Altonomy","category":["THE BLOCK"],"content":["On August 26th at 12pm ET \/ 9am PT, Frank Chaparro will be joined by industry executives exploring the state of institutional spot liquidity within digital assets.","You can learn about the panelists and register for the webinar below:","<iframe loading=\"lazy\" title=\"The Block Presents: Institutional Spot Liquidity -- Brought to you by Altonomy | The Block\" src=\"https:\/\/app.livestorm.co\/p\/5e065f7c-fcb8-4c70-a294-6a5d6388ec14\/form\" width=\"100%\" height=\"360\" frameborder=\"0\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><\/iframe>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">About the Panelists:<\/strong>","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Ricky Li, Co-Founder of Altonomy<\/strong>","Ricky Li, Co-founder of Altonomy. Now based in New York, he is a veteran trader in the cryptocurrency market and traditional commodities markets. Li holds a CFA Charter and Ph.D. in Computer Science from Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute.","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Meltem Demirors, Chief Strategy Officer, CoinShare<\/strong>","Meltem Demirors is Chief Strategy Officer of CoinShare, an investment firm that manages hundreds of millions in assets on behalf of a global investor base, and is a trusted partner to investors and entrepreneurs navigating the digital asset ecosystem. Meltem oversees the firm’s managed strategies group and its New York office, and leads corporate development as a board director. Previously, she was part of the founding team of Digital Currency Group. She teaches at MIT and Oxford, and serves on the WEF Blockchain Council.","<strong data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Daniel Matuszewski, Partner, CMS Holdings<\/strong>","Daniel Matuszewski is a tenured industry expert, starting his career at Kraken, followed by Circle Trade. Dan is currently co-founder and partner at CMS holdings.","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"CMS","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"August 26th","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Oxford","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Daniel Matuszewski","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"CFA Charter","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Digital Currency Group","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Kraken","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"New York","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Circle Trade","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"MIT","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Computer Science","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"WEF Blockchain Council","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CMS Holdings","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Ricky Li","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Frank Chaparro","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Sponsored","The Block"]}