{"summary":"Marie-Anne Barbat-Layani, a former banking lobbyist, received the green light from the two houses of the French parliament to lead the nation’s Financial","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/178272\/new-chief-appointed-for-french-financial-regulator","publishDate":"2022-10-19T06:52:01","id":9964,"type":null,"title":"New chief appointed for French financial regulator","category":["REGULATION"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Marie-Anne Barbat-Layani, a former banking lobbyist, received the green light from the two houses of the French parliament to lead the nation’s Financial Markets Authority (autorité des marchés financiers) on Wednesday. Her role will include overseeing the registration of crypto firms in France.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Barbat-Layani begins her non-renewable, five-year term after a vote of 20 in favor, one against in the Senate, and 35 to 27 in the National Assembly. She will replace Robert Ophèle, whose term came to a close at the end of July.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Barbat-Layani has worked in both the public sector – including a post as a financial attaché in France's permanent representation office for the European Union (EU) – and in the private sector, notably as the managing director of the French Banking Federation.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The French finance authority has previously expressed great interest in the EU’s comprehensive Markets in Crypto-Assets legislation for the regulation of cryptocurrencies and service providers, which will most likely roll out in 2024.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The provisions under MiCA are \"all the more necessary since the French system for registering service providers on digital assets is showing its limits,” the AMF <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.actu-juridique.fr\/breves\/droit-financier\/rapport-annuel-de-lamf-point-detape-sur-la-strategie-supervision2022\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">said<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> in a statement in May.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In the last month, France saw one of its major banks, Société Générale, <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/177478\/france-approves-its-third-biggest-bank-to-operate-digital-asset-services\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">obtain<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> regulatory approval to operate as a digital asset service provider. Crypto exchanges <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/linked\/145117\/france-approves-binance-to-operate-digital-asset-trading-services\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Binance<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> and <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/173312\/crypto-com-wins-approval-to-operate-in-france\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Crypto.com<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> also saw their registration approved this year.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">While France is taking steps towards creating a fintech-friendly hub, Barbat-Layani also warned that crypto firms can also have their licenses taken away, as an integral feature of the system, CoinDesk <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.coindesk.com\/policy\/2022\/10\/19\/french-lawmakers-approve-new-boss-for-finance-watchdog\/?utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=rss&amp;utm_campaign=headlines\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">reported<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Paris-based crypto service provider, Bykep, had its registration with the AMF <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.amf-france.org\/en\/news-publications\/news-releases\/amf-and-acpr-announce-withdrawal-bykeps-sass-registration-dasp\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">withdrawn<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> due to “failure” to comply with anti-money laundering provisions on September 27. However, their LinkedIn page highlights their registration with the AMF.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"France","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"May","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Barbat","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Paris","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Anne Barbat","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"EU","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"July","content":"DATE"},{"type":"French Banking Federation","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"fintech","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Robert Ophèle","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Wednesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"September 27","content":"DATE"},{"type":"last month","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Crypto","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"AMF","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Marie","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"2024","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Société Générale","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"European Union (EU","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"CoinDesk","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"National Assembly","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Bykep","content":"LOCATION"},{"type":"Layani","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Senate","content":"ORGANIZATION"}],"hashtag":["BINANCE"],"authors":["Inbar Preiss","The Block"]}