{"summary":"The challenger bank says it is building a “war chest for acquisitions”.","webName":"theblock.co","link":"https:\/\/www.theblock.co\/post\/143560\/starling-bank-raises-130-5-million-at-2-5-billion-evaluation","publishDate":"2022-04-26T08:30:47","id":9973,"type":null,"title":"Starling Bank raises £130.5 million at £2.5 billion valuation","category":["STARTUPS"],"content":["<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">UK-based challenger bank Starling Bank has completed a £130.5 million internal fundraising round at a £2.5 billion valuation.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">The funding came from existing investors Fidelity Management and Research Company, RPMI Railpen, Qatar Investment Authority, Goldman Sachs and Harald McPike.<\/span><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In a statement on Tuesday, the company said the money would enable it to continue growth and “build a war chest for acquisitions.”&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">“We are looking at a number of potential targets,\" a spokesperson added.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Although the bank declined to go into specifics about targets, The Block understands that Starling Bank is interested in acquiring lenders, and is currently looking at specialist lender Kensington Mortgages. This Is Money <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.thisismoney.co.uk\/money\/markets\/article-10444787\/Barclays-bid-mortgage-firm-Kensington-race-Starling.html\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">first reported<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> Starling’s interest in the business in January.&nbsp;<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">Starling Bank was founded in 2014 by Anne Boden as an alternative bank account provider. Boden has previously said that the company aims to go public by 2023.<\/span>","<span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">In July last year, Starling Bank <\/span><a href=\"https:\/\/www.starlingbank.com\/news\/starling-bank-acquires-mortgage-lender-fleet-mortgages\/\" data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\">acquired<\/span><\/a><span data-v-f87c67ca=\"\"> buy-to-let mortgages lender Fleet Mortgages in a £50 million cash and share deal.<\/span>","© 2023 The Block. All Rights Reserved. This article is provided for informational purposes only. It is not offered or intended to be used as legal, tax, investment, financial, or other advice."],"entity":[{"type":"Qatar Investment Authority","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"2014","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Anne Boden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"2023","content":"DATE"},{"type":"January","content":"DATE"},{"type":"July last year","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Fidelity Management and Research Company","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"RPMI Railpen","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Goldman Sachs","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Tuesday","content":"DATE"},{"type":"Starling Bank","content":"ORGANIZATION"},{"type":"Starling","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Boden","content":"PERSON"},{"type":"Harald McPike","content":"PERSON"}],"hashtag":[],"authors":["Callan Quinn","The Block"]}